<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="STS.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?><xml>
    <sts stsNum="003">STS-3</sts>
    <mission type="test" org="nasa">Mission: Third Shuttle Mission/Office of Space Science-1 (OSS-1)</mission>
    <orbiter oName="columbia">Space Shuttle: Columbia</orbiter>
    <launchPad sBase="kennedySpaceCenter" padNum="39A">Launch Pad: 39A</launchPad>
    <launch sDateTime="1982-03-22T11:00:00">Launched: March 22, 1982 at 11:00:00 a.m. EST</launch>
    <landPad eBase="whiteSands">Landing Site: White Sands, New Mexico</landPad>
    <land eDateTime="1982-03-30T09:04:46">Landing: March 30, 1982 at 9:04:46 a.m. MST</land>
    <duration time="P8DT4M46S">Mission Duration: 8 days, 0 hours, 4 minutes and 46 seconds</duration>
    <altitude alt="147">Orbit Altitude: 147 nautical miles</altitude>
    <inclination deg="38">Orbit Inclination: 38.0 degrees</inclination>
    
    <desc cargo="none">Testing continued of space shuttle systems for qualification for operational flights. Testing of remote manipulator system and measurements of thermal response of orbiter in various attitudes to sun conducted. Get Away Special test canister and Spacelab pallet-mounted experiments for NASA's Office of Space Science-1 (OSS-1) carried in payload bay. OSS-1 obtained data on near-Earth space environment, including contamination (gases, dust, etc.) introduced into space by orbiter itself. Other experiments: Monodisperse Latex Reactor (MLR), Electrophoresis Equipment Verification Test (EEVT), Heflex Bioengineering Test (HBT) and first Shuttle Student Involvement Program (SSIP) experiment. Problems encountered: space sickness, malfunctioning toilet, thermostat difficulty and unexplained static interfering with crew sleep. Auxiliary power unit registered overheating during ascent, but functioned properly during descent. Three communications links were lost.
    
        Crew consisted of Commander Jack R. Lousma and Pilot C. Gordon Fullerton.</desc>
</xml>