<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="STS.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?><xml>
    <sts stsNum="074">STS-74</sts>
    <mission type="test" org="nasa">Mission: Second Shuttle-Mir Docking</mission>
    <orbiter oName="atlantis">Space Shuttle: Atlantis</orbiter>
    <launchPad sBase="kennedySpaceCenter" padNum="39A">Launch Pad: 39A</launchPad>
    <launch sDateTime="1995-11-12T07:30:43.071">Launched: November 12, 1995 at 7:30:43.071 a.m. EST</launch>
    <landPad eBase="kennedySpaceCenter">Landing Site: Kennedy Space Center, Florida</landPad>
    <land eDateTime="1995-11-20T12:01:27">Landing: November 20, 1995 at 12:01:27 p.m. EST</land>
    <duration time="P8DT4H30M44S">Mission Duration: 8 days, 4 hours, 30 minutes, 44 seconds</duration>
    <altitude alt="213">Orbit Altitude: 213 nautical miles</altitude>
    <inclination deg="51.6">Orbit Inclination: 51.6 degrees</inclination>
    
    <desc cargo="ODS">STS-74 marked second docking of U.S. Space Shuttle to Russian Space Station Mir, continuing Phase I activities leading to construction of International Space Station later this decade. Mission illustrated international flavor of space station effort: shuttle crew included Hadfield, fourth Canadian to fly on shuttle but first Canadian mission specialist. Hardware in payload bay included Canadian-built Remote Manipulator System (RMS) arm, U.S.-built Orbiter Docking System (ODS), Russian-built docking module and solar array and U.S.-Russian-built solar array. Awaiting Atlantis aboard Mir were two Russian cosmonauts and a German cosmonaut, along with Russian and European Space Agency research samples and equipment.
    
    Unlike first docking flight during which crew exchange took place, second docking focused on delivery of equipment to Mir. Primary payload of mission was Russian-built Docking Module (DM), designed to become permanent extension on Mir to afford better clearances for Shuttle-Mir linkups. Two solar arrays were stowed on DM for later transfer to Mir by spacewalking cosmonauts.
    
    Crew consisted of Commander Kenneth D. Cameron, Pilot James D. Halsell Jr., Mission Specialists Jerry L. Ross, William S. McArthur Jr. and Chris A. Hadfield.</desc>
    
</xml>