<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="STS.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?><xml>
    <sts stsNum="075">STS-75</sts>
    <mission type="satLaunch" org="nasa">Mission: TSS-1R; USMP-3</mission>
    <orbiter oName="columbia">Space Shuttle: Columbia</orbiter>
    <launchPad sBase="kennedySpaceCenter" padNum="39B">Launch Pad: 39B</launchPad>
    <launch sDateTime="1996-02-22T15:18:00">Launched: February 22, 1996, 3:18:00 p.m. EST</launch>
    <landPad eBase="kennedySpaceCenter">Landing Site: Kennedy Space Center, Florida</landPad>
    <land eDateTime="1996-03-09T08:58:21">Landing: March 9, 1996, 8:58:21 a.m. EST</land>
    <duration time="P15DT17H41M25S">Mission Duration: 15 days, 17 hours, 41 minutes, 25 seconds</duration>
    <altitude alt="160">Orbit Altitude: 160 nautical miles</altitude>
    <inclination deg="28.45">Orbit Inclination: 28.45 degrees</inclination>
    
    <desc cargo="TSS-1R, USMP-3">Reflight of U.S./Italian Tethered Satellite System (TSS-1R) marred by loss of satellite on flight day three, although valuable scientific data was still gathered. Other primary payload, U.S. Microgravity Payload-3 (USMP-3), performed nominally. TSS considered primary payload at beginning of mission and USMP-3 primary following TSS operations.
    
    TSS flew previously on Mission STS-46 in June 1992, but experiment operations curtailed due to jammed tether. TSS concept designed to study electrodynamics of a tether system in electrically charged portion of Earth's atmosphere called the ionosphere. Satellite provided by Italy and tether/deployer assembly U.S.-built. Twelve investigations — six NASA, five Italian Space Agency (ASI) and one U.S. Air Force — planned. Deployment of TSS-1R on STS-75 delayed one day to allow troubleshooting of onboard TSS computers by flight crew. Excellent scientific data was being gathered when tether snapped on flight day three as satellite was just short of full deployment of about 12.8 miles (20.6 kilometers). Satellite immediately began speeding away from orbiter as a result of orbital forces and the crew was never in any danger. Reason for tether break not immediately clear and investigative board convened on ground to determine cause. Crew retracted deployer and remaining tether following day.
    
    Meanwhile, scientists did gather useful data from curtailed deployment. Some experiments conducted using free-flying satellite and attached tether before it re-entered Earth's atmosphere and broke up.
    
    Crew consisted of Commander Andrew M. Allen, Pilot Scott J. Horowitz, Payload Commander Franklin R. Chang-Diaz, Mission Specialists Maurizio Cheli, Jeffrey A. Hoffman, Claude Nicollier and Umberto Guidoni.</desc>
    
</xml>