<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="STS.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?><xml>
    <sts stsNum="084">STS-84</sts>
    <mission type="crewTransfer" org="nasa">Mission: Sixth Shuttle-Mir Docking</mission>
    <orbiter oName="atlantis">Space Shuttle: Atlantis</orbiter>
    <launchPad sBase="kennedySpaceCenter" padNum="39A">Launch Pad: 39A</launchPad>
    <launch sDateTime="1997-05-15T04:07:48">Launched: May 15, 1997 4:07:48 a.m. EDT</launch>
    <landPad eBase="kennedySpaceCenter">Landing Site: Kennedy Space Center, Florida</landPad>
    <land eDateTime="1997-05-24T09:27:44">Landing: May 24, 1997, 9:27:44 a.m. EDT</land>
    <duration time="P9DT23H19M56S">Mission Duration: 9 days, 23 hours, 19 minutes, 56 seconds</duration>
    <altitude alt="184">Orbit Altitude: 184 statute miles</altitude>
    <inclination deg="51.6">Orbit Inclination: 51.6 degrees</inclination>
    
    <desc cargo="supplies">Sixth Shuttle-Mir docking highlighted by transfer of fourth successive U.S. crew member to the Russian Space Station. U.S. astronaut Mike Foale exchanged places with Jerry Linenger, who arrived at Mir Jan. 15 with the crew of shuttle mission STS-81.
    
    Transfer of items to and from Mir proceeded smoothly and was completed ahead of schedule. One of first items transferred to the station was an Elektron oxygen-generating unit. Altogether about 249 items were moved between the two spacecraft, and about 1,000 pounds of water moved to Mir, for a total of about 7,500 pounds of water, experiment samples, supplies and hardware.
    
    Other activities conducted during the mission included investigations using the Biorack facility, located in the SPACEHAB Double Module in Atlantis' payload bay, a photo survey of Mir during docked operations, environmental air samplings and radiation monitoring.
    
    Crew consisted of Commander James D. Halsell, Pilot Susan L. Still, Payload Commander Janice E. Voss, Mission Specialists Donald A. Thomas, Michael L. Gernhardt, Payload Specialists Roger Crouch and Greg Linteris.</desc>
    
</xml>