<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="STS.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?><xml>
    <sts stsNum="41D">STS-41D</sts>
    <mission type="satLaunch" org="nasa">Mission: SBS-D; Satellite Business System SYNCOM IV-2; Solar Wing TELSTAR</mission>
    <orbiter oName="discovery">Space Shuttle: Discovery</orbiter>
    <launchPad sBase="kennedySpaceCenter" padNum="39A">Launch Pad: 39A</launchPad>
    <launch sDateTime="1984-08-30T08:41:50">Launched: August 30, 1984 at 8:41:50 a.m. EDT</launch>
    <landPad eBase="edwardsAirForceBase">Landing Site: Edwards Air Force Base, Calif.</landPad>
    <land eDateTime="1984-09-05T06:37:54">Landing: September 5, 1984 at 6:37:54 a.m. PDT</land>
    <duration time="P6DT56M4S">Mission Duration: 6 days, 0 hours, 56 minutes, 4 seconds</duration>
    <altitude alt="184">Orbit Altitude: 184 nautical miles</altitude>
    <inclination deg="28.5">Orbit Inclination: 28.5 degrees</inclination>
    
    <desc cargo="SBS-D, SYNCOM IV-2, TELSTAR">Three satellites deployed during this mission: Satellite Business System SBS-D, SYNCOM IV-2 (also known as LEASAT2) and TELSTAR. The 102-foot-tall, 13-foot-wide Office of Application and Space Technology (OAST-1) solar wing extended from the payload bay. The wing carried different types of solar cells and extended to its full height several times. It demonstrated large lightweight solar arrays for a future in building large facilities in space such as a space station. Other payloads included were: Continuous Flow Electrophoresis System (CFES) Ill; Radiation Monitoring Equipment (RME); Shuttle Student Involvement Program (SSIP) experiment; lMAX camera, being flown for a second time; and an Air Force experiment, Cloud Logic to Optimize Use of Defense Systems (CLOUDS).
    
    Crew consisted of Commander Henry W. Hartsfield, Jr., Pilot Michael L. Coats, Mission Specialists Judith A. Resnick, Steven A. Hawley, Richard M. Mullane and Payload Specialist Charles D. Walker.</desc>
    
</xml>