<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="STS.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?><xml>
    <sts stsNum="61A">STS-61A</sts>
    <mission type="spacelabConstruct" org="nasa">Mission:D-1 Spacelab Mission (First German Dedicated Spacelab)</mission>
    <orbiter oName="challenger">Space Shuttle: Challenger</orbiter>
    <launchPad sBase="kennedySpaceCenter" padNum="39A">Launch Pad: 39A</launchPad>
    <launch sDateTime="1985-10-30T12:00:00">Launched: October 30, 1985, 12:00:00 p.m. EST</launch>
    <landPad eBase="edwardsAirForceBase">Landing Site: Edwards Air Force Base, Calif.</landPad>
    <land eDateTime="1985-11-06T09:44:53">Landing: November 6, 1985, 9:44:53 a.m. PST</land>
    <duration time="P7DT44M51S">Mission Duration: 7 days, 0 hours, 44 minutes, 51 seconds</duration>
    <altitude alt="207">Orbit Altitude: 207 nautical miles</altitude>
    <inclination deg="57">Orbit Inclination: 57 degrees</inclination>
    
    <desc cargo="spacelab d-1">The dedicated German Spacelab (D-1) mission was conducted in a long module configuration, which featured a Vestibular Sled designed to give scientists data on the functional organization of human vestibular and orientation systems. Spacelab D-1 encompassed 75 numbered experiments, most performed more than once. The mission included basic and applied microgravity research in fields of materials science, life sciences and technology, and communications and navigation. Though the orbiter was controlled from Johnson Space Center, scientific operations were controlled from the German Space Operations Center at Oberpfaffenhofen, near Munich. Other objectives: Global Low Orbiting Message Relay (GLOMR) satellite deployed from Get Away Special canister.
    
    Crew consisted of Commander Henry W. Hartsfield, Jr., Pilot Steven R. Nagel, Mission Specialists James F. Buchli, Guion S. Bluford, Bonnie J. Dunbar and Payload Specialists Reinhard Furrer, Ernst Messerschmid and Wubbo J. Ockels.</desc>
    
    
    
    
</xml>