<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="STS.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?><xml>
    <sts stsNum="61B">STS-61B</sts>
    <mission type="satLaunch" org="business">Mission: MORELOS-B; AUSSAT-2; SATCOM KU-2</mission>
    <orbiter oName="atlantis">Space Shuttle: Atlantis</orbiter>
    <launchPad sBase="kennedySpaceCenter" padNum="39A">Launch Pad: 39A</launchPad>
    <launch sDateTime="1985-11-26T19:29:00">Launched: November 26, 1985, 7:29:00 p.m. EST</launch>
    <landPad eBase="edwardsAirForceBase">Landing Site: Edwards Air Force Base, Calif.</landPad>
    <land eDateTime="1985-12-03T13:33:49">Landing: December 3, 1985, 1:33:49 p.m. PST</land>
    <duration time="P6DT21H4M49S">Mission Duration: 6 days, 21 hours, 4 minutes, 49 seconds</duration>
    <altitude alt="225">Orbit Altitude: 225 nautical miles</altitude>
    <inclination deg="57">Orbit Inclination: 57 degrees</inclination>
    
    <desc cargo="MORE LOS-B, AUSSAT-2,SATCOM KU-2">Three communications satellites were deployed: MORE LOS-B (Mexico), AUSSAT-2 (Australia) and SATCOM KU-2 (RCA Americom). MORELOS-B and AUSSAT-2 were attached to the Payload Assist Module-D motors, SATCOM KU-2 to a PAM-D2 designed for heavier payloads. Two experiments were conducted to test assembling erectable structures in space: Experimental Assembly of Structures in Extravehicular Activity (EASE) and Assembly Concept for Construction of Erectable Space Structure (ACCESS). The experiments required two space walks by Spring and Ross lasting five hours, 32 minutes, and six hours, 38 minutes, respectively. Middeck payloads: Continuous Flow Electrophoresis System (CFES); Diffusive Mixing of Organic Solutions (DMOS); Morelos Payload Specialist Experiments (MPSE) and Orbiter Experiments (OEX). In payload bay: Get Away Special and IMAX Cargo Bay Camera (ICBC).
    
    Crew consisted of Commander Brewster H. Shaw, Jr., Pilot Bryan D. O'Connor, Mission Specialists Mary L. Cleave, Sherwood C. Spring, Jerry L. Ross and Payload Specialists Rodolfo Neri Vela and Charles D. Walker.</desc>
    
    
    
</xml>