<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<listBibl><bibl><author>Perry, James</author><title>Mimosa: or, The sensitive plant; A poem. Dedicated to Mr. Banks, and addressed to
            Kitt Frederick, Dutchess of Queensberry, Elect.</title><editor/><publisher/><pubPlace>London</pubPlace><date> 1779</date><note> This publication is a poem about the Mimosa plant, discovered on Otaheite. In the
            dedication to this poem, author James Perry speaks to Mr. Banks, imploring him to spread
            the word about this plant and its many significant properties. </note></bibl><bibl><author>Various</author><title>The fugitive miscellany. Being a collection of such fugitive pieces, in prose and
            verse, as are not in any other collection. With many pieces never before published. </title><editor/><publisher/><pubPlace>London</pubPlace><date>1774</date><note>At the end of this compilation, a list of "Lately Published" is featured. One of these
            is listed as "An Epistle from OBEREA, Queen of Otaheite, to Joseph Banks, Esq" which is
            translated by T.Q.Z. Esq. who was, at the time, professor of the Otehiete language in
            Dublin.</note></bibl><bibl><author>Fitzgerald, Gerald.</author><title>The injured islanders, or the influence of art upon the happiness of nature: a
            poetical epistle from Oberea of Otaheite to Captain Wallis. By the ...</title><editor/><publisher/><pubPlace>Dublin</pubPlace><date> 1779</date><note> The author of this poem takes on the persona of Oberea of Otaheite in address to
            Captain Wallis, speaking of how her way of living has been completely transformed by her
            being in contact with Wallis and Cook.</note></bibl><bibl><author><!-- MISSING --></author><title>Omiah's farewell; inscribed to the ladies of London.</title><editor><!-- MISSING --></editor><publisher>printed for G. Kearsly, in Fleet-Street, MDCCLXXVI.</publisher><pubPlace>London</pubPlace><date>1776</date><note> This is a poem in epistolary form from the native Omiah to the ladies of London. The
            preface details the purpose and context of this poem: Omiah is to return home to
            Otaheite.</note></bibl><bibl><author>Alexander, William</author><title>The history of women, from the earliest antiquity, to the present time; giving some
            account of almost every interesting particular concerning ... </title><title/><editor><!-- MISSING --> &gt;</editor><publisher>London : printed for W. Strahan, and T. Cadell, in the Strand,
            MDCCLXXIX</publisher><pubPlace>London</pubPlace><date>1783</date><note>This publication goes into detail about many different cultural aspects of Tahitian women. </note></bibl></listBibl>