<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="comments_schema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<media source="nbcNews" category="">
    <title>joan Rivers' Doctors' Failed to Identify Deteorating Vital Signs'</title>
    <mainContent>
        <link>http://entertainment.nbcnews.com/_news/2014/11/10/26581600-state-joan-rivers-doctors-failed-to-identify-deteriorating-vital-signs?lite</link>
        <author>Maria Elena Fernandez</author>
        <description>DISCUSSIONS
            21 comments from 17 people</description>
        <statistics>
            <subscribers>0</subscribers>
            <views>0</views>
            <likes>0</likes>
            <dislikes>0</dislikes>
            <totalComments>21</totalComments>
            <publishDate>Monday November 10, 2014</publishDate>
        </statistics>
    </mainContent>
    <commentSection>
        <comment tone="neutral">
            <commenter>DudetteOne</commenter>
            <sentence structure="good">There was speculation when she died of a relatively "routine" surgery that someone who didn't like her jokes and political views may have had something to do with it. Of course all surgery is risky, and given her age, there was more risk. But anyone who wished her gone could've assumed that would deflect any investigation. I don't think she was "done in". What do you think?</sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="negative">
            <commenter>Amused In The Midwest</commenter>
            <sentence structure="good">Meaning Ms. Rivers will now sue the whizz out of the medical facility enriching herself and her attorneys, but mostly her attorneys.  This will do little to ensure that a mistake never happens again, if in reality, a mistake happened.</sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="negative">
            <commenter>Der Scherzfragaer</commenter>
            <sentence structure="good">Who<expunc>??</expunc> She's already forgotten.</sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="negative">
            <commenter>Kristen St.Clair</commenter>
            <sentence structure="good"><acronym>Omg</acronym>! My mouth is on the floor reading this! Bottom line. This clinic, it appears, suffers from not one oversight but a grotesque array of issues that push the border on non-compliance to a new low. Wow. Just Wow. The individuals involved in this procedure need to reach around and cop a good feel of their unravaged anal tissues because it's about to be scathed with hellish pursuit. And rightfully so!
                Foremost; what was going on in that procedure room. I am a critical care registered nurse to lay out my credentials, for my assessment of what went wrong if I'm to read into this story correctly...
                Strike one. No consent! Informed Consent wasn't obtained. <acronym>Omg</acronym>! You didn't even have her legal permission! Wow!
                Strike two. Who are all these people in the procedure room<expunc>!!!</expunc> What a nightmare! She will give you an autograph sowhen she wakes up! <acronym>Omg</acronym>. That's horrifyinonto many levels. People gawking at you while your unconscious<expunc>!!!!!</expunc> Who knows what they were doing, but it's unnerving at best.
                Strike three. How many ENTs does it take to screw in a light bulb<expunc>?!</expunc>
                2/3...or two and a third unpreviledged bloak to be exact. This whole procedure in my mind is this grotesque charade with people taking selfies at the patients bedside. It's after they have had too much fun and overlook her during this absolutely critical time that they bottom out her vitals, from an undoubted overdose of propofol. This along with no compensary or standby hemodynamic support is what caused her death. In layman's terms. They bottomed her vitals out on the sedation (which caused the decrease in BP). They could have easily corrected an over<expunc>-... </expunc>I'll say versus dosage due to misconception of the term. Give her some norepinephrine and stabilize the pressure before proceeding any further. But this isn't done. She bottoms out and we now have a critical condition which should have never happened. This clinic messed up big time. The discrepancy in medical documentation comes from no one person being in charge of this whole nightmare scenario. If there was, they did a pathetic job. No one knows how much propofol was administered?! Who is pushing drugs on her and why?! Where is her nurse?! You better be sure if she were my patient. No one beťter come near her with a syringe of anything without knowledge or immediate say so. This is why I ask. Who was in charge of 'her'. It appears no one was. It is semi the doctors fault, I mean legally it will be them because they<expunc>...</expunc> Geez. Well technically they didn't even assume liability because they don't have a legal consent. <acronym>Smdh</acronym>! So it seems some doctors (3 of them) are shouting out separate orders, no one in charge, in a room full of nonliscensed and licensed personel (who knows who was in there) . It's a wonder this place has even had its door opened this long before this type of situation occurred. It's an awful mess. All the power to the family and state and other regulatory agencies (OSHA and JACHO) who are going to go after this tip top group<expunc>...</expunc> They deserve it. So reach back and cop a good feel ladies and gents <expunc>...</expunc> They are coming.</sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="negative">
            <commenter>Ann-3468510</commenter>
            <sentence structure="good">Joan died of greed, vanity and old age. period! Who could save that wretch anyway wasn't she like back from the dead a few times too many anyway.</sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="negative">
            <commenter>fireflyva</commenter>
            <sentence structure="good">After 15 years working in hospitals, I can say that this happens so much more frequently than people would believe. I know that this took place in a free standing clinic but it is still very similar to a hospital. Hospitals and doctors do their best to cover it up, and if they can't, both the hospital and doctor(s) then try and locate someone lower on the food chain to blame. Then, if that doesn't work, the hospital and doctors turn on one another. The point to this is that when a physician is actually held accountable it's usually because they can't find someone else to take the fall.</sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="negative">
            <commenter></commenter>
            <sentence structure="poor">While I wish this had not happened (compassion), I have to say that if she didn't know the odds - after good lord knows how many surgeries to keep looking "young" - of being put to sleep for surgery <caps>ESPECIALLY</caps> the older you get, than she was the reason she died, not the doctors. Good grief!! She <caps>WAS NOT YOUNG</caps>. Look at her face<expunc>.........</expunc>surgery after surgery. Get over it. No one is immune to the possibility of death.</sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="negative">
            <commenter>TJ-1693521</commenter>
            <sentence structure="good">She was 81 years old give it a rest.</sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="negative">
            <commenter>Buffalo_Bob</commenter>
            <sentence structure="good">Melissa and a <obscenity censored="partial">$hithouse</obscenity> full of lawyers are all going to get well over this.</sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="negative">
            <commenter>lavh</commenter>
            <sentence structure="good">This was not vanity, it was not plastic surgery. It was arrogance and complacency on the part of the physician and the clinic. She died as a result of receiving inadequate care. Airway procedures can be dicey. Barring no co-morbidities, she would have been better served at a more aptly prepared facility.</sentence>
        </comment>
    </commentSection>
</media>
