<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="comments_schema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<media source="nbcNews" category="">
    <title>Obamacare's 2.0 Health Insurance Enrollment Period Begins</title>
    <mainContent>
        <link>http://health.nbcnews.com/_news/2014/11/15/26619499-obamacares-20-health-insurance-enrollment-period-begins?lite</link>
        <author>Reuters</author>
        <description>DISCUSSIONS
            350 comments from 85 people</description>
        <statistics>
            <subscribers>0</subscribers>
            <views>0</views>
            <likes>0</likes>
            <dislikes>0</dislikes>
            <totalComments>350</totalComments>
            <publishDate>Saturday November 15, 2014</publishDate>
        </statistics>
    </mainContent>
    <commentSection>
        <comment tone="negative">
            <commenter>hjfromtx</commenter>
            <sentence structure="good">How sad for American journalism. Nothing on NBC about the deceit and lies by this administration and the cost of what it will be! Wake up America, NBC is still obamas stooge!</sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="negative">
            <commenter>Rex-1306908 </commenter>
            <sentence structure="good">This should prove to be interesting. There will probably some sticker shock and awe about increased premium rates and higher deductibles. Any figures on how many of the young and healthy are not signing up, knowing that they don't have to worry about the penalty fee, unless they have a tax refund coming?
It probably will never be repealed, but I am sure the Republicans will try to redo parts of it, and get rid of the medical equipment tax.</sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="negative">
            <commenter>leroy brown</commenter>
            <sentence structure="good">Step right up folks and get your Obamacare, the best health care in the land! And don't be fooled by cheap knockoff plans, make sure it says "Obamacare," and you'll know you are getting the best care possible.  That's "Obamacare," get yours today!!</sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="negative">
            <commenter>Radical2</commenter>
            <sentence structure="good">Yes, when it comes to identifying actual problems with Obamacare, Republicans have SO much credibility: Ridiculously Insane Anti-Obamacare Ad</sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="negative">
            <commenter>DudetteOne</commenter>
            <sentence structure="good">We the people pay for the revamped Obamacare website, we pay for subsidies for others who cannot afford the high deductibles on their new plans, we paid for the politicians who passed this overly complicated law, etc. Plus we pay our own higher premiums, higher deductibles, higher co-pays, etc. And we pay when jobs are lost, hours are cut, etc. We should willingly pay to get this debacle of a law repealed, and show we are smarter than the politicians and architects of this law who wrote it in a way to "obscure" its true nature from the "stupid" voters.</sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="negative">
            <commenter>Common Man-3493893</commenter>
            <sentence structure="good">Time to enroll in 0bama/Gruber care. The people in government and its architect Gruber knew they had to have the support of stupid people and they got it.</sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="negative">
            <commenter>XDm9mm</commenter>
            <sentence structure="good">Let it collapse on itself.   The SCOTUS will have to find for the actual <caps>WORDING</caps> of the law and not what the "intention" was.
                That will toss it back into the hands of Congress and it will be chipped away to nothing.</sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="neutral">
            <commenter>Plantagenet </commenter>
            <sentence structure="good">It does seem as if the primary purpose of the ACA was to insure that the perpetual poor have a direct road to medicaid especially if their primary disability is fitting into a minority class.</sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="negative">
            <commenter></commenter>
            <sentence structure="poor"><acronym>LOL</acronym>...go ahead sign up for that crap. Like eating your own vomit. <acronym>BTW</acronym> where are the stories of the videotaped comments by Gruber of how its all an intentional load of crap but you're all too stupdi to know it?</sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="neutral">
            <commenter></commenter>
            <sentence structure="good">ACA is quite popular among those who benefit from it. It is politically impossible to repeal it. The less popular parts of the law like penalties for not carrying insurance will never be enforced. If anything, subsidies will become more generous, cover more people including people illegally here and tourists. There'll be strictures on insurance companies to waive deductibles, abolish the concept of networks etc. A simple tweak to the licensing law will be done to require medical establishments and doctors to accept ACA plans, Medicaid etc. After all, can't the CEOs and doctors and the rich sacrifice a little? And while we're at it, why have the anti-people policy of making premium payments to keep coverage active? Why not force coverage to be automatic and cover all events, so one single monthly premium payment of $100 made one single time covers the person for life?</sentence>
        </comment>
    </commentSection>
</media>
