<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<?xml-model href="comments_schema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<media source="nbcNews" category="">
    <title>Why Are Old Assault Claims Against Bill Cosby Back?</title>
    <mainContent>
        <link>http://entertainment.nbcnews.com/_news/2014/11/17/26629012-why-are-old-assault-claims-against-bill-cosby-back?d=1</link>
        <author>Maria Elena Fernandez</author>
        <description>DISCUSSIONS
            105 comments from 59 people</description>
        <statistics>
            <subscribers>0</subscribers>
            <views>0</views>
            <likes>0</likes>
            <dislikes>0</dislikes>
            <totalComments>105</totalComments>
            <publishDate>Monday November 17, 2014</publishDate>
        </statistics>
    </mainContent>
    <commentSection>
        <comment tone="negative">
            <commenter>tom-1042767</commenter>
            <sentence structure="good">Let's troll some bait and see what hits. 15 minutes of fame?</sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="positive">
            <commenter>Sonya in Tx</commenter>
            <sentence structure="good">I'll only believe it when there is a polygraph test from this current accuser.
                I won't condemn anyone who hasn't had their day in court.</sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="negative">
            <commenter>bobs ur uncle</commenter>
            <sentence structure="good"><acronym>SNL</acronym> will have him on - Cosby refused &amp; stated he'd be the rape victim of bad comedy writing.</sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="negative">
            <commenter>spike-322306</commenter>
            <sentence structure="good">I have no idea about Cosby's guilt or innocence.  However, I do know that Mike Tyson, a convicted rapist and abuser, has a TV show and is often on other programs.  To me, that is beyond belief. </sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="negative">
            <commenter>Apocraphy </commenter>
            <sentence structure="good">The claims are back because he never did the time for the crimes.</sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="positive">
            <commenter>orchidchick</commenter>
            <sentence structure="good">Cosby is rich &amp; famous &amp; respected.  Who better to use to get your 15 min. of fame by accusing him of rape and all the stories are the same?  He gave them herbal medicine?  I'll concede he may have had sex with them.  Who knows?</sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="negative">
            <commenter></commenter>
            <sentence structure="poor">Freaking NBC <expunc>...</expunc>of course they are going to come to the defense of Bill Cosby due to the fact that they made alot of money off "The Cosby Show"in the 80's<expunc>....</expunc>and it just so happens that they are about to release another sitcom with him being the star<expunc>...</expunc>so naturally they have to defend their Golden Goose<expunc>....</expunc>since Bill Cosby is one of the few entertainers that can attract all demographic groups<expunc>!!!!!</expunc></sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="negative">
            <commenter>backtobasics-1076842</commenter>
            <sentence structure="good">Two reasons: Press time and money. Nothing else.</sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="positive">
            <commenter>@realtruejohn</commenter>
            <sentence structure="good">I don't know if the accusations are true. I hope Mr. Cosby is innocent. But even if he never raped anyone, he is failing as a role model. I don't claim to have any expertise in the law. But one thing I do understand is psychology. I understand the behavior patterns of the accused, and whether it supports a pattern of guilt or innocence. I also understand the psychology of victims, and of why a rape victim may stay silent for years and only muster the courage to speak up later. Most importantly, I understand the psychology of the public. The public needs answers. That is precisely the reason why he should deal with the accusations again. If he is innocent, he needs to take responsibility to fight off these accusations. He signed up for the role of "role model" and now he needs to fulfill it. And if the accusations surface again in 5 years, he will owe it to the public to fight them yet again. That is the price of fame.</sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="negative">
            <commenter>starfox7000</commenter>
            <sentence structure="good">This seems a bit strange.  These women were drugged and raped and they did not immediately go to the police department and get examined to have this confirmed<expunc>???</expunc>  What the <obscenity censored="none">hell</obscenity>.  xxx years later you remember you were drugged and raped?  How do you even know you were raped if you were, as reported from your own lips, <caps>DRUGGED</caps><expunc>????</expunc>  This is making absolutely no sense at all. 
                And most importantly.  A message to all your women seeking to hang around rich and famous guys.  Knock it off<expunc>!!!</expunc>  You will not be rich and famous by being a celebrity star-seeker.  You do not need to go back to <caps>ANY ONE</caps>'s apartment alone, no matter how much money they have.  And if you do go, take a friend with you.  These are just women that want fame and glory and when it doesn't happen, all of a sudden they were raped or molested and needed to "keep it quiet".  If you are under the impression that you have to "<obscenity censored="none">F**K*</obscenity> your way to the top, you will be one of these women in a few years.  Wake up<expunc>!!!</expunc></sentence>
        </comment>
    </commentSection>
</media>
