<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="comments_schema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<media source="nbcNews" category="">
    <title>Rosetta Images Show Philae Lander Bouncing Across Comet</title>
    <mainContent>
        <link>http://scitech.nbcnews.com/_news/2014/11/17/26628439-rosetta-images-show-philae-lander-bouncing-across-comet?lite</link>
        <author>Alan Boyle</author>
        <description>DISCUSSIONS
            16 comments from 14 people</description>
        <statistics>
            <subscribers>0</subscribers>
            <views>0</views>
            <likes>0</likes>
            <dislikes>0</dislikes>
            <totalComments>16</totalComments>
            <publishDate>Monday November 17, 2014</publishDate>
        </statistics>
    </mainContent>
    <commentSection>
        <comment tone="positive">
            <commenter>D.Man</commenter>
            <sentence structure="good"><obscenity censored="none">Damn</obscenity>,  i was hoping that they had at least gotten back some data concerning the boring installed by the drill.  I had a shred of hope that they would find some sort of primitive bacteria or exotic amino acid(s) within the ice sample. Looks like we'll have to wait 4-6 months to even find out what was collected.</sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="negative">
            <commenter>orthotox</commenter>
            <sentence structure="good">What do I think? I'm not sure, but I <caps>DON'T</caps> think it's "poignant" (NBC) or "sad" (Rosetta). It's a machine bouncing on a rock in the void of space.</sentence>
        </comment>
        <comment tone="negative">
            <commenter>Brisaber</commenter>
            <sentence structure="good">Since we're being trivial here, a common definition of poignant is: causing a strong feeling of sadness.  As NBC used the term, "a poignant series of images", this is perfectly appropriate. It may not cause a feeling of sadness on your part, but for many people it does.Also, the probe is not "bouncing on a rock in the void of space".  At least not any longer.  It seems to have settled onto the surface quite nicely, thank you.</sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="positive">
            <commenter>Bart Sampson</commenter>
            <sentence structure="good">Our battery technology has come a long way since this thing left earth.</sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="negative">
            <commenter>Just some Guy With an Opinion</commenter>
            <sentence structure="good">It doesn't show up because the aliens that live inside the "comet" have already snatched it and pulled it inside. The conspiracy theorists are probably right this time!</sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="negative">
            <commenter>Agent Orange</commenter>
            <sentence structure="good">This thing cost more than a billion dollars, and nobody thought of installing an OnStar, or LoJack system?  Should be a standard feature. Uh, a satellite radio, maybe?</sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="positive">
            <commenter>DarkRange</commenter>
            <sentence structure="poor">I can hear it now<expunc>...</expunc> "Earth to Philae Lander<expunc>......</expunc>wakey wakey<expunc>.....</expunc>eggs and bakey"</sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="negative">
            <commenter>Optimist-2618173</commenter>
            <sentence structure="good">Any oil on that comet? If not, this whole project's just another government boondoggle, at least as far as Repugnicans are concerned.</sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="negative">
            <commenter>sam-298381</commenter>
            <sentence structure="good">It's all a hoax by liberal, commie scientists to get everyone outside where they can be exposed to ebola. It's all in Saul Alinsksy's book.</sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="positive">
            <commenter>Rex-1306908</commenter>
            <sentence structure="good">Stunning photos considering the distance from Earth and the speed the whole ensemble is moving. Wonder what caused those areas that look "windblown". Perhaps some venting of gas and dust on previous trips around the Sun?</sentence>
        </comment>
    </commentSection>
</media>
