<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="comments_schema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<media source="nbcNews" category="">
    <title>U2 Frontman Bono Faces Surgery After Cycling Accident</title>
    <mainContent>
        <link>http://entertainment.nbcnews.com/_news/2014/11/16/26624118-u2-frontman-bono-faces-surgery-after-cycling-accident?lite</link>
        <author>M. Alex Johnson</author>
        <description>DISCUSSIONS
            27 comments from 16 people</description>
        <statistics>
            <subscribers>0</subscribers>
            <views>0</views>
            <likes>0</likes>
            <dislikes>0</dislikes>
            <totalComments>27</totalComments>
            <publishDate>Sunday November 16, 2014</publishDate>
        </statistics>
    </mainContent>
    <commentSection>
        <comment tone="positive">
            <commenter>ncernd-300898</commenter>
            <sentence structure="good">Give him a shot full of <caps>GMO</caps> something or other. Bet he will grow a new limb.</sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="positive">
            <commenter>Shannon Jackson </commenter>
            <sentence structure="good">Pretty sure there are lyrics to be had here. Both about the surgery and the Germany luggage incident. Anyone...?</sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="negative">
            <commenter>JamesPup </commenter>
            <sentence structure="good">He is <obscenity censored="full">@!$%#</obscenity> after all so he should be fine.</sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="negative">
            <commenter>Larry E.-10513838</commenter>
            <sentence structure="good">Why is he constantly looking for sympathy - just recently flying a risky jet around town he tosses a metal door to earth and his suitcase and calls it a near-death experience. Now, he falls off a cycle, endangering innocent people and has to cancel a show. Are you sure it isn't <caps>DRUGS</caps> like heroin. Sounds like he's wearing those glasses to hide sunday <caps>BLOODSHOT</caps> sunday <caps>EYES</caps>. Get a life and quit endangering the American people with stupidity.</sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="negative">
            <commenter>Larry E.-10513838 </commenter>
            <sentence structure="good">He jokes about cows being hit in the head by heavy metal doors and luggages tossed from 15,000 feet to earth. What a sick litterbug? Anyone else would get a hefty fine for endangering people and animals, or at least for littering and trying to destroy Earth. How in God's name is this fugitive passing through New York's customs without being arrested. Is he hiding out in a hotel under some alias. No wonder he cancelled the show in NY, he would be booed off the stage as we Americans don't like litterbugs and people who hurt innocent people and animals.</sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="negative">
            <commenter>Optimist-2618173</commenter>
            <sentence structure="good">U2 is still alive?</sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="negative">
            <commenter>Jonathan Reid-1158169</commenter>
            <sentence structure="good">Germany 4 days ago and then cycling in New York yesterday?  What the heck was he in Germany for?  Is he just flying around for the sake of flying around?  Sounds awfully wasteful to me.</sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="positive">
            <commenter>Jonathan Reid-1158169</commenter>
            <sentence structure="good">Apple decided to download him from his bicycle for free.</sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="positive">
            <commenter>AlwaysThePractical1 </commenter>
            <sentence structure="good">Dude has transportation issues.</sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="negative">
            <commenter>Goonbelly</commenter>
            <sentence structure="good">Bono's world is beginning to fall apart.</sentence>
        </comment>
    </commentSection>
</media>
