<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="comments_schema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<media source="nbcNews" category="">
    <title>Dr. Martin Salia's Death Shows Early Ebola Treatment Vital</title>
    <mainContent>
        <link>http://health.nbcnews.com/_news/2014/11/17/26628725-dr-martin-salias-death-shows-early-ebola-treatment-vital?d=1</link>
        <author>Maggie Fox</author>
        <description>DISCUSSIONS
            93 comments from 45 people</description>
        <statistics>
            <subscribers>0</subscribers>
            <views>0</views>
            <likes>0</likes>
            <dislikes>0</dislikes>
            <totalComments>93</totalComments>
            <publishDate>Monday November 17, 2014</publishDate>
        </statistics>
    </mainContent>
    <commentSection>
        <comment tone="negative">
            <commenter>Tim Frenchko</commenter>
            <sentence structure="good">Confederate soldiers should have had a price on their heads.</sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="negative">
            <commenter>Jim in Auburn</commenter>
            <sentence structure="good">Too bad they could not save him. <acronym>RIP</acronym> And now a few conspiracy theories<expunc>.....</expunc> Ebola is a racist disease because most that have died are black. Ebola is a disease created by western countries to kill black people, of all the people brought into the U.S., the only ones to die were black. And the vast majority of people that have died are black. The U.S. Does not give the same level of care to black people brought into the country with Ebola.</sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="negative">
            <commenter>Bill-695432</commenter>
            <sentence structure="good">Who is the <obscenity censored="partial">dipshtz</obscenity> standing next to the patient without any protective gear?</sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="neutral">
            <commenter>Dotsie Watson</commenter>
            <sentence structure="good">Maybe blacks are more affected by it than whites?</sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="negative">
            <commenter></commenter>
            <sentence structure="good">From the article: Experts have said all along it’s not unusual to get a negative test for Ebola the first time. It takes a while for the virus to build up in the blood. Smith said people usually develop fever about a week after infection. “If you check right then, often you get a false negative,” Smith told a news conference. “Usually you have fever for three to four days, then you start getting other symptoms like diarrhea, nausea and vomiting,” he added. That’s when patients then almost always test positive. If there’s enough virus in the blood to set off a positive test, it’s also enough to cause more advanced symptoms. So, wait, that Ebola Nurse Kaci said she was totally safe because she'd tested negative<expunc>...</expunc> yeah, about that<expunc>...</expunc></sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="negative">
            <commenter>Billy Rubin</commenter>
            <sentence structure="good">He was an experienced doctor treating himself for Malaria in a place known for widespread Ebola??  So far it looks like defeating Ebola is easy, if treated early with IV fluids and keeping the electrolytes balanced. Why can't they do this in Africa?</sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="negative">
            <commenter>Tim Frenchko</commenter>
            <sentence structure="poor">Warn them in authority over you do the right thing.</sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="negative">
            <commenter>you are clown</commenter>
            <sentence structure="good">What can it tell us?
                1)The <caps>SAFETY OFFICER</caps> in the photo drank too much coolaid.
                2)People with Ebola should be treated where they are when diagnosed. No more flying them into our country.
                3)Ebola sucks and we don't want it in our country at all.</sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="negative">
            <commenter>DudetteOne</commenter>
            <sentence structure="good">Most people think Dr Martin Salia was a hero for treating Ebola patients in West African countries, risking his own health and life. Some people think he deserved treatment in the USA because he was a hero, and a legal US resident, and because "We can". Who thinks it was wise to bring someone in the end stage of the disease to the USA, when he was most infectious, just so his family could cremate or bury him here? Especially since in the end stage, care is strictly palliative, relieving pain and symptoms, making someone more comfortable before they die, without attempting to cure the patient. Why risk giving Ebola traction in America?</sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="negative">
            <commenter>rosethornne</commenter>
            <sentence structure="good">"But he hadn't been treating Ebola patients and he'd already come through a 21-day incubation period after a close call with an Ebola patient. And his first blood test for Ebola came back negative on November 7"So Nurse Stompyfoot has been completely vindicated in her proclamations that she posed absolutely zero chance of any risk to anyone since she had felt fine for a while and had a negative test.</sentence>
        </comment>
    </commentSection>
</media>
