<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="comments_schema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<media source="nbcNews" category="">
    <title>As Pump Prices Tumble, Gas Guzzlers Soar and Fuel Sippers Slide</title>
    <mainContent>
        <link>http://business.nbcnews.com/_news/2014/11/16/26621960-as-pump-prices-tumble-gas-guzzlers-soar-and-fuel-sippers-slide?lite</link>
        <author>Paul A. Eisenstein</author>
        <description>DISCUSSIONS
            163 comments from 63 people</description>
        <statistics>
            <subscribers>0</subscribers>
            <views>0</views>
            <likes>0</likes>
            <dislikes>0</dislikes>
            <totalComments>163</totalComments>
            <publishDate>Sunday November 16, 2014</publishDate>
        </statistics>
    </mainContent>
    <commentSection>
        <comment tone="negative">
            <commenter>Lee-the liberal gun nut</commenter>
            <sentence structure="good">Wait, what? Gas is cheap? news to me.</sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="neutral">
            <commenter>Hunter Hutchins</commenter>
            <sentence structure="good">I drive the same thing I did before the gas went to $4. Gets about 30 MPG in town.</sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="negative">
            <commenter>Michael</commenter>
            <sentence structure="good">Are people really so short sighted and stupid that they think gas prices are going to stay this low? Well, they just elected a bunch anti-working class Republitwits to congress, so I guess they are, but gas can jump to six dollars a gallons just as quickly as it dropped to three! Idiots...</sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="negative">
            <commenter></commenter>
            <sentence structure="good">Errr... yeah! Gas is so incredibly cheap right now that I am considering buying a more costly and less efficient car! Clearly a slow news day for NBC...</sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="negative">
            <commenter>joemike404</commenter>
            <sentence structure="good">Americans have got to be the most monumentally stupid and self-centered people on the planet.</sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="negative">
            <commenter>JasperWall1</commenter>
            <sentence structure="good">Pretty hard to tow a cattle trailer with a prius.</sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="negative">
            <commenter>Joanie24</commenter>
            <sentence structure="good">I come from the State that is economically 49th in this country. Most working people who earn less then the medium income as other states cannot afford hybrid cars, electric batter or otherwise that car manufacturers put a high price on. I am still driving my 1999 Chevy Tracker that manufacturers stopped building because people loved them so much, they hang onto them. General Motors should have continued to build and sell them to keep marketing Trackers to include economically pressed families who are able to afford them. Instead, the small SUVs today are not cheap and maintenance is also not cheap in today's world. I will drive my 99' till it drives no more. That vehicle is known to hold up to over 300k miles with little care. Mine still looks like up to date vehicles. Ha Ha<expunc>!!</expunc> With just 144k miles on it now with really good body integrity. I expect it to keep working like the pink bunny. If GM brought the Tracker back as it was manufactured back then, they would fly out the door really fast. Consumer Reports rated them really good.</sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="negative">
            <commenter>ted415784</commenter>
            <sentence structure="good">Gas is Cheap? Only if your uncle lives in Saudi Arabia and owns an oil well! Theyre acting like gas prices have been falling for Decades. It has only been, what, 2 weeks since gas prices started to drop and that can go right the other direction in a heart beat like we have seen in the past! No thanks, been burned one too many times by erratic fuel prices and still trying to unload the gas guzzler I have now. Who ever wrote this article is living in a dream world or Daddy Exxon pays their bills</sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="neutral">
            <commenter>Puling Marplot</commenter>
            <sentence structure="good">I never cared what the gas price is. I drive a 4x4 diesel 3/4 ton truck to just cruise around in. Have a couple 1&amp;1/2 ton trucks to do more serious work.</sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="negative">
            <commenter>Just Some Guy With an Opinion</commenter>
            <sentence structure="good">Yes, in the couple weeks that gas has dipped a measly .30-.40/gal SUV sales have just absolutely skyrocketed and fuel efficient cars are practically extinct. Get your head out of your <obscenity censored="none">ass</obscenity>.</sentence>
        </comment>
    </commentSection>
</media>
