<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="comments_schema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<media source="nbc" category="various">
    <title>All NBC Comments</title>
    <mainContent>
        <link></link>
        <author></author>
        <description></description>
        <statistics>
            <subscribers>0</subscribers>
            <views>0</views>
            <likes>0</likes>
            <dislikes>0</dislikes>
            <totalComments>0</totalComments>
            <publishDate></publishDate>
        </statistics>
    </mainContent>
    <commentSection>

        <comment tone="negative">
            <commenter>hjfromtx</commenter>
            <sentence structure="good">How sad for American journalism. Nothing on NBC about the deceit and lies by this administration and the cost of what it will be! Wake up America, NBC is still obamas stooge!</sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="negative">
            <commenter>Rex-1306908 </commenter>
            <sentence structure="good">This should prove to be interesting. There will probably some sticker shock and awe about increased premium rates and higher deductibles. Any figures on how many of the young and healthy are not signing up, knowing that they don't have to worry about the penalty fee, unless they have a tax refund coming?
                It probably will never be repealed, but I am sure the Republicans will try to redo parts of it, and get rid of the medical equipment tax.</sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="negative">
            <commenter>leroy brown</commenter>
            <sentence structure="good">Step right up folks and get your Obamacare, the best health care in the land! And don't be fooled by cheap knockoff plans, make sure it says "Obamacare," and you'll know you are getting the best care possible.  That's "Obamacare," get yours today!!</sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="negative">
            <commenter>Radical2</commenter>
            <sentence structure="good">Yes, when it comes to identifying actual problems with Obamacare, Republicans have SO much credibility: Ridiculously Insane Anti-Obamacare Ad</sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="negative">
            <commenter>DudetteOne</commenter>
            <sentence structure="good">We the people pay for the revamped Obamacare website, we pay for subsidies for others who cannot afford the high deductibles on their new plans, we paid for the politicians who passed this overly complicated law, etc. Plus we pay our own higher premiums, higher deductibles, higher co-pays, etc. And we pay when jobs are lost, hours are cut, etc. We should willingly pay to get this debacle of a law repealed, and show we are smarter than the politicians and architects of this law who wrote it in a way to "obscure" its true nature from the "stupid" voters.</sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="negative">
            <commenter>Common Man-3493893</commenter>
            <sentence structure="good">Time to enroll in 0bama/Gruber care. The people in government and its architect Gruber knew they had to have the support of stupid people and they got it.</sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="negative">
            <commenter>XDm9mm</commenter>
            <sentence structure="good">Let it collapse on itself.   The SCOTUS will have to find for the actual <caps>WORDING</caps> of the law and not what the "intention" was.
                That will toss it back into the hands of Congress and it will be chipped away to nothing.</sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="neutral">
            <commenter>Plantagenet </commenter>
            <sentence structure="good">It does seem as if the primary purpose of the ACA was to insure that the perpetual poor have a direct road to medicaid especially if their primary disability is fitting into a minority class.</sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="negative">
            <commenter></commenter>
            <sentence structure="poor"><acronym>LOL</acronym>...go ahead sign up for that crap. Like eating your own vomit. <acronym>BTW</acronym> where are the stories of the videotaped comments by Gruber of how its all an intentional load of crap but you're all too stupdi to know it?</sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="neutral">
            <commenter></commenter>
            <sentence structure="good">ACA is quite popular among those who benefit from it. It is politically impossible to repeal it. The less popular parts of the law like penalties for not carrying insurance will never be enforced. If anything, subsidies will become more generous, cover more people including people illegally here and tourists. There'll be strictures on insurance companies to waive deductibles, abolish the concept of networks etc. A simple tweak to the licensing law will be done to require medical establishments and doctors to accept ACA plans, Medicaid etc. After all, can't the CEOs and doctors and the rich sacrifice a little? And while we're at it, why have the anti-people policy of making premium payments to keep coverage active? Why not force coverage to be automatic and cover all events, so one single monthly premium payment of $100 made one single time covers the person for life?</sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="neutral">
            <commenter>DudetteOne</commenter>
            <sentence structure="good">There was speculation when she died of a relatively "routine" surgery that someone who didn't like her jokes and political views may have had something to do with it. Of course all surgery is risky, and given her age, there was more risk. But anyone who wished her gone could've assumed that would deflect any investigation. I don't think she was "done in". What do you think?</sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="negative">
            <commenter>Amused In The Midwest</commenter>
            <sentence structure="good">Meaning Ms. Rivers will now sue the whizz out of the medical facility enriching herself and her attorneys, but mostly her attorneys.  This will do little to ensure that a mistake never happens again, if in reality, a mistake happened.</sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="negative">
            <commenter>Der Scherzfragaer</commenter>
            <sentence structure="good">Who<expunc>??</expunc> She's already forgotten.</sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="negative">
            <commenter>Kristen St.Clair</commenter>
            <sentence structure="good"><acronym>Omg</acronym>! My mouth is on the floor reading this! Bottom line. This clinic, it appears, suffers from not one oversight but a grotesque array of issues that push the border on non-compliance to a new low. Wow. Just Wow. The individuals involved in this procedure need to reach around and cop a good feel of their unravaged anal tissues because it's about to be scathed with hellish pursuit. And rightfully so!
                Foremost; what was going on in that procedure room. I am a critical care registered nurse to lay out my credentials, for my assessment of what went wrong if I'm to read into this story correctly...
                Strike one. No consent! Informed Consent wasn't obtained. <acronym>Omg</acronym>! You didn't even have her legal permission! Wow!
                Strike two. Who are all these people in the procedure room<expunc>!!!</expunc> What a nightmare! She will give you an autograph sowhen she wakes up! <acronym>Omg</acronym>. That's horrifyinonto many levels. People gawking at you while your unconscious<expunc>!!!!!</expunc> Who knows what they were doing, but it's unnerving at best.
                Strike three. How many ENTs does it take to screw in a light bulb<expunc>?!</expunc>
                2/3...or two and a third unpreviledged bloak to be exact. This whole procedure in my mind is this grotesque charade with people taking selfies at the patients bedside. It's after they have had too much fun and overlook her during this absolutely critical time that they bottom out her vitals, from an undoubted overdose of propofol. This along with no compensary or standby hemodynamic support is what caused her death. In layman's terms. They bottomed her vitals out on the sedation (which caused the decrease in BP). They could have easily corrected an over<expunc>-... </expunc>I'll say versus dosage due to misconception of the term. Give her some norepinephrine and stabilize the pressure before proceeding any further. But this isn't done. She bottoms out and we now have a critical condition which should have never happened. This clinic messed up big time. The discrepancy in medical documentation comes from no one person being in charge of this whole nightmare scenario. If there was, they did a pathetic job. No one knows how much propofol was administered?! Who is pushing drugs on her and why?! Where is her nurse?! You better be sure if she were my patient. No one beťter come near her with a syringe of anything without knowledge or immediate say so. This is why I ask. Who was in charge of 'her'. It appears no one was. It is semi the doctors fault, I mean legally it will be them because they<expunc>...</expunc> Geez. Well technically they didn't even assume liability because they don't have a legal consent. <acronym>Smdh</acronym>! So it seems some doctors (3 of them) are shouting out separate orders, no one in charge, in a room full of nonliscensed and licensed personel (who knows who was in there) . It's a wonder this place has even had its door opened this long before this type of situation occurred. It's an awful mess. All the power to the family and state and other regulatory agencies (OSHA and JACHO) who are going to go after this tip top group<expunc>...</expunc> They deserve it. So reach back and cop a good feel ladies and gents <expunc>...</expunc> They are coming.</sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="negative">
            <commenter>Ann-3468510</commenter>
            <sentence structure="good">Joan died of greed, vanity and old age. period! Who could save that wretch anyway wasn't she like back from the dead a few times too many anyway.</sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="negative">
            <commenter>fireflyva</commenter>
            <sentence structure="good">After 15 years working in hospitals, I can say that this happens so much more frequently than people would believe. I know that this took place in a free standing clinic but it is still very similar to a hospital. Hospitals and doctors do their best to cover it up, and if they can't, both the hospital and doctor(s) then try and locate someone lower on the food chain to blame. Then, if that doesn't work, the hospital and doctors turn on one another. The point to this is that when a physician is actually held accountable it's usually because they can't find someone else to take the fall.</sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="negative">
            <commenter></commenter>
            <sentence structure="poor">While I wish this had not happened (compassion), I have to say that if she didn't know the odds - after good lord knows how many surgeries to keep looking "young" - of being put to sleep for surgery <caps>ESPECIALLY</caps> the older you get, than she was the reason she died, not the doctors. Good grief!! She <caps>WAS NOT YOUNG</caps>. Look at her face<expunc>.........</expunc>surgery after surgery. Get over it. No one is immune to the possibility of death.</sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="negative">
            <commenter>TJ-1693521</commenter>
            <sentence structure="good">She was 81 years old give it a rest.</sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="negative">
            <commenter>Buffalo_Bob</commenter>
            <sentence structure="good">Melissa and a <obscenity censored="partial">$hithouse</obscenity> full of lawyers are all going to get well over this.</sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="negative">
            <commenter>lavh</commenter>
            <sentence structure="good">This was not vanity, it was not plastic surgery. It was arrogance and complacency on the part of the physician and the clinic. She died as a result of receiving inadequate care. Airway procedures can be dicey. Barring no co-morbidities, she would have been better served at a more aptly prepared facility.</sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="negative">
            <commenter>Da Noid</commenter>
            <sentence structure="good">Talk about cutting off your nose to spite your face.  There is an old saying...don't let the perfect be the enemy of the good. If your sole disagreement with Senator Portman is his stance on same-sex unions then you deserve to be a loser on Election Day.</sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="negative">
            <commenter>6dogs</commenter>
            <sentence structure="good">Someday Portman will be appreciated for his endeavors, but not today. Mr. Rafferty, you said in your writing, " is beginning to feel the backlash from social conservatives as he prepares for his re-election campaign." That should be "social" conservatives, Fixed it or you.</sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="negative">
            <commenter>Grene Tea</commenter>
            <sentence structure="good">"I will not cross that moral line to vote for him"---
                What Social Conservative idiots refuse to comprehend, is that allowing the same sex couples to marry poses no "moral threat" to them and others at all.
                According to these nuts, we should be passing laws and fines on those who engage in pre marital sex. The fact that their neighbors are allowed to engage in per-martial sex bothers them, according to their petty "logic".
                Should we then look for Candidates who promise to defend marital and or godly sex and "morally cleanse" America? Why do they cherry pick sins?
                Who is forcing these nuts to divorce their spouse to go marry someone of the same sex? Who is telling them to do anything that would cause them to "cross the moral line"?</sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="negative">
            <commenter>pauleky</commenter>
            <sentence structure="good">I have several conservative friends. Most of my family votes Republican. Not one of them is against gay marriage. This will only increase. From now on, a GOP candidate that is virulently anti-gay will only have a shrinking number of folks who will support him or her. It's time for the GOP to come out of the Dark Ages on this issue. Voters such as myself have not voted Republican for decades due to their stances on social issues (among others, of course). I'd be much more likely to consider a Republican if they'd stop being ignorant when it comes to gay folks. It's way past time to stop the idiocy.</sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="positive">
            <commenter>Zappy-3519957</commenter>
            <sentence structure="good">Ideological purity is a requirement in today's GOP. It's refreshing to see at least one republican stand up to their hatred of gays.</sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="negative">
            <commenter>Baron Marbot-3100778</commenter>
            <sentence structure="good">I have read many good comments here but this is basically one group wanting to impose their morality on another group.  There is nothing American about such an idea and it goes against the freedom of (and from) religion clause in the US Constitution.  Don't like gay marriage, then don't allow it in your religious institutions.  But your religious restrictions have no place in our government, and each and every citizen is entitled to the full protection and benefits of the law.  That includes those granted in the case of marriage. Marriage needs to be a legal union of two people, not a religious expression. </sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="negative">
            <commenter>skrekk</commenter>
            <sentence structure="good">National polls show the same thing<expunc>.....</expunc>at 94% opposition teabaggers are the #1 demographic which opposes equal rights for gays.   They're dumb bigots to the core and their real agenda is social conservatism and Christian sharia law, contrary to their claim that they're not concerned with social issues.    Teabaggers are really just warmed-over John Birchers and really represent just the most extreme right wing of the <caps>GOP</caps>.</sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="negative">
            <commenter>Malinda-3622677</commenter>
            <sentence structure="poor"> The Very Reverend Pastor Larry Robinson's Christian outrage will  be abated when the Gay-abetting Portmans haul the vile spawn of their loins to the Village Common for public stoning.  While there's still a spark of life in this God-defying miscreant, he'll be burned at the stake.
                Pastor  Larry, like Cotton Mather, the Westboro Baptists, Liberty University-ites, ISIS, Ugandan Brothers-in-Christ, Taliban, Opus Dei, and Duck Dynasty know the True Words of Magic Sky Guy. The cursed disbelieving those Words, like the Portsmans, pere, mere et fils are Damned to Hell. Mind your manners, especially, you so-called "moderates," Reverend Mr. Robinson may be visiting you next.
                Ramen, Ramen, Ramen, <caps>RAMEN</caps>!</sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="negative">
            <commenter>Larry-2672013 </commenter>
            <sentence structure="poor">Bottom line:American "Christians" - aren't.</sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="positive">
            <commenter>Mike-2802274</commenter>
            <sentence structure="good">It's good to see someone representing the GOP actually standing up for what the party claims to represent; among other things, equality, and keeping govt. out of people's personal lives.  Most GOP'ers preach about this equality for all, and then turn around and pick and choose who that applies to.</sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="negative">
            <commenter>Lee-the liberal gun nut</commenter>
            <sentence structure="good">Wait, what? Gas is cheap? news to me.</sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="neutral">
            <commenter>Hunter Hutchins</commenter>
            <sentence structure="good">I drive the same thing I did before the gas went to $4. Gets about 30 MPG in town.</sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="negative">
            <commenter>Michael</commenter>
            <sentence structure="good">Are people really so short sighted and stupid that they think gas prices are going to stay this low? Well, they just elected a bunch anti-working class Republitwits to congress, so I guess they are, but gas can jump to six dollars a gallons just as quickly as it dropped to three! Idiots...</sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="negative">
            <commenter></commenter>
            <sentence structure="good">Errr... yeah! Gas is so incredibly cheap right now that I am considering buying a more costly and less efficient car! Clearly a slow news day for NBC...</sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="negative">
            <commenter>joemike404</commenter>
            <sentence structure="good">Americans have got to be the most monumentally stupid and self-centered people on the planet.</sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="negative">
            <commenter>JasperWall1</commenter>
            <sentence structure="good">Pretty hard to tow a cattle trailer with a prius.</sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="negative">
            <commenter>Joanie24</commenter>
            <sentence structure="good">I come from the State that is economically 49th in this country. Most working people who earn less then the medium income as other states cannot afford hybrid cars, electric batter or otherwise that car manufacturers put a high price on. I am still driving my 1999 Chevy Tracker that manufacturers stopped building because people loved them so much, they hang onto them. General Motors should have continued to build and sell them to keep marketing Trackers to include economically pressed families who are able to afford them. Instead, the small SUVs today are not cheap and maintenance is also not cheap in today's world. I will drive my 99' till it drives no more. That vehicle is known to hold up to over 300k miles with little care. Mine still looks like up to date vehicles. Ha Ha<expunc>!!</expunc> With just 144k miles on it now with really good body integrity. I expect it to keep working like the pink bunny. If GM brought the Tracker back as it was manufactured back then, they would fly out the door really fast. Consumer Reports rated them really good.</sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="negative">
            <commenter>ted415784</commenter>
            <sentence structure="good">Gas is Cheap? Only if your uncle lives in Saudi Arabia and owns an oil well! Theyre acting like gas prices have been falling for Decades. It has only been, what, 2 weeks since gas prices started to drop and that can go right the other direction in a heart beat like we have seen in the past! No thanks, been burned one too many times by erratic fuel prices and still trying to unload the gas guzzler I have now. Who ever wrote this article is living in a dream world or Daddy Exxon pays their bills</sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="neutral">
            <commenter>Puling Marplot</commenter>
            <sentence structure="good">I never cared what the gas price is. I drive a 4x4 diesel 3/4 ton truck to just cruise around in. Have a couple 1&amp;1/2 ton trucks to do more serious work.</sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="negative">
            <commenter>Just Some Guy With an Opinion</commenter>
            <sentence structure="good">Yes, in the couple weeks that gas has dipped a measly .30-.40/gal SUV sales have just absolutely skyrocketed and fuel efficient cars are practically extinct. Get your head out of your <obscenity censored="none">ass</obscenity>.</sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="negative">
            <commenter>Tim Frenchko</commenter>
            <sentence structure="good">Confederate soldiers should have had a price on their heads.</sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="negative">
            <commenter>Jim in Auburn</commenter>
            <sentence structure="good">Too bad they could not save him. <acronym>RIP</acronym> And now a few conspiracy theories<expunc>.....</expunc> Ebola is a racist disease because most that have died are black. Ebola is a disease created by western countries to kill black people, of all the people brought into the U.S., the only ones to die were black. And the vast majority of people that have died are black. The U.S. Does not give the same level of care to black people brought into the country with Ebola.</sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="negative">
            <commenter>Bill-695432</commenter>
            <sentence structure="good">Who is the <obscenity censored="partial">dipshtz</obscenity> standing next to the patient without any protective gear?</sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="neutral">
            <commenter>Dotsie Watson</commenter>
            <sentence structure="good">Maybe blacks are more affected by it than whites?</sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="negative">
            <commenter></commenter>
            <sentence structure="good">From the article: Experts have said all along it’s not unusual to get a negative test for Ebola the first time. It takes a while for the virus to build up in the blood. Smith said people usually develop fever about a week after infection. “If you check right then, often you get a false negative,” Smith told a news conference. “Usually you have fever for three to four days, then you start getting other symptoms like diarrhea, nausea and vomiting,” he added. That’s when patients then almost always test positive. If there’s enough virus in the blood to set off a positive test, it’s also enough to cause more advanced symptoms. So, wait, that Ebola Nurse Kaci said she was totally safe because she'd tested negative<expunc>...</expunc> yeah, about that<expunc>...</expunc></sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="negative">
            <commenter>Billy Rubin</commenter>
            <sentence structure="good">He was an experienced doctor treating himself for Malaria in a place known for widespread Ebola??  So far it looks like defeating Ebola is easy, if treated early with IV fluids and keeping the electrolytes balanced. Why can't they do this in Africa?</sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="negative">
            <commenter>Tim Frenchko</commenter>
            <sentence structure="poor">Warn them in authority over you do the right thing.</sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="negative">
            <commenter>you are clown</commenter>
            <sentence structure="good">What can it tell us?
                1)The <caps>SAFETY OFFICER</caps> in the photo drank too much coolaid.
                2)People with Ebola should be treated where they are when diagnosed. No more flying them into our country.
                3)Ebola sucks and we don't want it in our country at all.</sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="negative">
            <commenter>DudetteOne</commenter>
            <sentence structure="good">Most people think Dr Martin Salia was a hero for treating Ebola patients in West African countries, risking his own health and life. Some people think he deserved treatment in the USA because he was a hero, and a legal US resident, and because "We can". Who thinks it was wise to bring someone in the end stage of the disease to the USA, when he was most infectious, just so his family could cremate or bury him here? Especially since in the end stage, care is strictly palliative, relieving pain and symptoms, making someone more comfortable before they die, without attempting to cure the patient. Why risk giving Ebola traction in America?</sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="negative">
            <commenter>rosethornne</commenter>
            <sentence structure="good">"But he hadn't been treating Ebola patients and he'd already come through a 21-day incubation period after a close call with an Ebola patient. And his first blood test for Ebola came back negative on November 7"So Nurse Stompyfoot has been completely vindicated in her proclamations that she posed absolutely zero chance of any risk to anyone since she had felt fine for a while and had a negative test.</sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="positive">
            <commenter>D.Man</commenter>
            <sentence structure="good"><obscenity censored="none">Damn</obscenity>,  i was hoping that they had at least gotten back some data concerning the boring installed by the drill.  I had a shred of hope that they would find some sort of primitive bacteria or exotic amino acid(s) within the ice sample. Looks like we'll have to wait 4-6 months to even find out what was collected.</sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="negative">
            <commenter>orthotox</commenter>
            <sentence structure="good">What do I think? I'm not sure, but I <caps>DON'T</caps> think it's "poignant" (NBC) or "sad" (Rosetta). It's a machine bouncing on a rock in the void of space.</sentence>
        </comment>
        <comment tone="negative">
            <commenter>Brisaber</commenter>
            <sentence structure="good">Since we're being trivial here, a common definition of poignant is: causing a strong feeling of sadness.  As NBC used the term, "a poignant series of images", this is perfectly appropriate. It may not cause a feeling of sadness on your part, but for many people it does.Also, the probe is not "bouncing on a rock in the void of space".  At least not any longer.  It seems to have settled onto the surface quite nicely, thank you.</sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="positive">
            <commenter>Bart Sampson</commenter>
            <sentence structure="good">Our battery technology has come a long way since this thing left earth.</sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="negative">
            <commenter>Just some Guy With an Opinion</commenter>
            <sentence structure="good">It doesn't show up because the aliens that live inside the "comet" have already snatched it and pulled it inside. The conspiracy theorists are probably right this time!</sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="negative">
            <commenter>Agent Orange</commenter>
            <sentence structure="good">This thing cost more than a billion dollars, and nobody thought of installing an OnStar, or LoJack system?  Should be a standard feature. Uh, a satellite radio, maybe?</sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="positive">
            <commenter>DarkRange</commenter>
            <sentence structure="poor">I can hear it now<expunc>...</expunc> "Earth to Philae Lander<expunc>......</expunc>wakey wakey<expunc>.....</expunc>eggs and bakey"</sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="negative">
            <commenter>Optimist-2618173</commenter>
            <sentence structure="good">Any oil on that comet? If not, this whole project's just another government boondoggle, at least as far as Repugnicans are concerned.</sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="negative">
            <commenter>sam-298381</commenter>
            <sentence structure="good">It's all a hoax by liberal, commie scientists to get everyone outside where they can be exposed to ebola. It's all in Saul Alinsksy's book.</sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="positive">
            <commenter>Rex-1306908</commenter>
            <sentence structure="good">Stunning photos considering the distance from Earth and the speed the whole ensemble is moving. Wonder what caused those areas that look "windblown". Perhaps some venting of gas and dust on previous trips around the Sun?</sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="positive">
            <commenter>ncernd-300898</commenter>
            <sentence structure="good">Give him a shot full of <caps>GMO</caps> something or other. Bet he will grow a new limb.</sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="positive">
            <commenter>Shannon Jackson </commenter>
            <sentence structure="good">Pretty sure there are lyrics to be had here. Both about the surgery and the Germany luggage incident. Anyone...?</sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="negative">
            <commenter>JamesPup </commenter>
            <sentence structure="good">He is <obscenity censored="full">@!$%#</obscenity> after all so he should be fine.</sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="negative">
            <commenter>Larry E.-10513838</commenter>
            <sentence structure="good">Why is he constantly looking for sympathy - just recently flying a risky jet around town he tosses a metal door to earth and his suitcase and calls it a near-death experience. Now, he falls off a cycle, endangering innocent people and has to cancel a show. Are you sure it isn't <caps>DRUGS</caps> like heroin. Sounds like he's wearing those glasses to hide sunday <caps>BLOODSHOT</caps> sunday <caps>EYES</caps>. Get a life and quit endangering the American people with stupidity.</sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="negative">
            <commenter>Larry E.-10513838 </commenter>
            <sentence structure="good">He jokes about cows being hit in the head by heavy metal doors and luggages tossed from 15,000 feet to earth. What a sick litterbug? Anyone else would get a hefty fine for endangering people and animals, or at least for littering and trying to destroy Earth. How in God's name is this fugitive passing through New York's customs without being arrested. Is he hiding out in a hotel under some alias. No wonder he cancelled the show in NY, he would be booed off the stage as we Americans don't like litterbugs and people who hurt innocent people and animals.</sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="negative">
            <commenter>Optimist-2618173</commenter>
            <sentence structure="good">U2 is still alive?</sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="negative">
            <commenter>Jonathan Reid-1158169</commenter>
            <sentence structure="good">Germany 4 days ago and then cycling in New York yesterday?  What the heck was he in Germany for?  Is he just flying around for the sake of flying around?  Sounds awfully wasteful to me.</sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="positive">
            <commenter>Jonathan Reid-1158169</commenter>
            <sentence structure="good">Apple decided to download him from his bicycle for free.</sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="positive">
            <commenter>AlwaysThePractical1 </commenter>
            <sentence structure="good">Dude has transportation issues.</sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="negative">
            <commenter>Goonbelly</commenter>
            <sentence structure="good">Bono's world is beginning to fall apart.</sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="negative">
            <commenter>tom-1042767</commenter>
            <sentence structure="good">Let's troll some bait and see what hits. 15 minutes of fame?</sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="positive">
            <commenter>Sonya in Tx</commenter>
            <sentence structure="good">I'll only believe it when there is a polygraph test from this current accuser.
                I won't condemn anyone who hasn't had their day in court.</sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="negative">
            <commenter>bobs ur uncle</commenter>
            <sentence structure="good"><acronym>SNL</acronym> will have him on - Cosby refused &amp; stated he'd be the rape victim of bad comedy writing.</sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="negative">
            <commenter>spike-322306</commenter>
            <sentence structure="good">I have no idea about Cosby's guilt or innocence.  However, I do know that Mike Tyson, a convicted rapist and abuser, has a TV show and is often on other programs.  To me, that is beyond belief. </sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="negative">
            <commenter>Apocraphy </commenter>
            <sentence structure="good">The claims are back because he never did the time for the crimes.</sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="positive">
            <commenter>orchidchick</commenter>
            <sentence structure="good">Cosby is rich &amp; famous &amp; respected.  Who better to use to get your 15 min. of fame by accusing him of rape and all the stories are the same?  He gave them herbal medicine?  I'll concede he may have had sex with them.  Who knows?</sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="negative">
            <commenter></commenter>
            <sentence structure="poor">Freaking NBC <expunc>...</expunc>of course they are going to come to the defense of Bill Cosby due to the fact that they made alot of money off "The Cosby Show"in the 80's<expunc>....</expunc>and it just so happens that they are about to release another sitcom with him being the star<expunc>...</expunc>so naturally they have to defend their Golden Goose<expunc>....</expunc>since Bill Cosby is one of the few entertainers that can attract all demographic groups<expunc>!!!!!</expunc></sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="negative">
            <commenter>backtobasics-1076842</commenter>
            <sentence structure="good">Two reasons: Press time and money. Nothing else.</sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="positive">
            <commenter>@realtruejohn</commenter>
            <sentence structure="good">I don't know if the accusations are true. I hope Mr. Cosby is innocent. But even if he never raped anyone, he is failing as a role model. I don't claim to have any expertise in the law. But one thing I do understand is psychology. I understand the behavior patterns of the accused, and whether it supports a pattern of guilt or innocence. I also understand the psychology of victims, and of why a rape victim may stay silent for years and only muster the courage to speak up later. Most importantly, I understand the psychology of the public. The public needs answers. That is precisely the reason why he should deal with the accusations again. If he is innocent, he needs to take responsibility to fight off these accusations. He signed up for the role of "role model" and now he needs to fulfill it. And if the accusations surface again in 5 years, he will owe it to the public to fight them yet again. That is the price of fame.</sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="negative">
            <commenter>starfox7000</commenter>
            <sentence structure="good">This seems a bit strange.  These women were drugged and raped and they did not immediately go to the police department and get examined to have this confirmed<expunc>???</expunc>  What the <obscenity censored="none">hell</obscenity>.  xxx years later you remember you were drugged and raped?  How do you even know you were raped if you were, as reported from your own lips, <caps>DRUGGED</caps><expunc>????</expunc>  This is making absolutely no sense at all. 
                And most importantly.  A message to all your women seeking to hang around rich and famous guys.  Knock it off<expunc>!!!</expunc>  You will not be rich and famous by being a celebrity star-seeker.  You do not need to go back to <caps>ANY ONE</caps>'s apartment alone, no matter how much money they have.  And if you do go, take a friend with you.  These are just women that want fame and glory and when it doesn't happen, all of a sudden they were raped or molested and needed to "keep it quiet".  If you are under the impression that you have to "<obscenity censored="none">F**K*</obscenity> your way to the top, you will be one of these women in a few years.  Wake up<expunc>!!!</expunc></sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="negative">
            <commenter>William Charles DeMuth</commenter>
            <sentence structure="poor">I am not sorry, but I must admit I was disapointed</sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="neutral">
            <commenter>Walking Talking D B Cooper</commenter>
            <sentence structure="good">Wish I knew how to do that.</sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="negative">
            <commenter></commenter>
            <sentence structure="good">Worst of all he is sorry because seeing Paris Hilton nude turned him gay.</sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="neutral">
            <commenter>Whoever</commenter>
            <sentence structure="poor">14:59.999</sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="negative">
            <commenter>MoreJustice</commenter>
            <sentence structure="good">He's right about the vulnerability. There are so many holes its basically Swiss Cheese security. Its why I don't use the internet for any kind of financial stuff or transactions. Hopefully he straightens himself out and jail does him some good. But I don't trust him to go straight. When he gets out and starts feeling safe, he may go back to it. Learning from past mistakes. The thrill of "getting away with it" is strong in this one master Yoda. He didn't seem that sorry.</sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="negative">
            <commenter>Senior Analyst</commenter>
            <sentence structure="good">You don't have to be a hacker to get into Paris Hilton.</sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="negative">
            <commenter>Vincent Blake</commenter>
            <sentence structure="good">Privilege is one hell of a drug, isn't it. Maybe a 4-year bid will straighten him out (particularly if it's in General Population).</sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="negative">
            <commenter>TruthComesHere</commenter>
            <sentence structure="good">I guess he didn't like what he saw.</sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="negative">
            <commenter>Subhuman Mongrel</commenter>
            <sentence structure="poor">Libtards<expunc>,,,,,</expunc> what can you do?</sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="negative">
            <commenter>pained1</commenter>
            <sentence structure="good">He should apologize for getting her back in the public consciousness</sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="positive">
            <commenter>Jonathan Reid-1158169</commenter>
            <sentence structure="good">Meanwhile at the Cat Institute, leading feline scientists have announced that Phase Three of world domination is proceeding as planned with Phase Four (elimination of all vacuum cleaners) running into early issues.</sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="positive">
            <commenter>Brisaber</commenter>
            <sentence structure="good">I, for one, welcome our new cat overlords.</sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="positive">
            <commenter>Barry-NJ</commenter>
            <sentence structure="good">Cats (and dogs) have always been our overlords.</sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="neutral">
            <commenter>helicohunter</commenter>
            <sentence structure="good">"Tolerate". A very appropriate word. Cats still have some evolving left to do.</sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="negative">
            <commenter>Mike in B-more</commenter>
            <sentence structure="good">"Cats still have some evolving left to do." As do dogs, humans, monkeys, 'pet' birds, cattle, sheep, pigs, etc. I grew up on a farm - the farm was not complete <caps>UNLESS</caps> there were at least one dog and multiple cats - the dog to make sure the other (domesticated) animals 'behaved' themselves, the cats to hunt and kill rats and mice for supplemental food for themselves. And I'll not even comment on how humans need to evolve, especially <caps>CON</caps>servatives.</sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="negative">
            <commenter>helicohunter</commenter>
            <sentence structure="good">As if evolution is a deterministic process with goals. Evolution is something that will happen when pressure is applied to populations of a species otherwise that population will inevitably die off. Cats are less social toward their human hosts than dogs because dogs are simply more domesticated than cats. Which brings me to the point that the evolution of cats, and to a greater degree, dogs has been guided by humans through selective breeding rather than natural selection.</sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="neutral">
            <commenter>inmissouri</commenter>
            <sentence structure="good">Why? They've evolved to the point where they can train their humans very well.</sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="negative">
            <commenter>Rex-1306908</commenter>
            <sentence structure="good">We're doing quite well Mike, beating the hell out of you Democ<caps>RATS</caps> last week. Or is that Demo<caps>CRAPS</caps>?</sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="neutral">
            <commenter>SouthwestPA</commenter>
            <sentence structure="poor">meow meow meow meow, meow you!</sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="positive">
            <commenter>Jim-1301592</commenter>
            <sentence structure="good">The article made note of genes for fear. Never really perceived cats that way, even though when I grew up the phrase "scaredy cat" was frequently heard - sometimes as an epithet and sometimes as a dare.</sentence>
        </comment>
        
        

    </commentSection>
</media>
