<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="comments_schema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<media source="youtube" category="informational">
    <title>How Houdini DIED (in Slow Motion) - Smarter Every Day 108</title>
    <mainContent>
        <link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=QJ9lNRAjTQM</link>
        <author>SmarterEveryDay</author>
        <description>There is much speculation about the death of Houdini. Many of the detail remain mysterious. I hope you enjoy this look into the possibilities.
            
            A special thanks to Mike Chang of SixPackShortcuts for letting me punch him in the gut as hard as I could. Check his stuff out: http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=eilw4-...
            Did I mention HE LET ME PUNCH HIM AS HARD AS I COULD?
            
            Music "A little discomfort, a whole lot of Freedom", and "Piano Improvisation" by A Shell In The Pit.
            You know Gordon's music by now. It's all good.
            http://ashellinthepit.bandcamp.com/
            
            I shot the punch with a Phantom MIRO LC320S made by Vision Research:
            http://www.visionresearch.com/Product...
            
            With thanks to Houdini Historian
            John Cox, who provided the drawing at 1:07
            For more information about Houdini visit John's blog
            "Wild about Harry"
            http://www.wildabouthoudini.com
            
            A big thank you to Ben Eells who responded to my call for help on Facebook and spent both a Saturday and a Sunday to shoot footage of Houdini's grave for us. He originally went on Saturday but the graveyard was closed for the Sabbath. I didn't know that! I'm getting Smarter Every Day I guess. </description>
        <statistics>
            <subscribers>2233672</subscribers>
            <views>15381940</views>
            <likes>40149</likes>
            <dislikes>6430</dislikes>
            <totalComments>3461</totalComments>
            <publishDate>Dec 26, 2013</publishDate>
        </statistics>
    </mainContent>
    <commentSection>
        
        <comment tone="neutral">
            <commenter>JayJayPlayzMC</commenter>
            <sentence structure="poor">Houdini had died from the punches because he had something in his stomach that was a big sac and when the guy punched him that sac had broken and all  the acid had spilled out and infected everything and thats when he had died</sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="negative">
            <commenter>S.A.P. Productions</commenter>
            <sentence structure="good">The six pack expert, without a six pack.</sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="positive">
            <commenter>Niels Douma</commenter>
            <sentence structure="good">I actually had a rock in my ear, but you took it... Can I have it back please?</sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="negative">
            <commenter>Ben Cooper</commenter>
            <sentence structure="good">The self proclaimed six-pack expert with such a huge layer of fat that his abdominal muscles aren't visible - even when he flexes...</sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="negative">
            <commenter>gardenmomof2</commenter>
            <sentence structure="poor">stop using stupid disgusting thumbnails that have nothing to do with your video. You are just a huge monster of a youtuber by deceite and lies. good job.</sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="neutral">
            <commenter>HireDeLune</commenter>
            <sentence structure="good">I read a biography on Houdini when I was 7.
                Apparently some muscle heads came in after a show to talk to Houdini, and they made some bets on whether he could take punches to the abs. Houdini said sure, but before he could clench his muscles the young man had punched him.</sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="positive">
            <commenter>Dusty</commenter>
            <sentence structure="poor">it's wrong to say that he's an american magician when he's actualy from hungary... only cus he lived in america doesn't mean he's an american... Nice video tho! <emote>:)</emote></sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="positive">
            <commenter>TCG- TheCasualGamer</commenter>
            <sentence structure="poor">i was listenning with only one earbud and whan u said whats in your ear, i freaked out, i froze and u picked up the rock and i was like <acronym>fiu</acronym>! its real life</sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="negative">
            <commenter>Grymyrk</commenter>
            <sentence structure="good">People don't dislike mike because they're jealous, they dislike him because he's a snake oil salesman.</sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="neutral">
            <commenter>mark2shark</commenter>
            <sentence structure="good">Harry wasn't ready..some idiot took a cheap cowardly punches when he wasn't ready.</sentence>
        </comment>
        
    </commentSection>
</media>
