<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="comments_schema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<media source="nbcNews" category="">
    <title>Gay Marriage Foes Yet to Prove Formidable Threat to Rob Portman</title>
    <mainContent>
        <link>http://nbcpolitics.nbcnews.com/_news/2014/11/17/26628201-gay-marriage-foes-yet-to-prove-formidable-threat-to-rob-portman?d=1</link>
        <author>Andrew Rafferty</author>
        <description>DISCUSSIONS
            331 comments from 47 people
        </description>
        <statistics>
            <subscribers>0</subscribers>
            <views>0</views>
            <likes>0</likes>
            <dislikes>0</dislikes>
            <totalComments>331</totalComments>
            <publishDate>Monday November 17, 2014</publishDate>
        </statistics>
    </mainContent>
    <commentSection>
        <comment tone="negative">
            <commenter>Da Noid</commenter>
            <sentence structure="good">Talk about cutting off your nose to spite your face.  There is an old saying...don't let the perfect be the enemy of the good. If your sole disagreement with Senator Portman is his stance on same-sex unions then you deserve to be a loser on Election Day.</sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="negative">
            <commenter>6dogs</commenter>
            <sentence structure="good">Someday Portman will be appreciated for his endeavors, but not today. Mr. Rafferty, you said in your writing, " is beginning to feel the backlash from social conservatives as he prepares for his re-election campaign." That should be "social" conservatives, Fixed it or you.</sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="negative">
            <commenter>Grene Tea</commenter>
            <sentence structure="good">"I will not cross that moral line to vote for him"---
                What Social Conservative idiots refuse to comprehend, is that allowing the same sex couples to marry poses no "moral threat" to them and others at all.
                According to these nuts, we should be passing laws and fines on those who engage in pre marital sex. The fact that their neighbors are allowed to engage in per-martial sex bothers them, according to their petty "logic".
                Should we then look for Candidates who promise to defend marital and or godly sex and "morally cleanse" America? Why do they cherry pick sins?
                Who is forcing these nuts to divorce their spouse to go marry someone of the same sex? Who is telling them to do anything that would cause them to "cross the moral line"?</sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="negative">
            <commenter>pauleky</commenter>
            <sentence structure="good">I have several conservative friends. Most of my family votes Republican. Not one of them is against gay marriage. This will only increase. From now on, a GOP candidate that is virulently anti-gay will only have a shrinking number of folks who will support him or her. It's time for the GOP to come out of the Dark Ages on this issue. Voters such as myself have not voted Republican for decades due to their stances on social issues (among others, of course). I'd be much more likely to consider a Republican if they'd stop being ignorant when it comes to gay folks. It's way past time to stop the idiocy.</sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="positive">
            <commenter>Zappy-3519957</commenter>
            <sentence structure="good">Ideological purity is a requirement in today's GOP. It's refreshing to see at least one republican stand up to their hatred of gays.</sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="negative">
            <commenter>Baron Marbot-3100778</commenter>
            <sentence structure="good">I have read many good comments here but this is basically one group wanting to impose their morality on another group.  There is nothing American about such an idea and it goes against the freedom of (and from) religion clause in the US Constitution.  Don't like gay marriage, then don't allow it in your religious institutions.  But your religious restrictions have no place in our government, and each and every citizen is entitled to the full protection and benefits of the law.  That includes those granted in the case of marriage. Marriage needs to be a legal union of two people, not a religious expression. </sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="negative">
            <commenter>skrekk</commenter>
            <sentence structure="good">National polls show the same thing<expunc>.....</expunc>at 94% opposition teabaggers are the #1 demographic which opposes equal rights for gays.   They're dumb bigots to the core and their real agenda is social conservatism and Christian sharia law, contrary to their claim that they're not concerned with social issues.    Teabaggers are really just warmed-over John Birchers and really represent just the most extreme right wing of the <caps>GOP</caps>.</sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="negative">
            <commenter>Malinda-3622677</commenter>
            <sentence structure="poor"> The Very Reverend Pastor Larry Robinson's Christian outrage will  be abated when the Gay-abetting Portmans haul the vile spawn of their loins to the Village Common for public stoning.  While there's still a spark of life in this God-defying miscreant, he'll be burned at the stake.
                Pastor  Larry, like Cotton Mather, the Westboro Baptists, Liberty University-ites, ISIS, Ugandan Brothers-in-Christ, Taliban, Opus Dei, and Duck Dynasty know the True Words of Magic Sky Guy. The cursed disbelieving those Words, like the Portsmans, pere, mere et fils are Damned to Hell. Mind your manners, especially, you so-called "moderates," Reverend Mr. Robinson may be visiting you next.
                Ramen, Ramen, Ramen, <caps>RAMEN</caps>!</sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="negative">
            <commenter>Larry-2672013 </commenter>
            <sentence structure="poor">Bottom line:American "Christians" - aren't.</sentence>
        </comment>
        
        <comment tone="positive">
            <commenter>Mike-2802274</commenter>
            <sentence structure="good">It's good to see someone representing the GOP actually standing up for what the party claims to represent; among other things, equality, and keeping govt. out of people's personal lives.  Most GOP'ers preach about this equality for all, and then turn around and pick and choose who that applies to.</sentence>
        </comment>
    </commentSection>
</media>
