<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<listBibl><bibl><author>Perry, James</author><title>Mimosa: or, The sensitive plant; A poem. Dedicated to Mr. Banks, and addressed to Kitt Frederick, Dutchess of Queensberry, Elect.</title><editor/><publisher/><pubPlace>The second edition, with additions. London,  1779. Eighteenth Century Collections Online. Gale. University of Pittsburgh Libraries</pubPlace><date> Sep.18, 2013</date><note> it's an interesting poem, and we are looking for literature so this one is apprpriate for the assigment.
        </note></bibl><bibl><author>Fitzgerald, Gerald.</author><title>The injured islanders; or, the influence of art upon the happiness of nature.</title><editor/><publisher/><pubPlace>London,  MDCCLXXIX. [1779]. Eighteenth Century Collections Online. Gale. University of Pittsburgh Libraries </pubPlace><date> Sept. 18, 2013</date><note>
        </note><author>Fitzgerald, Gerald.</author><note>it might be useful to us because it describes nature in Tahiti and we are looking for such things. literature and language, useful for this profect, understadn their vocabulary </note></bibl><bibl><author>Alexander, William (d. 1783)</author><title>The history of women, from the earliest antiquity, to the present time; giving some account of almost every interesting particular concerning that sex, among all nations, ancient and modern. By William Alexander, M.D. In two volumes.</title><editor>London : printed for W. Strahan, and T. Cadell, in the Strand, MDCCLXXIX. [1779].</editor><publisher>W. Strahan and T. Cadell</publisher><pubPlace>London</pubPlace><date>1779</date><note>The term Otaheite found references to Otaheite. This helped find a voyage logs of when Otaheite was mentioned.
            Also the date range from 1750-1790 narrowed the search to the date range that Captain Wallis's voyages were documented.</note></bibl><notes>I wasn't sure about this one but volume 2 seems like it could be usuful</notes><listBibl><sourceDesc><p><author> William Stork</author><title> A description of East-Florida, with a journal, kept by John
            Bartram of Philadelphia, botanist to His Majesty for the Floridas;
            upon a journey from St. Augustine up the River St. John's, as far as
            the lakes. With explanatory botanical notes. Illustrated with an
            accurate Map of East-Florida, and two Plans; one of St. Augustine,
            and the other of the Bay of Espiritu Santo. </title><publisher> London : sold by W. Nicoll, at No. 51, St. Paul's Church
            Yard; and T. Jefferies, at Charing-Cross, Geographer to his
            Majesty</publisher><pubPlace> London</pubPlace><date> 1769</date><note> The term is used in the text when Dr. Solander himself is
            mentioned. the part of the text also talks about the others in his
            company.</note></p></sourceDesc></listBibl></listBibl>