<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<listBibl><bibl><author>Various</author><title>The fugitive miscellany. Being a collection of such fugitive pieces, in prose and
            verse, as are not in any other collection. With many pieces never before published. </title><vol>2</vol><editor/><publisher/><pubPlace>London</pubPlace><date>1774</date><note>The hit for poe was the word poem, but when you search inside the work for Otaheite you get a poem that was written as though it were from Oberea to Banks. It might be worth looking at because it references actual events from the voyage logs.</note></bibl><bibl><author>Fitzgerald, Gerald.</author><title>The injured islanders; or, the influence of art upon the happiness of nature.</title><editor/><publisher/><pubPlace>London, MDCCLXXIX. [1779]. Eighteenth Century Collections Online. Gale. University
            of Pittsburgh Libraries </pubPlace><date> Sept. 18, 2013</date><note> This one is already on the Obdurodon site but I figured I'd leave it on the list just in case.</note></bibl><bibl><author>Alexander, William (d. 1783)</author><title>The history of women, from the earliest antiquity, to the present time; giving some
            account of almost every interesting particular concerning that sex, among all nations,
            ancient and modern. By William Alexander, M.D. In two volumes.</title><editor>London : printed for W. Strahan, and T. Cadell, in the Strand, MDCCLXXIX.
            [1779].</editor><publisher>W. Strahan and T. Cadell</publisher><pubPlace>London</pubPlace><date>1779</date><vol>1,2</vol><note>Not sure if we should keep this one or not. It seems to draw a lot of information from the voyage accounts but doesn't summarize them as much as other works. </note></bibl><bibl><author><!-- MISSING --></author><title>Omiah's farewell; inscribed to the ladies of London.</title><editor><!-- MISSING --></editor><publisher>printed for G. Kearsly, in Fleet-Street, MDCCLXXVI.</publisher><pubPlace>London</pubPlace><date>1776</date><note>Worth keeping because it is an example of a poem that was written using the voyage accounts rather than just a summary.</note></bibl></listBibl>