<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <!--ebb: Need to rewrite XSLT to calculate dates from start to end of term. Non XSLT solution: To begin for a new year, autogenerate a list of dates and days of week in Excel (start with manually entering the first week's dates, and add +7 to each; format as ISO dates. 
            Paste in template xml file and autotag day and week divs. 
            Then manually correct with holidays and Fall Break, etc.-->
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Syllabus: Coding and Data Visualization</title>
            <author>Elisa E. Beshero-Bondar</author>
            <author>Gregory H. Bondar</author>
            <sponsor>The University of Pittsburgh at Greensburg</sponsor>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>First digital edition in TEI, date: <date from="2016-01" to="2016-04">Spring
                  2016</date>. P5.</edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>University of Pittsburgh at Greensburg</authority>
            <pubPlace>Greensburg, PA, USA</pubPlace>
            <date>2016</date>
            <availability>
               <licence>Distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike
                  4.0 International License</licence>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <p>Spring 2016 is the fourth time a version of this course has been taught, and this is
               the third XML edition of the syllabus. This course is a new alternate course to the
               Coding and Digital Archives course taught in Fall 2015. The first edition of this
               course syllabus was in Fall 2013, in HTML only at <ptr
                  target="http://www.pitt.edu/~ebb8/DHDS/"/>.</p>
         </seriesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>Born digital.</p>
         </sourceDesc>

      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <front>
         <div type="courseID" style="outer">
            <head>Coding and Data Visualization</head>
            <p>Humanities 1050 / Social Sciences 1051</p>
            <div type="logo">
               <head>
                  <graphic url="blue-eye-icon-transMed.png" mimeType="image/png"/>
                  <desc>Pitt-Greensburg Digital Studies Logo: I Code!</desc>
               </head>
            </div>

            <div type="meetTimes">
               <p>
                  <hi rend="em">Spring 2016:</hi> Classes meet M W F 10:30 - 11:20 AM, 210 Cassell
                  Hall</p>
            </div>
            <div type="CRN">
               <p>Course Enrollment and Electives Info: </p>
               <list>
                  <item>Hum 1050: (Digital Humanities) course registration number:
                        <idno>29922</idno>
                  </item>
                  <item>Socsci 1051: (Digital Studies) course registration number:
                        <idno>29923</idno>
                  </item>
                  <item>Satisfies a core course requirement for <ref
                        target="http://greensburg.pitt.edu/academics/info/digital-studies"
                        >Pitt-Greensburg's Digital Studies Certificate</ref>
                  </item>
                  <item>Fulfills HM, Q2, or SS General Electives at Pitt-Greensburg</item>
               </list>
            </div>
            <div type="faculty">
               <head>Instructors</head>
               <p>co-taught by: <ref target="http://www.pitt.edu/~ebb8/">Prof. Elisa
                     Beshero-Bondar</ref>; email: ebb8 at pitt.edu and <ref
                     target="http://www.personal.psu.edu/ghb1/">Prof. Gregory Bondar</ref>; email:
                  ghb2 at pitt.edu</p>
               <p>Elisa's Office Hours in <hi rend="em">FOB 204</hi>
               </p>
               <list>
                  <!--ebb: check this!-->
                  <item>Mon. 4-5:30 PM</item>
                  <item>Thurs. 4-5:30 PM</item>
                  <item>after class in our computer lab, and by appointment (such as T or H between
                     10:30 AM and 1:30 PM)</item>
               </list>
               <p>Greg's Office Hours in <hi rend="em">FOB 104</hi>
               </p>
               <!--ebb: Check with Greg about this! -->
               <list>
                  <item>Mon. and Wed., 2 - 4 PM</item>
                  <item>and by appointment</item>
               </list>

            </div>
            <div type="online">
               <head>The Webs Where We Work:</head>
               <list>
                  <item>
                     <ref target="http://newtfire.org/dh/CDV.html">Course Home Website:
                        http://newtfire.org/dh/CDV.html</ref> Home of our syllabus and
                     schedule.</item>

                  <item><ref target="https://github.com/ebeshero/DHClass-Hub">DHClass-Hub:
                        https://github.com/ebeshero/DHClass-Hub</ref> Class GitHub Repository and
                     Issues Board</item>


                  <item>
                     <ref target="https://courseweb.pitt.edu">Courseweb:
                        https://courseweb.pitt.edu</ref> To submit homework assignments and exams
                     and read private course announcements</item>
                  <item>
                     <ref target="http://dh.obdurodon.org/file-naming_conventions.xhtml">How to
                        Construct Filenames for Courseweb Homework Submissions</ref>
                     <note> (courtesy of Obdurodon)</note>
                  </item>

                  <item>Server Access Instructions for Web Project Development on newtFire: [To Be
                     Announced]</item>

               </list>

            </div>
            <div type="projects">
               <head>Course Projects</head>
               <list>
                  <item>
                     <ref target="projectGuide.html">Guidelines for Projects Developed in This
                        Course</ref>
                  </item>
                  <item>
                     <ref target="studentProjects.html">Student Course Projects</ref>
                  </item>
               </list>
            </div>
            <div type="guides">
               <head>
                  <ref target="index.html">Explanatory Guides</ref>
               </head>
               <list>
                  <item>GitHub Tutorials:
                     <list>
                        <item><ref target="http://newtfire.org/dh/explainGitShell.html">Our orientation to GitHub via Command Line</ref></item>
                        <item><ref target="http://dh.obdurodon.org/github.xhtml">Obdurodon's orientation via Desktop Client</ref></item>
                        
                     </list>
                  </item>

                  <item>
                     <ref target="explainXML.html">Introduction to XML</ref>
                  </item>
                  <item>
                     <ref target="explainRNG.html">Guide to Schema Writing with Relax NG</ref>
                  </item>
                  <item>Regular Expressions (Regex)
                     <list><item><ref target="explainRegex.html">our tutorial on Regex</ref></item>
                        <item><ref target="http://www.regular-expressions.info/tutorial.html">Regular-Expressions.info Tutorial</ref>: a mine of helpful detail on regular expression matching,</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>
                     <ref target="explainHTML.html">Introduction to XHTML (and HTML)</ref>
                  </item>
                  <item>
                     <ref target="explainCSS.html">Introduction to Cascading Stylesheets (CSS)</ref>
                  </item>
                  <item>Javascript Resources: <list>
                     <item>
                        <ref target="http://dh.obdurodon.org/javascript.html">Introduction to
                           Javascript</ref>
                     </item>
                     <item>
                        <ref target="http://dh.obdurodon.org/javascript/classListToggle.xhtml"
                           >Javascript Toggling with classList and switch</ref>
                     </item>
                  </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>
                     <ref target="explainXPath.html">Follow the XPath!</ref>
                  </item>

                  <item>Schematron Resources:
                     <list>
                     <item><ref target="explainSchematron.html">Guide to Schema Writing with Schematron</ref></item>
                        <item><ref target="explainSchematronIdRefs.html">Explain @xml:id Lists and Testing with Schematron</ref></item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                     <item><ref target="explainXSLT.html">Introduction to XSLT</ref>
                  </item>
                  <item>
                     <ref target="explainXQuery.html">XQuery and the eXist XML Database</ref>
                  </item>
                  <item>SVG Tutorials, Editors, and Ideas: <list>
                        <item>
                           <ref target="http://tutorials.jenkov.com/svg/index.html">Jakob Jenkov's
                              SVG Tutorial</ref>: very thorough and handy reference</item>

                        <item>
                           <ref target="http://www.w3schools.com/svg/svg_intro.asp">w3 schools SVG
                              tutorial</ref>: a quick introduction, but not so thorough at the
                           Jenkov tutorial</item>
                        <item>
                           <ref target="http://www.math.wsu.edu/kcooper/M300/svgcheat.php">SVG Cheat
                              Sheet</ref>
                        </item>
                        <item>Obdurodon: <ref target="http://dh.obdurodon.org/svg-embedding.xhtml"
                              >How to Embed SVG in an XHTML Page</ref>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                           <ref target="http://www.carto.net/svg/samples/xslt/">carto:net: Using
                              XSLT to create SVG Content</ref>: We do all this in oXygen, but this
                           shows an alternative command-line processing of XSLT. </item>
                        <item>
                           <ref target="http://www.mathsisfun.com/geometry/unit-circle.html"
                              >Geometry of a Circle</ref> (for help if you want to plot points or
                           wedges on a circle). </item>
                     </list>
                     <list>
                        <item>Editors: (good for some freeform work): <ref
                              target="http://svg-edit.googlecode.com/svn/branches/2.5.1/editor/svg-editor.html"
                              >Google Code Online SVG Editor</ref>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                           <ref target="http://inkscape.org/en/">Inkscape</ref>: free SVG
                           software</item>
                     </list>
                     <list>
                        <item>Ideas: <ref target="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Diagram">Wikipedia's
                              page on diagrams</ref>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                           <ref target="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chart">Wikipedia on
                              charts</ref>
                        </item>

                     </list>
                  </item>
              
                 
                  <item>
                     <ref target="http://ebeshero.github.io/thalaba/cytosc.html">Introduction to
                        Network Analysis and Cytoscape for XML Coders</ref>
                  </item>
                  <item><ref target="housestyle.html">newtFire House Style</ref></item>


               </list>
            </div>
         </div>
      </front>
      <body>
         <div type="description" style="main">
            <head>Coding and Digital Archives: Course Description</head>
            <p>This course is all about doing interesting things with texts using computers and
               digital technology. Your professors are researchers of literature and anthropology,
               not computer programmers, and we teach this course based on our experience with
               collaborating on digital humanities projects, some of which you may find on <ref
                  target="newtfire.org">http://newtfire.org</ref>. We teach this course with an
               emphasis on working with texts as artifacts of human culture shaped primarily with
               words and letters—the forms of "written" language transferable to many media
               (including image and sound) that we can study with computer tools that we design for
               ourselves based on the questions we ask. We work with computers in this course as
               precision instruments that help us to read and process great quantities of
               information, and that lead us to make significant connections, ask new kinds of
               questions, and build models and interfaces to change our reading and thinking
               experience as people curious about human history, culture, and creativity. </p>
            <p>Our class is one of the core courses of <ref
                  target="http://greensburg.pitt.edu/academics/info/digital-studies"
                  >Pitt-Greensburg's Digital Studies Certificate</ref>, and it satisifes a range of
               general education requirements in quantitative reasoning, behavioral sciences, and
               humanities. That is because this course is distinctively interdisciplinary, one of a
               very few available at Pitt, in engaging formal and quantitative reasoning through
               computer coding in ways that matter to students in humanities and social sciences who
               are not training to be computer scientists. Students gain hands-on experience in this
               course with applying computer coding to represent and investigate cultural materials.
               As we design projects together, you will gain practical experience in editing and you
               will certainly fine-tune your precision in writing and thinking.</p>
            <p> We will be working primarily with eXtensible Markup Language (XML) because it is a
               powerful tool for modelling texts that we can adapt creatively to our interests and
               questions. XML represents a standard in adaptability and human-readability in digital
               code, and it works together with related technologies with which you will gain
               working experience: You'll learn how to write XPath expressions: a formal language
               for searching and extracting information from XML code which serves as the basis for
               transforming XML into many publishable forms, using XSLT and XQuery. You'll learn to
               write XSLT: a programming "stylesheet" transforming language designed to convert XML
               to publishable formats, as well as XQuery, a query (or search) language for
               extracting information from XML files bundled collectively. You will learn how to
               design your own systematic coding methods to work on projects, and how to write your
               own rules in schema languages (like Schematron and Relax-NG) to keep your projects
               organized and prevent errors. You'll gain experience with an international XML
               language called TEI (after the Text Encoding Initiative) which serves as the
               international standard for coding digital archives of cultural materials. Since one
               of the best and most widely accessible ways to publish XML is on the worldwide web,
               you'll gain working experience with HTML code (a markup language that is a kind of
               XML) and styling HTML with Cascading Stylesheets (CSS). We will do all of this with
               an eye to your understanding how coding works—and no longer relying without question
               on expensive commercial software as the "only" available solution, because such
               software is usually not designed with our research questions in mind. </p>
            <p>Students who complete this course will gain skills in digital project management and
               web development, and their digital projects will distinguish them as investigators
               and makers, able to wield computers creatively and effectively for human interests.
               Your success will require patience, dedication, and regular communication and
               interaction with us, working through assignments on a daily basis. Your success will
               NOT require perfection, but rather your regular efforts throughout the course, your
               documenting of problems when your coding doesn't yield the results you want. Homework
               exercises are a back-and-forth, intensive dialogue between you and your instructors,
               and we plan to spend a great deal of time with you individually over these as we work
               together. Our guiding principle in developing assignments and working with you is
               that the best way for you to learn and succeed is through regular practice as you
               hone your skills. Our goal is not to make you expert programmers (as we are far from
               that ourselves). Instead, we want you to learn how to apply coding technologies for
               your own purposes, how to track down answers to questions, how to think your way
               algorithmically (step-by-step) through problems to find good solutions.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="objectives" style="main">
            <head>Learning Objectives:</head>
            <list>
               <item>Work with Texts as Artifacts—As Physical and Virtual Objects: <list>

                     <item>Generate "digital surrogates": digitally represent facsimiles of rare
                        manuscripts and other kinds of documents, and make their content digitally
                        searchable.</item>
                     <item>Reflect and write on the issues and problems with digital representation,
                        as well as the capacity of the digital medium to enhance or add dimensions
                        to a physical text.</item>

                     <item>Learn and practice coding in eXtensible Markup Language (XML) and related
                        coding technologies: to "mark up," process, and extract information about
                        the structure, physical condition, and cultural contexts of textual
                        artifacts.</item>
                  </list>
               </item>
               <item>Gain Experience with Information Retrieval, "Distant Reading," and Autotagging
                  Techniques: <list>
                     <item>Write code to apply searching and data extraction methods through
                        multiple kinds of pattern-matching algorithms, including forms of regular
                        expression matching. Take conventional boolean searches and library database
                        searches to new levels.</item>
                     <item>Apply "mining" and "drilling" methods associated with "distant reading"
                        to apply computers to read and design more and differently than we could do
                        "manually" or with unassisted eyes and brains. </item>
                     <item>Learn how to "autotag" enormous texts or collections of texts, for
                        practical results: to code the structure of enormous texts from a distance,
                        in order to navigate them and make them accessible through distant
                        reading.</item>
                     <item>Reflect on and test the strong and weak points of "distant reading" and
                        processing methods: (What do we learn, and what is at stake in current
                        applications of digital "distant reading"?)</item>

                  </list>
               </item>
               <item>Gain Project Design and Editing Experience: <list>
                     <item>Gain digital editing experience with proposing, designing, and
                        contributing to one or more digital research projects, applying coding to
                        the preserving, sharing, and investigating of textual resources</item>
                     <item>Transform XML code into publishable web formats, to build or contribute
                        to a project website.</item>
                     <item>Design navigation elements, and build visual aids and models (such as
                        timelines and tree diagrams) from texts: to generate charts and images from
                        extracted data</item>
                     <item>Gain experience with plotting digital maps and charts, working with
                        historical maps, layered maps, and Google Earth</item>
                  </list>
               </item>
               <item>Last but not least: Discover that you read and write with "new eyes," with
                  greater precision and agility, thanks to your adventures in working with digital
                  texts!</item>
            </list>
         </div>
         <div type="courseMtls" style="main">
            <head>All the Tools You Need As We Begin:</head>

            <p>Download and install the following software on your own personal computer(s) on or
               before the first day of class. These software tools are available in our campus
               computing labs, too.</p>
            <list type="numbered">
               <item>
                  <hi rend="em">All students:</hi>
                  <ref target="http://www.oxygenxml.com/">&lt;oXygen/&gt;</ref>. The University of
                  Pittsburgh has purchased a site license for this software, which is installed in
                  the Pitt computer labs on multiple campuses, and it's in use in courses here at
                  Greensburg and at Oakland. The license also permits students enrolled in the
                  course to install the software on their home computers (for course-related use
                  only). When installing this on your own computers, <hi rend="em">you will need the
                     license key</hi>, which we have posted on our course Announcements section of
                     <ref target="https://courseweb.pitt.edu">Courseweb</ref>.</item>
               <item>All students require a good means of secure file transfer (SFTP) for homework
                  assignments and projects (also available in the campus computer labs). There are
                  several good options available. We recommend you download and install on your own
                  computers one (or more) of the following, depending on your platform: (Feel free
                  to experiment with these and others!) <list>
                     <item>
                        <hi rend="em">Windows users:</hi> one of the following FTP clients—the
                        functionality is similar: <list>
                           <item>
                              <ref
                                 target="http://www.wm.edu/offices/it/services/software/licensedsoftware/webeditingsftp/sshsecureshell/index.php"
                                 >SSH Secure Shell Client</ref>
                              <note> (this one is the most ad-free experience)</note>
                           </item>
                           <item>
                              <ref target="http://winscp.net/eng/download.php">WinSCP</ref>
                              <note>An alternative to SSH with a few more bells and whistles (This
                                 is one we used for a long time, since the 1990s, but we now use SSH
                                 and Filezilla more frequently.)</note>
                           </item>
                           <item> or <ref
                                 target="https://filezilla-project.org/download.php?show_all=1"
                                 >FileZilla</ref>
                              <note> (a great tool, but be wary of accepting its bundled ad offers
                                 as you install!)</note>
                           </item>
                        </list>
                     </item>
                     <item>
                        <hi rend="em">Mac users:</hi>
                        <list>
                           <item>
                              <ref target="http://fetchsoftworks.com/fetch/">Fetch</ref> (students
                              may obtain free licenses at <ref
                                 target="http://fetchsoftworks.com/fetch/free"
                                 >http://fetchsoftworks.com/fetch/free</ref>)</item>
                           <item>or <ref
                                 target="https://filezilla-project.org/download.php?show_all=1"
                                 >FileZilla</ref>
                              <note>(a great tool, but be wary of accepting its bundled ad offers as
                                 you install!)</note>
                           </item>
                        </list>
                     </item>
                     <item>
                        <hi rend="em">Linux users:</hi> You probably don't need to install anything,
                        but look at how your system handles secure file transfer (SFTP).
                           <note>(FileZilla or other clients designed for Linux
                           environments.)</note>
                     </item>
                  </list>
               </item>

               <item><hi rend="em">Read the <ref target="CDV.html">Course Description</ref></hi> and
                  this Syllabus page to see how this course works on a day-to-day basis.</item>
               <item>This course fulfills general education requirements in Q2, NS, SS, and HM, and
                  it fulfills a core requirement for <ref
                     target="http://greensburg.pitt.edu/academics/info/digital-studies">the Digital
                     Studies Certificate at Pitt-Greensburg</ref>. Think about where this course
                  might fit in your academic career, and how you might apply the skills you learn
                  here.</item>
               <item>No coding experience? Don't worry! You are in very good company. We don't
                  expect any of you to have written a line of computer code before now. Past
                  students in this course who never saw anything like markup or XML code have
                  designed projects (<ref target="http://newtfire.org/dh/studentProjects.html">like
                     these</ref>) and even spoken about them at an undergraduate conference! You'll
                  help continue some of these projects we've started, and you'll learn to build and
                  create digital tools for yourself with skills we hope you will keep
                  developing.</item>


            </list>
         </div>
         <div type="optionalTexts" style="main">
            <head>Optional Texts (Helpful Reference Guides):</head>
            <list>
               <item>
                  <bibl>
                     <author>Michael Kay</author>, <title>XSLT 2.0 and XPath 2.0: Programmer's
                        Reference</title>, <edition>4th edition</edition>
                     <publisher>(Wiley Publishing</publisher>, <date>2008</date>) <idno>ISBN-13:
                        978-0-470-19274-0</idno>
                  </bibl>
                  <note> This is really THE authoritative word on XSLT and XPath, written by a
                     designer of the official W3C specifications of XSLT 2.0 that we're using. We
                     are learning from this book ourselves and consult it frequently! We're not
                     requiring that you buy it, but we recommend it to have a powerful reference at
                     your fingertips and for learning more on your own. There's a kindle edition
                     available but poorly designed for searching, so we (actually) prefer the
                     hardcover print edition. If you're going to purchase it, be sure you pick up
                     the current edition (not the earlier ones).</note>
               </item>
               <item>
                  <bibl>
                     <author>Bruce Hyslop, Lenny Burdette, and Chris Casciano</author>, <title>The
                        Web Design Pocket Guide Boxed Set</title> (includes 3 books: <title>The HTML
                        Pocket Guide</title>, <title>The JavaScript Pocket Guide</title>, and
                        <title>The CSS Pocket Guide</title>) <publisher>(Pearson / Peachpit Pocket
                        Guides</publisher>, <date>2010</date>). <idno>ISBN-13: 978-0321743749</idno>
                  </bibl>
                  <note> You can probably locate much of the content of these books online, on sites
                     like <ref target="http://www.w3schools.com/">w3schools.com</ref> (which we use
                     ourselves), but we've discovered that sometimes it's handy to have print
                     reference guides around when working on computer projects!</note>
               </item>

            </list>
         </div>
         <div type="grading" style="main">
            <head>Grading:</head>
            <div type="homework">
               <head>Homework Exercises (35%):</head>
               <p>Regular homework exercises are key to the active learning process in this course.
                  Each day will involve some small assignment, building to the larger course
                  projects. Students must complete (on time) at least 90% of each homework component
                  (coding assignments, short response papers, blog postings and responses, in order
                  to pass the course. For students who complete the 90% requirement, the homework
                  taken all together, is worth 35% of your course grade.</p>
               <div type="coding">
                  <p>
                     <hi rend="em">Coding assignments:</hi> These are assignments you'll complete by
                     writing code to achieve a specified result by applying a coding method you are
                     learning. Often, there will be multiple ways of accomplishing the task. You
                     will receive lots of feedback from us, in the form of posted results and
                     individual commentary on your assignments as needed. If you don't achieve the
                     result you want, you may still receive full credit so long as you have made a
                     serious attempt to describe your process, what else you tried, what results you
                     expected vs. what results you got, and what you think went wrong. Documenting
                     problems is key to the learning process, and sometimes the documentation
                     process helps lead you to the solution and always helps your learning
                     process.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="papers">
                  <p>
                     <hi rend="em">Response papers:</hi> We'll assign short response papers (about 1
                     to 2 pages) to online readings or as evaluations of significant digital
                     humanities web projects and resources. Your response should do more than
                     summarize the article or site (which you could just do by skimming or reading
                     the first paragraph), but should demonstrate a thoughtful reflection on
                     specific ideas and issues. When evaluating a web resource, don't simply praise
                     or condemn it without going into details about why a key component is effective
                     or poorly designed. Good response papers demonstrate care and reflection, and
                     you may choose to respond to the overarching ideas of a piece, or to selected
                     details of specific interest. </p>
               </div>
               <div type="blogPost">
                  <p>
                     <hi rend="em">Project postings:</hi> These will begin on your GitHub pages
                     after you have formed teams to work on the course project. As you work on
                     course projects in teams, we expect that each team (not each individual
                     student) will post a project update, usually by Friday of a given week. These
                     postings should be brief status reports about your project work: what you've
                     accomplished in the preceding week, what problems you're facing, what you've
                     been learning, resources you've been discussing, and should conclude by
                     discussing what you plan to do the following week.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="blogResponse">
                  <p>
                     <hi rend="em">Project responses:</hi> Again, these begin after you have formed
                     project teams. Each student (not each team this time) must post one response to
                     a blog posting by some other team, usually due on a Monday (or the class period
                     following the team project posts). These responses can be brief but for credit
                     (and to be useful) they need to be thoughtful: something more than "good work!"
                     or "very interesting!" Respond to something specific in teh blog: make a
                     suggestion, offer a critique, ask or answer a question, discuss how something
                     in the blog post gave you an idea for your project, share a resource you've
                     found that may be helpful for the others.</p>
               </div>
            </div>
            <div type="participation">
               <head>Participation: In Class and on the DH-ClassHub(15%):</head>
               <p> Coding and programming in real life is a social activity, and professionals in
                  the real world aren't "know-it-all" experts who work alone, but rather are tuned
                  into discussion boards and regularly ask and answer questions to stay sharp and to
                  learn from their community. In this class, we want you to work together and talk
                  to each other and your instructors as your community resource, so we have built
                  this into our course participation grade as a formal expectation. <hi rend="em"
                     >Beginning by week two, we'll expect each student to post at least once per
                     week on our online class discussion board</hi>, and we strongly encourage you
                  to do more than this minimum. Ask questions, make suggestions, share helpful
                  resources you've found. Help each other out by trying to answer questions (and
                  read the instructor posts too as we wade in to help). Your instructors will likely
                  be dominating the class time as we model concepts and methods, so the discussion
                  boards give you all a good space to form into a coding community to help each
                  other and reflect together. Also, if you have a question about an assignment, <hi
                     rend="em">always think of the discussion board as your first resource</hi> to
                  check for helpful hints and to post your questions, because others may have the
                  same question and answers are best shared! Of course you may e-mail us, but we
                  really prefer you go the discussion board first, and doing so is, after all, worth
                  course credit as your participation grade.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="exams">
               <head>Quizzes and Tests (15%):</head>
               <p>As scheduled throughout the course there will be several (probably about six to
                  eight) short quizzes and tests that will take roughly half of the class period
                  time. These will ask you to demonstrate your knowledge of coding practices and
                  vocabulary learned in an immediately preceding portion of the course. We will drop
                  your lowest two scores on these exams. (No make-up exams are given: see course
                  policies below.) </p>
            </div>
            <div type="final-project">
               <head>Project (35%):</head>
               <p> Within the first three weeks of the course, we will familiarize you with some of
                  our ongoing projects and their associated research questions. These include the
                     <ref target="http://pacific.pitt.edu">Digital Archives and Pacific Cultures
                     Site</ref>, <ref target="http://mitford.pitt.edu">the Digital Mitford
                     Archive</ref>, and a site presenting <ref
                     target="http://www.pitt.edu/~ebb8/EmilyDickinson16/1601.html">manuscript
                     variants in Emily Dickinson's Fascicle 16</ref>. You will be working in teams
                  to contribute to these ongoing projects, to develop a site of your own designed to
                  enhance these projects or take them in a new direction. The direction you take
                  will be partly shaped by you in conversation with the instructors.
                  <!--We will also assign you to
                  propose a project based on a text or set of texts that interest you and suggest a
                  promising research question to explore with our coding methods, and we'll respond
                  to these to help you refine your ideas. We'll ask you all to read each other's
                  refined proposals, and the class as a whole (working with the instructors) will
                  select which of these we want to pursue through the term, and form groups to begin
                  work.-->
                  Development of the project will involve doing a careful document analysis,
                  developing a coding plan and rules to follow, coding your text(s), and developing
                  programs to address your research question. It will also involve designing a
                  project site to represent your research questions, the texts and your processing
                  of them, as well as to share your coding scripts and to reflect on the results of
                  your investigation. We will post milestones you must meet for the projects
                  throughout the term. Project teams must meet 90% of the project milestone due
                  dates in order to receive a passing grade. It is expected that project teams meet
                  regularly (each week), check in with the instructors, and delegate tasks to each
                  other. Reporting on project progress is required as part of the regular homework
                  assignments for the course. Teams are encouraged to meet with us instructors
                  during (or outside) our scheduled office hours. In the last few weeks of the
                  course, almost all of your course work outside class will be devoted to project
                  development, applying the methods you've been learning across the semester.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="scale">
               <head>Grading Scale:</head>
               <p>Grades are posted on Courseweb, and follow this standard scale: A: 93-100%, A-:
                  90-92%, B+: 87-89%, B: 83-86%, B-: 80-82%, C+: 77-79%, C: 73-76%, C-: 70-72%, D+:
                  67-69%, D: 60-66%, F: 59% and below. In taking the course on a S / NC (pass-fail)
                  basis, students must earn a C to receive Satisfactory credit. We give G grades
                  (incomplete) at our discretion and only in conformity with the guidelines in the
                  Pitt-Greensburg Bulletin: <ref
                     target="http://www.bulletins.pitt.edu/greensburg/upg-academicpolicies.htm#Anchor-Grading-9431"
                     >http://www.bulletins.pitt.edu/greensburg/upg-academicpolicies.htm#Anchor-Grading-9431</ref>.</p>
            </div>
         </div>
         <div type="policies" style="main">
            <head>Course Policies:</head>
            <p>Each day we are covering material that builds on earlier material and assignments, so
               your success depends upon regular attendance and completing each assignment on
               time.</p>
            <div type="daily">
               <head>Attendance:</head>
               <p> We strictly require your attendance, as it is not only a setback to yourself but
                  to the entire class and the success of our projects if students are repeatedly
                  absent. Students must attend at least 90% of our class meetings in order <hi
                     rend="em">to pass</hi> the course. Late arrival—particularly a pattern of
                  repeated late arrivals—may be counted as absences at our discretion. Attendance
                  will be recorded for every class, and each student can earn percentage points
                  added towards their total course grade based on the following scale: Zero or one
                  absence: +3 pts; Two absences: +2 pts; Three or more: +0 pts. To earn credit, you
                  must be present in the classroom by the beginning of class, until class is
                  dismissed. For your own sanity, do not miss two consecutive classes. If you are
                  experiencing a genuine emergency or crisis, alert us and provide documentation.
                  (We do not want you to attend class if you have a fever or flu-like symptoms! If
                  you wish to be excused from two or more consecutive class meetings due to your own
                  documented illness, please contact one of the following: the Office of the Vice
                  President for Academic Affairs, Prof. Wes Jamison (724-836-9988 or jamison at
                  pitt.edu), our Campus Health Center (Nurse Patty or Pamela Reed, 724-836-9947 or
                  upgdoc at pitt.edu), or the Director of Counseling, Gayle Pamerleau (gaylep at
                  pitt.edu), who can then officially alert all of your professors.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="deadlines">
               <head>Deadlines:</head>
               <p> Your daily homework for this course is time-sensitive! Coding assignments,
                  response papers, and other homework exercises must be uploaded to CourseWeb (or to
                  Box, or the Sandbox server as specified), by the date and time indicated by the
                  instructors. Homework assignments will be posted online to our class DHDS website
                  and linked from our schedule, so students who miss class are nevertheless expected
                  to consult the schedule and submit assignments on time. Because we post and share
                  answers to homework exercises after submission deadlines, we will not accept late
                  homework submissions. In order to pass the course, students must submit at least
                  90% of the regular homework assignments, and complete at least 90% of the work in
                  each component of the course.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="makeUp">
               <head>Exam Policy:</head>
               <p> Similarly, because we will be posting answers or sharing them in class, we do not
                  give make-up examinations. However, we will drop your lowest two exam scores for
                  the class, so that you may miss up to two exams without penalty.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="courtesy">
               <head>Classroom Courtesy:</head>
               <p>Our class is fast paced, and requires that we all be making the best use we can of
                  our in-person class sessions. Arriving late and leaving early disrupts the
                  important collective mental activity of class. So does in-class texting and
                  checking your cell phone. While class is in progress, talking disruptively,
                  leaving the classroom, texting or using a cell phone or computer, reading a
                  newspaper, or other distracting behavior will be actively discouraged, and may
                  result in a deduction in your Participation grade. Please respect what we do in
                  the classroom: attend class regularly, and come prepared to contribute your
                  questions and ideas.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="email">
               <head>E-mail:</head>
               <p>Each student is issued a University email address (username@pitt.edu) upon
                  admission. This email address may be used by the University for official
                  communication with students. Students are expected to read email sent to this
                  account on a regular basis. Failure to read and react to University communications
                  in a timely manner does not absolve the student from knowing and complying with
                  the content of the communications. The University provides an email forwarding
                  service that allows students to read their email via other service providers
                  (e.g., Hotmail, AOL, Yahoo). Students who choose to forward their email from their
                  pitt.edu address to another address do so at their own risk. If email is lost as a
                  result of forwarding, it does not absolve the student from responding to official
                  communications sent to their University email address. To forward email sent to
                  your University account, go to http://accounts.pitt.edu, log into your account,
                  click on Edit Forwarding Addresses, and follow the instructions on the page. Be
                  sure to log out of your account when you have finished. (For the full Email
                  Communication Policy, go to <ref
                     target="http://www.bc.pitt.edu/policies/policy/09/09-10-01.html"
                     >http://www.bc.pitt.edu/policies/policy/09/09-10-01.html</ref>.)</p>
            </div>


            <div type="integrity">
               <head>Academic Integrity</head>
               <p>
                  <hi rend="em">Source Citation and Plagiarism:</hi> One goal of our course is to
                  reflect on how best to cite sources in digital contexts. We will consider how and
                  why such citations differ from documenting printed texts. We will also consider
                  the ease and frequency with which digital texts and graphics are plagiarized on
                  the worldwide web, and discuss how the omission of source citations detracts from
                  the authority of a digital information resource. We expect you to practice mindful
                  source citation, and plagiarism on your part will have very serious
                  consequences.</p>
               <p>Plagiarism falsely represents another source’s words or ideas as your own, and, if
                  you commit plagiarism in this course, you will receive a final course grade of F
                  and be reported to the Vice President of Academic Affairs. Representing the voice
                  of another individual as your own voice constitutes plagiarism, however generous
                  that person may be in “helping” you with an assignment. Turning in an assignment
                  generated collectively under the name of a single individual is considered
                  plagiarism. <hi rend="em">When instructed to collaborate on a project, project
                     collaborators share collective authorship and should identify themselves
                     directly as a team.</hi> To avoid plagiarism, cite your sources whenever you
                  quote, paraphrase, or summarize material, or use digital images from any outside
                  source (including websites, articles, books, course readings, Courseweb postings,
                  or someone else’s notes). When using the “copy” and “paste” features as you read
                  and research, be sure that you are carefully marking that these passages are
                  unprocessed from their source, so that you know to process it later. Forgetting to
                  do so not only produces sloppy work but (whether you intended it or not) results
                  in a false representation. As long as you make a good faith and clear effort to
                  cite your sources, you will not be faulted for plagiarism, but your work will be
                  penalized if citations are inaccurate, unclear, or lack important information.
                  Cheating on exams or exercises will also receive a final course grade of F and
                  will be reported to the Vice President of Academic Affairs.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="disability">
               <head>Disability Services:</head>
               <p>If you have a disability for which you are or may be requesting an accommodation,
                  you are encouraged to contact both your instructor and the Director of the
                  Learning Resources Center, Dr. Lou Ann Sears, Room 240 Millstein Library Building
                  (724) 836-7098 (voice) or los3 at pitt.edu as early as possible in the term.
                  Learning Resources Center will verify your disability and determine reasonable
                  accommodations for this course.</p>
            </div>
         </div>
         <div type="resources">
            <head>Resources</head>
            <p>We gratefully acknowledge <ref target="http://dh.obdurodon.org/">David Birnbaum's
                  Digital Humanities course</ref> as our starting point and resource for much of our
               development. Other useful resources include:</p>
            <list>
               <item>
                  <ref target="https://exam.obdurodon.org/">eXam Center</ref>: a learning resource
                  for quizzing yourself on coding that we're learning in class. <note>(We need to
                     arrange for you to have individual accounts here to sign in and take the
                     quizzes.)</note>
               </item>
               <item>
                  <ref target="http://www.mulberrytech.com/papers/schematron-Philly.pdf">Schematron:
                     an intro guide</ref>
               </item>
               <item>
                  <ref target="http://programminghistorian.org/lessons/">The Programming Historian
                     (full collection of tutorials)</ref>
               </item>
               <item>
                  <ref target="http://programminghistorian.org/lessons/topic-modeling-and-mallet"
                     >Getting Started with Topic Modelling and MALLET</ref>
               </item>
               <item>
                  <ref target="http://www.naturalearthdata.com/">Natural Earth (mapping
                     resource)</ref>
               </item>
            </list>
         </div>
         <div type="extProjects">
            <head>Projects and Sites That Inspire Us</head>
            <list>
               <item>
                  <ref target="http://obdurodon.org">Obdurodon</ref>: where we learned what we can
                  teach, and where we're still learning.</item>
               <item><ref target="http://vtm.epfl.ch/page-109337.html">Venice Time Machine</ref>:
                  very ambitious, enormous project team of faculty and students to study and model a
                  thousand years of Venice, digitizing "kilometers of archives."</item>
               <item>
                  <ref target="http://mapoflondon.uvic.ca/index.htm">Map of Early Modern
                     London</ref>
               </item>
               <item>
                  <ref target="http://lordbyron.cath.lib.vt.edu/index.php?choose=About">Lord Byron
                     and His Times</ref>: The very thoughtful stylistic design of this important
                  project reproduces the style of nineteenth-century print and layout. The content
                  makes many rare materials about Lord Byron's social network searchable and
                  connected to the web of linked open data. </item>
               <item>
                  <ref target="http://shelleygodwinarchive.org/">The Shelley-Godwin Archive</ref>:
                  digitizes the manuscripts of Percy and Mary Shelley, and Mary Shelley’s parents,
                  William Godwin and Mary Wollstonecraft—manuscripts often written in multiple
                  hands. Provides an important study of the Frankenstein notebooks to demonstrate
                  how much of a role Percy Shelley played in the writing of Frankenstein. The
                  archive provides a good model of the use of TEI for manuscript encoding and of
                  complex and multiple visualizations of manuscript texts. </item>
               <item>
                  <ref
                     target="http://jetson.unl.edu:8080/cocoon/tokenx/index.html?file=../xml/base.xml"
                     >TokenX: a text visualization, analysis, and play tool</ref>
               </item>
               <item>
                  <ref target="http://homes.cs.washington.edu/~jheer//files/zoo/">A Tour Through the
                     Visualization Zoo</ref> (Lots of fascinating approaches to visualizing
                  information in dynamic graphs and maps)</item>
               <item>
                  <ref target="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Xe1TZaElTAs">Clay Shirky on Love,
                     Internet Style</ref> (9 minutes of Youtube inspiration: on what lasts, and why
                  community matters in our digital worlds.)</item>

            </list>
         </div>


         <div type="schedule">
            <head>Coding and Data Visualization</head>
            <div type="week" n="1">
               <div type="day">
                  <head>
                     <date when="2016-01-06">W 01-06</date>
                  </head>
                  <div type="inclass">
                     <p>Welcome! Intro to the course, and Intro to XML and working in
                        &lt;oXygen/&gt;: Write your first XML. <hi>Mindful File Management</hi>
                           (<ref target="http://dh.obdurodon.org/file-naming_conventions.xhtml">how
                           to name</ref>, store, share, and submit files in this course). Setting up
                        accounts for web server and for GitHub. <ref
                           target="http://www.simplyrecipes.com/recipes/gazpacho">Gazpacho
                           Soup</ref>
                     </p>
                  </div>
                  <div type="assign">
                     <list>
                        <item>By Fri. 1/8: Install &lt;oXygen/&gt; software on your own computers.
                              <ref target="https://courseweb.pitt.edu">Instructions and license key
                              posted on Courseweb</ref>.</item>
                        <item>Read our <title level="a"><ref target="explainXML.html">Introduction
                                 to XML</ref></title>, and read <title level="a"><ref
                                 target="http://dh.obdurodon.org/file-naming_conventions.xhtml"
                                 >File-Naming Conventions for Courseweb Homework
                              Submissions</ref></title>.</item>
                        <item><hi rend="strong">First XML exercise for New Students:</hi> Look at
                           this recipe for <ref
                              target="http://www.simplyrecipes.com/recipes/gazpacho">gazpacho
                              soup</ref>. What if you were running a restaurant and needed to create
                           a system to file it according to ingredients to purchase, to track
                           quantities per unit serving--and this recipe were one of, say, 100 other
                           recipes you're keeping on file? Or, what if you needed to adapt it with
                           markup to fit a system like we see at the GitHub-based recipe center <ref
                              target="http://forkthecookbook.com/">ForktheCookbook.com</ref>? Think
                           about a good system for tagging the file for this long-term situation,
                           and mark up your file accordingly. Experiment with this and write a
                           complete XML file in a way that makes sense to represent the recipe, and
                           try to make use of elements as well as attributes in your markup. There
                           is no single way to do this exercise, but we want you to think about how
                           you nest levels of information (elements within elements), and the
                           relationship between elements and attributes in XML: Can the attributes
                           hold information from the main text, perhaps removing it from the body of
                           the text?) Submit the results on Courseweb, in the folder labelled
                           "Upload Assignments Here," before our next class.</item>
                        <item><hi rend="strong">Continuing Students:</hi>
                           <list>
                              <item>Work on project code or your choice of an interesting XML coding
                                 challenge.</item>
                              <item>Help us test-pilot some new methods with GitHub: See instructors
                                 for details.</item>
                           </list></item>
                        <item><hi rend="em">By Fri. 1/8 or Mon. 1/11:</hi> Read <ref
                              target="http://dh.obdurodon.org/github.xhtml">the Obdurodon GitHub
                              tutorial</ref>, then create your GitHub account. Clone <ref
                              target="https://github.com/ebeshero/DHClass-Hub">our class GitHub
                              repository</ref> to your local machine(s). Practice opening an Issue
                           and pushing files to the Sandbox directory.</item>

                     </list>
                  </div>
               </div>
               <div type="day">
                  <head>
                     <date when="2016-01-08">F 01-08</date>
                  </head>
                  <div type="inclass">
                     <p>Setting up GitHub, Working in the Cloud and campus lab access. "Markup" vs.
                        "Markdown." Discussion of the XML recipe homework: XML Comments, Validity,
                        and Well-formedness, and how to work with oXygen. Web Accounts: collect
                        info.</p>
                  </div>
                  <div type="assign">

                     <list>
                        <item><hi rend="em">XML Exercise 2:</hi> Choose the text of one letter from
                           one of the following websites (click through until you see a complete
                           letter), and copy its text into &lt;oXygen/&gt;. Then, mark it up in XML,
                           using your own system of tagging, as seems appropriate, to code the
                           structure and the content of the document. Save and name your document
                           according to the File-Naming Conventions (which hold for all coding
                           homework in this course), and upload to Courseweb. Options: <list>
                              <item>
                                 <ref target="http://www.pbs.org/wgbh/aia/part4/4h2925.html">
                                    Harriet Jacobs: Selected Writings and Correspondence </ref>
                              </item>
                              <item>
                                 <ref target="http://englishhistory.net/byron/letters.html"> Lord
                                    Byron: Selected Letters </ref>
                              </item>
                              <item>
                                 <ref
                                    target="http://www.woolfonline.com/timepasses/?q=letters/overview"
                                    >Virginia Woolf letters</ref>
                              </item>
                           </list>
                        </item>
                        <item><hi rend="em"><ref
                                 target="https://github.com/ebeshero/DHClass-Hub/issues/10">Reading
                                 and Discussion Post on GitHub</ref></hi> Read Gabrielle Kirilloff,
                              <ref target="http://gk.obdurodon.org/seminar/seminarPaper.xhtml"
                              >“&lt;Traversing_the_Tree/&gt;”</ref><!--, the short article, <ref
                           target="http://www.idsnews.com/article/2015/04/frankenstein-novel-analyzed"
                           >“Frankenstein novel analyzed”</ref>-->
                           <!--and scroll through <ref
                              target="http://balisage.net/Proceedings/vol13/html/Piez01/BalisageVol13-Piez01.html"
                              >Wendell Piez's conference talk and images for the Balisage Markup
                              Conference 2014</ref>. If you like, you can take a close look at his <ref
                                 target="https://github.com/wendellpiez/Luminescent/blob/master/lmnl/frankenstein-as-published.lmnl"
                                 >LMNL code of Frankenstein on GitHub</ref>.-->
                           Then go to our class GitHub Issues page to discuss: <hi rend="em"
                              >Discussion Prompts:</hi>
                           <list>
                              <item>What perspective does Kirilloff provide on the kinds of XML
                                 markup we are learning, the history and context of hierarchical
                                 markup, and its potential issues?</item>
                              <item>Consider the examples of overlapping hierarchies in Kirilloff's
                                 reading: What ideas are presented for how to deal with these in
                                 code, and how effective might these be? Is it possible to write XML
                                 to get around the problems raised in these pieces?</item>
                           </list> For full credit, your posts should make specific reference to
                           passages in Kirilloff's essay, and reflect on those passages. Raising
                           questions is encouraged, and so is responding to each other.</item>
                     </list>

                  </div>
               </div>
            </div>
            <div type="week" n="2">
               <div type="day">
                  <head>
                     <date when="2016-01-11">M 01-11</date>
                  </head>
                  <div type="inclass">
                     <list>
                        <item>Discussion of homework, and XML: Validity and Well-formedness.</item>
                        <item>Document Analysis, Overlapping Hierarchies, and Coding: Exercise with
                              <ref target="http://www.online-literature.com/coleridge/640/">Kubla
                              Khan</ref></item>

                     </list>


                  </div>
                  <div type="assign">
                     <p><hi rend="em">XML exercise 3:</hi> Review our feedback on your coding
                        exercises so far and submit revisions if we asked you to. Mark up a text of
                        your choice (any genre; manageable but reasonable size; foreign languages
                        welcome). Work on applying attributes with your elements, and doing so in a
                        careful and systematic way. </p>

                  </div>
               </div>
               <div type="day">
                  <head>
                     <date when="2016-01-13">W 01-13</date>
                  </head>
                  <div type="inclass">
                     <p>The concept of "UX."</p>
                     <p>XML projects in digital humanities. Introduce some or all of the following
                        Pitt-Greensburg student projects:</p>

                     <list>
                        <item><ref target="http://nelson.newtfire.org/">Nell Nelson
                           Project</ref></item>
                        <item><ref target="http://dickinson16.newtfire.org/">Emily Dickinson
                              Fascicle 16</ref></item>
                        <item><ref target="http://pacific.pitt.edu/dhds/youTube/">YouTube Comment
                              Analysis Project</ref></item>
                        <!--  <item><ref target="http://pacific.pitt.edu">Pacific Project</ref></item>
                  <item><ref target="http://digitalmitford.org">Digital Mitford Project</ref></item>-->
                     </list>
                  </div>
                  <div type="assign">
                     <p><hi rend="em">Response Paper:</hi> Choose one of the following large-scale
                        Digital Humanities projects to explore, and write a response paper
                        addressing 1) what distinctive approaches the site takes to sharing
                        information and visualizing data, 2) whether and how the site shares its
                        methods or information sources behind its visuals, and 3) the effectiveness
                        of the user experience (“UX”) in navigating at least one or two significant
                        areas of the site.</p>
                     <list>

                        <item><ref target="http://lotrproject.com/">LOTR Project: Visualizing
                              Tolkien's Works on the Web</ref></item>
                        <item><ref target="http://menus.nypl.org/">What's on the menu?</ref> (be
                           sure to read the About page for the project goals)</item>
                        <item><ref target="http://orbis.stanford.edu/">ORBIS: The Stanford
                              Geospatial Network Model of the Roman World</ref></item>

                     </list>
                     <p>Read <title level="a"><ref target="explainRNG.html">Intro to Relax
                           NG</ref></title>.</p>
                  </div>
               </div>
               <div type="day">
                  <head>
                     <date when="2016-01-15">F 01-15</date>
                  </head>
                  <div type="inclass">
                     <p><hi rend="em">Test 1: XML, markup.</hi></p>
                     <p>Schema Languages: Writing the Rules. Writing Relax NG</p>
                  </div>
                  <div type="assign">
                     <p><hi rend="em">Relax NG exercise 1:</hi> Write a Relax NG schema for one of
                        the XML documents you created for an earlier assignment (XML exercise 2 or
                        3), and upload it an your XML file to Courseweb.</p>
                    
                  </div>
               </div>
            </div>
            <div type="week" n="3">
               <div type="day">
                  <head>
                     <date when="2016-01-18">M 01-18 <note>drop-add period ends T
                        01-19</note></date>
                  </head>
                  <div type="inclass">
                     <p><hi>Martin Luther King's Birthday: No classes.</hi></p>
                  </div>
                  <div type="assign">
                     <p>. . . .</p>
                  </div>
               </div>
               <div type="day">
                  <head>
                     <date when="2016-01-20">W 01-20</date>
                  </head>
                  <div type="inclass">
                     <p>Relax NG: mixed content, data types. Projects: discussion.</p>
                  </div>
                  <div type="assign">
                     <p><hi rend="em">Relax NG exercise 2: </hi>This time, choose a small text
                        (maybe one of the letters from the first assignment that you did NOT mark up
                        before, or anything you like). Perform document analysis, write a schema,
                        and mark up the text according to the schema.</p>
                  </div>
               </div>
               <div type="day">
                  <head>
                     <date when="2016-01-22">F 01-22</date>
                  </head>
                  <div type="inclass">
                     <list>
                        <item>Relax NG issues</item>
                        <item>Projects Designed by students: <ref
                              target="http://bamfs.obdurodon.org/index.xhtml">Profanities in Quentin
                              Tarantino’s Screenplays</ref> (with network analysis), and <ref
                              target="http://translate.obdurodon.org/">Divergences in Machine
                              Translation: Examining Harry Potter texts processed by Google
                              Translate across multiple language families</ref></item>
                     </list>
                  </div>
                  <div type="assign">
                     <list>
                        <item><hi rend="em">Relax NG exercise 3:</hi> Choose a small text of a
                           different type or genre than last time, perform document analysis, write
                           a schema, and mark up the text according to the schema.</item>
                        <item><hi rend="em">GitHub Discussion: Network Analysis</hi> Read my blog on an XML-based network analysis project I am working on: <ref
                              target="https://digitalromanticist.wordpress.com/2013/08/23/spectacular-intersections-of-place-in-southeys-thalaba-the-destroyer/"
                              >Spectacular intersections of place in Southey’s <hi rend="em">Thalaba
                                 the Destroyer</hi></ref> and <ref target="https://github.com/ebeshero/DHClass-Hub/issues/117">take part in a DHClass-Hub Discussion</ref> to reflect on the network analysis represented here
                           and how it works, what patterns it might be revealing, and what questions
                           or ideas it raises for you regarding digital methods to analyze
                           texts.</item>
                        <item><ref target="https://github.com/ebeshero/DHClass-Hub/issues/116"><hi
                                 rend="em">DHClass-Hub Post and Discussion on Project
                              Proposals:</hi></ref><list>
                              <item>Beginning this weekend, through next Wed. 1/27: Post proposal
                                 ideas for team projects to work on this semester. Each student
                                 should post an idea for the class to consider: a project involving
                                 XML markup to be managed within a team of 2-4 students to
                                 investigate something we could study and visualize from our markup
                                 more effectively with computers than with human reading and
                                 description alone. All projects must involve a team of at least two
                                 persons, but this first exploratory proposal is an individual
                                 assignment.</item>
                              <item>Each of you must respond to at least one of the proposed ideas
                                 from another student and indicate suggestions or further ideas. You
                                 may respond to more than one if you like, and indicate which
                                 proposals interest you to work on. </item>
                                 <item>Proposal discussions will run through next week, until class time on Friday 1/29 when we will form project teams.</item>

                           </list>
                        </item>
                     </list>
                  </div>
               </div>
            </div>
            <div type="week" n="4">
               <div type="day">
                  <head>
                     <date when="2016-01-25">M 01-25</date>
                  </head>
                  <div type="inclass">
                     <p>Network Analysis with XML: Discussion of Thalaba project</p>
                   
                  </div>
                  <div type="assign">
                     <list><item><hi rend="em"><ref target="https://github.com/ebeshero/DHClass-Hub/issues/113">Reading and DHClass-Hub Discussion Exercise on Graphing and Validity</ref>:</hi> 
                        Read <ref target="http://people.stat.sfu.ca/~cschwarz/Stat-650/Notes/PDF/ChapterBadgraphs.pdf"><title level="a">A short tour of bad graphs</title></ref> and join our GitHub discussion exercise, which involves your posting examples of biased or otherwise problematic graphs you find on the web.</item>
                     <item>Discussion Board posts and responses on project project proposals</item></list>

                  </div>
               </div>
               <div type="day">
                  <head>
                     <date when="2016-01-27">W 01-27</date>
                  </head>
                  <div type="inclass">
                     <p>Discussion: Graphing, Visualizations, Validity. See <ref
                           target="http://homes.cs.washington.edu/~jheer//files/zoo/">A Tour Through
                           the Visualization Zoo</ref>.</p>
                     <p>Review of Relax-NG</p>
                     <p>
                        <hi rend="em">Form project teams (today or F 1/29)</hi></p>
                     <p>If time, introduce regular expression matching (Regex)</p>
                  </div>
                  <div type="assign">
                     <p>Review our comments on your Relax NG homeworks and practice writing Relax NG in preparation for test.</p>
                     <p>Read our <title level="a"><ref target="explainRegex.html">Intro to Regular
                              Expressions</ref></title> and start looking at <ref
                           target="http://www.regular-expressions.info/quickstart.html">the Regular
                           Expressions Quick Start</ref> in prep for next class.</p>
                     <p>Discussion Board posts and responses on project project proposals</p>
                  </div>
               </div>
               <div type="day">
                  <head>
                     <date when="2016-01-29">F 01-29</date>
                  </head>
                  <div type="inclass">
                     <p><hi rend="em">Test 2: Relax NG</hi></p>
                     <p>Up-Conversion with Regular Expressions: Using Find &amp; Replace in
                        &lt;oXygen/&gt; (class exercise)</p>
                  </div>
                  <div type="assign">
                     <list>
                        <item>Follow the instructions here <ref target="#dateRef">at the top of this Syllabus page</ref> to install an FTP client of your choice on your computer, and follow our instructions posted on <ref target="https://courseweb.pitt.edu">Courseweb's Announcements page</ref> to use that FTP client to access your web space on newtFire at the Pittsburgh Supercomputing Center.</item>
                        <item>Consult our <title level="a"><ref target="explainRegex.html">Intro to
                                 Regular Expressions</ref></title> and <ref
                              target="http://www.regular-expressions.info/quickstart.html">the
                              Regular Expressions Quick Start</ref> as you work on the
                           exercise:</item>
                        <item><ref target="RegexExerciseBlithedale.html"><hi>Regex Exercise 1:</hi> Convert the text of a novel into XML</ref></item>
                        <item>Think about <ref target="https://github.com/ebeshero/DHClass-Hub/issues/116">Project Proposals posted on our DHClass-Hub</ref> and respond to the ones we have posted on the GitHub Discussion board. What ideas do you have for the projects proposed, and which one(s) might you want to help with? 
                           For consideration: Bocaccio, Blake, Nelson, and Dickinson</item>
                     </list>
                  </div>
               </div>
            </div>
            <div type="week" n="5">
               <div type="day">
                  <head>
                     <date when="2016-02-01">M 02-01</date>
                  </head>
                  <div type="inclass">
                     <p>Regular Expressions. Inside-out or Outside-in? Greedy Matching.</p>
                  </div>
                  <div type="assign">
                     <list>
                        <item><ref target="RegexExerciseVoyage.html"><hi rend="em">Regex Exercise
                           2:</hi> Voyage Log</ref></item>
                   
                        <item>Project Dev Assignment: Each project team creates a GitHub repository, and members create forks.</item>
                     </list>
                  </div>
               </div>
               <div type="day">
                  <head>
                     <date when="2016-02-03">W 02-03</date>
                  </head>
                  <div type="inclass">
                     <list><item><ref target="http://amadis.newtfire.org/">Amadis in Translation</ref> project (<ref target="https://github.com/ebeshero/Amadis-in-Translation">GitHub repository</ref>): special guest, Helena Bermúdez Sabel. Regular Expressions in the Amadis project.</item>
                     <item>Regular Expressions: thinking algorithmically. Selecting for what’s not
                        there, complicated patterns</item></list>
                  </div>
                  <div type="assign">
                     <list>
                        <item><ref target="RegexExercisePlay.html"><hi rend="em">Regex Exercise
                                 3:</hi> Convert a play to XML</ref></item>
                        <item>Read our <title level="a"><ref target="explainHTML.html">Introduction
                                 to XHTML (and HTML)</ref></title>.</item>
                     </list>
                  </div>
               </div>
               <div type="day">
                  <head>
                     <date when="2016-02-05">F 02-05</date>
                  </head>
                  <div type="inclass">
                     <p>XML and the Web: HTML and CSS. SFTP into the Apache Server for newtFire.
                        File directories and their association with web URLs.</p>
                  </div>
                  <div type="assign">
                     <list>
                        <item>Work with our <title level="a"><ref target="explainHTML.html"
                                 >Introduction to XHTML (and HTML)</ref></title>, and our <title
                              level="a"><ref target="explainCSS.html">Introduction to Cascading
                                 Stylesheets (CSS)</ref></title>. Experiment with writing a simple
                           HTML page with an image file, and an associated CSS stylesheet
                           file.</item>
                        <item><hi rend="em"><ref target="HTMLExercise1.html">HTML/CSS Exercise 1</ref>:</hi> NOTE: Do not submit this assignment on Courseweb. Instead, submit this
                           homework by using FTP to post to our newtFire web server.</item>
                     </list>
                  </div>
               </div>
            </div>
            <div type="week" n="6">
               <div type="day">
                  <head>
                     <date when="2016-02-08">M 02-08</date>
                  </head>
                  <div type="inclass">
                     <p>The Web and its namespaces: HTML, XHTML, HTML5....and CSS. What happens on
                        the server side vs. the client side with JavaScript vs. PHP. Perspective on
                        database servers. </p>
                  </div>
                  <div type="assign">
                     <list>
                        <item>Read <title level="a"><ref target="http://learnlayout.com/">Learn CSS
                                 Layout</ref></title>, and consult <ref
                              target="http://www.w3schools.com/css/">w3 Schools CSS Reference</ref>
                           as you code. (Also, check out <ref
                              target="http://paletton.com/#uid=1000u0kllllaFw0g0qFqFg0w0aF"
                              >Paletton</ref> to help think about choosing balanced color schemes.
                           Experiment with writing CSS to control font, layout, color, backgrounds. </item>
                        <item><hi rend="em"><ref target="HTMLExercise2.html">HTML/CSS Exercise 2</ref></hi> (As with HTML Exercise 1, submit this
                              homework by using FTP to post to our newtFire web server.)</item>
                     </list>
                  </div>
               </div>
               <div type="day">
                  <head>
                     <date when="2016-02-10">W 02-10</date>
                  </head>
                  <div type="inclass">
                     <p>How XML code structure matters for web transforms and delivery: Why we need
                        to navigate XML with XPath. Introducing XPath: Paths, Axes.</p>
                  </div>
                  <div type="assign">
                     <list>
                        <item>First, carefully read our <ref target="explainXPath.html">Introduction
                              to XPath: <title level="a">Follow the XPath!</title></ref> As you
                           read, try experimenting with the XPath expressions on our page, by
                           downloading the explainXPath.html file, opening it in oXygen, and
                           experimenting in the XPath window with some of our expressions. Then,
                           move on to Xpath Exercise 1.</item>
                        <item><ref target="XPathExercise1.html"><hi rend="em">XPath Exercise
                              1</hi></ref>
                        </item>
                     </list>
                  </div>
               </div>
               <div type="day">
                  <head>
                     <date when="2016-02-12">F 02-12</date>
                  </head>
                  <div type="inclass">
                     <p><hi rend="em">Regular Expressions Exam.</hi></p>
                     <p>Using XPath to climb trees—up and down and side to side. Predicate
                        expressions: <hi rend="em">[ ]</hi>. <hi rend="em">(Grouping)</hi> and <hi
                           rend="em">[Position()]</hi>. XPath syntax: some tricks.</p>
                  </div>
                  <div type="assign">
                     <list>
                        <item><ref target="XPathExercise2.html"><hi rend="em">XPath Exercise
                              2</hi></ref></item>
                        <item>Begin reading <title level="a"><ref
                                 target="http://dh.obdurodon.org/functions.xhtml">The Xpath
                                 Functions We Use Most</ref></title>.</item>
                     </list>
                  </div>
               </div>
            </div>
            <div type="week" n="7">
               <div type="day">
                  <head>
                     <date when="2016-02-15">M 02-15</date>
                  </head>
                  <div type="inclass">
                     <p>XPath Functions: some common functions we use and how to write them: <hi
                           rend="em">count(), not(), distinct-values()</hi>. XPath for the <hi
                           rend="em">text() node</hi> to grab strings: <hi rend="em"
                           >string-join()</hi>, <hi rend="em">contains(string 1, string 2)</hi>. </p>
                     <p>Using Regular Expressions in XPath.</p>
                  </div>
                  <div type="assign">
                     <list>
                        <item>Read (and consult) <title level="a"><ref
                                 target="http://dh.obdurodon.org/functions.xhtml">The Xpath
                                 Functions We Use Most</ref></title>
                        </item>
                        <item><ref target="XPathExercise3.html"><hi rend="em">XPath Exercise 3:</hi>
                              experimenting with functions</ref></item>
                        <item>Read Wendell Piez's <ref
                              target="http://www.balisage.net/Proceedings/vol13/html/Piez01/BalisageVol13-Piez01.html"
                              >Hierarchies within range space: From LMNL to OHCO</ref>, and post on
                           the <ref target="https://github.com/ebeshero/DHClass-Hub/issues/146">DHClass-Hub Issues Board Discussion</ref>.</item>

                     </list>
                  </div>
               </div>
               <div type="day">
                  <head>
                     <date when="2016-02-17">W 02-17</date>
                  </head>
                  <div type="inclass">
                     <p>Guest lecture by Wendell Piez (Piez Consulting Services) about
                        overlapping hierarchies and markup possibilities</p>

                  </div>
                  <div type="assign">
                     <list>
                        <item>
                           <ref target="XpathExercise4.html"><hi rend="em">XPath Exercise 4:</hi>
                              Manipulating Strings</ref>. </item>
                        <item> Read our <ref
                              target="explainSchematron.html">Guide
                              to Schema Writing with Schematron</ref>.</item>
                     </list>
                  </div>
               </div>
               <div type="day">
                  <head>
                     <date when="2016-02-19">F 02-19</date>
                  </head>
                  <div type="inclass">
                     <p>writing an XPath-based Schema language: Schematron, and how we use it with
                        Relax-NG</p>
                     <p>Examples of Schematron in our (Greensburg) projects</p>
                  </div>
                  <div type="assign">
                     <list>
                        <item><hi rend="em"><ref
                                 target="SchematronExercise1.html">Schematron Exercise 1</ref></hi></item>
                        <item>Read <ref target="http://dh.obdurodon.org/schematron-skyrim.xhtml">Validating References with Schematron</ref></item>
                     </list>
                  </div>
               </div>
            </div>
            <div type="week" n="8">
               <div type="day">
                  <head>
                     <date when="2016-02-22">M 02-22</date>
                  </head>
                  <div type="inclass">
                     <list>
                        <item>Schematron in Projects</item>
                        <item>Using Personographies, Placeographies, Prosopographies: <ref target="explainSchematronIdRefs.html">Keeping track
                           of xml:ids with Schematron</ref></item>
                        <item><hi>Decision:</hi> XPath Exam on Friday
                           week</item>
                     </list>
                  </div>

                  <div type="assign">
                     <list><item><hi rend="em"><ref target="SchematronExercise2.html">Schematron Exercise 2</ref></hi></item>
                        <item>Read our tutorial on <ref target="explainSchematronIdRefs.html">Coding with Unique Identifiers and How to Test for them with Schematron</ref>,
                     and use this in the Schematron homework: add <code>@xml:id</code> checking rules to your Schematron file, pulling from this tutorial.</item>
                        <item>Read our <ref target="http://newtfire.org/dh/explainXSLT.html">Introduction to XSLT</ref> in preparation for the next class.</item>
                     </list>
                  </div>
               </div>
               <div type="day">
                  <head>
                     <date when="2016-02-24">W 02-24</date>
                  </head>
                  <div type="inclass">
                     <p>Introducing XSLT and XQuery: how we use each.</p>
                     <p>Orientation to XSLT (eXtensible Stylesheet Language Transformations). XSL
                        Transformations from XML to XML, and from XML to HTML. Namespaces</p>
                     <p>The Weirdness that is XSL Template Matching: Where we use XPath, and where
                        we <hi rend="em">don’t</hi> use XPath in XSLT.</p>
                     <p>Identity Transformations</p>
                  </div>
                  <div type="assign">
                     <list>
                        <item>Read our <ref target="explainXSLT.html">Intro to XSLT</ref>.</item>
                        <item><hi rend="em"><ref target="XSLTExercise1.html">XSLT Exercise 1: an
                                 Identity Transformation</ref></hi>.</item>
                        <item><hi rend="em">To read this week</hi>, or before you start work on XSLT
                           2 (by this weekend): <list>
                              <item><title level="a"><ref
                                       target="http://dh.obdurodon.org/developing-xslt.xhtml"
                                       >Developing an XSLT Stylesheet</ref></title></item>
                              <item><title level="a"><ref
                                       target="http://dh.obdurodon.org/algorithms.xhtml">Thinking in
                                       algorithms</ref></title></item>

                           </list>
                        </item>
                     </list>
                  </div>
               </div>
               <div type="day">
                  <head>
                     <date when="2016-02-26">F 02-26</date>
                  </head>
                  <div type="inclass">
                     <p><hi rend="em">XPath Exam</hi>
                     <!--ebb: Or we could make this a (new) Schematron exam! -->
                     </p>
                     <p>XSLT to HTML: How it works: the template rule for the document node, and
                        succeeding template rules.</p>
                     <p>What happens with <hi>xsl:apply-templates</hi>, <hi>xsl:value-of</hi>, and Attribute Value Templates.</p>

                  </div>
                  <div type="assign">
                     <list>
                        <item><ref target="XSLTExercise2_CDV.html">XSLT Exercise 2</ref></item>
                        <item>To help guide you with XSLT and prepare for next class, read and consult:<list>
                              <item><title level="a"><ref
                                       target="http://dh.obdurodon.org/developing-xslt.xhtml"
                                       >Developing an XSLT Stylesheet</ref></title></item>
                              <item><title level="a"><ref
                                       target="http://dh.obdurodon.org/algorithms.xhtml">Thinking in
                                       algorithms</ref></title></item>
                           <item><title level="a"><ref target="http://dh.obdurodon.org/modal-xslt.html">Modal XSLT</ref></title></item>
                           </list>
                        </item>
                       
                     </list>
                  </div>

               </div>
            </div>

            <div type="week" n="9">
               <div type="day">
                  <head>
                     <date when="2016-02-29">M 02-29</date>
                  </head>
                  <div type="inclass">
                     <p>Pull vs. Push processing (and why we tend
                        to work with XQuery for Pull processing)</p>
                  </div>
                  <div type="assign">
                     <list>

                        <item>Review and consult <title level="a"><ref target="http://dh.obdurodon.org/modal-xslt.html">Modal XSLT</ref></title> and <title level="a"><ref target="http://dh.obdurodon.org/avt.xhtml">XSLT
                              Attribute Value Templates</ref></title> tutorials as you work on the XSLT exercises this week.
                           exercise.</item>
                        <item><hi rend="em"><ref target="XSLTExercise3_CDV.html">XSLT Exercise
                              3</ref></hi></item>
                      
                     </list>
                  </div>
               </div>
               <div type="day">
                  <head>
                     <date when="2016-03-02">W 03-02</date>
                     <!--ebb: Sigma Tau Delta Conference 3/2 - 3/5 Consider introducing SVG here!-->
                  </head>
                  <div type="inclass">
                     <p>How to make internal links on a webpage with XSLT and AVTs</p>
                     <p>Introducing XQuery and eXist, the XML database. </p>
                  </div>
                  <div type="assign">
                     <list>
                        <item><hi rend="em"><ref target="XSLTExercise4_CDV.html">XSLT Exercise
                           4</ref></hi></item>
                        <item><!--ebb: Update the XQUERY MATERIALS for PSC eXist!-->Read <ref
                           target="http://www.stylusstudio.com/xquery-primer.html">Michael Kay's
                           XQuery Tutorial</ref> and our <ref
                              target="http://newtfire.org/dh/explainXQuery.html">Introduction to
                              XQuery and the eXist XML Database</ref> in preparation for the next
                           class.</item>
                        
                     </list>
                  </div>
               </div>

               <div type="day">
                  <head>
                     <date when="2016-03-04">F 03-04</date>
                     <!--ebb: Sigma Tau Delta Conference 3/2 - 3/5 -->
                  </head>
                  <div type="inclass">
                     <p>Learning to write XQuery: collections and documents, queries and FLWORs</p>
                     <p>XQuery online and offline: in eXist and in &lt;oXygen/&gt;</p>
                    
                  </div>
                  <div type="assign">
                     <list><item>Work with <ref target="http://www.stylusstudio.com/xquery-primer.html"
                        >Michael Kay's XQuery Tutorial</ref> and our <ref
                           target="http://newtfire.org/dh/explainXQuery.html">Introduction to
                           XQuery and the eXist XML Database</ref> as you orient yourself to
                        XQuery and the eXist database environment.</item>
                     <item><hi><ref target="XQueryExercise1.html">XQuery Exercise
                        1</ref></hi></item>
                        <item>Work on <hi>Project Development Take-Home Midterm</hi></item>
                     </list>
                  </div>
               </div>
            </div>
            <div type="week" n="10">
               <div type="day">
                  <head>
                     <date when="2016-03-07">M 03-07 - F 03/13</date>
                  </head>
                  <div type="inclass">
                     <p><hi>Spring Break: No Classes</hi></p>
                  </div>
                  <div type="assign">
                     <p>. . . .</p>
                  </div>

               </div>
            </div>
            <div type="week" n="11">
               <div type="day">
                  <head>
                     <date when="2016-03-14">M 03-14</date>
                  </head>
                  <div type="inclass">
                     <p>XQuery: Writing FLWOR statements and outputting HTML</p>

                  </div>
                  <div type="assign">
                     <p><hi><ref target="XQueryExercise2.html">XQuery Exercise 2</ref></hi></p>
                  </div>
               </div>
               <div type="day">
                  <head>
                     <date when="2016-03-16">W 03-16</date>
                  </head>
                  <div type="inclass">
                     <p>Nested FLWORS and HTML output</p>
                     <p>Project Discussion</p>
    
                  
                     

                  </div>
                  <div type="assign">
                     
                     <p><hi><ref target="https://github.com/ebeshero/DHClass-Hub/issues/161">Complete Project Midterm</ref></hi></p>
                    
                    
                  </div>
               </div>
               <div type="day">
                  <head>
                     <date when="2016-03-18">F 03-18</date>
                  </head>
                  <div type="inclass">
                     <p>XML that makes graphics: SVG (Scalable Vector Graphics). Drawing elements,
                        and screen grid coordinates. </p>
                     <p>Introduce with <ref target="http://www.w3schools.com/svg/default.asp">w3Schools SVG Tutorial</ref>.</p>
                     
                  </div>
                  <div type="assign">
                    
                     <p>Work through <ref target="http://www.w3schools.com/svg/default.asp">the w3schools SVG tutorial</ref> to complete the SVG basic and SVG shapes pages. 
                        Filters, gradients, examples, and reference are optional.</p>
                     <p><hi><ref target="SVGExercise1.html">SVG Exercise 1</ref></hi></p>
                
 
                  </div>
               </div>
            </div>
            <div type="week" n="12">
               <div type="day">
                  <head>
                     <date when="2016-03-21">M 03-21 <note>Stephen Ramsay is in Pittsburgh this week. See <ref target="http://www.humcenter.pitt.edu/sites/default/files/Stephen%20Ramsay%20Flyer%20-%20Copy.pdf">schedule of events</ref>. 
                           <!--2016-01-10 ebb: Post link to schedule here. And let's see about bringing some students to the Pgh events. -->
                        </note>
                     </date>
                  </head>
                  <div type="inclass">
 
                     <p>XQuery: Nesting FLWORS: when and why </p>
                     <p>XQuery to SVG: Pulling data, choosing visualization formats: Timelines</p>
                     <p>Saving output in the eXist database</p>

                  </div>
                  <div type="assign">
                     <list>
                        <item><hi><ref target="SVGExercise2_CDV.html">SVG Exercise 2 (with XQuery)</ref></hi></item>
                     </list>
                     <p>In preparation for Steve Ramsay's visit, read his blog posting on <ref target="http://stephenramsay.us/2013/04/30/dh-and-cs/"><title level="a">DH and CS</title></ref>, and choose at least one of the following two to continue reading and discussing on our DHClass-Hub:</p>
                     <list>
                        <item> <ref
                           target="https://web.archive.org/web/20140604085234/http://www.playingwithhistory.com/wp-content/uploads/2010/04/hermeneutics.pdf">
                           <title level="a">The hermeneutics of screwing around</title></ref>, or</item>
                           <item><ref
                              target="http://digitalcommons.unl.edu/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=1056&amp;context=englishfacpubs">
                              <title level="a">In praise of pattern</title></ref> </item>
                     </list>
                     <p> Post at least twice before Wednesday's class, to reflect and respond to each other about <title level="a">DH and CS</title> and one of the other two short articles by Stephen Ramsay on <ref
                        target="https://github.com/ebeshero/DHClass-Hub/issues/">our DHClass-Hub
                        Discussion of Stephen Ramsay’s work</ref>.</p>
                     

                  </div>
               </div>
               <div type="day">
                  <head>
                     <date when="2016-03-23">W 03-23</date>
                  </head>
                  <div type="inclass">
                     <p></p>
                     <p>Guest presentation by Stephen Ramsay (University of Nebraska)</p>
       
                  </div>
                  <div type="assign">
                     <p><ref target="SVGExercise2_CDV.html">continued work on SVG Exercise 2 (Part 1 of Timeline)</ref></p>
                    
                  </div>
               </div>
               <div type="day">
                  <head>
                     <date when="2016-03-25">F 03-25</date>
                  </head>
                  <div type="inclass">
  
                     <p>Review of SVG timeline assignment.</p>
                     <p>Project files in eXist</p>
                  </div>
                  <div type="assign">
                     <p><hi><ref target="SVGExercise3_CDV.html">SVG Exercise 3 (Part 2 of the Timeline)</ref></hi></p>
                    
                  </div>
               </div>
            </div>
            <div type="week" n="13">
               <div type="day">
                  <head>
                     <date when="2016-03-28">M 03-28</date>
                  </head>
                  <div type="inclass">
                     <p>XQuery to Network Analysis: generating plain text data for Cytoscape</p>
                     
                  </div>
                  <div type="assign">
                     <p><hi><ref target="SVGExercise4_CDV.html">XQuery to SVG: Bar Graph or Your Choice</ref></hi></p>
                     
                  </div>
               </div>
               <div type="day">
                  <head>
                     <date when="2016-03-30">W 03-30</date>
                  </head>
                  <div type="inclass">
                     <p>Network Analysis Processing and Filtering; Running the Network Analyzer.
                        Common Network stats: degree centrality, node centrality, edge betweenness,
                        shortest paths</p>
                     <p>XQuery from eXist to Web: Building the Database into the Web Project</p>
                    
                  </div>
                  <div type="assign">
                     <list>
                        <item>Read <ref target="http://ebeshero.github.io/thalaba/cytosc.html"><title level="a">An Introduction to Network Analysis and Cytoscape for XML Coders</title></ref></item>
                        <item><ref target="http://cytoscape.org/">Install Cytoscape on your computer</ref>, together with the appropriate Java package. Note: This is also installed in the campus computer labs, so you may work with it there, too or instead of on your own computer. If you have trouble with the installation, locate Cytoscape in the campus computer labs.
                           Begin familiarizing yourself with the Cytoscape interface, working with Cytoscape session files (with .cys extension) posted in Class Examples, Network-Workshop folder in our <ref target="https://github.com/ebeshero/DHClass-Hub">DHClass-Hub</ref>. Try importing one of my Cytoscape session files (.cys) following my tutorial.
                        
                        </item>
         
                     </list>
                  </div>
               </div>
               <div type="day">
                  <head>
                     <date when="2016-04-01">F 04-01</date>
                  </head>
                  <div type="inclass">
                     <p>XQuery to Network Analysis: preparing data for import. TSV and CSV formats.</p>
                    
                  </div>
                  <div type="assign">
                     
                     <p><hi><ref target="NetworkExercise1.html">XQuery to Network Analysis: Exercise, Part 1</ref></hi></p>
                    
                  </div>
               </div>
            </div>
            <div type="week" n="14">
               <div type="day">
                  <head>
                     <date when="2016-04-04">M 04-04</date>
                  </head>
                  <div type="inclass">
                     
                    <p>XQuery to Network Analysis: Working in Cytoscape, filtering data.</p>
                
                  </div>
                  <div type="assign">
                    <list> <item><hi><ref target="NetworkExercise2.html">XQuery to Network Analysis: Exercise, Part 2</ref></hi></item>
                       <item>Read Obdurodon’s <ref
                        target="http://dh.obdurodon.org/javascript.xhtml">Introduction to
                        Javascript</ref></item></list>
                   
                  </div>
               </div>
               <div type="day">
                  <head>
                     <date when="2016-04-06">W 04-06</date>
                  </head>
                  <div type="inclass">
                     <list>
                        <item>How JavaScript works (client side), and how to write it.</item>
                     </list>

                  </div>
                  <div type="assign">
                     <p><hi><ref target="JavaScript_SSI_Exercise1.html">Server Side Includes and
                        JavaScript Exercise 1</ref></hi></p>
                     
                    
                  </div>
               </div>
               <div type="day">
                  <head>
                     <date when="2016-04-08">F 04-08</date>
                  </head>
                  <div type="inclass">
                     <p>More JavaScript! Writing JavaScript functions.</p>

                  </div>
                  <div type="assign">
                     <list>
                        
                        <item>Read Obdurodon's <ref target="javascript_piece-by-piece.xhtml"
                           >JavaScript Piece By Piece tutorial</ref></item>
                        <item>Read Elisa's Obdurodon tutorial, <ref
                           target="http://dh.obdurodon.org/javascript/classListToggle.xhtml"
                           >JavaScript Toggling with classList and switch</ref></item>
                        <item><hi><ref target="JavaScriptExercise2.html">Javascript Exercise
                           2</ref></hi></item>
                        
                     </list>
               
                  </div>
               </div>
            </div>
            <div type="week" n="15">
               <div type="day">
                  <head>
                     <date when="2016-04-11">M 04-11</date>
                  </head>
                  <div type="inclass">
                     <list>
                        <item>JavaScript with SVG for Dynamic Activity on an Image</item>
                        <item>JavaScript, SVG, and CSS with your HTML: Putting it All
                           Together</item>
                     </list>
                     <p>Projects and Portfolios. <ref target="https://creativecommons.org/">Creative
                           Commons Licenses</ref></p>

                  </div>
                  <div type="assign">
                   
                     <p><hi>JavaScript Exercise 3 [TBD] <!--ebb: REHASH THIS ASSIGNMENT TO PULL FROM XQUERY--></hi>:
                        JavaScript with SVG</p>
                     <p><hi>Website Development and Review</hi> Exercise [TBD]</p>

                  </div>
               </div>
               <div type="day">
                  <head>
                     <date when="2016-04-13">W 04-13</date>
                  </head>
                  <div type="inclass">
                     <p>Web Development: Projects</p>
                  </div>
                  <div type="assign">
                     <p>Project Design Work</p>
                  </div>
               </div>
               <div type="day">
                  <head>
                     <date when="2016-04-15">F 04-15</date>
                  </head>
                  <div type="inclass">
                     <list>
                        <item>Set Project Presentation Schedule</item>
                        <item>Web Development: Projects</item>
                     </list>
                  </div>
                  <div type="assign">
                     <p>Project Design Work</p>
                  </div>
               </div>
            </div>
            <div type="week" n="16">
               <div type="day">
                  <head>
                     <date when="2016-04-18">M 04-18</date>
                  </head>
                  <div type="inclass">
                     <p>Web Development: Projects</p>
                  </div>
                  <div type="assign">
                     <p>Project Design Work</p>
                  </div>
               </div>
               <div type="day">
                  <head>
                     <date when="2016-04-20">W 04-20</date>
                  </head>
                  <div type="inclass">
                     <p>Project Presentations and Review</p>
                  </div>
                  <div type="assign">
                     <p><hi rend="em">GitHub Issues</hi>: (For everyone but the project presenters
                        for today): Post a review, as detailed as possible for a project team other
                        than your own; a project that was presented today.</p>
                  </div>
               </div>
               <div type="day">
                  <head>
                     <date when="2016-04-22">F 04-22</date>
                  </head>
                  <div type="inclass">
                     <p>Project Presentations and Review</p>
                  </div>
                  <div type="assign">
                     <p><hi rend="em">GitHub Issues</hi>: (For everyone but the project presenters
                        for today): Post a review, as detailed as possible for a project team other
                        than your own; a project that was presented today.</p>
                  </div>
               </div>
            </div>
            <div type="week">
               <div type="day">
                  <head><date>Thurs. 4/28 by 11:59 PM</date></head>
                  <div type="assign">
                     <p>
                        <hi>Projects due.</hi>
                     </p>
                  </div>
               </div>
            </div>


         </div>


      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
