<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<article><heading><title>Episcopal Diocese prepares for secession vote</title><pubDate>September 9, 2008 12:00 AM </pubDate><author>By Ann Rodgers </author><pubSource>Pittsburgh Post-Gazette</pubSource></heading><body><p>In response to a lawsuit led by one of its parishes, the <diocese><sect type="Episcopal"/> Diocese of <location>Pittsburgh</location></diocese> has agreed to have a court-appointed neutral party inventory all of its property and assets as it prepares for a final vote on seceding from the <church><sect type="Episcopal"/> Church.</church></p><p>The agreement between representatives of the diocese and <parish>Calvary Episcopal Church, <location>Shadyside</location>,</parish> came after a hearing yesterday before <who name="Joseph M. James"/>, president judge of Common Pleas Court. In<date> 2005</date>, he oversaw a settlement after<parish> Calvary</parish> sued the diocese to prevent the transfer of property from the denomination to individual parishes.</p><p><parish>
Calvary</parish> has led a minority of parishes that oppose <who name="Bishop Robert Duncan"/>'s plan to leave the U.S. branch of the <sect type="Anglican"/> Communion and realign with the more conservative <sect type="Anglican"/> Province of the <location>Southern Cone in South America</location> over concerns about doctrine and sexual ethics. A final vote is set for Oct. 4.</p><p>The <date>2005</date> agreement said that property held by the central diocese -- such as endowment funds, but not necessarily parish property -- would continue to be held by the <quote sp="anon">"<diocese><sect type="Episcopal"/> Diocese of <location>Pittsburgh</location></diocese> of the <church><sect type="Episcopal"/> Church of the <location>United States of America</location></church>"</quote> whether or not any parishes or diocesan leaders secede. <parish>Calvary</parish> claims that the diocese has violated its end of the <date>2005</date> agreement.</p><p>The diocese will pursue <quote sp="Rev. Peter Frank">"a fair and equitable distribution of property"</quote> if the realignment resolutions pass, said its spokesman, the <who name="Rev. Peter Frank"/>.</p><p>The diocese also agreed yesterday to permit parishes that oppose secession to divert diocesan support payments to escrow accounts that would remain in the <church><sect type="Episcopal"/> Church.
</church>
The agreement assumes that new leaders affiliated with the church will be elected for <location>Pittsburgh</location> if <who name="Bishop Robert Duncan"/> secedes.</p><p><quote sp="Walter DeForest">"It is highly likely that <who name="Bishop Robert Duncan"/> and the other leadership of the diocese will purport to separate from the <church><sect type="Episcopal"/> Church</church>, and it is our position that the court order of <date>Oct. 14, 2005</date>, addresses what will happen in that regard,"</quote> said <who name="Walter DeForest"/>, attorney for <parish>Calvary</parish>.</p><p><quote sp="Walter DeGorest">"It is certainly the position of <parish>Calvary</parish> that the new leadership of the diocese will be in charge of those assets."</quote></p></body></article>