<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../../../Schema/songSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?><xml>
    <info>
        <title ref="#2-PCTS-11">Play Crack The Sky</title>
        <album ref="#2-DE">Deja Entendu</album>
        <track n="11"/>
        <tempo bpm="118"/>
        <key/>
        <songWriter>
            <li n="1">Jesse Lacey</li>
        </songWriter>
        <composer>Jesse Lacey</composer>
        <songLength>00:05:27</songLength>
    </info>
    <song>
        <verse n="1">
            <line n="1">We sent out the SOS call.</line>
            <line n="2">It was a <refer img="time">quarter past four in the morning</refer> when the storm broke our second
                anchor line.</line>
            <line n="3"><refer img="time">Four months</refer> at <refer img="water">sea</refer>, <refer img="time">four months</refer> of calm <refer img="water">seas</refer> to be pounded in the <refer img="water">shallows</refer>
                off the tip of Montauk Point.</line>
            <line n="4">They call them rogues, they travel fast and alone.</line>
            <line n="5">One-hundred-foot faces of <refer img="rel">God's</refer> good <refer img="water">ocean</refer> gone wrong.</line>
            <line n="6">What they call love is a risk, cause you will always get hit out of nowhere
                by some wave and end up on your own.</line>
            <line n="7">The hole in the hull defied the crews attempts to bail us out.</line>
            <line n="8">And <refer img="water">flooded</refer> the engines and radio and half buried bow.</line>
        </verse>

        <!--bb: guitar refrain -->

        <verse n="2">
            <line n="9">Your tongue is a rudder.</line>
            <line n="10">It steers the whole ship.</line>
            <line n="11">Sends your words past your lips or keeps them safe behind your
                teeth.</line>
            <line n="12">But the wrong words will strand you.</line>
            <line n="13">Come off course while you sleep.</line>
            <line n="14">Sweep your boat out to <refer img="water">sea</refer> or dashed to bits on the reef.</line>
            <line n="15">The vessel groans the ocean pressures its frame.</line>
            <line n="16">To the port I see the lighthouse through the sleet and rain.</line>
            <line n="17">And I wish for one more day to give my love and repay debts.</line>
            <line n="18">But the morning finds our bodies washed up thirty miles west.</line>
        </verse>

        <!--bb: pause -->

        <verse n="3">
            <line n="19">They say that the captain stays fast with the ship through still and
                storm.</line>
            <line n="20">But this ain't the Dakota, and the water is cold.</line>
            <line n="21">We won't have to fight for long.</line>
        </verse>

        <!--bb: pause -->

        <outro><line n="22">This is the end.</line>
            <line n="23">This story's old but it goes on and on until we disappear.</line>
            <line n="24">Calm me and let me taste the salt you breathed while you were
                underneath.</line>
            <line n="25">I am the one who haunts your <refer img="bed">dreams</refer> of mountains sunk below the <refer img="water">sea</refer>.</line>
            <line n="26">I spoke the words but never gave a thought to what they all could
                mean.</line>
            <line n="27">I know that this is what you want.</line>
            <line n="28">A <refer img="death">funeral</refer> keeps both of us apart.</line>
            <line n="29">You know that you are not alone.</line>
            <line n="30">Need you like <refer img="water">water</refer> in my lungs.</line>
            <line n="31">This is the end.</line></outro>
    </song>

</xml>