<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<eccoLocation><sourceDesc><p>Search terms extracted from the following text: <bibl><author>Hawkesworth, John,
                    1715?-1773.</author><title>An account of the voyages undertaken by the order of
                    His present Majesty: for making discoveries in the Southern Hemisphere, ... By
                    John Hawkesworth, LL.D. In three volumes. ...
                    [pt.2]</title><pubPlace>London</pubPlace><publisher>printed for W. Strahan; and
                    T. Cadell</publisher><date>1773</date></bibl></p></sourceDesc><body><head>Search Terms from Chapters [VIII and IX] </head><list type="successful"><item><term> Solander <num type="hits">1</num></term><listBibl><sourceDesc><p><author> William Stork</author><title> A description of East-Florida, with a journal, kept by John
                                Bartram of Philadelphia, botanist to His Majesty for the Floridas;
                                upon a journey from St. Augustine up the River St. John's, as far as
                                the lakes. With explanatory botanical notes. Illustrated with an
                                accurate Map of East-Florida, and two Plans; one of St. Augustine,
                                and the other of the Bay of Espiritu Santo. </title><publisher> London : sold by W. Nicoll, at No. 51, St. Paul's Church
                                Yard; and T. Jefferies, at Charing-Cross, Geographer to his
                                Majesty</publisher><pubPlace> London</pubPlace><date> 1769</date><note> The term is used in the text when Dr. Solander himself is
                                mentioned. the part of the text also talks about the others in his
                                company.</note></p></sourceDesc></listBibl></item><item><term> Owhaw <num type="hits">24</num></term><listBibl><bibl><author/>Cook, James. <title/>A compendious history of Captain Cook's first
                        and second voyages. The first Performed in the Years 1768, 1769, 1770, 1771,
                        in the Endeavour <pubPlace/>London <date/>1784 <note>recounting the
                            trip</note></bibl><bibl><author/>Henry, David. <title/>An historical account of all the voyages
                        round the world, performed by English navigators; including those lately
                        undertaken by order of His present Majesty. The whole faithfully extracted
                        from the journals of the voyagers. ... In four volumes. ...
                        <pubPlace/>London <date/>1773-74 <note>Discuss the trip in comparison to
                            others</note></bibl></listBibl></item><item><term> Tomio <num type="hits">58</num></term><listBibl><bibl><author/><title/>Beauties of nature and art displayed, in a tour through the world;
                        ... Illustrated and embellished with copper plates. <editor/><publisher/><pubPlace/>London <date/>1774-75 <note>In association with the
                            journey</note></bibl></listBibl></item></list><unsuccessful><item><term>Banks</term><term type="Mr.Banks"/><note>Be more specific or associate it with something else</note></item><item><term>Green</term><term type="Mr.Green"/></item></unsuccessful></body></eccoLocation>