<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../../schemas/LocationSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?><location type="city/town">
    <name n="Lavender Town">Lavender Town</name>
    <des>A small town covered in a beautiful hue of purple. </des>
    <PoI>

        <place>
            <placeName>Pokemon Tower </placeName>
            <des><pref>Pokémon Tower</pref> is a seven-floor graveyard that holds the grave of
                departed Pokémon. On all seven floors, the tower houses hundreds of graves of
                deceased Pokémon. Many people visit the building daily to pay their respects to the
                fallen. On all floors other than the first two, though, the possibility of being
                attacked by wild Pokémon is present. Populated by <pers>Channelers</pers>, it was
                notable for numerous ghost sightings (Pokémon killed by <pers>Team Rocket</pers>),
                as well as the location of <pers>Team Rocket's</pers> kidnapping of <pref>Mr.
                    Fuji</pref>. Although players can encounter Ghost-type Pokémon here, they can
                not be seen or captured unless they have a <item>Silph Scope</item>. </des>
        </place>

        <place>
            <placeName>Kanto Radio Tower</placeName>
            <des> The tower was converted to the <pref>Kanto Radio Tower</pref>, with all graves
                being moved to either the <pref>House of Memories</pref> or underground. The new
                    <pref>House of Memories</pref> is placed where the <pref>Poké Mart</pref> has
                been before. The <pref>Kanto radio tower</pref> can be entered, like its Johto
                counterpart, but only the ground floor, as the upper floors are completely off
                limits. This was done to prevent a similar take over that was seen in Johto. Talking
                to the receptionist on the ground floor, the player can receive a <item>Pokégear
                    radio card</item> for Kanto. </des>
        </place>

        <place>
            <placeName>Lavender Volunteer Pokémon House</placeName>
            <des> The <pref>Lavender Volunteer Pokémon House</pref> located in central
                    <pref>Lavender Town</pref>, was founded by <pers>Mr. Fuji</pers> in order to
                care for abandoned and orphaned Pokémon. Many members of the organization live in
                the safe house, looking after the abandoned Pokémon. Many Pokémon have stayed at the
                    <pref>Volunteer Pokémon House</pref> over time, including <pokemon dexNum="054">Psyduck</pokemon>, <pokemon dexNum="033">Nidorino</pokemon>, and after the
                    <pers>Team Rocket</pers> attack on the Pokémon Tower, <pokemon dexNum="104">Cubone</pokemon>. </des>
        </place>

    </PoI>
</location>