<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<article><heading><title>Woman Is Named Episcopal Leader </title><author>By NEELA BANERJEE</author><pubdate>Published: June 19, 2006</pubdate></heading><body><p><date>COLUMBUS, Ohio, June 18</date> — The <church><sect type="Episcopal"/> Church</church> elected <who name="Bishop Katharine Jefferts Schori"/> of <location>Nevada</location> as its presiding bishop on Sunday, making her the first woman to lead a church in the worldwide <sect type="Anglican"/> Communion.</p><p>Many Episcopalians gathered here for the church's triennial general convention cheered the largely unexpected choice of <who name="Bishop Katharine Jefferts Schori"/>, 52, the lone woman and one of the youngest of the seven candidates for the job. Her election was a milestone for the <church><sect type="Episcopal"/> Church</church>, which began ordaining women only in <date>1976.</date></p><p>She takes on her new responsibilities at a particularly fraught moment in the history of the <church><sect type="Episcopal"/> Church</church>, the <nat origin="American"/> branch of the <sect type="Anglican"/> Communion, the world's <stat>third-largest church body</stat>, with <stat>77 million members</stat>. She was elected to succeed Presiding <who name="Bishop Frank T. Griswold"/>, who will retire in November when his nine-year term ends.
</p><p>At the last general convention, in <date>2003</date>, the church consented to the election of an openly gay man, the <who name="Rev. V. Gene Robinson"/>, as bishop of New Hampshire. The decision deeply offended some Episcopalians in the <location>United States</location> and many <sect type="Anglican"/> primates abroad, who saw it as blatant disregard of Scripture.
</p><p>Since then, some <location>United States</location> congregations have left the <church><sect type="Episcopal"/> Church</church>, and primates overseas have threatened schism. <who name="Bishop Katharine Jefferts Schori"/> supported <who name="Bishop V. Gene Robinson"/>'s election in <date>2003</date>, and the <diocese><sect type="Episcopal"/> Diocese of <location>Nevada</location></diocese> permits the blessing of same-sex unions. Moreover, that <who name="Bishop Katharine Jefferts Schori"/> is a woman could further strain relations with three dioceses in the <location>United States</location> and many <sect type="Anglican"/> provinces that refuse to ordain women as priests and bishops, critics of the vote said Sunday. 
</p><p>But <who name="Bishop Katharine Jefferts Schori"/> held out hope of mending any breaks that her election or previous positions on issues might cause.

        <quote sp="Bishop Katharine Jefferts Schori">"Alienation is often a function of not knowing another human being,"</quote> she said at a news conference after her election. <quote sp="Bishop Katharine Jefferts Schori">I have good relations with almost all the other bishops, those who agree and those who don't agree with me. I will bend over backwards to build good relations with those who don't agree with me."</quote><who name="Bishop Katharine Jefferts Schori"/>'s election was a crowning moment in her meteoric rise in the <church><sect type="Episcopal"/> Church.</church> She was <stat>ordained just 12 years ago</stat>, after leaving a career as an oceanographer.

<quote sp="Rev. Susan Russell">"I'm thrilled,"</quote> said the <who name="Rev. Susan Russell"/>, the president of Integrity, an advocacy group for gay and lesbian Episcopalians. <quote sp="Rev. Susan Russell">"I'm a cradle Episcopalian. I remember when there were no women priests. I remember when they said the church was going to split over the ordination of women. What we're giving as a Father's Day gift to the Anglican Communion is a woman primate, and that is wonderful."</quote></p><p>But some at the general convention said <who name="Bishop Katharine Jefferts Schori"/>'s lack of experience as a church leader, especially of a large diocese, would be tested by the tensions in her denomination.

<quote sp="Rev. William L. Sachs">"Can she run a big ship of state?"</quote> asked the <who name="Rev. William L. Sachs"/>, director of research at the <sect type="Episcopal"/> Church Foundation, the church's analysis arm. <quote sp="Rev. William L, Sachs">"She is certainly smart enough, and she gets it. But can she translate that into an actual program?"</quote></p><p>Some critics were quick to focus on her sex, asserting that her election was an affront to others in the denomination who opposed the ordination of women. They described it as further evidence of the church's drift from the shared beliefs of the greater <sect type="Anglican"/> Communion.

<quote sp="Bishop Robert W. Duncan Jr.">"In many ways the election speaks for itself,"</quote><who name="Bishop Robert W. Duncan Jr."/> of <location>Pittsburgh</location> said in a statement. <who name="Bishop Robert W. Duncan Jr."/> is the moderator of the <sect type="Anglican"/> Communion Network, a theologically conservative group of <diocese><sect type="Episcopal"/> dioceses</diocese>. <quote sp="Bishop Robert W. Duncan Jr.">"For the <sect type="Anglican"/> Communion worldwide, this election reveals the continuing insensitivity and disregard of the <church><sect type="Episcopal"/> Church</church> for the present dynamics of our global fellowship.</quote>"

<who name="Bishop Katharine Jefferts Schori"/> will be the 26th presiding bishop of the <church><sect type="Episcopal"/> Church</church>. As such, she will represent the church in meetings with other <sect type="Anglican"/> leaders from around the world and with leaders of other religious groups. But her powers are limited because of the <church><sect type="Episcopal"/> Church's</church> tradition of autonomy for its dioceses, including the right to elect their own bishops.
</p><p>That regard for autonomy has allowed three dioceses — those in <location>Quincy, Ill.</location>; <location>Fort Worth</location>; and <location>San Joaquin, Calif.</location> — to resist the ordination of women. In <location>Quincy</location>, at least, <who name="Bishop Katharine Jefferts Schori"/> would not be welcome, said the <who name="Rev. H. W. Herrmann"/>, rector of <parish>St. John's Episcopal Church</parish> there.

<quote sp="Rev. H. W. Herrmann">"Just like we can't use grape juice and saltines for Communion, because it isn't the right matter, we do not believe that the right matter is being offered here,"</quote> Mr. Herrmann said in an interview on Sunday.
</p><p>But no issue facing <who name="Bishop Katharin Jefferts Schori"/> is likely to be as daunting as the fight over ordaining gay bishops.
</p><p>In <date>October 2004</date>, a committee appointed by the Archbishop of <location>Canterbury</location>, <who name="Rowan Williams"/>, issued a report to head off a possible schism over the sexuality debate. That document, the Windsor Report, recommended that the <church><sect type="Episcopal"/> Church</church> apologize for the consecration of <who name="Bishop V. Gene Robinson"/>, stop blessing same-sex couples and place a moratorium on the election of gay bishops.</p><p><who name="Bishop Katharine Jefferts Schori"/> served on a commission that responded to the Windsor Report with recommendations that were less stringent. A committee at the general convention has been struggling to amend those recommendations, which have yet to come to a vote before the clergy and the lay deputies.
</p><p><who name="Bishop Katharine Jefferts Schori"/>'s role on the commission has only increased the suspicion of some critics. <quote sp="Rev. Dr. Kendall Harmon">"Her gender has to be combined with her response to Windsor,"</quote> said the <who name="Rev. Dr. Kendall Harmon"/>, a critic of the church and theologian-in-residence at <parish>St. Paul's Episcopal Church in <location>Summerville, S.C.</location></parish> Speaking of other <sect type="Anglican primates"/>, he said, <quote sp="Rev. Dr. Kendall Harmon">"Their anxiety will be focused less on her gender than her theology."</quote></p><p>Beyond the fight over gay bishops, there is the question of how <who name="Bishop Katharine Jefferts Schori"/> will be received by foreign church leaders and the heads of other religious groups. Church experts predicted that her election might further strain relations with the Vatican, which cooled to the church after the election of <who name="Bishop V. Gene Robinson"/> three years ago. 
</p><p>Her election may also increase pressure on the <church>Church of England</church> to break its deadlock over electing female bishops.</p></body></article>