<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<listbibl><bibl><author>Perry, James</author><title>Mimosa: or, The sensitive plant; A poem. Dedicated to Mr. Banks, and addressed to Kitt Frederick, Dutchess of Queensberry, Elect.</title><editor/><publisher/><pubPlace>The second edition, with additions. London,  1779. Eighteenth Century Collections Online. Gale. University of Pittsburgh Libraries</pubPlace><date> Sep.18, 2013</date><note> it's an interesting poem, and we are looking for literature so this one is apprpriate for the assigment.
        Search mimosa, poem. only 2 hits for this one. try searching pendicles, effence. not much comes up. </note></bibl><bibl><author>Alexander, William (d. 1783)</author><title>The history of women, from the earliest antiquity, to the present time; giving some account of almost every interesting particular concerning that sex, among all nations, ancient and modern. By William Alexander, M.D. In two volumes.</title><editor>London : printed for W. Strahan, and T. Cadell, in the Strand, MDCCLXXIX. [1779].</editor><publisher>W. Strahan and T. Cadell</publisher><pubPlace>London</pubPlace><date>1779</date><note>The term Otaheite found references to Otaheite. This helped find a voyage logs of when Otaheite was mentioned.
            Also the date range from 1750-1790 narrowed the search to the date range that Captain Wallis's voyages were documented.</note></bibl><notes>I wasn't sure about this one but volume 2 seems like it could be usuful. 8 hits. Search wiht author, and the place. </notes><bibl><author>Fitzgerald, Gerald.</author><title>The injured islanders; or, the influence of art upon the happiness of nature.</title><editor/><publisher/><pubPlace>London,  MDCCLXXIX. [1779]. Eighteenth Century Collections Online. Gale. University of Pittsburgh Libraries </pubPlace><date> Sept. 18, 2013</date><note>
        </note><author>Fitzgerald, Gerald.</author><note>it might be useful to us because it describes nature in Tahiti and we are looking for such things. 
        4 hits. Search Earfe, gardenia's die, bluphing, these terms were not succesful, but im note sure what others to do, nothing really comes up. i might be doing something wron, hence the reason i asked to meet for help.  </note></bibl></listbibl>