<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="McDermottOHaraPoemSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<twinkie>
    <head>SLEEPING ON THE WING</head>
    <lg n="1">
        <l n="1">Perhaps it is to avoid some great sadness,</l>
        <l n="2">as in a Restoration tragedy the hero cries "Sleep!</l>
        <l n="3">O for a long sound sleep and so forget it!"</l>
        <l n="4">that one flies, soaring above the shoreless city,</l>
        <l n="5">veering upward from the pavement as a pigeon</l>
        <l n="6">does when a car honks or a door slams, the door</l>
        <l n="7">of dreams, life perpetuated in parti-colored loves</l>
        <l n="8">and beautiful lies all in different languages.</l>
    </lg>
    <lg n="2">
        <l n="9">Fear drops away too, like the cement, and you</l>
        <l n="10">are over the Atlantic. Where is Spain? where is</l>
        <l n="11">who? The Civil War was fought to free the slaves,</l>
        <l n="12">was it? A sudden down-draught reminds you of gravity</l>
        <l n="13">and your position in respect to human love. But</l>
        <l n="14">here is where the gods are, speculating, bemused.</l>
        <l n="15">Once you are helpless, you are free, can you believe</l>
        <l n="16">that? Never to waken to the sad struggle of a face?</l>
        <l n="17">to travel always over some impersonal vastness,</l>
        <l n="18">to be out of, forever, neither in nor for!</l>
    </lg>
    <lg n="3">
        <l n="19">The eyes roll asleep as if turned by the wind</l>
        <l n="20">and the lids flutter open slightly like a wing.</l>
        <l n="21">The world is an iceberg, so much is invisible!</l>
        <l n="22">and was and is, and yet the form, it may be sleeping</l>
        <l n="23">too. Those features etched in the ice of someone</l>
        <l n="24">loved who died, you are a sculptor dreaming of space</l>
        <l n="25">and speed, your hand alone could have done this.</l>
        <l n="26">Curiosity, the passionate hand of desire. Dead,</l>
        <l n="27">or sleeping? Is there speed enough? And, swooping,</l>
        <l n="28">you relinquish all that you have made your own,</l>
        <l n="29">the kingdom of your self sailing, for you must awake</l>
        <l n="30">and breathe your warmth in this beloved image</l>
        <l n="31">whether it's dead or merely disappearing,</l>
        <l n="32">as space is disappearing and your singularity.</l>
    </lg>
    <date when="1957">1957</date>
</twinkie>