<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../schema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?><root>
    <head>
        <episode>DEEP SIX</episode>
        <writer>David Slack</writer>
        <director>Ciro Nieli</director>
        <storyboard>Kalvin Lee, Rafael Rosado, Alan Wan</storyboard>
        <animation>Dong Woo Animation Company, Ltd.</animation>
        <source>https://teentitans.fandom.com/wiki/Deep_Six_(Transcript)</source>
        <issueList>
            <issueInfo link="../comic/issue-33.xml"/>
        </issueList>
    </head>
    <characterList>
        <charList type="nonrecurring" id="Captain">Captain</charList>
        <charList type="recurring" id="Trident" subtype="villain">Trident</charList>
        <charList type="nonrecurring" id="Crewman">Crewman</charList>
        <charList type="recurring" id="Robin" subtype="titan">Robin</charList>
        <charList type="recurring" id="Starfire" subtype="titan">Starfire</charList>
        <charList type="recurring" id="Raven" subtype="titan">Raven</charList>
        <charList type="recurring" id="Cyborg" subtype="titan">Cyborg</charList>
        <charList type="recurring" id="BeastBoy" subtype="titan">Beast Boy</charList>
        <charList type="recurring" id="Aqualad" subtype="titan">Aqualad</charList>
        <charList type="nonrecurring" id="Tridents" subtype="villain">Tridents</charList>
        <charList type="nonrecurring" id="Trident1" subtype="villain">Trident 1</charList>
        <charList type="nonrecurring" id="Trident2" subtype="villain">Trident 2</charList>
        <charList type="nonrecurring" id="Trident3" subtype="villain">Trident 3</charList>
        <charList type="nonrecurring" id="Trident4" subtype="villain">Trident 4</charList>
        <charList type="nonrecurring" id="Trident5" subtype="villain">Trident 5</charList>
        <charList type="nonrecurring" id="Trident6" subtype="villain">Trident 6</charList>
        <charList type="nonrecurring" id="Trident7" subtype="villain">Trident 7</charList>
        <charList type="nonrecurring" id="Trident8" subtype="villain">Trident 8</charList>
        <charList type="nonrecurring" id="Trident9" subtype="villain">Trident 9</charList>
    </characterList>
    <body>
        <act n="0">
            <title>Prologue</title>
            <sd><stageDesc category="open-shot">Opening shot: choppy waves roiling in a violent thunderstorm at night.</stageDesc> Riding the
                swells, a freighter sails into view toward the camera. Three crewmen struggle to
                secure a tarp over a group of several dozen 55-gallon drums; two other such
                collections have already been covered. The captain steers the steadiest course
                possible under the circumstances as waves break on the bow and the wind threatens to
                pull the sheeting out of the men's hands. <stageDesc category="close-up">Close-up of the drums</stageDesc>, showing them to be
                marked with the universal symbol for radiation hazards. One tips over and rolls away
                across the deck, but a booted foot comes down to stop it.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Captain">Captain</spkr>
                <sd>over the loudspeaker</sd>Watch it!<sd><directNote kind="cut">Cut to him</directNote>, with a microphone in his
                    hand.</sd>Any of that toxic junk goes into the bay, we're all in deep
                trouble!</sp>

            <sd>The ship is in Jump City Bay, then. There is a flash of lightning during this line,
                which clears to show a silhouette at the window. <stageDesc category="close-up">Close-up</stageDesc>: <charDesc ref="#Trident">it is a reptilian figure
                with glowing yellow eyes, and it lifts a long trident</charDesc>. Back to the deck, where the
                men are still struggling to get the waste squared away. There is an explosion from
                around the corner of the wheelhouse, followed by the walls and windows blowing out.
                When the dust clears, we are inside the ruined structure; the captain is sprawled on
                his back, at the feet of the intruder. This is<char>Trident</char>.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Captain">Captain</spkr>Who...or what are you?</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Trident">Trident</spkr>I am excellence. I am perfection. I am
                <char>Trident</char></sp>

            <sd>On the end of this, a flash from the weapon's points illuminates him fully, think of
                the Creature from the "Black Lagoon" and you have the idea. <stageDesc category="close-up">Close-up of the captain</stageDesc>,
                who cries out and shields his eyes from a sudden flare, then pull back.<char>Trident</char>is
                gone. Now a few waves spill onto the port side, carrying the creature up with them.
                He holds a large clamp with a cable attached.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Crewman">Crewman</spkr>Hey!</sp>

            <sd>The clamp is attached to the railing, and <char>Trident</char> goes over the side. <directNote kind="pan">Pan to
                starboard</directNote>, where he immediately climbs onto the deck with an identical device.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Crewman">Crewman</spkr>He's everywhere!</sp>

            <sd>This one is also hooked on, and<char>Trident</char>jumps ship again. The crew barely has time
                to look toward the stern before seeing him repeating the performance there as well;
                he glares back at them and leaps back into the water. Staggering and groaning, the
                captain crosses the wheelhouse and looks out through the hole in its walls. After
               <char>Trident</char>submerges, the cables on his clampspull taut and start to drag the ship
                down, stern first. Back to the deck.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Captain">Captain</spkr>
                <sd>over the loudspeaker</sd>Abandon ship! Abandon ship!</sp>

            <sd>The panicked crew makes to follow this order. <stageDesc category="long-shot">Long shot of the freighter</stageDesc>, its bow
                rising higher and higher and finally slipping beneath the waves as a life raft
                floats by, carrying the captain and crew. The last they see of their vessel is
                <char>Trident</char> perched triumphantly atop the prow. <stageDesc category="close-up">Close-up of his weapon's points</stageDesc> as they
                drop below the surface, then <directNote kind="cut">cut to the utterly flabbergasted seafarers</directNote>, trying to
                figure out how they lost their ship and a huge consignment of radioactive leftovers
                in one fell swoop. <directNote kind="pan">Pull back to a <stageDesc category="long-shot">long shot</stageDesc></directNote> of their rubber craft bobbing in the
                maelstrom. A final lightning strike blacks out the screen when it recedes.</sd>

            <cue>OPENING THEME (sung in Japanese)</cue>

        </act>
        <act n="1">
            <title>Act One</title>
            <sd><stageDesc category="open-shot">Opening shot: the exterior of Titans Tower</stageDesc>, seen from the level of the water in the
                bay. It is now the next morning. <directNote kind="tilt">Tilt down into the depths</directNote> and <directNote kind="fade">fade to black</directNote>.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Robin">Robin</spkr>
                <sd>voice over</sd>Begin launch sequence.</sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="fade">Fade in to <char>Robin</char></directNote>, strapped into a driver's seat wit a steering yoke in front of him.
                He wears a microphone headset and presses several buttons on a panel. <directNote kind="cut">Cut to each of
                the other Titans in time with their lines</directNote>; they are similarly situated in individual
                cockpits, and through the windows around them water is flowing by. The Titans are in
                the T-Sub, their five-man submersible.</sd>

            <sd>The notation "headset" will be used to indicate lines that are heard over the
                communications system, without the speaker being in frame.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Robin">Robin</spkr>Main power online.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Starfire">Starfire</spkr>Oxygen tanks at maximum.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Raven">Raven</spkr>Defensive systems active.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>Twin-turbo hydrojet engine purring like a
                kitten.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>
                <sd>lounges in his chair</sd>And your secret weapon is ready to rock.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>
                <sd>headset</sd>Only time you qualify as a secret weapon is after eating a tofu bean
                burrito.</sp>

            <sd>These words surprise the little green guy and then make him good and angry. A vein
                stands out on his forehead; <directNote kind="cut">cut to <char>Cyborg</char></directNote>.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>
                <sd>headset</sd>Uh, 'scuse me, bud. Can you breathe underwater? Uh-uh. Can you be
                any fish in the sea?</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>
                <sd>grudgingly</sd>Uh-uh.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>
                <sd>headset</sd>Didn't think so.</sp>

            <sd>Back to him, saluting and cracking knuckles.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Robin">Robin</spkr>
                <sd>headset</sd><char>Beast Boy's</char> right. His skills are essential to our mission.</sp>

            <sd>Back to <char>Cyborg</char> <directNote kind="gag">Sight gag: the shape-shifter blows a loud raspberry, and his tongue
                flicks out from the headphones to cover the hefty Titan with drool</directNote>. <directNote kind="cut">Cut to
                Robin</directNote>.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Robin">Robin</spkr>We have to find out what this<char>Trident</char>guy is
                planning. If it takes forty barrels of toxic waste, I doubt it's environmentally
                friendly.</sp>

            <sd>The engines have finished warming up. <directNote kind="dissolve">Dissolve to an <stageDesc category="overhead-shot">overhead view</stageDesc></directNote> of him and <directNote kind="pull">pull
                back slowly</directNote> to frame the entire T-Sub. It is orange, shaped something like a manta
                ray, with the five cockpits in a cross formation. Bow: <char>Robin</char> Port: Starfire.
                Center: <char>Beast Boy</char> Starboard: <char>Raven</char> Stern: <char>Cyborg</char> The craft is on a platform that
                is descending in a water-filled shaft. Head-on view of a horizontal chute that
                connects with this passage; the platform slides down level with this, and the camera
                pulls back as floodlights in the sides switch on. <directNote kind="cut">Cut to Robin</directNote>.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Robin">Robin</spkr>Titans! Launch!</sp>

            <sd>The engines hit first gear, and the T-Sub shoots along the chute, steadily gaining
                speed and pushing<char>Robin</char>back into his seat. It approaches a closed hatch, which
                slides open upon approach to reveal the bottom of Jump City Bay. The vessel blasts
                out, to the sound of jubilant whooping from <char>Cyborg</char> and soon recedes into the blue
                depths. <directNote kind="dissolve">Dissolve to a <stageDesc category="close-up">close-up</stageDesc> of a passing school of fish</directNote>; the team chugs straight
                through them, disrupting the formation.<char>Starfire</char>watches them while Beast Boy
                watches her.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Starfire">Starfire</spkr>Oooh, wondrous!</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>If you think they're cool, wait 'til you see
                me out there kicking butt. First, I'm going shark.</sp>

            <sd>He turns his teeth to points and gnashes them. Close-up of a button labeled MIC;
                <char>Cyborg</char> reaches up to press it, and the sound cuts off, he has killed <char>Beast Boy's</char>
                audio. Back to the little showoff, whose teeth are still heard clicking together,
                but now much softer and muffled as if underwater; his next line sounds this way as
                well. His dental profile returns to normal.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>
                <sd>taps his headset</sd>Hey! What just...is this thing on? Hey, cut it out!</sp>

            <sd><char>Cyborg</char> turns the mic back on.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>
                <sd>innocently</sd>Goodness me. I seem to have accidentally switched off <char>Beast Boy's</char>
                microphone.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Raven">Raven</spkr>
                <sd>headset</sd>Could you go ahead and accidentally leave it off?</sp>

            <sd>That vein in the green forehead throbs again as the sonar start to beep. <stageDesc category="close-up">Close-up of
                the display</stageDesc>, on which a red dot is flashing.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Robin">Robin</spkr>
                <sd>from o.c.</sd>Sonar contact.<sd><directNote kind="cut">Cut to him</directNote>.</sd><char>Beast Boy</char> Ready to go?</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>
                <sd>taking off his headset</sd>Dude, I was born ready.<sd>He unbuckles his
                    harness.</sd>Time to do what I do best.<sd>sinks out of sight, looking at <char>Raven</char>
                    across the way</sd>Try not to be jealous.</sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="cut">Cut to her cockpit</directNote>. Through the transparent canopy, a gargantuan green-and-black
                creature rises into view and stops briefly, with its eye at her level, to blink at
                her before ascending again.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Raven">Raven</spkr>He just put on three hundred thousand pounds.</sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="pull">Pull back</directNote> to a <stageDesc category="long-shot">long shot of the T-Sub</stageDesc>. <char>Beast Boy</char> <transform class="fish">has become a whale</transform>.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Raven">Raven</spkr>
                <sd>headset</sd>I am so jealous.</sp>

            <sd>He swims off, the T-Sub following, and heads toward the wreck of the freighter at
                the floor of the bay. As they move closer, <transform class="fish">he becomes a hammerhead shark</transform>. The
                unhealthy cargo that was on the deck has been entirely cleared away.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Robin">Robin</spkr>There's our ship, but where's the cargo?</sp>

            <sd>He fires up a set of exterior searchlights to keep a fix on <char>Beast Boy's</char> position.
                The green predator swims along the hull; <directNote kind="cut">cut to inside a large rent in it</directNote> and <directNote kind="pan">pan to
                follow him through</directNote>.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>
                <sd>headset</sd>If this dude's bad enough to sink a whole ship, those barrels could
                be anywhere by now.</sp>

            <sd>He continues on o.c., passing a figure hidden in the murky shadows. It looks after
                him and then swims up and away. Outside, the T-Sub describes a slow circle around
                the wreck, keeping lights trained on it. <directNote kind="pan">Pan from here to <char>Trident</char></directNote>, who is standing
                by the hull; he watches for a moment and then swims along the ship's length to the
                breach. Inside,<char>Beast Boy</char>makes his way out toward open water, and the second figure
                ducks away from the opening just as the floodlight beam reaches it. The green shark
                goes after him; <directNote kind="cut">cut to a <stageDesc category="long-shot">long shot</stageDesc> of the freighter</directNote>. The shadowed figure flees the
                scene as<char>Beast Boy</char>keeps a long tail on him.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Robin">Robin</spkr>Looks like<char>Beast Boy</char>found <char>Trident</char></sp>

            <sd>The chase continues; now the T-Sub pulls away from the freighter to follow them
                both, but<char>Trident</char>drops into their wake to tail everyone. A blast from his weapon
                hits the starboard wing.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>
                <sd>groans angrily</sd>Looks like<char>Trident</char>found us!</sp>

            <sd><char>Beast Boy</char> is still back of the mystery swimmer; <transform class="fish">transforming into a barracuda</transform>, he
                puts on a burst of speed and begins to close the gap. <char>Trident's</char> shots pepper the
                water around the submarine; he scores a hit just off the port side of <char>Robin's</char>
                cockpit.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Robin">Robin</spkr><char>Cyborg</char> Bring us about! <char>Raven</char> Get ready to
                fire!</sp>

            <sd>The vessel does a swift U-turn, only to find itself alone in the water after doing
                so.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>
                <sd>looks around</sd>Where'd he go?</sp>

            <sd>Still nothing. Now<char>Starfire</char>scans the depths through her canopy; a blast strikes it,
                and she finds him floating dead ahead of her and gasps.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Starfire">Starfire</spkr>He is there!</sp>

            <sd>Not for long; now he passes <char>Raven</char></sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Raven">Raven</spkr>No! That way!</sp>

            <sd>He moves again; Cyborg catches sight.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>It's him!</sp>

            <sd>He opens fire on the fleeing T-Sub, scoring a few near misses before properly
                correcting his aim. Alarms go off in the cockpits.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Robin">Robin</spkr>He can't be in three places at once! Head for
                that--</sp>

            <sd><stageDesc category="close-up">Close-up of two draining power gauges on the panel</stageDesc>.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>
                <sd>from o.c.</sd>The engines are fried!<sd><directNote kind="cut">Cut to him</directNote>.</sd>We're going down!</sp>

            <sd>They proceed to do so at an alarming rate. The second figure seen in the freighter
                takes in the scene; the four Titans descending far too quickly for their own good,
               <char>Trident</char>bombarding the stern at will, and turns to the camera. We can see no
                features except two bright gleams for eyes. Waves of energy begin to radiate from
                the forehead, exactly after the style of Aquaman's underwater telepathy. This is
                <char>Aqualad</char></sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Aqualad">Aqualad</spkr>Your friends are in danger.</sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="cut">Cut to <char>Beast Boy</char></directNote>, <transform class="fish">now a bull shark</transform>; the message reaches him.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>My friends are in what? Whoa! How did you say
                that? Dude! How did I say that?<sd>He sees the T-Sub.</sd>Hey!</sp>

            <sd>He charges after his teammates.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>Okay.<sd><transform class="fish">He becomes a swordfish</transform>.</sd>Hero
                time. This is my big chance to prove I'm the--<sd>Something blue and black flashes
                    past.</sd>--best?</sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="pull">Pull back</directNote>.<char>Aqualad</char>has just left him in the dust; he strains to catch up. The T-Sub,
                meanwhile, is being used for <char>Trident's</char> target practice. <stageDesc category="close-up">Close-up of him</stageDesc>, blazing
                away; suddenly he is knocked down o.c. by a hit from behind. <charDesc ref="#Aqualad">Aqualad is now seen in
                full detail for the first time-roughly the same age as the Titans; blue scaly skin
                on fingers, upper arms and chest; black on forearms, hands, legs, and neck; pure
                black eyes without whites and long hair of the same color</charDesc>.</sd>

            <sd>The badly damaged craft drops into a fissure on the bay/ocean floor. Inside, water
                has begun to spurt in through cracks in the hull, shorting out the controls.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>Main power's down! Hydrojets are toast and we're
                leaking air!</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Robin">Robin</spkr>Tell me something I don't know.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Raven">Raven</spkr>Okay. We're all going to drown.</sp>

            <sd>The outer structure begins to creak as the T-Sub descends toward crush depth in the
                fissure.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>Hull's starting to give. We sink much deeper, the
                pressure's gonna crush us.</sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="cut">Cut to a rock formation</directNote>.<char>Aqualad</char>is thrown into view to slam against it back first,
                and<char>Trident</char>moves in on him. A sudden charge by the young fellow sends both tumbling
                into the open to grapple a bit before<char>Trident</char>starts throwing punches.<char>Aqualad</char>swims
                up quickly, then comes down behind<char>Trident</char>and gets him in a headlock. <char>Beast Boy</char>
                <transform class="fish">again a swordfish</transform>, zips by.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>Let Pretty Boy wrestle.<sd><transform class="fish">becomes a
                    squid</transform></sd>Only<char>Beast Boy</char>can save a whole submarine.</sp>

            <sd>He goes into a sharp dive, preparing to do just that.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Robin">Robin</spkr>Titans! Brace for impact!</sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="cut">Cut to outside</directNote>, in the fissure.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>
                <sd>headset</sd>Oh, man!</sp>

            <sd>They grind against the wall. At the edge,<char>Aqualad</char>is kicked down to the surface by
                the escaping <char>Trident</char> he looks after the villain, then down at the impending
                disaster, and uses his telepathic powers to summon two nearby whales. The T-Sub
                drops like a rock, at least, like a rock that has been dropped underwater, as <char>Beast
                Boy</char> races after it.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>I got it, I got it!<sd>The whales pass
                    him.</sd>Huh?</sp>

            <sd>They pull in neatly under the doomed vessel and bear it upward to the top of the
                fissure.<char>Beast Boy</char>can only watch, hopelessly confused.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>They got it? How come they got it?</sp>

            <sd><char>Aqualad</char> pulls into view by him.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Aqualad">Aqualad</spkr>Because I asked for their help.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>You talk to fish? Yeah, right.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Aqualad">Aqualad</spkr>I'm talking to you, aren't I?</sp>

            <sd>A big sweat drop appears briefly on the squid's head.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>Well, I, uh...technically, I'm a squid.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Aqualad">Aqualad</spkr>It's called telepathy. Follow me.</sp>

            <sd>He swims away.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>
                <sd>very snarky; a vein throbs on his head</sd>"It's called telepathy."</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Aqualad">Aqualad</spkr>
                <sd>from o.c.</sd>I heard that.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>
                <sd>flushes angrily</sd>Who is this guy?</sp>

            <sd>He follows.</sd>

            <sd><directNote kind="dissolve">Dissolve to a cavern with a large body of water inside</directNote>. Something approaches the
                surface from beneath and comes up to reveal itself as the T-Sub, which floats slowly
                to the shore.<char>Robin</char>and<char>Starfire</char>are the first ones off; they look around in
                amazement, and<char>Robin</char>lets off a low whistle.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Starfire">Starfire</spkr>Beautiful.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>
                <sd>from o.c.</sd>It's not beautiful!<sd><directNote kind="cut">Cut to him</directNote>, also on shore.</sd>It's
                totaled! Aw, man, I never even got to use the seismic blasters!</sp>

            <sd><char>Raven</char> has debarked now.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Raven">Raven</spkr>Where are we?</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Aqualad">Aqualad</spkr>
                <sd>from o.c.</sd>My place.</sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="cut">Cut to another part of the cavern</directNote>; he rises to the water's surface on the back of a
                beaching whale. Jumping high and far, he lands on the shore as the marine mammal
                submerges again.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Aqualad">Aqualad</spkr>I told the whales to bring you here.</sp>

            <sd>He crosses to <char>Raven</char></sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Raven">Raven</spkr>
                <sd>blushes</sd>Okay...uh...thanks.</sp>

            <sd><char>Starfire</char> pops up.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Starfire">Starfire</spkr>
                <sd>also blushes</sd>Oh, yes, truly, truly, thank you so much for saving us.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>
                <sd>from o.c.</sd>He saved you?<sd><directNote kind="cut">Cut to him</directNote>, leaving the water in human
                form.</sd>Hel-lo? I was there, too, you know.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>You stopped<char>Trident</char>from kebabbing us with that
                souped-up shrimp fork?</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Robin">Robin</spkr>Way to go!</sp>

            <sd>Sweat drop on the green temple.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>Well, I was gonna, but...</sp>

            <sd><char>Aqualad</char> crosses to them.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Aqualad">Aqualad</spkr>I'm <char>Aqualad</char> Sorry I didn't introduce myself
                earlier. We Atlanteans try to keep a low profile.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>
                <sd>sarcastically, shaking hands</sd>Good job. Don't think anybody even noticed
                you.</sp>

            <sd>The girls certainly have. Behind his back,<char>Raven</char>and<char>Starfire</char>are positively
                smitten; their eyes have become hearts, and more of these float up from them. <char>Raven</char>
                is first to recover.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Raven">Raven</spkr>You're from Atlantis?</sp>

            <sd>He nods.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Aqualad">Aqualad</spkr>And so is <char>Trident</char></sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="dissolve">Dissolve</directNote> to a <directNote kind="freeze-frame">holographic freeze-frame of <char>Trident</char></directNote> blasting the landscape. On the
                next line, two other scenes come up to replace it; they show him lifting a piece of
                a marble column he has broken, then firing at fleeing people.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Aqualad">Aqualad</spkr>
                <sd>from o.c.</sd>He's the worst criminal in Atlantis, with an ego to match.</sp>

            <sd>A full-figure shot of said criminal now appears, and<char>Aqualad</char>steps into view before
                it.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Aqualad">Aqualad</spkr><char>Trident</char> claims he's perfect in every way,
                    <sd><directNote kind="pull">Pull back</directNote>; the Titans are gathered at the projector.</sd>so he thinks he can
                do whatever he wants.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Robin">Robin</spkr>Any idea what he wants with all that toxic
                waste?</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Aqualad">Aqualad</spkr>Whatever it is, it'll be bad for both our worlds.
                He's already gained some kind of new power. It's like he can be everywhere at
                once.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Raven">Raven</spkr>Noticed that.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Aqualad">Aqualad</spkr>As long as we're after the same guy, maybe we can
                help each other.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>
                <sd>pushing<char>Robin</char>and<char>Raven</char>o.c.</sd>Whoa, hey, no, we're good. Got the whole
               <char>Trident</char>thing under control. 'Sides, I'm sure there's a school of minnows somewhere
                that need your--</sp>

            <sd><char>Robin</char> reaches into view and yanks him away. <directNote kind="cut">Cut to ground level</directNote>, the camera pointing
                straight up at the ceiling, as all five Titans lean in for a huddle.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Raven">Raven</spkr>We're at the bottom of the ocean.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>Our sub's Swiss cheese.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Starfire">Starfire</spkr>And we cannot breathe water.</sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="pull">Pull back</directNote>; their host is standing at a short distance.<char>Robin</char>pokes his head up.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Robin">Robin</spkr>We'll take any help you can give us.</sp>

            <sd><char>Aqualad</char> nods.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Aqualad">Aqualad</spkr>
                <sd>calling o.c.</sd>Hey, Tramm!</sp>

            <sd>At the other end of the cavern, a half-clamshell on the floor flips up to reveal a
                manhole underneath. What climbs out is a reptilian humanoid, perhaps three feet
                tall, in short overalls and wearing a backpack. The eyes are very large, protruding
                from the sides of the head. This is Tramm; he runs to the group, saying something in
                his own language.<char>Aqualad</char>kneels to him.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Aqualad">Aqualad</spkr>Want to give these people a hand with their
                sub?</sp>

            <sd>Tramm babbles excitedly, cracks his knuckles, and claps his hands before running to
                it.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Aqualad">Aqualad</spkr>Tramm's good with tools.</sp>

            <sd>One high jump carries him onto the hull and deposits him near a breach. Muttering to
                himself a bit, he reaches in and brings up the severed ends of two groups of cables.
                These are stretched out and laid over the broken edges; now he dips into his pack
                and yanks out a jackhammer-like device, which he plies with gusto. <char>Cyborg</char> runs
                up.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>Yo, careful! That's my sub you're messing
                with!</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Aqualad">Aqualad</spkr>
                <sd>crosses in front of the others</sd>And while he's helping you, I'll track down
                <char>Trident</char></sp>

            <sd>He has nearly reached the water's edge when<char>Beast Boy</char>runs up. They begin to push
                each other out of the way, becoming gradually more forceful.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>You mean I'll track down <char>Trident</char></sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Aqualad">Aqualad</spkr>That's okay, I can handle it.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>Thanks, but I think I should do this.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Aqualad">Aqualad</spkr>Seriously, I'll take care of it!</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>Would you just get out of my--?</sp>

            <sd>They grab each other.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#BeastBoy and Aqualad">Beast Boy and Aqualad</spkr>Let me go!</sp>

            <sd>The fracas continues for a few more seconds before<char>Robin</char>comes over.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Robin">Robin</spkr>Guys!<sd>He pushes them apart.</sd>Why don't you both
                go track him down together?</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Aqualad">Aqualad</spkr>I usually work alone.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>Yeah. Me too.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Aqualad">Aqualad</spkr>You do not! You're part of a team!</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>
                <sd>approximates Tramm's head briefly</sd>And you hang out with Tramm the fish-boy!
                What's your point?</sp>

            <sd>They glare at each other;<char>Robin</char>backs them up again.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Robin">Robin</spkr>Hey! Arguing isn't going to stop <char>Trident</char> Now get out
                and search, both of you.</sp>

            <sd>The two give each other one more dirty look before diving into the water.<char>Robin</char>just
                stands there and shakes his head disgustedly. <directNote kind="fade">Fade to black</directNote>.</sd>

        </act>
        <act n="2">
            <title>Act Two</title>
            <sd><stageDesc category="open-shot">Opening shot: Beast Boy</stageDesc>, <transform class="fish">as a squid</transform>, and<char>Aqualad</char>swimming near the ocean floor. They
                stop for a look around.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Aqualad">Aqualad</spkr>
                <sd>points</sd>I searched that region yesterday.<sd>moves in an opposite
                    direction</sd>We'll start over--</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>Look. I'm sure you're some kind of local hero,
                but I'm a real hero from the big city. So just let me call the shots...<sd><transform class="fish">He
                    becomes a dolphin</transform>.</sd>...and try to keep up.</sp>

            <sd>Clicking sounds emerge from him; the dolphin equivalent of sonar tracking, as he
                swims around<char>Aqualad</char>a bit. Finally, he concentrates on one heading.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>I'm picking something up on my sonar! Come
                on!</sp>

            <sd>He moves out quickly, but his partner only eases forward a bit. What he has located
                is a group of real dolphins; they dart playfully around him.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Aqualad">Aqualad</spkr>
                <sd>smirking</sd>Congratulations. You found other dolphins.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>I knew that.</sp>

            <sd><char>Aqualad</char> moves in and hits them with a burst of telepathy, after which they swim off
                together.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Aqualad">Aqualad</spkr>They told me where to find <char>Trident</char> Try to keep
                up.</sp>

            <sd>He moves o.c.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>Oh, I'll do better than that.</sp>

            <sd>He follows; <directNote kind="cut">cut to the Atlantean</directNote>, making good time, as the Titan catches up and
                pulls ahead. He puts in second gear, and the informal race ranges over the ocean
                floor, weaving around the occasional rock formation Finding himself neck and neck
                with <char>Beast Boy</char> <transform class="fish">who changes from a dolphin to a barracuda</transform>,<char>Aqualad</char>keeps
                accelerating to try and maintain the lead. In a twinkling, the barracuda has turned
                into a swordfish and moved ahead once more despite <char>Aqualad's</char> best efforts. <stageDesc category="close-up">Close-up
                of the new runner-up</stageDesc>, who has suddenly halted.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Aqualad">Aqualad</spkr>
                <sd>alarmed</sd><char>Beast Boy</char> Stop!</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>
                <sd>from o.c.</sd>What's the matter?</sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="cut">Cut to <char>Beast Boy</char></directNote>, still going full tilt. Placed just behind him, the camera moves to
                keep him in focus as he races toward <char>Trident</char> who is squarely in his path.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>Am I too fast for y--?</sp>

            <sd>A collision with the undersea villain's chest cuts off his taunt; he drops, dazed,
                to the floor as<char>Aqualad</char>catches up.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>
                <sd>looking up at Trident</sd>Heh...how's it going?</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Trident">Trident</spkr>Keep your thoughts to yourself, inferior
                fool!</sp>

            <sd>On the end of this line he brings out his weapon and fires it up.<char>Beast Boy</char>ducks
                away just in time to avoid the attack;<char>Trident</char>strafes the ground near his feet, but
                <char>Aqualad's</char> swimming tackle cuts him off. Both fall out of sight behind a ridge.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>Oh, no, you don't!<sd><transform class="fish">He becomes a bull
                    shark</transform>.</sd>This time, he's mine!</sp>

            <sd>He approaches the ridge, but stops short when<char>Trident</char>jumps up onto it from behind.
                The three prongs blaze like a machine gun, but a lucky snap of the jaws breaks the
                shaft and silences them. Not giving up so easily,<char>Trident</char>reaches out with one big
                hand and seizes <char>Beast Boy</char> <transform class="fish">who becomes a squid</transform> and wraps his tentacles around the
                enemy. They tumble behind the ridge.</sd>

            <sd><directNote kind="pull">Pan from here to another formation</directNote>.<char>Aqualad</char>and<char>Trident</char>back around it and into
                view; they are grappling for a hold on the fork, which is now whole again. The
                black-haired hero finally wrenches it away, throwing his opponent several yards, and
                breaks it over his knee.</sd>

            <sd><directNote kind="cut">Cut to the first ridge</directNote>. Here come<char>Beast Boy</char>and<char>Trident</char>again; the latter gets
                himself free of those tentacles and throws the big green squid at the camera.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>INCOMING!!</sp>

            <sd><char>Aqualad</char> catches him with his face and has a very hard time peeling those tentacles
                away. When he can see again, he gives<char>Beast Boy</char>a very nasty look.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>I said, "Incoming".</sp>

            <sd>Both look in toward the second fight; <directNote kind="cut">cut to Trident</directNote>, swimming that way toward a
                dark grotto.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Aqualad">Aqualad</spkr>
                <sd>from o.c.</sd>He's getting away!</sp>

            <sd>He and<char>Beast Boy</char>move in. <directNote kind="cut">Cut to behind them</directNote> and <directNote kind="pull">pan across the interior</directNote>. No one
                here.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>Hmmm...</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Aqualad">Aqualad</spkr>
                <sd>furiously</sd>Where were you back there?</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>Where was I? Fighting<char>Trident</char>by myself!</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Aqualad">Aqualad</spkr>You barely laid a tentacle on him! At least I
                managed to break his weapon!</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>Dude, that's just wrong. I so broke that fork
                thing!</sp>

            <sd><char>Aqualad</char> grits his teeth to deliver a crushing response or a right hook, but before
                he can make up his mind,<char>Trident</char>swims past and goes deeper into the grotto. <char>Beast
                Boy</char> looks in a different direction and sees a pair of eyes shining in the black
                distance.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#BeastBoy and Aqualad">Beast Boy and Aqualad</spkr>
                <sd>point in opposite directions</sd>There he goes!</sp>

            <sd>both glare at each other</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>I saw him! He's that way! I'm right, you're
                wrong! End of story!<sd>swims where he indicated</sd>If you don't believe me, see
                you later!</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Aqualad">Aqualad</spkr>I'm telling you, he's this way! If you want to go
                that way, be my guest, but I'm going to catch <char>Trident</char></sp>

            <sd>He points off at the appropriate moments, then swims in his direction after
                finishing the line. <directNote kind="dissolve">Dissolve to another part of this grotto</directNote>. As he advances, columns
                of flame and steam shoot up from the ground; undersea geysers spout off. After he
                has passed o.c.,<char>Trident</char>emerges from within the boiling fumes and sets off in
                pursuit. <directNote kind="cut">Cut to Aqualad</directNote>, who suddenly finds himself on the receiving end of a tackle
                just like the one he laid on the evildoer. More steam blows across the screen; when
                the view clears, we see<char>Beast Boy</char>sulking along the path he has chosen.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>Pretty-boy know-it-all showoff. Thinks he's
                so--</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Trident">Trident</spkr>
                <sd>from o.c.</sd>Worthless scum!<sd><directNote kind="cut">Cut to him</directNote>, standing up with the trident again
                    in his hand.</sd>You cannot defeat perfection!</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>How many of those fork thingies do you
                have?</sp>

            <sd>The wielder just snarls and unloads a few blasts that cause<char>Beast Boy</char>to almost tie
                himself in knots as he dodges.<char>Trident</char>fires again and again to send the green
                kraken running for cover. As the aggressor closes in, <char>Beast Boy</char> <transform class="reptile">turns into a turtle</transform>
                and yanks his head and legs into the shell. Now the trident is thrust at him, but
                its points merely clang off the hard carapace; a follow-up blast does no damage but
                sends him hurtling through the dark depths.<char>Trident</char>drifts after him.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Trident">Trident</spkr>I will win! I always win! I am superior!</sp>

            <sd>Out of the blackness shoots a claw that locks onto the wooden shaft. <char>Beast Boy</char> <transform class="fish">now
                a giant crab</transform>, is hauled up.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>And I thought<char>Aqualad</char>had a big ego.</sp>

            <sd>He lashes out with his other claw. <directNote kind="wipe">Wipe to the geyser patch</directNote>, where<char>Aqualad</char>drops
                into view to land flat on his back. Rubbing his head, he looks up and finds Trident
                hurling himself downward, namesake at the ready.<char>Aqualad</char>gets out of the way just in
                time and immediately has to dodge a bolt.<char>Trident</char>loses track of him, but only for a
                moment until the blue-and-black-skinned fighter darts back in and kicks him in the
                head. The trident and its user go flying in different directions; the former lands,
                points down, and sticks among the fire spurts.</sd>

            <sd>Both swimmers charge toward it, but<char>Trident</char>gets his hand out to reach first.
                <stageDesc category="close-up">Close-up of the shaft</stageDesc>; he closes his fingers around it. <directNote kind="pull">Pull back as he yanks it out</directNote>
                of the muck and takes a couple of swings that barely miss the blue-scaled chest.
                Next, he pulls it back over his shoulder for a couple of home-run swings that come a
                hair short of giving<char>Aqualad</char>a high-speed appendectomy. More lunges push him back
                toward the edge of one geyser, and he loses his balance and stumbles near the
                lip.</sd>

            <sd><char>Trident</char> raises the fork to impale the half-prone figure, who seizes the head to stop
                it just inches from his face. The two struggle,<char>Trident</char>gradually pushing the points
                toward their target, and then<char>Aqualad</char>does a quick sidestep and releases his grip.
                With his force not meeting any more resistance,<char>Trident</char>is flung forward into the
                geyser, which blows its top right on cue. The steam clears to leave<char>Aqualad</char>standing
                alone. He makes a beeline for a patch of light shining down from an opening above.
                <directNote kind="fade">Fade to white</directNote>, then <directNote kind="snap">snap to black</directNote>.</sd>

        </act>
        <act n="3">
            <title>Act Three</title>
            <sd><stageDesc category="open-shot">Opening shot: a cavern similar to the one<char>Aqualad</char>calls home</stageDesc>, but darker; this was
                the source of the light seen at the end of Act Two, with a rocky shore at the
                water's edge. He jumps out and comes across <char>Beast Boy</char> <transform class="human">who is back in human form</transform>.
                Both gasp, surprised.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#BeastBoy and Aqualad">Beast Boy and Aqualad</spkr>I just saw <char>Trident</char>...
                No, you didn't!... Yes, I did!<sd><directNote kind="gag">Sight gag: flames in the background</directNote>.</sd>Cut it
                    out!<sd>Gag ends.</sd></sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>I don't care what you saw! I fought
                <char>Trident</char></sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Aqualad">Aqualad</spkr>That's impossible!</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>
                <sd>a vein throbs on his forehead</sd>Okay, dude.</sp>

            <sd>His arms flailing, he tries to hit <char>Aqualad</char> but a long arm and a hand planted on his
                head stop him from getting close enough to do so.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>What is your problem?</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Aqualad">Aqualad</spkr>What is your problem? We're supposed to be on the
                same side, but you treat me like an enemy!</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>I don't need you on my side! This was my
                mission until you showed up!<sd>He lets up and pushes <char>Aqualad's</char> hand away.</sd>You
                think you're so cool, but I've got a news flash for you. You're not better than
                me!</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Aqualad">Aqualad</spkr>I don't think I'm better than you!</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>
                <sd>stunned</sd>You don't?</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Aqualad">Aqualad</spkr>Maybe you're better than me. Who cares? I just
                want to catch <char>Trident</char> And to do that, we need to stop fighting and start working
                together.</sp>

            <sd>He walks o.c. in a huff, but <char>Beast Boy's</char> brain has just slipped into gear.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>Working together...<sd>goes after
                    Aqualad</sd><char>Aqualad</char><sd><directNote kind="cut">Cut to both</directNote>.</sd>What if there's more than one
                <char>Trident</char></sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Aqualad">Aqualad</spkr>Don't be ridiculous. How could there be--?</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>I know, but what if there is? If he found a
                way to copy himself? He could be in two places at once. There wouldn't be just one
                <char>Trident</char> There'd be...</sp>

            <sd>A large glob of yellow slime falls onto his face to cut him off. Wiping himself
                clean, he looks toward the ceiling, as does <char>Aqualad</char> and the <directNote kind="tilt">camera tilts up quickly</directNote>
                to show a forest of large, gooey, translucent globules suspended there. Each has the
                outline of a figure inside.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Aqualad">Aqualad</spkr>
                <sd>from o.c.</sd>...Thousands.</sp>

            <sd><stageDesc category="close-up">Close-up</stageDesc>; the figures are revealed to be clones of <char>Trident</char> seemingly asleep. One
                opens its eyes and growls softly. Back to the two heroes.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>Uh-oh.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Aqualad">Aqualad</spkr>One<char>Trident</char>is bad...</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>...But this is...</sp>

            <sd>On the next line, <directNote kind="cut">cut to the area of the cavern in front of them</directNote>. The entire ceiling
                is covered with these sacs, and a horde of Tridents stands ready to fight. The
                "impossible" attacks and maneuvering seen up to this point need no further
                explanation.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Tridents">Tridents</spkr>...An army!</sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="pull">Pull back</directNote>. The hazardous waste drums from the sunken freighter stand in groups, with
                pipes running from them up to the forest of developing clones to nourish them. The
                multitudes on the ground roar and run at<char>Beast Boy</char>and <char>Aqualad</char> who brace for a
                full-scale throwdown and charge. Some are armed, others empty-handed.<char>Aqualad</char>knocks
                out a couple of them, dodging blasts from the trident held by another before
                levering it upward. One of the sacs is blown open; the<char>Trident</char>inside drops into the
                fray.</sd>

            <sd><char>Beast Boy</char> <transform class="mammal">now a polar bear</transform>, rushes in and raises an enormous paw. One clone tumbles
                to the ground, then another, and then a third raises his weapon and fires. Beast Boy
                is flung backward to crash into a console. Several drums of waste are connected to
                it, and on the screen is a red-letter message: "Hatching Sequence Beginning." Sparks
                fly after he hits; <transform class="human">back in human form</transform>, he stands up and rubs his head, and a big
                drop of sweat rolls down his temple.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>
                <sd>chuckles sheepishly</sd>Oops.<sd><char>Aqualad</char> fetches up next to him.</sd>
                Great.</sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="cut">Cut to a knot of Tridents</directNote>.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Trident1">Trident 1</spkr>My brilliant plan is already a success.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Trident2">Trident 2</spkr>If one of me was perfect...</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Trident3">Trident 3</spkr>...why not make more?</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Trident4">Trident 4</spkr>You can never have too much of a good
                thing.</sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="pan">Pan to others</directNote>.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Trident5">Trident 5</spkr>Once my army conquers Atlantis...</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Trident6">Trident 6</spkr>...I will declare war on the surface world!
                    <sd><directNote kind="cut">Cut to the two good guys</directNote>, then back as he continues.</sd>Everyone on the
                planet will bow down before me...</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Tridents">Tridents</spkr>...and praise my perfection!</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Aqualad">Aqualad</spkr>
                <sd>to Beast Boy</sd>Any bright ideas?</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>Just one. Try to keep up.<sd>to
                Tridents</sd>So, if you're all perfect, which one of you is the best?</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Tridents">Tridents</spkr>I am!...Huh?</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Aqualad">Aqualad</spkr>Come on. You can't all be the best. One of you
                must be better than the others.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Trident7">Trident 7</spkr>I am the original! I am the best!</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Trident8">Trident 8</spkr>You are not the original!</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Tridents">Tridents</spkr>I am!</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Trident9">Trident 9</spkr>Nonsense, you inferior fools! I am perfection!
                I am <char>Trident</char></sp>

            <sd>A brawl breaks out. <directNote kind="cut">Cut to<char>Beast Boy</char>and Aqualad</directNote>, who watch with great satisfaction
                the chaos they have provoked and wince at the sound of the ruckus. When it dies
                down, dazed or unconscious Tridents are sprawled everywhere on the cavern floor.
                Behind the pair, the word "Beginning" on the console panel has changed to a
                countdown clock that is nearly at zero.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Aqualad">Aqualad</spkr>Great idea.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>Kinda got it from you. Now we just have to
                stop those clones from hatching.</sp>

            <sd>They turn to the panel, which flashes as the final three seconds tick away. At zero,
                the clock is replaced by the word "Begin."</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#BeastBoy and Aqualad">Beast Boy and Aqualad</spkr>Too late!</sp>

            <sd>Screeches and yowls from above draw their attention; the newly matured <char>Trident</char>
                clones strain at the membranes holding them and break through. <char>Beast Boy</char> <transform class="mammal">turns into
                a hippopotamus</transform> and barrels into these ranks, knocking them every which way like
                bowling pins. He heads toward the water's edge, with<char>Aqualad</char>close behind, and both
                dive in; <transform class="fish">he becomes a swordfish upon submerging</transform>. Several members of the fresh crop
                go in after the pair, who are doing the underwater equivalent of burning
                rubber.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Aqualad">Aqualad</spkr>We can't let them escape! We have to find some
                way of sealing the exit!</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>Right now, I'm just worried about getting to
                the exit.</sp>

            <sd>The opposition, now out in full force, is making it a horse race.<char>Beast Boy</char>and
               <char>Aqualad</char>charge at the patch of light that marked the cavern's entrance earlier and
                get clear of the place, and then, as the Tridents pull closer, a very familiar
                silhouette pulls into view. They stop short.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Tridents">Tridents</spkr>Huh?</sp>

            <sd><stageDesc category="close-up">Close-up</stageDesc>; it is the T-Sub, back in proper working order thanks to Tramm's efforts.
                Two huge beams, issuing from emitters on the bow, slice the water and strike the
                upper edge of the cavern entrance. There is a mighty flash, which clears to show
                broken rock pouring down from the blast zone to wall up the pathway.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Robin">Robin</spkr>Yes!</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Raven">Raven</spkr>Cool!</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Starfire">Starfire</spkr>
                <sd>flashing V-for-Victory hand sign</sd>Victory!</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>Boo-yah! Seismic blasters worked like a charm!
                    <sd>gives a thumbs-up</sd>Nice repair job, Tramm.</sp>

            <sd>The fish-boy of the hour is in <char>Beast Boy's</char> cockpit; he waves his fists and blabbers
                happily in gratitude. <char>Beast Boy</char> now a squid, and<char>Aqualad</char>look toward the T-Sub's
                handiwork.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>Good thing<char>Trident</char>likes himself so much,
                'cause I'm thinking he won't see anybody else for a looong time.</sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="dissolve">Dissolve to the exterior of the Tower</directNote>, then to <char>Aqualad</char> Tramm, and the three male
                Titans standing among the rocks near the island's shore. It is now the next day, and
                <char>Beast Boy</char> is <transform class="human">back in human form</transform>. During the following line,<char>Raven</char>and<char>Starfire</char>pop
                up; they are again thoroughly lovestruck as when they first clapped eyes on the
                Atlantean in Act One.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Robin">Robin</spkr>
                <sd>to Aqualad</sd>Consider yourself an honorary Teen Titan.</sp>

            <sd><stageDesc category="close-up">Close-up of the honoree on the end of this</stageDesc>;<char>Robin</char>hands him a communicator that
                plays the opening phrase of the show's theme as its "ringtone." The device is
                disc-shaped, yellow around the edge, and black in the center with a large white T.
                He smiles calmly at the gift as<char>Raven</char>and<char>Starfire</char>practically hang over his
                shoulder to look at it. On the next two lines, they shift position a couple of times
                to keep<char>Aqualad</char>in plain sight.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Robin">Robin</spkr>We couldn't have done it without you. Thanks.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Aqualad">Aqualad</spkr>Right back at you. It's good to know there's
                people up here I can trust.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>
                <sd>to Tramm</sd>And it's good to know there's folks down there who can fix a
                hyperjet.</sp>

            <sd>Tramm replies with a hearty bit of gibberish that ends in an easily recognizable
                "boo-yah" as he taps his fists against <char>Cyborg's</char>. Now<char>Aqualad</char>makes eye contact with
                the girls.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Aqualad">Aqualad</spkr>Bye, <char>Raven</char>..Starfire.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Raven">Raven</spkr>
                <sd>flustered</sd>It was...nice to meet you.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Starfire">Starfire</spkr>Oh, very, very, very nice!</sp>

            <sd>She leans into him hard enough to push him o.c.; he ends up next to <char>Beast Boy</char></sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>What can I say, dude? You're the best.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Aqualad">Aqualad</spkr>Nah. You're the best.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>Yeah, you're right.<sd>stretches</sd>And if
                you ever want me to prove it, I'm always up for a race.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Aqualad">Aqualad</spkr>
                <sd>patting his head</sd>Just try and keep up.</sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="pull">Pull back to frame the others</directNote> at a distance in the background. The two rivals,
                turned reluctant partners, turned fast friends run toward the camera in an impromptu
                sprint. <directNote kind="freeze-frame">Freeze frame</directNote>; they are shoulder to shoulder and smiling broadly, and <directNote kind="fade">fade to
                black</directNote>.</sd>
        </act>
    </body>
</root>