<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../schema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?><root>
    <head>
        <episode>SWITCHED</episode>
        <writer>David Slack</writer>
        <director>Ciro Nieli</director>
        <storyboard>Kalvin Lee, Rafael Rosado, Alan Wan</storyboard>
        <animation>Dong Woo Animation Company, Ltd.</animation>
        <source>https://teentitans.fandom.com/wiki/Switched_(Transcript)</source>
        <issueList>
            <issueInfo link="../comic/issue-9.xml"/>
        </issueList>
    </head>
    <characterList>
        <charList type="nonrecurring" id="RobinPuppet">Robin Puppet</charList>
        <charList type="nonrecurring" id="RavenPuppet">Raven Puppet</charList>
        <charList type="nonrecurring" id="StarfirePuppet">Starfire Puppet</charList>
        <charList type="nonrecurring" id="CyborgPuppet">Cyborg Puppet</charList>
        <charList type="nonrecurring" id="BeastBoyPuppet">Beast Boy Puppet</charList>
        <charList type="nonrecurring" id="PuppetKing" subtype="villain">Puppet King</charList>
        <charList type="recurring" id="Raven" subtype="titan">Raven</charList>
        <charList type="recurring" id="Starfire" subtype="titan">Starfire</charList>
        <charList type="recurring" id="Cyborg" subtype="titan">Cyborg</charList>
        <charList type="recurring" id="BeastBoy" subtype="titan">Beast Boy</charList>
        <charList type="recurring" id="Robin" subtype="titan">Robin</charList>
    </characterList>
    <body>
        <act n="0">
            <title>Prologue</title>
            <sd><stageDesc category="open-shot">Opening shot: a closed stage curtain illuminated by a spotlight</stageDesc>. It opens, revealing
                a backdrop that depicts Titans Tower and the city proper behind it on the shore. A
                wooden <char>Robin</char> marionette drops into view and hangs before this scene, and the voice
                of the o.c. puppeteer speaks for it.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#RobinPuppet">Robin puppet</spkr>Titans! Go!</sp>

            <sd>The figure leaps across the stage, <directNote kind="pan">the camera panning to follow</directNote>, then looks back the
                way it came. It is alone.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#RobinPuppet">Robin puppet</spkr>Hey!</sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="pull">Pull back to frame the entire stage</directNote>. Figures in the likenesses of the other four are
                clustered at the other end. The same person provides all five voices, taking on the
                appropriate inflection for each. While the three boys' puppets have hinged mouths,
                similar to a soldier-shaped nutcracker, the two girls' puppets do not.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#RobinPuppet">Robin puppet</spkr>Aren't you guys coming?</sp>

            <sd><stageDesc category="close-up">Close-up of Raven</stageDesc>; <directNote kind="pan">pan to each in turn</directNote>.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#RavenPuppet">Raven puppet</spkr>What's the point? We can't possibly
                defeat the <char>Puppet King</char> </sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#StarfirePuppet">Starfire puppet</spkr>He is too clever and powerful, not
                to mention good-looking.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#CyborgPuppet">Cyborg puppet</spkr>Yeah. We should probably just
                surrender now.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#BeastBoyPuppet">Beast Boy puppet</spkr>Dude, I think we already
                have.</sp>

            <sd>The green puppet gestures upward on the end of this line, and the <directNote kind="pull">camera pulls back
                to frame the entire group</directNote> as they look that way and throw up their arms. <directNote kind="tilt">Tilt up to
                the platform above the stage</directNote> on the next line to reveal the puppeteer, <charDesc ref="#PuppetKing">a short,
                squat fellow in a military dress uniform and sash. His head is in shadow, obscuring
                a clear view of his face, but protuberant eyes and a small crown can be seen.</charDesc> This
                is the <char>Puppet King</char>  his natural voice is reminiscent of Peter Lorre.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#PuppetKing">Puppet King</spkr>Bravo, bravo. But enough rehearsal.<sd>He
                    drops the crosspieces to which the strings are attached.</sd>Time to start the
                show.</sp>

            <sd><stageDesc category="close-up">Close-up of the stage</stageDesc> on the end of this; the five marionettes fall in a jumble, and
                the curtain closes. <directNote kind="fade">Fade to black</directNote>.</sd>

            <cue>OPENING THEME</cue>

        </act>
        <act n="1">
            <title>Act One</title>
            <sd><stageDesc category="open-shot">Opening shot: outer space</stageDesc>.<char>Raven</char>rises into view near the camera, her eyes shut and
                her face composed.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Raven">Raven</spkr><sd>chanting</sd>Azarath Metrion Zinthos...Azarath
                Metrion Zinthos...</sp>

            <sd>During the previous line, the <directNote kind="pull">camera pulls back in steps to show her floating</directNote> a foot
                or so above the surface of a small asteroid. She is meditating.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Starfire">Starfire</spkr><sd>voice over, distant</sd><char>Raven</char> </sp>

            <sd>The background starts to crack and peel away;<stageDesc category="close-up"> close-up of Raven</stageDesc>, now considerably
                annoyed, as it keeps breaking up to reveal the operations center. The previous
                backdrop reflected <char>Raven's</char>  state of mind.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Starfire">Starfire</spkr><sd>voice over, closer</sd><char>Raven</char> </sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="pull">Pull back slightly to frame her</directNote> at the opening door;<char>Raven</char>has her back to it.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Starfire">Starfire</spkr>Please forgive my interruption, but have you
                seen <char>Robin</char> </sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Raven">Raven</spkr>No.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Starfire">Starfire</spkr>Oh.<sd>She turns to leave, but
                stops.</sd>Perhaps you have seen <char>Cyborg</char> </sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Raven">Raven</spkr>No.</sp>

            <sd><char>Starfire</char> turns again, but stops.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Starfire">Starfire</spkr><char>Beast Boy</char> </sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Raven">Raven</spkr>My eyes are closed, <char>Starfire</char>  I haven't seen
                anyone.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Starfire">Starfire</spkr>They must be doing the hanging out
                    someplace.<sd>She turns again; <stageDesc category="close-up">close-up as she stops</stageDesc>.</sd>Perhaps we should do
                the hanging out. We never have before, and conceivably it could be fun. We might
                journey to the mall of shopping, or perform braiding maneuvers upon each other's
                hair, or...</sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="pull">Pull back on this last word</directNote> to put<char>Raven</char>in frame. If she was annoyed before, she is
                now absolutely ready to explode: <directNote kind="gag">eyes bugging out, black flames outlining her head,
                and face set in a fierce grimace</directNote>.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Starfire">Starfire</spkr>You wish to be alone?</sp>

            <sd>She backs off.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Raven">Raven</spkr><sd>voice still composed</sd>How could you tell?</sp>

            <sd>She calms down again. <directNote kind="pull">Pull back across the operations center</directNote>; the background slides
                away in sections, one toward each edge of the screen, to put her back in outer
                space.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Raven">Raven</spkr><sd>chanting</sd>Azarath Metrion Zinth--</sp>

            <sd>The scene cracks open and falls apart, leaving a white field and <char>Cyborg's</char>  head
                behind her.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>MAIL CALL!!</sp>

            <sd>She lets out a long, shocked yell as the operations center reestablishes itself.
                Hitting the floor with a thud, she winds up in a heap before the three boys, who
                have just come in. <char>Cyborg</char> is carrying a crate.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Starfire">Starfire</spkr><sd>flyies to them</sd><char>Robin</char>  <char>Cyborg</char>  Beast
                Boy! You are back! It was...quiet while you were gone.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Raven">Raven</spkr><sd>stands up and dusts herself off</sd>Not that
                quiet.</sp>

            <sd>The crate is set down on the kitchen table; it bears a label reading "To: Teen
                Titans-Titan Tower."</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr><sd>as they all gather around</sd>Check it
                out. This was sitting by the front door. Fan mail, probably a gift from one of my
                many admirers.</sp>

            <sd><char>Raven</char> rolls her eyes. <stageDesc category="close-up">Close-up of Robin</stageDesc>, bent over for a closer look at the
                crate.</sd>

            <cue>Animation Error: Now "Titans Tower" has the S in the proper place.</cue>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Robin">Robin</spkr>Actually, it doesn't say who it's from.</sp>

            <sd><char>Cyborg</char> reaches into view and grabs the lid.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr><sd>from o.c.</sd>Well, one way to find out.</sp>

            <sd>He yanks it up; <directNote kind="cut">cut to inside as <char>Cyborg</char>  <char>Robin</char>  and<char>Starfire</char>peek in</directNote>.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>Whoa!</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Robin">Robin</spkr>Cool!</sp>

            <sd><char>Starfire</char> giggles; <char>Beast Boy</char> looks in.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>Honestly, I was kinda hoping for
                chocolate.</sp>

            <sd><char>Cyborg</char> reaches toward the camera; <directNote kind="cut">cut to him.</directNote> He brings up the puppet copy of
                himself seen in the prologue.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>Aww, isn't that cute? Puppet Cy has a light-up
                eye.</sp>

            <sd>It does indeed. <char>Beast Boy</char> and <char>Robin</char> have found their duplicates.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Robin">Robin</spkr><sd>pulling his puppet's belt buckle</sd>Yeah. They
                got all the details just right.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>Speak for yourself. I'm way better looking
                than this, and taller.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Raven">Raven</spkr><sd>looks at hers</sd>Someone certainly has a lot of
                time on their hands.</sp>

            <sd>On the end of this line, she pulls back the puppet's hood and finds that her
                hairline has also been recreated.<char>Starfire</char>giggles as she looks hers over and works
                it around a bit.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Starfire">Starfire</spkr>I have never seen such a whimsical device.</sp>

            <sd><stageDesc category="close-up">Close-up of it</stageDesc>; she makes it bow and speaks for it.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Starfire">Starfire</spkr><sd>from o.c., deep tone</sd>Hello,
                    <char>Starfire</char> <sd>leaning into view to shake, normal voice</sd>Hello, tiny wooden
                replica of <char>Starfire</char> </sp>

            <sd>Beast Boy's puppet jumps over behind <char>Robin's</char> .</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr><sd>from o.c.</sd>Dude!<sd>It delivers a kick
                    to the rear; <directNote kind="cut">cut to the two boys</directNote>.</sd>My puppet is totally kicking your puppet's
                butt!</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Robin">Robin</spkr>Not for long.</sp>

            <sd>Shifting his voice into kung fu mode, he makes his marionette strike Beast Boy's
                with a chop that sends it crashing into the wooden <char>Cyborg</char> </sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr><sd>from o.c.; puppet shakes its fist</sd>You want
                a piece of me, little man?</sp>

            <sd>The <char>Beast Boy</char> and <char>Robin</char> puppets keep taking swipes at each other as their operators
                provide good-natured fighting banter. <char>Cyborg</char> soon gets into the act as well; his
                replica swings into view to join the Three Stooges-style fracas. After a few
                seconds, <directNote kind="pull">pull back to frame the three Titans and Raven</directNote>, who watches with obvious
                contempt.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Raven">Raven</spkr>Boys.</sp>

            <sd><char>Starfire</char> comes to her, working her own puppet.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Starfire">Starfire</spkr>Shall my tiny replica do battle with your tiny
                replica?</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Raven">Raven</spkr>Knock yourself out.</sp>

            <sd>She tosses hers to<char>Starfire</char>and walks away, leaving only the camera on the receiving
                end of the latter's puzzled stare. Fade to black.</sd>

            <sd><directNote kind="fade">Fade in to the exterior of the Tower that night</directNote>. <directNote kind="cut">Cut to a series of overhead views</directNote>
                of the following: the entrance hall, the operations center, a corner of the hall,
                the storage area, the kitchen tables, complete with the open crate that contained
                the presents. Not a soul is seen in any of these shots. After a few moments of the
                last area, a hand shoots into view, accompanied by a few wisps of straw and the
                sound of splintering wood. The camera shifts to show the hand reaching up from the
                crate, with the previous views and others shown on the operations center monitors,
                cameras for after, hours surveillance. Next, the other hand emerges, and both brace
                against the crate's edge as a shadowed figure hoists itself out. The crown on the
                overlarge head gives it away as the <char>Puppet King</char>  All the monitors fill with static,
                and the screen snaps to black.</sd>

            <sd>Snap to an <stageDesc category="overhead-shot">overhead view</stageDesc> of<char>Starfire</char>asleep in her room. Her bed is circular, with
                pink sheets and blankets, and she is sleeping the wrong way around on top of the
                bedclothes, feet on the pillow, head hanging off the opposite edge. Her puppet lies
                nearby on a round stool. Initially, the camera frames her head near the top of the
                screen, but it soon rotates 180 degrees to bring her feet into that position.</sd>

            <sd><directNote kind="pull">Pull back across the room</directNote>; the door slides open. In a <stageDesc category="close-up">close-up of the sleeping girl</stageDesc>,
                we see the Puppet King's outline pop up just behind her, then duck away and come up
                at a different spot. He drops out of sight in a flash; she awakens and sits up a
                moment later as the door closes.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Starfire">Starfire</spkr><sd>gasping in fright</sd>Who is there?</sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="cut">Cut to a computer screen</directNote> flashing the words "Game Over" and showing a dead monkey
                that clutches a flower to its chest. Ghosts rise from the body. The camera moves
                past this and <directNote kind="zoom">zooms in on a set of bunk beds</directNote>, the bottom one of which is festooned
                with unmade sheets and dirty clothes. A sleeping silhouette can be seen on the top
                bunk; the voice gives it away as <char>Beast Boy</char> and this place as his room.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr><sd>talks in his
                sleep</sd>Ladies...please...</sp>

            <sd><stageDesc category="close-up">Close-up of the bunks</stageDesc>, <directNote kind="tilt">tilting up to the top</directNote>. He is cradling a sock; his figurine
                hangs from the headboard.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>...one at a time. You'll all get to take your
                picture with me.</sp>

            <sd>He makes as if to kiss the unwashed footwear as the <directNote kind="pull">camera pulls back</directNote>. The Puppet
                King has climbed up to the bunk, and he holds out a wooden crosspiece such as the
                ones attached to all the puppets. This one has no strings, but a green spot begins
                to glow on one of the six arms and <char>Beast Boy</char> is briefly surrounded with light of the
                same color. He shudders in his sleep, then relaxes, and a ghostly copy of the teen
                emerges from his body and enters the puppet.</sd>

            <sd><directNote kind="cut">Cut to the hall</directNote>. <char>Starfire's</char>  door opens; she steps out, missing the Puppet King's
                shadow as it passes at the far end.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Starfire">Starfire</spkr><sd>softly</sd>Hello? Hello?</sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="cut">Cut to <char>Cyborg's</char>  feet</directNote>; he is lying on the inclined table seen in his room during
                "Divide and Conquer." <directNote kind="pan">Pan to show the rest of his sleeping form</directNote>. One big hand grips
                his plaything to his chest. The intruder's hand pops up near the camera, holding
                that crosspiece; a blue-white spot now appears on one of the arms, and the big man
                is enveloped in that color light. He jerks awake with a sharp gasp, but his head
                soon rolls to one side as a specter of himself passes from his body to the puppet.
                The little red eye lights up,</sd>

            <sd><directNote kind="cut">Cut to the stairs</directNote>. The door opens and<char>Starfire</char>looks out, just as those short legs
                clamber up the stairs. She returns to normal volume.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Starfire">Starfire</spkr>Is someone there?</sp>

            <sd>In <char>Robin's</char>  room, his supine form is already swathed in red light. He drops o.c. as
                his ethereal form escapes its physical shell and passes to the puppet sitting atop
                some nearby bookshelves. The hall again;<char>Starfire</char>looks along it, her back to the
                camera, as a creepy chuckle echoes in the darkness; the same voice from the
                prologue. It gets louder; she turns to face us.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Starfire">Starfire</spkr>Huh?<sd>She approaches.</sd>If this is a joke,
                it is not--</sp>

            <sd>She cuts it off at the sound of an o.c. door being opened, and she turns toward it.
                <directNote kind="cut">Cut to just behind her</directNote>; it is <char>Raven's</char>  door, and she is looking out at <char>Starfire</char>  Both
                scream in sheer terror and surprise, their hair standing on end briefly. The short
                violet strands form the shape of the bird for which their wearer was named, with the
                sides forming wings and the widow's peak in front creating the head.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Starfire">Starfire</spkr><char>Raven</char>  You have also heard the strange
                noises?</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Raven">Raven</spkr>The strange noises of you talking outside my door?
                Hard to miss.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Starfire">Starfire</spkr>Oh.<sd>blushes</sd>Forgive me, I thought there
                was someone--</sp>

            <sd>This time, the thing that cuts her off is a blast from the o.c. <char>Cyborg's</char>  sonic
                cannon that just misses both of them. Turning toward its source, they find the other
                three Titans charging down the hall. <char>Robin</char> leaps for a kick as <transform class="reptile">Beast Boy turns into
                a dinosaur</transform> and charges ahead. The former nearly takes <char>Starfire's</char>  head off with the
                sole of his boot; the latter tries to get at <char>Raven</char>  but she creates energy barriers
                to slow him down a bit. The eyes of both aggressors are glowing.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Raven">Raven</spkr><char>Beast Boy</char>  it's me! Don't make me hurt you!</sp>

            <sd>He breaks through the shield she has put up and snaps at her. As<char>Starfire</char>flies over
                <char>Robin's</char>  head, he gets three discs ready in one hand and hurls them. She shoots them
                down with starbolts; the first two fizzle out, but the third explodes with great
                force when shot and she is thrown downward. <char>Cyborg</char> catches her, and we see that his
                eyes are glowing like those of the other two boys.</sd>

            <sd>Beast Boy has continued his advance against <char>Raven</char>  A swing of the tail knocks her
                down the hall, where <char>Cyborg</char> catches her as well and pins one girl under each
                arm.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Raven">Raven</spkr>Let me go!</sp>

            <sd><char>Robin</char> and <char>Beast Boy</char> approach; <transform class="human">the latter returns to human form</transform>.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Starfire">Starfire</spkr>Friends! Why do you attack us?</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#PuppetKing">Puppet King</spkr><sd>from o.c.</sd>Oh. They're not your
                friends anymore.</sp>

            <sd>He steps up, revealing himself in full detail for the first time. The head is quite
                large, with slick black hair parted in the middle and a hinged mouth just like the
                three boys' marionettes. He is a wooden figure brought to life.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#PuppetKing">Puppet King</spkr>They are my puppets.<sd>pulls out the
                    figures from behind his back</sd>These are your friends.</sp>

            <sd>He has trapped their souls within his wooden creations and taken control of the
                bodies. Now the puppets speak with the respective Titans' voices, sounding a bit
                muffled and very strained.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Robin">Robin (in Robin puppet's body)</spkr>Starfire!</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cyborg">Cyborg (in Cyborg puppet's body)</spkr><char>Raven</char> </sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#BeastBoy">Beast Boy (in Beast Boy puppet's body)</spkr>Help!</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Raven">Raven</spkr>Release them!</sp>

            <sd><char>Starfire</char> gasps.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#PuppetKing">Puppet King</spkr><sd>swings the puppets behind his
                    back</sd>Sorry, but you're not in charge here. You don't command me.<sd>He holds
                    up his crosspiece, which now shows lights on five of its arms, red for <char>Robin</char> 
                    orange for <char>Starfire</char>  blue for <char>Raven</char> </sd>I command you.</sp>

            <sd>Beast Boy and <char>Robin</char> raise the<char>Raven</char>and<char>Starfire</char>marionettes, respectively, and each
                girl groans as she is wreathed in her own color light, the beginning of the same
                process that took the souls of the boys.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#PuppetKing">Puppet King</spkr>And with the <char>Puppet King</char> pulling the
                strings, the Teen Titans will command the entire city.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Raven">Raven</spkr><sd>as her soul and <char>Starfire's</char> 
                escape</sd>Azarath...Metrion...Zinthos.</sp>

            <sd>Both pass out as a black starburst emerges from her forehead and flares over the
                entire hall, knocking everyone silly. The crosspiece spins away from its master's
                hand and skids along the floor.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#PuppetKing">Puppet King</spkr>My control!</sp>

            <sd>Beams shoot from the ends corresponding to the two girls, and their souls float free
                of the wooden receptacles and flash into the bodies of the prone girls, <char>Starfire's</char> 
                to<char>Raven</char>and vice versa. By the time the <char>Puppet King</char> has his control device back in
                hand, they have made it upright and sprinted off down the hall.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#PuppetKing">Puppet King</spkr>After them.</sp>

            <sd>The boys half-stand, half-float up to their feet, ready to pursue. <directNote kind="cut">Cut to a darkened
                section of the basement</directNote>; a grate in the ceiling swings open, and the two girls jump
                down through it. Only their eyes are visible as it swings shut over their heads and
                the chasers' feet are seen passing.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Starfire">Starfire</spkr><sd>softly</sd>The boys! <char>Raven</char>  What are we
                going to--?</sp>

            <sd><char>Raven</char> reaches over and switches on a hanging light bulb, and the two girls get a
                good eyeful of each other in their new situation. Each one's face shows the kind of
                expression she might have if she were still in her own body, and they give each
                other a long and very bewildered look. Both are at normal speaking volume now.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Raven">Raven (in Starfire's body)</spkr>Starfire?</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Starfire">Starfire (in Raven's body)</spkr><char>Raven</char> <sd>She gasps.</sd>You
                are me!<sd>Again, gasps louder and looks at herself.</sd>And I am you!</sp>

            <sd>Black energy crackles from her forehead and shatters the light bulb, putting them
                into near-total darkness again. <directNote kind="fade">Fade to black</directNote>.</sd>

        </act>
        <act n="2">
            <title>Act Two</title>
            <sd><stageDesc category="open-shot">Opening shot: an overhead pan along a street in Jump City</stageDesc>. It is now early the next
                morning. <char>Beast Boy</char>  as a falcon, pulls into view with a cry and moves ahead of the
                camera, searching for the two runaways. Ground level: his shadow passes over a
                manhole, and the entire street shakes briefly as its cover blows sky-high thanks to
                some out-of-control telekinesis. The steel circle slams back to the pavement,
                rattling loudly as it settles until <char>Starfire's</char>  hand reaches up and pushes it aside.
                She climbs out.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Starfire">Starfire (in Raven's body)</spkr>Oh, <char>Raven</char>  This is
                    awful!<sd><char>Raven</char> emerges.</sd>Terribly, horribly awful!</sp>

            <sd><char>Raven</char> heads down the sidewalk, pulling<char>Starfire</char>along behind her.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Raven">Raven (in Starfire's body)</spkr>Tell me about it.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Starfire">Starfire (in Raven's body)</spkr>Very well.<sd>gradually
                    panicking</sd><char>Robin</char>  <char>Cyborg</char>  and <char>Beast Boy</char> have been trapped inside tiny wooden
                bodies, while a nasty creature called the <char>Puppet King</char> has taken control of their
                real bodies, which he is using to hunt us down, and you and I are in the wrong
                bodies and--</sp>

            <sd>Throughout all of this, the powers of the body she has borrowed manifest themselves
                in the following three ways. A couple of parking meters bend themselves double,
                newspaper boxes spew their contents in all directions, and a mailbox melts down. The
                only thing that stops her flow of words is <char>Raven's</char>  hand on her shoulder, startling a
                gasp out of her.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Raven">Raven (in Starfire's body)</spkr>Starfire! You have to calm down.
                My powers are driven by emotion. The more you feel, the more energy you
                unleash.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Starfire">Starfire (in Raven's body)</spkr>But what if they find us?
                What if our friends are doomed?<sd>as a big sweat drop rolls down <char>Raven's</char> 
                head</sd>What if I am stuck looking like this forever?</sp>

            <sd>Her head spins on her neck several times, think The Exorcist.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Raven">Raven (in Starfire's body)</spkr>We'll fix it. I don't know how,
                but we will rescue the boys and we will get our bodies back.<sd>Pause.</sd>What's
                wrong with the way I look?</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Starfire">Starfire (in Raven's body)</spkr><sd>hastily</sd>Nothing.</sp>

            <sd>A pedestrian crossing signal above their heads explodes, she is still very much on
                edge.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Starfire">Starfire (in Raven's body)</spkr>I will try to calm
                    down.<sd>She exhales and closes her eyes.</sd>Peace...quiet...tranquil--</sp>

            <sd>A car parked next to them is launched straight up and crashes back to the ground,
                upside down, nearly two seconds later. Its alarm goes off.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Raven">Raven (in Starfire's body)</spkr>We are so doomed.</sp>

            <sd>A cry from <char>Beast Boy</char>  overhead o.c.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Starfire">Starfire (in Raven's body)</spkr><sd>points</sd><char>Beast
                Boy!</char></sp>

            <sd>From the ground view of the sky, tilting up from the pair. He is above the rooftops,
                illuminated by the full moon, but soon goes into a sharp descent with talons
                extended. Back to the girls, <directNote kind="zoom">zooming in</directNote>, on the start of the next line.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Raven">Raven (in Starfire's body)</spkr>You mean zombie Beast
                    Boy.<sd>pulls<char>Starfire</char>toward alley</sd>Run!</sp>

            <sd>As they follow the alley's turns,<char>Raven</char>starts jumping and flapping her arms, trying
                to get clear of the ground.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Raven">Raven (in Starfire's body)</spkr>Fly! Fly!</sp>

            <sd>After another turn or two, they slow to a walk.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Starfire">Starfire (in Raven's body)</spkr>We cannot fight them again. I
                do not wish to, and in our present condition, we would surely be defeated.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Raven">Raven (in Starfire's body)</spkr>Okay. How do you fly this
                thing?</sp>

            <sd>She gestures at herself.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Starfire">Starfire (in Raven's body)</spkr>You must feel flight.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Raven">Raven (in Starfire's body)</spkr>What?</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Starfire">Starfire (in Raven's body)</spkr>When you feel the unbridled
                joy of flight, you will fly.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Raven">Raven (in Starfire's body)</spkr>Unbridled joy? Not really my
                thing.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Starfire">Starfire (in Raven's body)</spkr><sd>points
                o.c.</sd>Look!</sp>

            <sd>The hand movement creates a black spark that throws<char>Raven</char>off her feet. Camera
                shift: now we see <char>Beast Boy</char> <transform class="mammal">as a tiger</transform>, rushing toward them.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Raven">Raven (in Starfire's body)</spkr>What do I have to feel to use
                starbolts?</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Starfire">Starfire (in Raven's body)</spkr>Righteous fury.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Raven">Raven (in Starfire's body)</spkr>Your alien strength?</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Starfire">Starfire (in Raven's body)</spkr>Boundless confidence.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Raven">Raven (in Starfire's body)</spkr>Never mind.</sp>

            <sd>She runs back the way they came and yanks<char>Starfire</char>along. As <char>Beast Boy</char> pursues, they
                take a different turn and wind up in a darker stretch of the alley. Something black
                swishes by in front, bringing them up short with a gasp; it straightens up to expose
                <char>Robin's</char>  silhouette. They back up a few steps only to find the green jungle cat
                blocking the retreat. He moves in a little closer and roars, and now <char>Robin</char> brings
                out his fighting staff and runs at them. <char>Beast Boy</char> pounces as well. The girls stand
                pat and sidestep at the last moment; the two hypnotized Titans collide in midair,
                and the staff socks <char>Beast Boy</char> in the head and goes flying along the alley.<char>Raven</char>and
               <char>Starfire</char>make tracks while the attackers lie dazed, <char>Robin</char> pinned under <char>Beast Boy</char> 
                The staff clunks down on the latter's head; both are soon on their feet to continue
                the chase.</sd>

            <sd>Yet another side passage in the alley.<char>Starfire</char>passes it, but<char>Raven</char>ducks in and
                reaches out to haul her opposite number back. They flatten themselves against the
                wall to stay out of sight of <char>Robin</char> and <char>Beast Boy</char>  who pass the corner without a
                second thought. A momentary relieved smile from<char>Raven</char>is cut off when two very large
                and familiar bionic hands smash through the bricks behind them.<char>Raven</char>screams in
                terror and is propelled upward at terrific speed by an inadvertent burst of
                telekinesis from <char>Starfire</char>  who runs off as <char>Cyborg</char> knocks the wall down.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Starfire">Starfire (in Raven's body)</spkr>Wait for me, please!</sp>

            <sd><char>Cyborg</char> drools a little bit as he looks after them. Now they round a corner and stop,
                but soon they are forced to back up when he steps in after them. He is visible only
                as a silhouette, and <char>Robin</char> and <char>Beast Boy</char> <transform class="human">in human form</transform>, join him. They close in;
                the girls back up to a dead-end wall.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Raven">Raven (in Starfire's body)</spkr>If I can't fly, you have to
                levitate. You know those words I always--?</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Starfire">Starfire (in Raven's body)</spkr>Yes!</sp>

            <sd>She sucks in a huge breath and holds it.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Raven">Raven (in Starfire's body)</spkr>Wait! You have to focus!</sp>

            <sd><char>Starfire</char> exhales</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Starfire">Starfire (in Raven's body)</spkr><sd>hastily</sd>Azarath
                Metrion Zinthos!</sp>

            <sd>She goes up like a rocket, dragging<char>Raven</char>by the hand, and both scream as they gain
                too much altitude. The three puppet Titans stare up after them; the two stop in
                midair before barreling over the trio's heads. Operating on the ragged edge of
                control,<char>Starfire</char>tows<char>Raven</char>up to roof level and beyond to soar over Jump
                City.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Starfire">Starfire (in Raven's body)</spkr>I wish to stop! Please tell
                me the way to stop!</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Raven">Raven (in Starfire's body)</spkr>Look at the ground and
                imagine--</sp>

            <sd><char>Starfire</char> turns her gaze downward; cut to her perspective of the passing city
                blocks.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Raven">Raven (in Starfire's body)</spkr><sd>from o.c.</sd>Wait!</sp>

            <sd>Back to them. The severely inexperienced pilot drops like a rock,<char>Raven</char>goes with
                her, and they slam down in a huge pile of trash between two buildings. After a
                moment, they poke their heads up;<char>Raven</char>shovels waste feverishly toward the
                street.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Starfire">Starfire (in Raven's body)</spkr>Ugh! I smell like the breath
                of a Snervian blork worm. <char>Raven</char>  what are you--?</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Raven">Raven (in Starfire's body)</spkr><sd>puts her index finger to
                    <char>Starfire's</char>  mouth</sd>Shhh!</sp>

            <sd>Leaning back to hide herself behind the berm she has made, she throws a trash bag at
               <char>Starfire</char>and lands it on her head to drive her down and out of sight. <char>Robin</char> and
                <char>Cyborg</char> walk into view from opposite directions and stop near the garbage to look
                around a bit. Not seeing anything worth attention, they continue on their respective
                patrols. <directNote kind="cut">Cut to behind the trash pile as they leave</directNote>, then <directNote kind="tilt">tilt down to the two girls</directNote>
                huddled behind it. A little aura of energy appears briefly around one of <char>Starfire's</char> 
                hands;<char>Raven</char>gives her a hard look as she moans sadly at having lost control again.
                The next two lines are delivered in hushed tones.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Starfire">Starfire (in Raven's body)</spkr>Peace, quiet,
                tranquility...peace, quiet, tranquility.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Raven">Raven (in Starfire's body)</spkr>It's all right. They're
                going.</sp>

            <sd>Their perspective, peering out at the departing pair through an opening in the wall
                of junk. <transform class="mammal">A large green rat</transform>, <char>Beast Boy</char>  pops into view; back to <char>Starfire</char>  who gasps
                in fright and is silenced by <char>Raven's</char>  hand on her mouth. The rodent sniffs the air a
                bit and climbs up the bags behind them as they remain stock-still. <stageDesc category="close-up">Extreme close-up
                of <char>Starfire's</char>  temple</stageDesc>; a drop of sweat forms and slides down to the hand over her
                mouth. <char>Raven's</char>  face is framed from nose to chin, with sweat sliding down her cheek
                as well and her lower lip caught nervously between her teeth. Back to <char>Beast Boy</char>  who
                is still sniffing about. The next words bring him to a stop.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#PuppetKing">Puppet King</spkr><sd>from o.c.</sd>Enough!</sp>

            <sd>The Titan scuttles away; pan to the two fugitives, who are still making no sound,
                then cut to <char>Robin</char> and <char>Cyborg</char>  <char>Beast Boy</char> rejoins them and takes human form; they turn
                toward the voice.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#PuppetKing">Puppet King</spkr><sd>from o.c.</sd>We will catch the other
                two after the ceremony is complete.</sp>

            <sd>On the end of this line, cut to a patch of brickwork on the building's upper stories
                and tilt down to ground level. He stands there, near the fetid castoffs, with the
                three boys' puppets still in hand, and he steps forward and holds them up.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Robin">Robin (in Robin puppet's body)</spkr>Ceremony?</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cyborg">Cyborg (in Cyborg puppet's body)</spkr>What ceremony?</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#PuppetKing">Puppet King</spkr>Just a little spell that will destroy you
                    three,<sd><directNote kind="cut">Cut to the hypnotized trio</directNote>; he continues o.c.</sd>and make your bodies
                mine forever.<sd><stageDesc category="close-up">Extreme close-up of him</stageDesc>.</sd>Come, my puppets.</sp>

            <sd>He walks away and they follow. After all have gone, <directNote kind="cut">cut to an alley behind the dump
                heap</directNote>. A few trash bags are flung away; the two girls step out, and<char>Raven</char>tries to
                get her auburn hair untangled.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Raven">Raven (in Starfire's body)</spkr>How can you stand having this
                much hair?</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Starfire">Starfire (in Raven's body)</spkr>Quickly, <char>Raven</char>  Our friends
                are in danger! We must follow and-</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Raven">Raven (in Starfire's body)</spkr><sd>pulling her back</sd>And
                what? Save them with my unusable powers while your unbridled emotions blow us to
                bits? Nice flying, by the way.</sp>

            <sd>A black aura surrounds <char>Starfire</char> </sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Starfire">Starfire (in Raven's body)</spkr><sd>angrily</sd>At least I am
                able to fly.<sd><char>Raven</char> digs in her ear.</sd>On my planet, even a newborn can unleash
                the joy of flight. But you are too busy being grumpy and rude to feel anything at
                all!</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Raven">Raven (in Starfire's body)</spkr>Maybe you haven't noticed, but
                my emotions are dangerous. I can't afford to feel anything.<sd>She turns her
                    back.</sd>You may have my body, but you know nothing about me.</sp>

            <sd>The aura dissipates.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Starfire">Starfire (in Raven's body)</spkr>Perhaps you are
                    right.<sd><char>Raven</char> turns to her.</sd>And if you and I are to overcome this ordeal,
                we must know everything about each other. So...begin sharing.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Raven">Raven (in Starfire's body)</spkr><sd>smiling</sd>All right.</sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="cut">Cut to a shot of them on the ground</directNote>, facing each other,<char>Starfire</char>cross-legged, Raven
                kneeling, and pull back slowly.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Raven">Raven (in Starfire's body)</spkr>I was born in a place called
                Azarath.</sp>

            <sd>Fade to black.</sd>

        </act>
        <act n="3">
            <title>Act Three</title>
            <sd><stageDesc category="open-shot">Opening shot: an overhead view of a run-down area in Jump City</stageDesc>. <directNote kind="pan">Pan to a decrepit
                old theater</directNote>, the Bijou, with a courtyard in front of it. There is a large stone
                fountain, behind which<char>Raven</char>and<char>Starfire</char>have hunkered down to keep an eye on the
                front entrance. <char>Beast Boy</char> <transform class="mammal">as a Doberman pinscher</transform>, paces at the bottom of the steps
                that lead up to it. Both girls keep their voices down on the next two lines.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Raven">Raven (in Starfire's body)</spkr>Safe to say we're not walking in
                through the front door. We'll have to try the roof.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Starfire">Starfire (in Raven's body)</spkr><sd>takes her
                hand</sd>Agreed. Now, do just as I instructed. Close your eyes and think of
                something joyful.</sp>

            <sd><char>Raven</char> rolls her eyes and sighs wearily.<char>Starfire</char>returns to normal volume.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Starfire">Starfire (in Raven's body)</spkr>You might choose flowers, or
                kittens, or the laughter of children, or--</sp>

            <sd>She gasps as she is hauled up by <char>Raven</char>  who has floated clear of the ground. Slowly
                but surely, they ascend to the roof and are not seen by <char>Beast Boy</char>  he perks up his
                ears and turns to look in their direction, but they are already out of sight. The
                girls touch down next to a locked trapdoor.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Starfire">Starfire (in Raven's body)</spkr>Very, very good! What was
                your joyful thought?</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Raven">Raven (in Starfire's body)</spkr>You don't want to know.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Starfire">Starfire (in Raven's body)</spkr>Oh, but I do. Please tell me.
                What did you imagine?</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Raven">Raven (in Starfire's body)</spkr>You not talking.</sp>

            <sd><char>Starfire's</char>  eyes pop.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Starfire">Starfire (in Raven's body)</spkr>Oh. Well...I am glad I was
                able to help.</sp>

            <sd><char>Raven</char> looks at her, then down at the lock, then at<char>Starfire</char>again.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Raven">Raven (in Starfire's body)</spkr>Your turn. Find your center.
                Focus your energy on the lock.</sp>

            <sd><char>Starfire</char> closes her eyes for a moment. When she opens them again, they are glowing
                white as when<char>Raven</char>uses her own powers; she raises her hands.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Starfire">Starfire</spkr>Azarath...Metrion...<sd>The lock floats up as
                    far as it can.</sd>...Zinthos.</sp>

            <sd>On the last word, she brings her hands down and the lock snaps. She giggles.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Raven">Raven (in Starfire's body)</spkr><sd>impressed</sd>Nice
                work.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Starfire">Starfire (in Raven's body)</spkr><sd>jumps
                up</sd>Success!</sp>

            <sd>The outburst causes her abilities to flare up; the trapdoor flies open and sends
                echoes throughout the theater.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Raven">Raven (in Starfire's body)</spkr><sd>sarcastically</sd>Nice
                work.</sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="cut">Cut to the catwalks in the auditorium</directNote> and <directNote kind="tilt">tilt down to the stage</directNote>. The Puppet King
                stands before a large bowl filled with blue-white flames. Candles have been set up
                and a scenery flat is to one side; the boys' puppets are hanging over the top edge
                of the latter. He has his wooden crosspiece in one hand and a test tube in the
                other. The echo of the trapdoor draws his attention, and he gestures with the
                controller toward the flat.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#PuppetKing">Puppet King</spkr>Search and destroy.</sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="cut">Cut to the flat</directNote>. The silhouettes of <char>Robin</char> and <char>Cyborg</char> stand beside it.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#PuppetKing">Puppet King</spkr><sd>from o.c.</sd>I do not want an
                    audience.<sd>They move off; back to him.</sd>Well, Titans...<sd>uncorks tube,
                    pours contents into a bowl</sd>...time for your grand finale.</sp>

            <sd>The flames blaze up. <directNote kind="cut">Cut to just below one of the catwalks</directNote> as sparks float toward
                it; <directNote kind="tilt">tilt up to show<char>Raven</char>and<char>Starfire</char>watching from here</directNote>.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Raven">Raven (in Starfire's body)</spkr><sd>horrified</sd>No.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#PuppetKing">Puppet King</spkr><sd>holds up the three figures</sd>It's
                going to be a real showstopper.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Robin">Robin (in Robin puppet's body)</spkr>Stop!</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cyborg">Cyborg (in Cyborg puppet's body)</spkr>Don't!</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#BeastBoy">Beast Boy (in Beast Boy puppet's body)</spkr>Please!</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cyborg">Cyborg (in Cyborg puppet's body)</spkr>Hey!</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Robin">Robin (in Robin puppet's body)</spkr>No!</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cyborg">Cyborg (in Cyborg puppet's body)</spkr>Stop!</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#BeastBoy">Beast Boy (in Beast Boy puppet's body)</spkr>Help!</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#PuppetKing">Puppet King</spkr>Don't worry. I'll take good care of your
                bodies. After all, they'll be mine forever.</sp>

            <sd><stageDesc category="close-up">Close-up of his upraised hand</stageDesc>; he lets go of the strings, and the puppets drop
                toward the flaming oblivion he has prepared for them. Before they can land in the
                bowl, though, <char>Starfire's</char>  telekinesis catches them and lifts them away to the
                catwalk. She sweeps the three wooden figures into a crushing hug.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Starfire">Starfire (in Raven's body)</spkr>My friends! You are
                unharmed!</sp>

            <sd>laughs</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Robin">Robin (in Robin puppet's body)</spkr>Starfire?</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Raven">Raven (in Starfire's body)</spkr>It's a long story.</sp>

            <sd>The angered villain gestures with his crosspiece; in response, his three victims
                step toward him. <char>Beast Boy</char> has returned to human form.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#PuppetKing">Puppet King</spkr>Go, my puppets! Capture them!</sp>

            <sd>They move out; <transform class="mammal">Beast Boy transforms into a vampire bat</transform> to fly up while Robin
                clambers up the scaffolding.<char>Starfire</char>stands on the catwalk, still reveling in her
                rescue of the puppets, but is yanked away by <char>Raven</char> </sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Raven">Raven (in Starfire's body)</spkr>Move!</sp>

            <sd>They run along the planks, but scream as <char>Beast Boy</char> brings them up short. Robin
                vaults up and crouches behind them, and <char>Cyborg</char> leaps onto the railing with his
                cannon ready to fire. The blast sends both girls and the puppets flying every which
                way; the latter tumble onto the stage in a heap.</sd>

            <cue>Animation goof: In this sequence, <char>Cyborg's</char>  left arm has the cannon.</cue>

            <sp><spkr ref="#BeastBoy">Beast Boy (in Beast Boy puppet's body)</spkr>Dude, get your
                butt outta my face!</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Robin">Robin (in Robin puppet's body)</spkr>Can't move. Deal with
                it.</sp>

            <sd>The girls are doing a little short-range skydiving of their own.<char>Starfire</char>tries to
                grab a curtain cord to stop herself,<char>Raven</char>does her best to start flying, and
                neither one has any success. <transform class="human">Beast Boy is in human form again</transform>; he hops onto the
                railing and <transform class="mammal">turns into a gorilla</transform>, and he and <char>Robin</char> jump over the edge. Their two
                targets have finally managed to hit the brakes and are floating near another
                catwalk. They scatter an instant before <char>Robin</char> swings across the space on a rope.
               <char>Starfire</char>makes her way through the jumble of rigging, barely staying ahead of him,
                and both light on a walk to face off.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Starfire">Starfire (in Raven's body)</spkr><sd>dodges a kick</sd><char>Robin</char> 
                I do not wish to fight you.</sp>

            <sd>She avoids his next punch, but he turns the move into a grab for her cloak and gets
                it, throwing her toward the railing. He moves a few steps toward her, ready to
                finish the job. <stageDesc category="close-up">Close-up of his feet when he stops</stageDesc>; one of them is within a loop of
                rope that lies on the boards.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Starfire">Starfire (in Raven's body)</spkr>But I will if I must!</sp>

            <sd>She levitates a nearby sandbag and drops it over the side. The rope attached to it
                is the same one whose loop <char>Robin</char> is standing in, and he is quickly dragged up by
                that leg. Now<char>Raven</char>flies through the support framework, doing her best to stay
                ahead of <char>Cyborg</char> and <char>Beast Boy</char>  both of whom are swinging among the cables to get at
                her. The latter finally finds a grip and bears her down to the catwalk, but she
                kicks him away and quickly backs up to the wall as <char>Cyborg</char> rejoins the attack.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Raven">Raven (in Starfire's body)</spkr><sd>to herself</sd>Okay, <char>Raven</char> 
                Starbolts. Just let go of your emotions, feel the righteous fury, and...</sp>

            <sd>The attempt comes to a very sudden end when <char>Cyborg</char> aims a punch at her and knocks
                out a few dozen bricks. <char>Beast Boy</char> tries to seize her again as well; she dodges away,
                but he counters by slamming his clasped hands onto the catwalk to break it. Raven
                hurtles toward the stage, but manages to reverse course and deliver a walloping
                uppercut that dumps the shape-shifter, <transform class="human">now back in human form</transform>, at <char>Cyborg's</char> 
                feet.</sd>

            <sd>The big man jumps onto the railing, grabs a rope, and swings across at her. She has
                just enough time to get airborne before those enormous metal boots crash through
                both sides. Realizing that he is now below her, she angles herself for a diving kick
                and connects to drive the rope out of his hands. He plunges toward the stage and
                passes <char>Starfire</char>  who gasps in shock and gathers her energy.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Starfire">Starfire (in Raven's body)</spkr>Azarath Metrion Zinthos!</sp>

            <sd>As she says this, <directNote kind="cut">cut to the pile of puppets on the stage</directNote>; they are directly
                underneath the falling Titan and will be crushed to toothpicks upon impact. The
                spell catches him and pushes him out of the way. Back to <char>Starfire</char>  who smiles a bit
                as she moves her hand to direct his motion; she looks upward, screams suddenly, and
                dodges a falling sandbag. A snarling <char>Robin</char> has gotten loose of the trap she sprang
                on him and is diving with enough speed to peel his lips back from his teeth. An
                instant after he lands on the catwalk, <char>Cyborg</char>  still moving under her influence,
                sails across and plows him away.</sd>

            <sd><char>Raven</char> lands on a higher walk and smiles down at <char>Starfire</char>  but a loud growl from
                above draws a shocked gasp and sets her running. <char>Beast Boy</char> <transform class="mammal">in gorilla form</transform> again,
                leaps down to her level in a bid to crush her, he misses, but the tremor from his
                landing throws her off her feet. She gets up and holds one hand straight out in
                front of herself as he approaches.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Raven">Raven (in Starfire's body)</spkr>Righteous fury, righteous fury,
                concentrate...</sp>

            <sd>A green spark flickers from the extended hand the beginning of a starbolt, but his
                swipe at her ends the experiment. She lifts off only to have one of her ankles
                caught by <char>Beast Boy</char>  he hurls her back to the catwalk and lifts his clasped hands to
                smash her apart once and for all. Only a last-second roll to one side saves her
                life. Fetching up against the railing, she looks down at the sound of a scream from
                <char>Starfire</char>  The latter is still dodging <char>Robin's</char>  strikes.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Starfire">Starfire (in Raven's body)</spkr><char>Raven</char>  help!</sp>

            <sd><char>Cyborg</char> charges in to throw a punch, but<char>Raven</char>can do nothing to help, Beast Boy
                plants one of those huge mitts on her head and lifts her up by it. She shakes loose
                and drives the sole of her boot in his face before leaping back to perch on a
                scaffolding.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Raven">Raven (in Starfire's body)</spkr>Starfire!</sp>

            <sd><char>Starfire</char> looks up toward her, <char>Robin</char> goes up for a kick, and those violet soles push
                off from the framework.<char>Raven</char>goes into the fastest dive she can do and tackles the
                Boy Wonder in midair, driving him off the catwalk and catching the edge of his cape
                in one hand to leave him hanging.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Starfire">Starfire (in Raven's body)</spkr>Not me!<sd>points
                down</sd>Them!</sp>

            <sd><char>Raven</char> follows her gaze; her face registers the same shock that set off her
                counterpart's panic. Overhead view of the stage, zooming in on the flaming vessel.
                The <char>Puppet King</char> runs toward it, carrying the three boys' replicas; cut to him as he
                holds them over the fire.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#PuppetKing">Puppet King</spkr>The <char>Puppet King</char> is in command!</sp>

            <sd><char>Raven's</char>  free hand blazes green.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Raven">Raven (in Starfire's body)</spkr>NO!!</sp>

            <sd>She hurls a full-strength starbolt to the the product of the fury she has been
                trying to capture that explodes with the force of a small bomb upon impact. The
                puppets and their maker are flung across the stage; his crosspiece arcs high over
                the scene, bounces off a sandbag, and drops neatly toward the blue-white fire. It
                flares up brilliantly when the wood falls in.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#PuppetKing">Puppet King</spkr><sd>gasps</sd>My control!</sp>

            <sd>The blaze shapes itself into an approximate likeness of his face, and he starts to
                twitch and jitter in his prone position. Light pours from his eyes and mouth.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#PuppetKing">Puppet King</spkr>NOOOOOOO!!</sp>

            <sd>The influence lifts him to his feet, and the three puppets tremble as the souls
                trapped within them fly free and return to the boys' bodies. <directNote kind="cut">Cut to Starfire</directNote>, whose
                spirit pours out of the blue-cloaked body it has been inhabiting, then <directNote kind="pan">pan to Raven</directNote>,
                whose spirit does likewise as <char>Robin</char> rests in her arms. The two girls' life forces
                intertwine briefly before returning to their proper homes.</sd>

            <sd><directNote kind="cut">Cut to the three puppets on the stage</directNote>, now just lifeless pieces of wood, and <directNote kind="pan">pan
                across a bit as<char>Starfire</char>lands</directNote> and sets <char>Robin</char> down.<char>Raven</char>joins them.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Starfire">Starfire</spkr>I am me!<sd>to Raven</sd>And you are you!</sp>

            <sd><char>Cyborg</char> and <char>Beast Boy</char> emerge from the wings. <transform class="human">The latter is in human form again</transform>, and
                all three have completely recovered from the madman's influence.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>And we're us!</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Robin">Robin</spkr>Thanks to you two.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr><sd>briefly turning one arm into a
                    gorilla's</sd>You go, girls!</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Starfire">Starfire</spkr><sd>gasps happily</sd><char>Raven</char>  we have done
                it!</sp>

            <sd><char>Raven</char> finds herself swept up in a wildly enthusiastic hug that is nowhere close to
                her liking.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Raven">Raven</spkr>You're hugging me...</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#PuppetKing">Puppet King</spkr><sd>off-screen,
                agonized</sd>NOOOOOOO!!</sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="pull">Pull back to frame him</directNote>, sprawled out on the stage and trying to crawl forward. The
                light still pours from his eyes and mouth.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#PuppetKing">Puppet King</spkr>The magic! Without it, I'm just a...</sp>

            <sd>The luminosity fades away, and he collapses as a slack-jawed, googly-eyed figurine
                without being able to finish the sentence. <directNote kind="fade">Fade to black</directNote>.</sd>

            <sd><directNote kind="fade">Fade in to the operations center</directNote>. It is now later in the day, and<char>Raven</char>floats near
                the windows, meditating. Her back is to the camera.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Raven">Raven</spkr><sd>chants</sd>Azarath Metrion Zinthos...<sd><stageDesc category="close-up">close-up
                    of her</stageDesc></sd>Azarath Metrion Zinthos...</sp>

            <sd>On the next line, the <directNote kind="pan">camera pans</directNote>/<directNote kind="tilt">tilts slightly</directNote> to show<char>Starfire</char>standing behind
                her.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Starfire">Starfire</spkr><char>Raven</char>  forgive my interruption, but...</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Raven">Raven</spkr>I haven't seen <char>Robin</char>  <char>Cyborg</char>  or <char>Beast Boy</char> </sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Starfire">Starfire</spkr><sd>hesitatntly</sd>Truthfully, I am wishing to
                join you in meditation.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Raven">Raven</spkr>Really?<sd>turns around</sd>All right.</sp>

            <sd><char>Starfire</char> flies over and assumes <char>Raven's</char>  pose, floating at the same height above the
                ground.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Raven">Raven</spkr><sd>closing eyes, turning to windows</sd>Find your
                center. Focus your energies, and...</sp>

            <sd>She faces the windows; pull back to frame both.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Raven #Starfire">Raven and Starfire</spkr><sd>chant together</sd>Azarath
                Metrion Zinthos...Azarath Metrion...</sp>

            <sd>On the end of the second repetition, <stageDesc category="close-up">close-up of Raven</stageDesc>. She breaks off and opens one
                eye as<char>Starfire</char>completes the mantra.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Raven">Raven</spkr>Starfire?</sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="pan">Pan to her</directNote>; she opens one eye.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Starfire">Starfire</spkr>Yes?</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Raven">Raven</spkr><sd>hesitantly</sd>After this...would you like to go
                to the mall?</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Starfire">Starfire</spkr><sd>nods</sd>Mmm-hmm.</sp>

            <sd>Both close their eyes.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Raven #Starfire">Raven and Starfire</spkr><sd>chant together</sd>Azarath
                Metrion Zinthos...</sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="cut">Cut to the same shot that began this final sequence</directNote>, with both girls floating before
                the panoramic view of Jump City Bay.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Raven #Starfire">Raven and Starfire</spkr><sd><directNote kind="fade">fading out</directNote></sd>Azarath
                Metrion Zinthos...</sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="fade">Fade to black</directNote>.</sd>
        </act>
    </body>
</root>