<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../schema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?><root>
    <head>
        <episode>THE SUM OF HIS PARTS</episode>
        <writer>David Slack</writer>
        <director>Ciro Nieli</director>
        <storyboard>Kalvin Lee, Rafael Rosado, Alan Wan</storyboard>
        <animation>Dong Woo Animation Company, Ltd.</animation>
        <source>https://teentitans.fandom.com/wiki/The_Sum_of_His_Parts_(Transcript)</source>
        <issueList>
            <issueInfo none="y"/>
        </issueList>
    </head>
    <characterList>
        <charList type="nonrecurring" id="MalePicnicker">Male Picnicker</charList>
        <charList type="nonrecurring" id="FemalePicnicker">Female Picnicker</charList>
        <charList type="recurring" id="Cyborg" subtype="titan">Cyborg</charList>
        <charList type="recurring" id="Starfire" subtype="titan">Starfire</charList>
        <charList type="recurring" id="Robin" subtype="titan">Robin</charList>
        <charList type="recurring" id="BeastBoy" subtype="titan">Beast Boy</charList>
        <charList type="recurring" id="Raven" subtype="titan">Raven</charList>
        <charList type="nonrecurring" id="Boy1">Boy 1</charList>
        <charList type="recurring" id="Mumbo" subtype="villain">Mumbo</charList>
        <charList type="nonrecurring" id="Computer1">Computer 1</charList>
        <charList type="nonrecurring" id="Voice">Voice</charList>
        <charList type="nonrecurring" id="Fixit" subtype="both">Fixit</charList>
        <charList type="nonrecurring" id="Computer2">Computer 2</charList>
        <charList type="nonrecurring" id="Boy2">Boy 2</charList>
    </characterList>
    <body>
        <act n="0">
            <title>Prologue</title>
            <sd><stageDesc category="open-shot">Opening shot: a park filled with people enjoying a beautiful afternoon.</stageDesc> <directNote kind="pan">Pan across
                the area; there is Frisbee-throwing, kite-flying, a young man and woman picnicking,
                the whole deal.</directNote></sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#MalePicnicker">Male Picnicker</spkr><sd>holds out a soda</sd>Soda?</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#FemalePicnicker">Female Picnicker</spkr>Why, I'd love one.</sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="cut">Cut to <stageDesc category="close-up">a close-up of <char>Cyborg</char></stageDesc>.</directNote> He has bent over something just down o.c., but then
                straightens up.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr><sd>Feels the fresh air.</sd>Mmm-mmm. Would you
                look at that. A little sunshine, a little breeze. Only one thing could make this day
                better.</sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="pull">Pull back a bit as he bends down again.</directNote> The thing in front of him is a barbecue
                grill, and he opens the lid to expose…</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>Four and a half pounds of baby back ribs.</sp>

            <sd>He lifts the rack away on a platter. <directNote kind="cut">Cut to a picnic table, where <char>Robin</char> is digging
                into a burger and <char>Starfire</char> is heartily sucking something down through a straw.</directNote>
                Positioned just over her right shoulder, <directNote>the camera does not allow us to see her
                drink on the table</directNote>. <char>Cyborg</char> sits down.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>Man, I love picnic food!</sp>

            <sd>He buries his face in the ribs, chomping huge mouthfuls of pork, and <char>Robin</char> matches
                that effort with the burger. <directNote kind="cut">Cut to <char>Starfire</char></directNote>; now the top of her glass can be
                seen.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Starfire">Starfire</spkr>Agreed, <char>Cyborg</char>.<sd>flushes happily</sd>This
                tangy yellow beverage is truly delightful.</sp>

            <sd>She swigs some more of it. Back to the two boys, who stop scarfing down their food
                to stare in surprise.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>Uh, <char>Starfire</char>?</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Robin">Robin</spkr>That’s mustard.</sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="gag">Sight gag: she hugs the container; the mustard jar, with its screw cap removed,
                giant size as smaller ones float past in the background.</directNote></sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Starfire">Starfire</spkr>Is there more?</sp>

            <sd>The sight gag ends; <char>Robin</char> and <char>Cyborg</char> cannot tear their eyes away from the scene and
                their food sits forgotten in their hands. A shred of meat is clearly heard falling
                from <char>Cyborg</char>’s face in the stillness. <directNote kind="pull">Pull back from the table</directNote> and <directNote kind="pan">pan to the tree
                where the grill is set up</directNote>. <char>Beast Boy</char>, as <transform class="mammal">a lemur</transform>, climbs around in the branches and
                hangs down from the lowest one by his tail; by the time he gets within reach of the
                grill, he is back in <transform class="human">human form</transform>. He picks up two hot dogs.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>Sweet! My tofu dogs are cooked to perfection.
                    <sd><directNote kind="pull">Pull back</directNote>; <char>Raven</char> sits in the shade of a nearby tree.</sd>Yo, <char>Raven</char>. Try one.
                They’re loaded with soybeany goodness.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Raven">Raven</spkr>I respect that you don’t eat meat. Please respect
                that I don’t eat fake meat.</sp>

            <sd><charDesc ref="Beast Boy">The vegetarian Titan</charDesc> proceeds to wolf down both dogs at once. <char>Cyborg</char> runs past; <directNote kind="cut">cut
                to him on the open grass, football in hand</directNote>.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>All right, y’all. Who wants to play some
                fool-ball?</sp>

            <sd><char>Robin</char>, <char>Beast Boy</char>, and <char>Starfire</char> run over, clamoring to get into the game. They cut
                off abruptly and look in <char>Raven</char>’s direction; <directNote kind="cut">cut to her</directNote>. She has not moved an
                inch.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Raven">Raven</spkr>I’ll be referee.</sp>

            <sd><stageDesc category="close-up">Close-up of the ball on the grass as <char>Cyborg</char> puts his hand on it.</stageDesc> <directNote kind="pull">Pull back to show
                him ready to hike to <char>Robin</char>, and <char>Beast Boy</char> and <char>Starfire</char> set to block.</directNote></sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Robin">Robin</spkr>Red! Twenty-three! Hut! Hut! Hut!</sp>

            <sd><stageDesc category="close-up">Close-up of the ball again on the last “hut.”</stageDesc> <char>Cyborg</char> hikes it back and then runs
                past the defensive line, and <char>Beast Boy</char> stands in front of <char>Robin</char> while <char>Starfire</char> goes
                after <charDesc ref="Cyborg">the running Titan</charDesc>.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>One Gotham City…</sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="cut">Cut to Cyborg in the open.</directNote></sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr><sd>from o.c.</sd>…two Gotham City…three
                Gotham City...</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr><sd>over the previous line</sd><oneLine>You can run, you can
                fly, but you can’t catch <charDesc ref="Cyborg">Cy</charDesc>!</oneLine></sp>
            <sd>Starfire flies after him now.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr><sd>from o.c.</sd>…four Gotham City…
                    <sd><char>Starfire</char> speeds up; back to <char>Beast Boy</char>.</sd>…five Gotham City!</sp>

            <sd><stageDesc category="close-up">Close-up of <char>Robin</char>, backing up to throw a pass.</stageDesc> He yells in sudden fear as the ground
                shakes; <directNote kind="cut">cut to the source</directNote>; <char>Beast Boy</char>, now <transform class="reptile">a charging triceratops</transform>. <charDesc ref="Robin">The Titans’ leader</charDesc>
                skids backward, then jumps onto <charDesc ref="Beast Bot">the green behemoth</charDesc>’s snout and runs straight down
                his back. Jumping clear of the tail, <char>Robin</char> fires a pass downfield. <directNote kind="cut">Cut to <char>Cyborg</char>,
                with no blockers anywhere in sight</directNote>, and <directNote kind="pan">pan to follow his run</directNote>. As he goes, <charDesc ref="Cyborg">the blue
                lights that shine through the transparent coverings of his cybernetic parts start to
                fade</charDesc>. <directNote kind="cut">Cut to the ball</directNote>, sailing through the air, <directNote kind="cut">then back to him</directNote>. <charDesc ref="Cyborg">The lights have
                come back on, but they soon fade again.</charDesc></sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>I got it! I got it! I--</sp>

            <sd>His face suddenly freezes, as does he, but <directNote kind="pan">the camera keeps panning ahead</directNote>. It
                finally stops and backs up quickly; <char>Cyborg</char> might as well be a statue for his total
                lack of motion. <charDesc ref="Cyborg">Hands still outstretched, feet frozen in the middle of a running
                stride.</charDesc> The football drops into view and bounces off the side of his head, and he
                slowly topples forward onto the grass.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Robin">Robin</spkr>Cyborg? Cyborg!</sp>

            <sd><charDesc ref="Cyborg">The big teenager’s mouth and normal eye close, and the red light of his eye implant
                winks out.</charDesc> Four very worried and surprised <char>Titans</char>, including <char>Beast Boy</char> in <transform class="human">human
                form</transform>, gather around him in short order. <directNote kind="fade">Fade to black.</directNote></sd>

            <cue>OPENING THEME</cue>

        </act>
        <act n="1">
            <title>Act One</title>
            <sd><directNote kind="black-screen">The screen remains black at this point.</directNote> Dialogue, when it starts, initially sounds
                as if it is being heard through a speaker.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#">Starfire</spkr><sd>voice over</sd><char>Cyborg</char>?<sd>A flicker of
                light.</sd><char>Cyborg</char>!</sp>

            <sd><stageDesc category="fullscreen">The words "Reserve Battery Activated" appear as the background lightens into a blank
                view that appears as if it could be on a badly tuned television set.</stageDesc> <stageDesc category="display">The display
                changes to "Power Remaining 00: 30: 00," and the clock starts to count down. This is
                <char>Cyborg</char>'s perspective.</stageDesc></sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Raven">Raven</spkr><sd>voice over o.c.</sd>What's wrong with him?
                    <sd>Static.</sd></sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr><sd>voice over o.c.</sd>Is he gonna be
                okay?</sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="black-screen">The view blacks out again</directNote> and <directNote>then gives way, as of an eye opening, to the four
                concerned teammates</directNote>. <stageDesc category="display">The poorly tuned, grainy quality remains for the moment.</stageDesc></sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Robin">Robin</spkr>Shh. I think he's coming to.</sp>

            <sd><stageDesc category="display">Now the image jumps a bit and gradually refines itself</stageDesc>, and the audio returns to
                normal.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Robin">Robin</spkr><char>Cyborg</char>! Are you all right?</sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="pull">Pull back</directNote>; <char>Starfire</char> and <char>Robin</char> help him up. <charDesc ref="Cyborg">His lights are back on.</charDesc></sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>Yeah.<sd>grunts</sd>Thanks.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Raven">Raven</spkr>What happened?</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>Something musta gone wrong with my systems.</sp>

            <sd>He raises his forearm, and <directNote kind="cut">the camera cuts to <stageDesc category="close-up">a close-up of it</stageDesc> as he brings up a
                display panel</directNote>. <stageDesc category="display">It shows a nearly-drained bar graph and the "Power Remaining"
                timer.</stageDesc></sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr><sd>from o.c.</sd>Oh, man!<sd><directNote kind="pull">Pull back to frame
                    him.</directNote></sd>My power cell's dying.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Starfire">Starfire</spkr><sd>panicked</sd>Dying?!?</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>It's only a battery. I'm fine. Happens every couple
                of years. Just a natural part of being unnatural.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Robin">Robin</spkr>So what do we do?</sp>

            <sd><char>Cyborg</char> picks up the football and hands it to <char>Robin</char>.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>You keep playing. I go home and change
                batteries.</sp>

            <sd>He starts away.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>You sure you don't want help?</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>Just 'cause I can't have fun doesn't mean y'all
                can't.</sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="dissolve">Dissolve to a patch of sunny sky, seen from slightly above ground level</directNote>, and <directNote kind="tilt">tilt
                down to <charDesc ref="Cyborg">the battery-powered Titan</charDesc> on the way back to home base</directNote>. The temporary
                shutdown is now weighing heavy on his mind.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr><sd>sighs</sd>Sure was a nice day.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Boy1">Boy 1</spkr><sd>from o.c.</sd><char>Cyborg</char>!</sp>

            <sd>Surprised, <char>Cyborg</char> turns around to see who has called his name. <directNote kind="pull">Pull back to show the
                speaker as <charDesc ref="Boy 1">a young fellow, perhaps ten years old</charDesc>, seen from behind.</directNote> On the next
                line, <directNote kind="shift">the camera shifts to show him in <charDesc ref="Boy 1">a baseball jersey, cap, and mitt</charDesc></directNote>.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Boy1">Boy 1</spkr>Whoa, <char>Cyborg</char>! It's really you! You're my favorite
                'cause, look!</sp>

            <sd><charDesc ref="Boy 1">He pulls off the mitt to expose a prosthetic hand.</charDesc></sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Boy1">Boy 1</spkr>You're just like me!</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>Um...yeah, I...I guess I am.</sp>

            <sd>Something starts beeping; an alarm from his systems, and he looks at his forearm.
                Opening the display panel, <stageDesc category="display">he finds the words "<char>Titan</char> Alert" flashing on it</stageDesc>.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Boy1">Boy 1</spkr>Cool!</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>Nice meeting you, kid, but I got butt to kick.</sp>

            <sd>He runs off.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Boy1">Boy 1</spkr>Cool!</sp>

            <sd><stageDesc category="display">The panel now shows the power bar and timer again, now with a bit over thirteen
                minutes to go.</stageDesc> <char>Cyborg</char> closes it and sprints resolutely across the park. <directNote kind="dissolve">Dissolve to
                <stageDesc category="close-up">a close-up of <charDesc ref="unknown">a nervous, gagged man whose eyebrows twitch in puzzlement</charDesc></stageDesc>.</directNote> He emits
                muffled yells as <directNote kind="pull">the camera pulls back a bit</directNote> and turns upside down. <directNote kind="pull">Pull back
                farther</directNote>; <charDesc ref="unknown">he is strapped into a straitjacket and hanging by his ankles from the
                ceiling of this place, a jewelry store</charDesc>. In the fore, loading the display cases'
                contents into a bag, is <charDesc ref="Mumbo">a magician in full formal attire: tuxedo, white gloves, long
                red cape, top hat, flower in lapel</charDesc>. <charDesc ref="Mumbo">Two odd features stand out; his blue skin and
                the black mask over his eyes.</charDesc> He turns from the case and bows to the captive. This
                is <char>the Amazing Mumbo</char>.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Mumbo">Mumbo</spkr>Thanks so much. You've been a wonderful audience. Now
                watch as <char>the Amazing Mumbo</char> vanishes into thin air!<sd>He produces a wand and twirls
                    it.</sd>Mumbo Jumbo!</sp>

            <sd>Pointing the wand at the ground, he conjures up a burst of light and smoke that
                fills the screen; when it clears, he is gone. <directNote kind="cut">Cut to the entrance to Tito's
                Junkyard, where he races into view.</directNote> His legs are pistoning so fast that they look
                something like those of the Road Runner in top gear. <char>Mumbo</char> races through the piles
                of discarded items, then skids to a stop and snaps his fingers. A large diamond,
                part of his haul from the robbery, appears between them.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Mumbo">Mumbo</spkr><sd>inspecting it with a loupe</sd>Not bad for a
                matinee.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Robin">Robin</spkr><sd>from o.c.</sd><oneLine>Show's over, <char>Mumbo</char>!</oneLine></sp>

            <sd><charDesc ref="Mumbo">The villainous legerdemain artist</charDesc> gasps and looks back over his shoulder; <directNote kind="pan">pan
                quickly to a ledge overlooking the junkyard</directNote>. All the <char>Titans</char> save <char>Cyborg</char> are
                there.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Robin">Robin</spkr><oneLine>Now hand over the jewels before the critics decide to
                trash your performance.</oneLine></sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Mumbo">Mumbo</spkr>Now, <char>Robin</char>, <oneLine>I'm sure there's a peaceful solution
                    here...<sd>He produces a lit bomb in each hand.</sd>...but this isn't it</oneLine>!</sp>

            <sd>He flings them at the four, who dive for cover to avoid the explosions. Laughing,
                <char>Mumbo</char> plucks a flower from his lapel and tosses it at <char>Robin</char>; it goes off at his feet
                and just misses him. <charDesc ref="Robin">The Boy Wonder</charDesc> lands at the edge of a trash pit, ready to go
                again, but <char>Cyborg</char>'s hand reaches up and pulls him in before he can do anything. The
                black mask hangs briefly in the air before falling after him. <directNote kind="cut">Cut to inside</directNote>; <charDesc ref="Cyborg">the big
                fellow</charDesc> has something strapped to his back.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>Who said you could start the party without me?</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Robin">Robin</spkr><char>Cyborg</char>?! What about your power cell?</sp>

            <sd>Something explodes very close to them; <directNote kind="cut">cut to the cackling <char>Mumbo</char>, who now has a
                handful of cherry bombs and is letting them fly in all directions</directNote>. <char>Starfire</char> and
                <char>Raven</char> have taken cover behind neighboring junk piles, and they return fire;
                starbolts from the former, a few strategically levitated and aimed pieces of waste
                from the latter. <char>Mumbo</char> dodges both girls' counterattacks and then jumps very high to
                avoid <char>Beast Boy</char>'s charge as <transform class="reptile">a velociraptor</transform>.</sd>

            <sd><directNote kind="cut">Back to <char>Robin</char> and <char>Cyborg</char> in the pit.</directNote></sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Robin">Robin</spkr>Go home. Get fixed. We can handle this without
                you.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>I won't let you guys fight alone.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Robin">Robin</spkr>And I won't let you put yourself in danger.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>I got it covered.</sp>

            <sd>He turns around, showing the thing on his back to be four car batteries wired
                together.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>External battery pack.<sd>He brings out his sonic
                    cannon.</sd><char>Teen Titans</char>! Go!</sp>

            <sd>One giant leap carries him out of the pit. <stageDesc category="close-up">Close-up of <char>Mumbo</char>, with his hat off.</stageDesc></sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Mumbo">Mumbo</spkr>Huh?</sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="pull">Pull back</directNote>; he has the hat in hand and is about to pull something out of it. A blast
                from the cannon hurls him to the other end of the junkyard; he groans as a tin can
                bounces off his head and the hat rolls to a stop nearby. Putting it on and standing
                up, he tugs at his shirt sleeve and starts to pull a long rope of knotted-together
                handkerchiefs from it.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Mumbo">Mumbo</spkr>Nothing up my sleeve...<sd>getting to the end, he
                    whips the rope forth</sd>...and, presto!</sp>

            <sd><char>Cyborg</char> is dashing in, but the silks wrap themselves tightly around his body to
                immobilize him.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>No!</sp>

            <sd>He is spilled to the ground in an instant. A sound from o.c. draws <char>Mumbo</char>'s attention
                elsewhere; <directNote kind="cut">cut to the source, <char>Robin</char>, angling himself for a flying kick</directNote>. <char>Mumbo</char> stands
                near one end of a pipe that juts from the trash piles.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Mumbo">Mumbo</spkr>Need a hand?</sp>

            <sd>He reaches into the pipe, and his hand comes out the other end; an impossibly long
                reach for any mere mortal-and grabs <char>Robin</char>'s cape. <charDesc ref="Robin">The young man</charDesc> flails his arms and
                legs, trying hopelessly to escape. <char>Mumbo</char>'s other hand shoots out from several other
                pipes and gives him a high-speed beating.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Raven">Raven</spkr>Azarath Metrion Zinthos!</sp>

            <sd>She heaves a few large appliances at <charDesc ref="Mumbo">the prestidigitator</charDesc>, who has stopped thrashing
                <char>Robin</char>. He just stands there and dispels her magic with a gesture; the junk remains
                suspended in midair for a moment and becomes a shower of rose petals at another wave
                of the hand.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Mumbo">Mumbo</spkr>You think that's good? Watch me pull a rabbit out of
                my hat!<sd>sweeps it off</sd>Hocus-pocus!</sp>

            <sd>Out comes a wave of stuffed rabbits that covers <char>Raven</char> from head to toe. <char>Mumbo</char> puts
                the hat back on and adjusts his gloves; now <char>Beast Boy</char>, <transform class="mammal">as a bighorn sheep</transform>, thunders
                straight at him.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Mumbo">Mumbo</spkr><sd>producing and spreading a deck of cards</sd>Pick
                a card, every card!</sp>

            <sd>Half the deck is now in each hand, and he throws the pasteboards straight ahead at
                <charDesc ref="Beast Boy">the superhero</charDesc>. When they reach him, they have grown to many times normal size, large
                enough to sweep him off his feet.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Mumbo">Mumbo</spkr>For my next trick, I'll require a lovely
                assistant.</sp>

            <sd>He whips a cane out of his cape on the end of this line and promptly reaches into
                the air with its hooked end. <directNote kind="cut">Cut to <char>Starfire</char> in flight</directNote>; she is caught around the
                waist and yanked down with a cry of surprise. A few wooden slats assemble themselves
                into a floating box that encloses her entire body except for head and feet, which
                protrude from the ends. The next thing to be brought out of the mad magician's cape
                is a long handsaw, which he brandishes over her. <annot>Obviously, he is about to attempt
                the old sawing-a-woman-in-half trick.</annot></sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Mumbo">Mumbo</spkr><sd>as a big sweat drop slides down behind <char>Starfire</char>'s
                    head</sd>It's only fair to warn you...<sd><directNote kind="cut">Cut to her</directNote>; he continues o.c.</sd>
                ...I have no idea what I'm doing.</sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="pull">Pull back.</directNote> <char>Cyborg</char> shoots across the screen and nails him with a huge flying tackle,
                and the two slide among the trash heaps, throwing up thick clouds of dust. They
                clear to leave <charDesc ref="Cyborg">the four-hundred-pound Titan</charDesc> pinning <charDesc ref="Mumbo">the villain</charDesc> to the ground.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Mumbo">Mumbo</spkr><oneLine>I hate fighting dirty. Shall we clean you up?</oneLine></sp>

            <sd>A jet of water squirts from the flower in his lapel, hitting <char>Cyborg</char> with the force
                of a fire hose and throwing him over the garbage mountains. He lands in a nearby
                dump truck; <directNote kind="cut">cut to inside</directNote>. The water has shorted out his jury-rigged power supply
                and knocked it off his back. <stageDesc category="display">A red light starts to flash on his forearm</stageDesc>; <stageDesc category="close-up">close-up of
                the display panel, counting down from five seconds</stageDesc>. <directNote kind="pull">Pull back as he tries to climb
                out</directNote>, then <directNote kind="cut">cut to the panel again</directNote>. The timer reaches zero, and his systems shut down
                as they did in the prologue. Frozen in place, he offers no resistance as the dump
                truck's hydraulics kick into gear. The load of garbage is dumped out the back,
                taking <char>Cyborg</char> and the car batteries with it, and falls into a Dumpster whose floor
                has rusted away. Beneath it is the entrance to an underground cavern; the refuse
                tumbles away in the blackness.</sd>

            <sd><char>Robin</char> runs to the truck.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Robin">Robin</spkr><char>Cyborg</char>? <char>Cyborg</char>!</sp>

            <sd>It kicks into gear; <char>Mumbo</char> is at the wheel.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Mumbo">Mumbo</spkr>Exit stage left.</sp>

            <sd>He floors the accelerator and peels out. The other three <char>Titans</char> gather behind <char>Robin</char>;
                <char>Beast Boy</char> is back in <transform class="human">human form</transform>.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Robin">Robin</spkr><char>Titans</char>! He's got <char>Cyborg</char>!</sp>

            <sd>They spread out to start a search. <directNote kind="dissolve">Dissolve to <stageDesc category="overhead-shot">an overhead view of the Dumpster</stageDesc></directNote> and
                <directNote kind="zoom">zoom in slowly</directNote>, then <directNote kind="dissolve">dissolve to just inside the cavern</directNote> and <directNote kind="tilt">tilt down from the
                entrance</directNote>. <charDesc ref="Cyborg">The missing Titan</charDesc> lies immobile among the rest of the trash; around him in
                the gloom, several round red eyes light up. He is dragged slowly toward them, after
                which they wink out. <directNote kind="fade">Fade to black.</directNote></sd>

        </act>
        <act n="2">
            <title>Act Two</title>
            <sd><directNote kind="black-screen">The word "Online" is typed onto the black screen, then disappears to make way for
                "Charging" in the same manner.</directNote></sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Computer1">Computer 1</spkr><sd>in time with the above</sd>Online.
                Charging.</sp>

            <sd>A horizontal band of white light crosses the middle of the screen and widens to fill
                the entire view. <stageDesc category="overhead-shot">The brightness yields to a shot of a large circular chamber with
                strong overhead lights</stageDesc>; <directNote>the camera is pointing up at the ceiling</directNote>. <char>Cyborg</char>'s hand
                reaches into view in time with his weary groans; this is his perspective. His
                systems are working again. <charDesc ref="Fixit">A male voice begins to speak; very level, measured,
                almost monotonic.</charDesc></sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Voice">Voice</spkr>You are operational.</sp>

            <sd>The speaker moves into view and looks down at <char>Cyborg</char>. <charDesc ref="Fixit">It is a tall android figure
                swathed in a long robe; all we can see for the moment is the head, which sports a
                flat, angular face marked by two glowing blue slits for eyes. Instead of hair,
                circuit pathways cover the scalp. This is Fixit.</charDesc></sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Fixit">Fixit</spkr>That is good.</sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="pull">Pull back.</directNote> Lying on a large table, <char>Cyborg</char> has several wires plugged into his chest.
                He groans.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>What's going--?</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Fixit">Fixit</spkr>Rest, friend.<sd>walks o.c.</sd>Your new power cell
                is not fully charged.</sp>

            <sd><stageDesc category="overhead-shot"><charDesc ref="Cyborg">The Titan</charDesc> reaches overhead and pulls down one of the lights to aim it across the
                chamber.</stageDesc> <directNote kind="cut">Cut to a motley group of robots in another area</directNote>; <charDesc ref="Robots">their eyes glow red,
                marking them as the ones that towed him in here</charDesc>.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr><sd>from o.c.</sd>Who are you?</sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="pan">The light pans across many others on elevated benches.</directNote></sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Fixit">Fixit</spkr><sd>from o.c.</sd>I am called <char>Fixit</char>.</sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="cut">Back to Cyborg.</directNote></sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>Whoa.</sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="cut">Cut to a darkened patch</directNote> and <directNote kind="pan">pan the light across the spectators again</directNote>.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Fixit">Fixit</spkr><sd>from o.c.</sd>You were broken. I have brought you
                here to be repaired.</sp>

            <sd>On the end of this, the light reaches the ceiling and <directNote kind="tilt">tilts down to illuminate him</directNote>.
                He crosses the chamber.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>Where's "here"?</sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="black-screen"><char>Fixit</char> moves into view near the camera; his robe blacks out the screen</directNote>. From here,
                <directNote kind="dissolve">dissolve to a group of buildings in Jump City, seem from ground level</directNote>. A plume of
                smoke wafts into view, and <directNote kind="pan">the camera pans</directNote>/<directNote kind="tilt">tilts down to the source</directNote>; it is the dump
                truck <char>Cyborg</char> landed in, which has crashed into a building. The other four <char>Titans</char>
                have caught up to it. <char>Mumbo</char> is nowhere in sight.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Starfire">Starfire</spkr><char>Cyborg</char> is not inside!</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Robin">Robin</spkr><sd>checks his tracking device</sd>And his locator
                signal is being jammed.<sd>puts it away</sd>This doesn't make sense.<sd><char>Beast Boy</char>
                    turns o.c.</sd>Why would <char>Mumbo</char> want to kidnap <char>Cyborg</char>?</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr><sd>from o.c.</sd>Guys!</sp>

            <sd><stageDesc category="close-up">Close-up of <charDesc ref="Mumbo">the illusionist</charDesc>'s discarded top hat on the ground.</stageDesc></sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr><sd>picks up <char>Mumbo</char>'s top hat</sd>Over here! I
                found something!</sp>

            <sd>peeks in</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Robin">Robin</spkr>I wouldn't--</sp>

            <sd>A huge flock of doves flies out of the hat. When they have gone, the four <char>Titans</char> are
                covered with feathers, <char>Beast Boy</char> most of all.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Raven">Raven</spkr>Way to go.</sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="snap">Snap to black</directNote>, then <directNote kind="fade">fade in to <stageDesc category="close-up">a close-up of <char>Cyborg</char>'s forearm</stageDesc></directNote>. <stageDesc category="display">He opens the display
                panel and finds the power bar completely lit and the message "Full Power 100%."</stageDesc></sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Fixit">Fixit</spkr><sd>from o.c.</sd>Charging is complete. The new power
                cell is functioning properly.</sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="pull">Pull back; <char>Cyborg</char> is unplugged and sitting up.</directNote> A couple of hovering robots complete
                a repair scan and float away.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>Yeah.<sd>stretches</sd>I'm feeling better. Lots
                better.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Fixit">Fixit</spkr>Of course you are.<sd>walking o.c.</sd>I am
                <char>Fixit</char>.</sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="cut">Cut to ceiling level</directNote>; <stageDesc category="overhead-shot">mechanical junk of all types tumbles into the chamber from an
                overhead chute</stageDesc>. <directNote kind="tilt">Tilt down to ground level as <char>Fixit</char> goes over to the pile.</directNote></sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Fixit">Fixit</spkr>Things come to me broken. I make repairs.<sd>He picks
                    up two small parts.</sd>Let me see.<sd>They float out of his hands; he studies
                    them.</sd>Yes...yes...hmm...pity.<sd>He picks up another one.</sd> Interesting.
                The damage is too extensive.<sd>It floats; he takes up a fourth.</sd> Perhaps if we
                can find another processor.</sp>

            <sd>During the previous line, <char>Cyborg</char> gets off the table and watches <char>Fixit</char> for some
                seconds. Finally, he waves and starts to leave.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>Well, thanks...for everything.</sp>

            <sd>Several of the red-eyed robots turn suddenly in his direction. The components <char>Fixit</char>
                had suspended in midair hit the ground, and he advances across the chamber with a
                new note of urgency in his voice.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Fixit">Fixit</spkr>You cannot leave.</sp>

            <sd><char>Cyborg</char>, at the exit, stops and turns back.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>I can't?</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Fixit">Fixit</spkr><sd>returns to normal tone</sd>You are not repaired,
                not fully.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>I'm not?</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Fixit">Fixit</spkr>My examination revealed many flaws, serious
                flaws.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr><sd>panicked</sd>Serious? How serious? What's wrong
                with me?</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Fixit">Fixit</spkr>There is no cause for alarm. More repairs are needed.
                More repairs will be made.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>But, I feel fine. Are you sure I'm--?</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Fixit">Fixit</spkr>Quite. Will you remain? It is for the best.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>Well, yeah, I guess.<sd><stageDesc category="display">works his forearm
                    controls</stageDesc></sd>Let me just tell my <charDesc ref="Titans">friends</charDesc> where I am.</sp>

            <sd>His back turned to <char>Fixit</char>, he does not notice that <charDesc ref="Fixit">the android's eyes have gone red</charDesc>.
                <stageDesc category="display">What he does notice is that when the display panel for his built-in communicator
                opens, it shows a badly garbled signal; jammed by the proprietor of the place.</stageDesc></sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>Whoa!<sd><charDesc ref="Fixit"><char>Fixit</char>'s eyes go blue again.</charDesc></sd> Something
                really is wrong with me.</sp>

            <sd>He shuts it off.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Fixit">Fixit</spkr><sd>gestures to the table</sd>Rest now. You may
                contact your <charDesc ref="Titans">friends</charDesc> later.<sd><char>Cyborg</char> climbs up.</sd>I am sure they are not too
                concerned.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr><sd>lying down</sd>Maybe they should be.</sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="cut">Cut to the other four <char>Titans</char> racing through the streets</directNote>, then <directNote kind="cut">to <stageDesc category="setting">a building front
                that has been garishly decorated with rainbow-colored clouds and stars</stageDesc></directNote>. <annot>No points
                for guessing who did this bit of graffiti.</annot> <directNote kind="pan">Pan to a parked bus</directNote>, which disappears in
                a puff of smoke, <directNote kind="pan">then to the location where it materializes</directNote>; a block or so down the
                road. The camera moves on to another corner, where a mailbox jumps into view under
                its own power, spits out a live rabbit, and bounces away a bit before doing this
                again. <directNote kind="pan">Pan to follow a young woman as she floats out from around this corner</directNote>; ten
                feet or so off the ground, horizontal, headfirst, with three large hoops encircling
                her body. <annot>The old "levitating woman" trick has received a new twist thanks to
                <char>Mumbo</char>.</annot></sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>I'll say this much for <char>Mumbo</char>; <oneLine>he's an easy act
                to follow</oneLine>.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Starfire">Starfire</spkr>Oh, I would commit myself to a life of
                muck-shoveling in the filth mines of Cornex if <char>Cyborg</char> could only be returned
                safely.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Raven">Raven</spkr>He was malfunctioning. He shouldn't have been
                helping.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Robin">Robin</spkr>I tried to stop him, but he's <char>Cyborg</char>.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Mumbo">Mumbo</spkr><sd>from o.c., distant</sd><char>Mumbo</char>-jumbo!</sp>

            <sd>The sound of a spell being cast is heard, and all four <char>Titans</char> run toward it. <directNote kind="cut">Cut to
                an ATM at a street corner</directNote>; it is spewing a mountain of cash onto the sidewalk. As
                the heroes run up, <directNote kind="pan">the camera pans away from them a bit to show two other machines
                exhibiting the same green diarrhea</directNote>. <char>Mumbo</char> is at the last one, hammering away at its
                keypad. He laughs, then cocks an eyebrow at the new arrival and sweeps his hat off;
                a replacement for the one he lost.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Mumbo">Mumbo</spkr>Sorry, folks.</sp>

            <sd>He holds the hat upright, open end down; all the money is promptly sucked up into it
                as if it were a vacuum cleaner, after which he puts it back on.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Mumbo">Mumbo</spkr>No time for autographs.</sp>

            <sd>He runs o.c.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Robin">Robin</spkr><char>Titans</char>! Get him!</sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="cut">Cut to inside an alley.</directNote> <charDesc ref="Mumbo">The magician</charDesc> runs along its course as <char>Raven</char> flies after
                him.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Mumbo">Mumbo</spkr>Open, says me!</sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="cut">Cut to the wall at the alley's dead end.</directNote> Responding to his command, the bricks
                disappear, several at a time, to make an opening big enough for him to pass through.
                They pop back into place just in time to stop <char>Raven</char> from following. <directNote kind="cut">Cut to <char>Mumbo</char>,
                still running along.</directNote> A loud lowing causes him to hit the brakes and yell in fear;
                <directNote kind="pull">pull back as the source steps into view</directNote>, <char>Beast Boy</char> as <transform class="mammal">a large bull</transform>. He snorts
                angrily and charges, and <directNote kind="cut">the camera cuts to his perspective as <char>Mumbo</char> pulls his cape
                off and holds it in front of him</directNote>. The garment is jerked away to reveal that a brick
                wall has suddenly appeared behind it. <char>Beast Boy</char> rams this head on, and <directNote kind="pull">the camera
                pulls back from the impact to show him lying dazed next to its remains</directNote>. <char>Mumbo</char> steps
                out from behind the masonry, his cape back on, and turns his hat into a sombrero
                with a flick of the wrist.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Mumbo">Mumbo</spkr>Olé!</sp>

            <sd>He turns the headgear back to normal and runs off down the alley. However, he is not
                alone for long; <char>Starfire</char> flies over the roof of an adjacent building and throws a
                starbolt at him as she takes over the pursuit. <stageDesc category="overhead-shot">Overhead view of him, with her shots
                peppering the ground on either side.</stageDesc> She pulls into view, and <directNote kind="cut">the camera cuts to
                him</directNote>; he conjures a bouquet in one hand.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Mumbo">Mumbo</spkr>Flowers for the lady.</sp>

            <sd>He tosses the bunch up over his shoulder and they explode in her face. A few more
                steps bring him to another dead end, where <char>Robin</char> drops into view to square off. His
                handy-dandy fighting staff is out and fully extended for a twirl in no time
                flat.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Mumbo">Mumbo</spkr>Abracadabra!</sp>

            <sd>A flash of light, and <transform class="reptile">the metal shaft has turned into a cobra</transform>. <char>Robin</char> yells in
                surprise and drops the venomous creature. <stageDesc category="close-up">Close-up of it on the ground as <char>Mumbo</char>'s
                shadow passes by and his laughter is heard</stageDesc>, then <directNote kind="cut">cut to him running up a flight of
                stairs to make his escape</directNote>. All four <char>Titans</char> charge after him, <char>Beast Boy</char> back in <transform class="human">human
                form</transform>.</sd>

            <sd><stageDesc category="close-up">Close-up of <char>Cyborg</char>'s full power gauge</stageDesc>; <directNote kind="pull">pull back slightly</directNote>. This is his
                perspective.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>I don't get it. All my sensors say I'm fine.</sp>

            <sd>He lowers his arm; <char>Fixit</char> approaches.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Fixit">Fixit</spkr>Your sensors are incomplete. Mine are more
                precise.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>Guess I'm just...<sd><directNote kind="pull">Pull back</directNote>; he lies on the
                    table; fully wired up.</sd>...getting kinda nervous. How long am I gonna be down
                here, anyway?</sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="cut">Cut to a gathering of robots on the chamber floor.</directNote> A small droid floats past
                them.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Fixit">Fixit</spkr><sd>from o.c.</sd>Repairs could take some time.
                    <sd><directNote kind="cut">Cut to him.</directNote></sd>Besides, why would you want to leave?<sd>The droid reaches
                    him; he grasps it.</sd>Look around you.</sp>

            <sd>A cable extends itself down from the ceiling, plugs into a port on <char>Fixit</char>'s forehead,
                and begins to glow red.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Fixit">Fixit</spkr>Look at yourself.<sd>Another droid floats over.</sd>
                You belong with us.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>No, I don't. I mean, you've got a nice place here
                and you've been really cool to me, but...<sd><directNote kind="cut">Back to <char>Fixit</char></directNote>; he continues o.c.</sd>
                ...I couldn't live down here. I don't know how you can.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Fixit">Fixit</spkr>What do you mean? The power supply is adequate.
                Replacement parts are easy to find.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>I need more than that! What about sunlight? What
                about fresh air? What about food?</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Fixit">Fixit</spkr>I do not require these things.<sd>The cable
                    disconnects.</sd>And when repairs are complete...<sd>walking o.c.</sd>
                ...neither will you.</sp>

            <sd><char>Cyborg</char> gets himself vertical and unplugs the lines hooked into his body.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>You know what? I'm feeling all right now. So thanks
                anyway, but I'm just gonna go.</sp>

            <sd>He walks away. <char>Fixit</char> turns from his work and puts even more urgency and command into
                his voice than when <charDesc ref="Cyborg">the patient</charDesc> first tried to clear out.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Fixit">Fixit</spkr>Stay.</sp>

            <sd><charDesc ref="Fixit">His eyes go red.</charDesc> <char>Cyborg</char> suddenly finds a number of spectator robots blocking his
                path. He takes a step back and is surprised by a few small ones that jump onto his
                shoulders and chest and grip firmly.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>Yo, what are you--?<sd><charDesc ref="Robot">A flexible arm reaches into
                    view and grabs his wrist.</charDesc></sd>Hey!</sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="cut">Cut to the source, another robot.</directNote> It reaches out with its other arm.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr><sd>from o.c.</sd>Let me go!</sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="cut">Back to him</directNote>; the second arm clamps onto his other wrist. He struggles against the
                contraptions' hold on him, but cannot break free. <directNote kind="pull">Pull back a distance</directNote>; several
                other members of <char>Fixit</char>'s legions extend cattle prods from their upper surfaces and
                electrify them. The current races along the two extended arms toward <charDesc ref="Cyborg">the captive</charDesc>,
                and as he starts to scream, <directNote kind="cut">the camera cuts to <char>Fixit</char>'s emotionless countenance</directNote> and
                <directNote kind="pan">pans to follow his gaze back to the table</directNote>. It tilts until it is nearly vertical, and
                <char>Cyborg</char> is carried into view and placed on it. He has been securely bound.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Fixit">Fixit</spkr>Repairs are not yet complete.</sp>

            <sd>The table swivels a bit to give <charDesc ref="Cyborg">the Titan</charDesc> a direct view of a large closed door. <directNote kind="zoom">Zoom
                in slowly.</directNote></sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Fixit">Fixit</spkr><sd>from o.c.</sd>Your biological components are
                imperfect and must be replaced.</sp>

            <sd>The door hisses open, releasing a cloud of vapor. Behind it is only blackness, but
                after a second or two this yields to show, hanging on a support framework, an array
                of secondhand robotic parts; enough to replace every remaining natural portion of
                <char>Cyborg</char>'s body. <annot>The face is missing its left eye, since he already has an implant on
                that side.</annot> A small gasp is heard from the o.c intended recipient of this overhaul.
                <directNote kind="cut">Cut to <stageDesc category="close-up">an extreme close-up of him</stageDesc>.</directNote></sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr><sd>horrified</sd>No.</sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="dissolve">Dissolve to <stageDesc category="close-up">a close-up of the robotic face</stageDesc>.</directNote> <directNote kind="fade">Everything except the glowing red right
                eye fades to black</directNote>; <directNote kind="fade">it does the same a moment later</directNote>.</sd>

        </act>
        <act n="3">
            <title>Act Three</title>
            <sd><directNote kind="black-screen">The screen remains black as the following line is spoken and the words are typed
                up.</directNote></sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Computer2">Computer 2</spkr><stageDesc category="display">Biological components removed. Repairs
                complete.</stageDesc></sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Fixit">Fixit</spkr><sd>voice over</sd>Awaken, <charDesc ref="Cyborg">friend</charDesc>. Awaken and <charDesc ref="Cyborg">see
                your new face</charDesc>.</sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="fade">The view flickers and gives way to a shot of <char>Cyborg</char>, seen from behind and looking in
                a mirror.</directNote> <charDesc ref="Cyborg">Every last scrap of organic tissue has been switched out for the
                artificial parts that had hung on the rack.</charDesc> He rubs a hand down the side of his
                face, then raises it in a fist with a growl of rage. <stageDesc category="close-up">Close-up of the reflection; the
                fist comes down and shatters the glass.</stageDesc> <directNote kind="black-screen">Behind it is blackness, with a point of
                light shining in the distance and shooting rays toward the camera. Cyborg is sucked
                into view toward this; it starts to grow, filling the screen.</directNote></sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>NOOOOOOOOO!!</sp>

            <sd>A flash of white, and we see him on <char>Fixit</char>'s examining table; back to normal, wired
                up, and now held to the table with thick steel bands. He yells in pure fear as his
                eyes snap open; the previous scene was a nightmare.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Fixit">Fixit</spkr><sd>from o.c.</sd>Do not be afraid.</sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="cut">Cut to him by the table.</directNote> <charDesc ref="Fixit">His eyes have assumed their normal blue color.</charDesc></sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Fixit">Fixit</spkr>You were dreaming.<sd>walking o.c.</sd>Sleep will not
                be necessary once repairs are complete.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr><sd>struggling</sd>What if I don't want to be
                repaired? What if I like me this way?</sp>

            <sd><char>Fixit</char> goes to the rack of parts.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Fixit">Fixit</spkr>Such thoughts come from your imperfect biological
                components.</sp>

            <sd>He raises a hand; a tool floats into it, and he does a bit of welding on he
                face.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Fixit">Fixit</spkr>They will be replaced momentarily.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>Not if I can help it.</sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="cut">Cut to a rooftop.</directNote> <char>Mumbo</char> leaps into view and bounds from building to building.
                <char>Starfire</char> flies after him, then <char>Raven</char>, and <char>Beast Boy</char> brings up the rear as <transform class="mammal">a
                kangaroo</transform>. <charDesc ref="Mumbo">The crazed magician</charDesc> makes one impossible jump after another as the three
                <char>Titans</char> struggle to keep up. <directNote kind="pull">Pull back to an overhead view</directNote>; <stageDesc category="overhead-shot"><char>Robin</char> gets into the
                action, hoofing it along the rooftops of higher buildings</stageDesc>. After a few more blocks,
                <char>Mumbo</char> stops dead and whirls to face them, bringing his wand to the ready.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Mumbo">Mumbo</spkr>Abracadabra!</sp>

            <sd>He waves the wand; <directNote kind="cut">cut to <charDesc ref="Raven Starfire">the two flyers</charDesc> and <charDesc ref="Beast Boy">the hopper</charDesc> as they scatter to avoid the
                hexes</directNote>.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Mumbo">Mumbo</spkr><sd>from o.c.</sd>Alakazam! Hocus-pocus!</sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="cut">Back to him.</directNote> He laughs madly, <annot>the top of his head flapping clear of his neck after
                the style of the Canadian characters on South Park</annot>.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Mumbo">Mumbo</spkr>You'll never stop <char>the Amazing Mumbo</char>! Never! Ne--</sp>

            <sd><stageDesc category="close-up">Close-up of his wand hand on the end of this line.</stageDesc> <charDesc ref="Robin">Something black and green</charDesc> whips
                past and carries the prop with it. <directNote kind="pull">Pull back; <char>Mumbo</char> is caught completely off
                guard.</directNote></sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Mumbo">Mumbo</spkr>Huh?</sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="cut">Cut to <char>Robin</char>, holding aloft the wand he swiped</directNote>; he breaks it in half. <char>Mumbo</char> screams
                as bags of money, all the loot from his crime spree, go flying out of his pockets.
                He then cries a waterfall while his top hat shrinks and disappears; finally, he
                collapses o.c. <directNote>Pull back to reveal that <charDesc ref="Mumbo">he is now an ordinary-looking old fellow</charDesc>, on
                his knees among the vast amounts of cash.</directNote> <char>Starfire</char>, <char>Raven</char>, and <char>Beast Boy</char> touch down
                behind him, and <char>Robin</char>'s shadow falls across him from the front. He is dragged up by
                his shirt front for a little face-to-face talk.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Robin">Robin</spkr>No more tricks! Where, is, <char>Cyborg</char>?</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Mumbo">Mumbo</spkr>How should I know?</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Robin">Robin</spkr>Where is he?!?</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Raven">Raven</spkr>You took him from the junkyard!</sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="pull">Pull back to frame everyone</directNote>; <char>Beast Boy</char> is in <transform class="human">human form</transform>.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Starfire">Starfire</spkr>What have you done with him?</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Mumbo">Mumbo</spkr>Nothing! Honest! When you broke the wand, you broke
                all my spells. Even if I had done something, it'd be over now. Poof! He'd be
                standing right here.</sp>

            <sd><char>Robin</char> drops him.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>If <charDesc ref="Cyborg">Cy</charDesc>'s not with him, then he's still back
                at--</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Robin, Beast Boy, Raven and Starfire">Robin, Beast Boy, Raven and
                    Starfire</spkr><sd>all together at the same time</sd>The junkyard!</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Mumbo">Mumbo</spkr><sd>smiling nervously</sd>So, do I still have to go
                to jail?</sp>

            <sd>He gets a very nasty look from the four <char>Titans</char> and his face falls. A big drop of
                sweat slides down his temple.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Mumbo">Mumbo</spkr>I thought so.</sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="cut">Cut to <char>Cyborg</char>, now straining mightily against the steel bands that hold him to the
                table.</directNote> <directNote kind="zoom">Zoom in past him to <char>Fixit</char>, who continues his spot repairs on the new parts.</directNote>
                He stops after a moment.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Fixit">Fixit</spkr>I am ready. We will begin now.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>Perfect timing.</sp>

            <sd>A mighty surge of muscle power breaks him loose. Unplugging himself, he slides off
                the table and makes a run for it. <charDesc ref="Fixit"><char>Fixit</char>'s eyes go red as he beams a command</charDesc>; <directNote kind="cut">cut to
                just outside the exit door, which closes in response</directNote>. <char>Cyborg</char> gasps an instant before
                it seals itself, <directNote kind="black-screen">blacking out the screen</directNote>; <directNote kind="snap">snap to him inside</directNote>.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>I didn't want to have to do this, but...</sp>

            <sd>He reconfigures his arm into cannon mode and prepares to fire, but the weapon merely
                fizzles out with a wisp of smoke.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>Huh?</sp>

            <sd><charDesc ref="Fixit"><char>Fixit</char>'s eyes are blue again.</charDesc></sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Fixit">Fixit</spkr><sd>advances toward the camera</sd>Your defensive
                systems have been disabled for the procedure. They will be reactivated when repairs
                are complete.</sp>

            <sd>Snarling, <char>Cyborg</char> runs at him, but <charDesc ref="Fixit">a red-eye flash sends several metal tentacles
                snaking down from the ceiling</charDesc>. They ensnare him just before he can tackle <char>Fixit</char>; he
                hauls fiercely at them and is able to reach one hand forward. <stageDesc category="close-up">Close-up of it, within
                inches of the hermit's robe.</stageDesc> The fingers close on the fabric and pull it away, and
                <directNote kind="tilt">the camera backs up to ground level and tilts up to give a good view of what is
                within</directNote>. <charDesc ref="Fixit">There is a jumble of internal organs heavily interwoven with cables and
                switches, even a small, fully jointed robotic arm. <char>Fixit</char>, then, is not a true
                android, but rather a mix of mechanical and organic parts just like the Titan he is
                trying to "repair."</charDesc></sd>

            <sd><char>Cyborg</char> sucks in a long, shocked gasp, but <char>Fixit</char> shows no trace of anger at having
                had his innards exposed to full view.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Fixit">Fixit</spkr>The biological malfunctions are growing worse.
                    <sd>closes his robe</sd>We must begin at once.</sp>

            <sd>He moves o.c. <directNote kind="cut">Cut to the floor of the underground cavern</directNote>; a circle of it is
                illuminated by the sunlight spilling in from above. The car batteries <char>Cyborg</char> had
                wired up to power himself lie in a jumble here. <char>Robin</char> drops into view and looks them
                over carefully; the other three <char>Titans</char> are gathered at the edge of the hole that
                leads in.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Robin">Robin</spkr>His battery pack. He must have fallen down here.
                    <sd><char>Beast Boy</char> jumps down as well.</sd><charDesc ref="Starfire">Star</charDesc>! Can you give us some light?</sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="pull">Pull back</directNote>; now all four <char>Titans</char> are underground. One of <char>Starfire</char>'s hands begins to
                glow, and she holds it up to substitute for a torch. They advance into the
                gloom.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Robin">Robin</spkr><char>Cyborg</char>!</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr><charDesc ref="Cyborg">Cy</charDesc>!</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Starfire">Starfire</spkr><char>Cyborg</char>?</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Robin">Robin</spkr><char>Cyborg</char>!</sp>

            <sd>After they have passed o.c., <directNote kind="black-screen">leaving the screen blacked out</directNote>, <directNote kind="snap">snap to <stageDesc category="long-shot">a long shot of
                the chamber</stageDesc></directNote>. <char>Cyborg</char> has again been secured to the table, and <char>Fixit</char> has bent to his
                work. Sparks fly from the welding in progress, to the sound of weak moaning.
                <stageDesc category="close-up">Close-up of one hand, which twitches convulsively, then of <char>Fixit</char>'s expressionless
                face.</stageDesc> The sparks' glare plays over his flat features.</sd>

            <sd><directNote kind="snap">Snap to black, the lightless exterior part of the cavern.</directNote> <charDesc ref="Titans">The other four teammates</charDesc>
                advance into view, but stop at the sound of machinery moving o.c. <char>Robin</char> gasps in
                surprise; <directNote kind="pull">pull back to frame the source, one after another of <char>Fixit</char>'s robots,
                blocking the forward path and cutting off retreat</directNote>. <char>Beast Boy</char> cranes his neck for a
                look at the biggest of the lot.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>Wow...<sd>He chuckles nervously.</sd>Uh, any
                of you guys seen <charDesc ref="Cyborg">a dude about this tall with one red eye and titanium body
                armor</charDesc>?</sp>

            <sd><stageDesc category="gag">He reaches up to indicate the height on "this tall," then turns his left eye red and
                adopts an approximate likeness of <char>Cyborg</char> in time with the other two features he
                names.</stageDesc> The robots' only response is to step forward in readiness for battle. <char>Robin</char>
                backs up a step of his own; <char>Beast Boy</char> has assumed his normal appearance.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Robin">Robin</spkr><char>Teen Titans</char>! Go!</sp>

            <sd><char>Starfire</char> stays put while the other three spread out. She throws a string of
                starbolts at the robot advancing toward her and blows it apart with the last one.
                <char>Robin</char> punches another to send sparks flying, then smashes it to junk with a high
                kick. A third is forcing <char>Beast Boy</char> back into the inky shadows, so that his eyes are
                all that can be seen of him. We hear a low growl from that corner, and the lights
                come up to show that he has transformed into <transform class="mammal">a huge gorilla</transform> and caught the
                mechanical aggressor in a crushing grip. He tears it apart and sets out to find
                others.</sd>

            <sd><char>Raven</char> raises her arm to cast a spell as the lights go out entirely on her. Two black
                slashes of energy cross the screen; <directNote kind="fade">fade in to show the biggest robot of the lot,
                with two glowing incisions crossing its upper body</directNote>. The thing shorts out, slides
                apart along the fault lines <char>Raven</char> has opened, and explodes.</sd>

            <sd><stageDesc category="close-up">Close-up of <char>Fixit</char>'s tray of tools.</stageDesc> One floats up, then another; <directNote kind="pull">pull back to frame
                him, still hard at work</directNote>. The two devices hover nearby within easy reach, and he
                takes one of them in hand after a moment. A piece of <char>Cyborg</char>'s armor plating clatters
                to the floor. Now <char>Fixit</char> takes the robotic face off the rack; <directNote kind="cut">cut to <stageDesc category="close-up">a close-up of
                <charDesc ref="Cyborg">the madly struggling Titan</charDesc></stageDesc> as the shadow of <charDesc ref="Fixit">his single-minded repairman</charDesc> falls over
                him</directNote>, then to his perspective.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Fixit">Fixit</spkr>Do not resist. It is for the best.</sp>

            <sd><stageDesc category="lower">He lowers the face toward the camera.</stageDesc> <directNote kind="cut">Cut to <char>Cyborg</char>.</directNote></sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>No, it isn't! If you take out my biological
                components...</sp>

            <sd>The face is set in place; his next three lines sound as if they are coming through a
                speaker set in it. <stageDesc category="close-up">Extreme close-up of the right eye behind the red glass.</stageDesc></sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>...you take out the best part of me! The part that
                makes me who I am!</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Fixit">Fixit</spkr>Your memories, your "self", will be preserved.
                    <sd><stageDesc category="close-up">His eyes go red; close-up of them.</stageDesc></sd>I will download them into your new
                brain.</sp>

            <sd><charDesc ref="Fixit">The port on his forehead opens to allow a cable to extend outward.</charDesc> It plugs itself
                into <char>Cyborg</char>'s new face, right between the eyes.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>No...you can't do this, please! You don't
                understand!</sp>

            <sd><stageDesc category="close-up">Extreme close-up of the right eye, squeezed tightly shut.</stageDesc> <directNote kind="zoom">It opens as the camera
                zooms in through the pupil.</directNote></sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>NOOOOOOOOO!!</sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="dissolve">The screen flickers briefly and begins to show scenes from the prologue and Act One,
                dissolving from one to the next</directNote>; <char>Fixit</char> is copying memories to his own system. <directNote kind="pan">Pan
                across the park...<char>Cyborg</char>, <char>Robin</char>, <char>Starfire</char> at the picnic table...<char>Starfire</char> hugging the
                mustard jar...<char>Cyborg</char> and <char>Robin</char> staring at her in disbelief...gathering for the
                football game...<char>Raven</char> asking what happened to him when he conked out (mirror image
                from original scene)...the start of the game's first play...<char>Robin</char> backing up for a
                pass...<char>Beast Boy</char> counting down to tackle...the ball sailing through the air...<char>Cyborg</char>
                going long for the catch...the other four <char>Titans</char>, waiting to see if he will come
                around from the shutdown...<char>Starfire</char> and <char>Robin</char> helping him up...<charDesc ref="Boy 1">the boy with the
                artificial hand</charDesc> running up to say hello...the catcher's mitt being removed to expose
                the prosthesis...then a flash of white, and we are back in the chamber.</directNote> <char>Fixit</char> cries
                out and stumbles away from <char>Cyborg</char>, the connecting cable retreating into his
                forehead. He crashes to the ground.</sd>

            <sd>In the outer portion of the cavern, the shots <char>Starfire</char> is holding in check light up
                the area again. She, <char>Raven</char>, and <char>Beast Boy</char>, the last back in <transform class="human">human form</transform>, have found
                themselves staring at a great many robots who have been knocked out by their
                combined efforts. <directNote kind="pan">Pan to <char>Robin</char>, who is trying to catch his breath</directNote>; he starts in
                surprise at the sound of o.c. machinery. <directNote kind="cut">Cut to the source, another squadron
                struggling to move forward</directNote>, then <directNote kind="cut">to him as he backs up into the other three</directNote>. The
                units totter toward them and then go dead-incapacitated by the shock to <char>Fixit</char>'s
                system.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Robin">Robin</spkr>Huh?</sp>

            <sd>The floor of the chamber. The face that was to have replaced <char>Cyborg</char>'s drops next to
                the table, whose steel restraints have all been broken, and <charDesc ref="Cyborg">the real McCoy</charDesc> climbs
                off and kneels groaning next to it. <char>Robin</char> reaches into view and puts a hand on his
                shoulder.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Robin">Robin</spkr><sd>from o.c.</sd><char>Cyborg</char>!<sd><directNote kind="pull">Pull back to frame
                    both.</directNote></sd>Are you okay?</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>Yeah.</sp>

            <sd>They straighten up. <directNote kind="pull">Pull back; the other three <char>Titans</char> are in the chamber as
                well.</directNote></sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Fixit">Fixit</spkr><sd>from o.c., wistfully</sd>So...beautiful.</sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="cut">Cut to just behind <char>Cyborg</char></directNote> and <directNote kind="zoom">zoom in slowly over his shoulder</directNote>. <char>Fixit</char> is kneeling by
                the rack of parts.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Fixit">Fixit</spkr>I had forgotten how beautiful. The world...
                    <sd><char>Cyborg</char> walks up.</sd>...through your eyes.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>Through human eyes. The same kind you have.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Fixit">Fixit</spkr><sd>looks at his hands</sd>Perhaps I am the one in
                need of repairs.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>And maybe I'm the guy who can help repair you.</sp>

            <sd>He holds out a hand, and <charDesc ref="Fixit">the fellow mechanical half-breed</charDesc> smiles and takes hold,
                allowing himself to be helped to his feet.</sd>

            <sd><directNote kind="dissolve">Dissolve to a patch of clear sky</directNote> and <directNote kind="tilt">tilt down to the park</directNote>. Once again, people are
                enjoying the fine weather in their own way. <directNote kind="cut">Cut to <stageDesc category="long-shot">a long shot of the <char>Titans</char></stageDesc>, save
                <char>Cyborg</char>, gathered around a picnic basket set out on a blanket.</directNote> The fifth member of
                the team walks into view, carrying the football, but is stopped by a familiar
                voice.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Boy1">Boy 1</spkr><sd>from o.c.</sd><char>Cyborg</char>! Hey, <char>Cyborg</char>!</sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="cut">Cut to him</directNote>; he runs up, <charDesc ref="Boy 1">with his mitten gone and prosthesis fully exposed</charDesc>, and he
                has a friend with him.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Boy1">Boy 1</spkr><sd>to his friend</sd>See? It's <char>Cyborg</char>. He's just like
                me!</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Boy2">Boy 2</spkr>Whoa, cool!</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>I am just like you. <oneLine>But it's not your arm that
                makes us the same.<sd><directNote kind="cut">Cut to the two; he points at the first boy's heart and
                    continues o.c.</directNote></sd>It's the stuff connected to it.</oneLine></sp>

            <sd>Both beam at this; <directNote kind="pull">pull back to frame him</directNote>.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>Now, go deep!</sp>

            <sd>They do so, laughing, and he lets the pigskin fly. <directNote kind="tilt">Tilt up</directNote> and <directNote kind="pan">pan to follow its
                spiraling flight across the park</directNote>, then <directNote kind="fade">fade to black</directNote>.</sd>
        </act>
    </body>
</root>