<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../schema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?><root>
    <head>
        <episode>CAR TROUBLE</episode>
        <writer>David Slack</writer>
        <director>Ciro Nieli</director>
        <storyboard>Kalvin Lee, Rafael Rosado, Alan Wan</storyboard>
        <animation>Dong Woo Animation Company, Ltd.</animation>
        <source>https://teentitans.fandom.com/wiki/Car_Trouble_(Transcript)</source>
        <issueList>
            <issueInfo none="y"/>
        </issueList>
    </head>
    <characterList>
        <charList type="recurring" id="Cyborg" subtype="titan">Cyborg</charList>
        <charList type="recurring" id="BeastBoy" subtype="titan">Beast Boy</charList>
        <charList type="recurring" id="Raven" subtype="titan">Raven</charList>
        <charList type="recurring" id="Robin" subtype="titan">Robin</charList>
        <charList type="recurring" id="Starfire" subtype="titan">Starfire</charList>
        <charList type="nonrecurring" id="Sammy">Sammy</charList>
        <charList type="nonrecurring" id="Cash">Cash</charList>
        <charList type="nonrecurring" id="Overload">Overload</charList>
        <charList type="nonrecurring" id="Boy">Boy</charList>
        <charList type="recurring" id="Gizmo" subtype="villain">Gizmo</charList>
        <charList type="nonrecurring" id="Waitress">Waitress</charList>
    </characterList>
    <body>
        <act n="0">
            <title>Prologue</title>
            <sd><stageDesc category="open-shot">Opening shot: a litter of auto parts and tools on a garage floor.</stageDesc> The sound of
                mechanical work is heard from o.c., and <directNote kind="pan">the camera pans across the jumble</directNote> and <directNote kind="cut">cuts
                to each of the following in turn</directNote>. First, a bit of spot welding is carried out. Sheet
                metal is cut to make a body panel, after which a shock absorber is set in place and
                a hubcap is bolted on. Next, a taillight is installed; in this shot, we see <char>Cyborg</char>'s
                hand holding the part; he is the one putting this vehicle together. <stageDesc category="overhead-shot">An engine is
                lowered toward the camera on an overhead crane</stageDesc>, <directNote kind="black-screen">blacking out the screen when it is
                close enough</directNote>. From here, <directNote kind="snap">snap to <stageDesc category="close-up">a close-up of it in place</stageDesc></directNote>; <char>Cyborg</char> reaches into view
                and torques a couple of bolts. <stageDesc category="close-up">Extreme close-up of the open hood</stageDesc>, which he closes
                before smiling and removing a rag from his shoulder to wipe his forehead.</sd>

            <sd><char>Cyborg</char> climbs into the driver's seat and presses a button on the dashboard. No
                response.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>Huh?</sp>

            <sd>He hunches down over the steering wheel and starts grumbling to himself. A thought
                balloon appears over his head, with assorted components scrolling by as if on a
                stock ticker. After a few seconds, they are replaced by a glowing light bulb. <char>Cyborg</char>
                straightens up as the balloon evaporates, he has hit on something.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>Ha!</sp>

            <sd>He snaps his fingers and opens a panel on his chest. A circuit board pops out; he
                removes this and slips it into a slot on the dash. Rubbing his hands gleefully, he
                tries the starter button again. This time, the engine sputters as he grimaces
                nervously, and then it roars in full voice and brings an enormous smile to his
                face.</sd>

            <sd><directNote kind="dissolve">Dissolve to him standing by the vehicle, which is now covered with a tarp.</directNote> <annot>His
                garage doubles as the storage area of Titans Tower seen in "Final Exam" and
                "Switched."</annot> The other <char>Titans</char> are gathered nearby.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>Drum roll, please!</sp>

            <sd><char>Beast Boy</char> turns into <transform class="mammal">a lemur</transform> and starts thumping his belly to fill the request.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>Ladies and gentlemen, and whatever <char>Beast Boy</char>
                is...</sp>

            <sd><char>Beast Boy</char> returns to his <transform class="human">human form</transform>.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr><sd>angrily</sd>Hey, <char>Cyborg</char>. You want a drum
                roll or not?</sp>

            <sd>He drops out of sight, and the sound effect, the real thing this time, he starts
                back up.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>Sorry.<sd>with increasing fervor</sd>It is my great
                pleasure to present, for the first time anywhere, the thing you've all been waiting
                for, my coolest, hottest, baddest creation--</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Raven">Raven</spkr>Just get on with it.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>I give you the future of <char>Titans</char> transportation, the
                one, the only...</sp>

            <sd>He whips the tarp away, backing o.c. as he does so. <annot>The car he built stands fully
                exposed for the first time</annot>: <charDesc ref="T-Car">white body with blue trim along sides and front bumper
                that resembles the circuitry seen through the transparent coverings on <char>Cyborg</char>'s
                body</charDesc>.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr><sd>from o.c.</sd>...<char>T-CAR</char>!!</sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="cut">Cut to <char>Robin</char>, who stares wide-eyed in admiration.</directNote> The other three onlookers peek out
                from behind him; <char>Raven</char> is considerably less enthused than the rest.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>Dude!</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Robin">Robin</spkr>Cool!</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Starfire">Starfire</spkr>Oooooh!</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr><sd>patting it</sd>Yep, she's my baby.</sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="cut">Cut to a close-up of each part as he names it.</directNote></sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr><sd>from o.c.</sd><charDesc ref="T-Car">One-hundred-thousand-horsepower
                plasma-turbine engine...all-terrain hoverjets...antilock air brakes...and an onboard
                computer that links with my systems, so I can literally feel the road.</charDesc></sp>

            <sd>A small panel pops up in front of the array of processors to show his hugely
                grinning face. <char>Starfire</char> and the other two boys are still very much impressed, but
                <char>Raven</char> has fallen asleep on her feet.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>Whoa!</sp>

            <sd><char>Robin</char> whistles.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Starfire">Starfire</spkr>Amazing!</sp>

            <sd><stageDesc category="close-up">Close-up of the driver's side door.</stageDesc> During the next line, the window rolls down to
                give a good view of the interior and <directNote kind="cut">the camera cuts to the sound system control
                panel, which promptly comes to life</directNote>.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr><sd>from o.c.</sd>And of course, <charDesc ref="T-Car">leather seats,
                power windows, and a booming stereo are all standard</charDesc>.</sp>

            <sd>A heavy beat starts up. <stageDesc>Now the <char>Titans</char>' silhouettes and the <char>T-Car</char> appear against a
                blue background.</stageDesc> <directNote kind="gag">Sight gag: two enormous speakers pop out of the roof, cranking the
                line up so high that everyone but <char>Cyborg</char> is blown off their feet.</directNote> The gag ends, and
                up come <char>Beast Boy</char>, <char>Robin</char>, and <char>Starfire</char>, all momentarily dazed and disheveled from
                the sonic onslaught.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>Sweet!</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Robin">Robin</spkr>Nice!</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Starfire">Starfire</spkr>It sings!</sp>

            <sd><char>Raven</char> stands, close enough for <stageDesc category="close-up">the camera to frame her face in extreme close-up</stageDesc>. She
                is still absolutely unaffected by the demonstration in any way.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Raven">Raven</spkr>Can we go now?</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>You bet, <char>Raven</char>. I'll take you anyplace you want to
                go.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>The beach!</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Robin">Robin</spkr>The movies!</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Starfire">Starfire</spkr>The swamp moons of Drenthax IV!</sp>

            <sd>The two boys are so floored by this that they keel over; she blushes in
                embarrassment.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Starfire">Starfire</spkr>He said anyplace.</sp>

            <sd>As they get up and <char>Robin</char> rubs his head, his communicator sounds off. He checks
                it.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Robin">Robin</spkr>Trouble!</sp>

            <sd>The engine revs up; <char>Cyborg</char> is already at the wheel.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>I'll drive!</sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="snap">Snap to black.</directNote></sd>

            <cue>OPENING THEME</cue>

        </act>
        <act n="1">
            <title>Act One</title>
            <sd><stageDesc category="open-shot">Opening shot: the <char>T-Car</char> rolling on a winding mountain road.</stageDesc> It is nighttime, and the
                Tower is visible in the distance. Inside, <char>Raven</char> peeks out from behind <char>Cyborg</char>'s seat;
                <char>Robin</char> is next to her.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Raven">Raven</spkr>Are we there yet?</sp>

            <sd><char>Cyborg</char> grinds his teeth a bit.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>NO!!</sp>

            <sd><stageDesc category="close-up">Close-up of the dashboard.</stageDesc> <char>Starfire</char>'s hands zip here and there, pressing every
                button within reach, as her giddy laughter is heard from o.c. <directNote kind="pull">Pull back; she is
                riding shotgun and completely freaking him out with her goofing off.</directNote> The next two
                lines are spoken together.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Starfire">Starfire</spkr>So many fascinating buttons!...<charDesc ref="T-Car">Your baby</charDesc> is
                most entertaining...Ooooh!</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>Stop!...Don't!...Careful with...Not the ejector
                seat!...Would you cut it...</sp>

            <sd>The windshield wipers start up; <char>Starfire</char> gasps and laughs.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Starfire">Starfire</spkr>Look! They are dancing!</sp>

            <sd>He is so stunned, he cannot speak for a moment.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr><sd>looks in the rear view mirror</sd>Yo!</sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="cut">Cut to just outside the rear door on the passenger side.</directNote> The window is down, and
                Beast Boy, as <transform class="mammal">a St. Bernard</transform>, is leaning out to savor the wind. Drool spatters
                everywhere from his lolling tongue.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr><sd>angrily, leans into view</sd>I know you're not
                drooling on my paint job.</sp>

            <sd>He backs away; <charDesc ref="Beast Boy">the green canine</charDesc> reverts to <transform class="human">human form</transform> and laughs sheepishly. Saliva
                still dribbles down his cheek.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>My bad.</sp>

            <sd>Up front, <char>Starfire</char>'s eyes are still glued to those wipers. <char>Cyborg</char> shuts them off,
                deflating her mood considerably, and he smiles and lets off a relieved sigh at
                having gotten everything back under control.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>All right, y'all, hang on. Time to kick <charDesc ref="T-Car">my baby</charDesc>
                into high gear and see what she can--</sp>

            <sd>They reach Jump City.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Robin">Robin</spkr><sd>leans forward and points</sd>There! Stop the
                car!</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr><sd>disappointed</sd>Oh, man...</sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="cut">Cut to the exterior of Cook's Electronics.</directNote> Lights blaze and pulse through the open
                front entrance as several screaming people run for cover. The <char>T-Car</char> skids across the
                parking lot and comes to a very neat stop at the curb. First out is <char>Beast Boy</char>, who
                stumbles dizzily to the pavement, then <char>Robin</char>, who has himself a bit more under
                control.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Robin">Robin</spkr>Titans! Go!</sp>

            <sd>All but <char>Cyborg</char> charge toward the store. <directNote kind="cut">Cut to a close-up of the steering wheel</directNote>; he
                fits a locking device into place to immobilize it. Now he is out and wiping the
                windshield lovingly; the <char>T-Car</char> has been moved to a proper parking space.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>Coming!</sp>

            <sd><charDesc ref="Sammy and Cash">Two teenage boys sidle up, one short, one tall and wearing sunglasses, with a
                toothpick in his mouth. Both fit the profile of the typical 1950s street gang
                member: T-shirt, jeans, leather jacket.</charDesc> <charDesc ref="Sammy">The short one is <char>Sammy</char></charDesc>, <charDesc ref="Cash">the tall one
                <char>Cash</char></charDesc>.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Sammy">Sammy</spkr>Dude! That is phat!</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cash">Cash</spkr><charDesc ref="T-Car">Sweet ride. She yours?</charDesc></sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr><charDesc ref="T-Car">Built her with my own two hands, using the finest
                parts and cutting-edge techn--</charDesc></sp>

            <sd>He trails off into a surprised yell as <char>Raven</char> reaches into view and seizes him by the
                ear to drag him into Cook's.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Raven">Raven</spkr><sd>disgustedly</sd>Boys.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>Whoa! Almost forgot to switch on the alarm.</sp>

            <sd>He pulls out a keychain remote and hits a button; the headlights flash and a siren
                blips briefly to show that the alarm is now active. <char>Cash</char> and <char>Sammy</char> back up a step at
                this, but continue to gaze upon the home-built conveyance. After a second or two,
                they trade a knowing look.</sd>

            <sd><directNote kind="cut">Cut to inside the store.</directNote> <stageDesc category="setting">High-voltage arcs play among shelves of stereo speakers,
                which crumble into dust that is quickly sucked down. Televisions and VCRs receive
                the same treatment.</stageDesc> <directNote kind="cut">Cut to the ceiling</directNote>, awash in current, and <directNote kind="tilt">tilt down to frame the
                far wall</directNote>. <charDesc ref="Overload">Standing there is a large figure composed entirely of electricity save for
                a small dark patch at its center; the arms are outstretched, forming the source of
                the arcs. This is <char>Overload</char>.</charDesc></sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Overload">Overload</spkr>Mine! All mine!</sp>

            <sd><stageDesc category="close-up">In close-up, <charDesc ref="Overload">we see that the dark patch is a circuit board whose pathways form a
                grinning one-eyed face</charDesc>.</stageDesc> <directNote kind="pan">Pan to the five <char>Titans</char> at the entrance as he turns toward
                them.</directNote></sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Robin">Robin</spkr><oneLine>If you're going to take all that stuff...<sd>They
                    rush in.</sd>...you'd better be ready to pay for it.</oneLine></sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Overload">Overload</spkr><charDesc ref="Titans">Foolish biologicals.</charDesc> <char>Overload</char> will
                destroy!</sp>

            <sd>He pounds the floor, sending a few thousand amperes straight at the team; they
                scatter to avoid the shock. <char>Robin</char> leaps high and has his fighting staff out and
                extended in a trice, and he twirls to block the shot and then flings a handful of
                discs. <char>Overload</char> deflects these easily and blasts <char>Robin</char> across the store; he passes
                <char>Raven</char> as he tumbles. She levitates several pieces of hardware.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Raven">Raven</spkr>Azarath Metrion Zinthos!</sp>

            <sd>The items rocket toward <char>Overload</char> and disappear into his body; instead of being hurt,
                though, he merely grows several feet and roars heartily. She retreats to where <char>Beast
                Boy</char> is crouched atop a display case.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>Smooth.</sp>

            <sd>Turning into <transform class="mammal">a rabbit</transform>, <char>Beast Boy</char> hops down and <char>Raven</char> bugs out just before the case
                is blown apart. Now <char>Starfire</char> gets into the game with a pass over the walking spark
                plug's head and a string of starbolts without effect. His counterstrike sends her
                careening out of control to crash into the wall, not too far from <char>Cyborg</char>.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>Yo, <charDesc ref="Overload">Radiohead</charDesc>!<sd>leans to the camera; <stageDesc category="close-up">extreme
                    close-up</stageDesc></sd><oneLine>Listen to this!</oneLine></sp>

            <sd>He backs up again, <charDesc ref="Cyborg">framing his right arm in sonic cannon mode</charDesc>, and lets off a huge
                beam and a mighty yell at the same time. This attack also does no visible damage.
                <char>Overload</char> pours himself into a handy stereo speaker, which grows large enough to
                reach the ceiling and puts out a thundering wall of sound. A second yell, this one
                of pain, comes from <char>Cyborg</char> as he is hurled the length of the showroom, slamming into
                a column and tumbling to the floor.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Overload">Overload</spkr><sd>from o.c., grabbing <char>Cyborg</char></sd>Mine!</sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="cut">Cut to <charDesc ref="Overload">the supercharged evildoer</charDesc>, holding the struggling <char>Cyborg</char> aloft.</directNote></sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr><oneLine>I'll bet you're not waterproof!</oneLine></sp>

            <sd>He throws a devastating right jab that makes <char>Overload</char> drop him and skid across the
                floor toward a water cooler some distance away. The bottle flies overhead, and a
                fair amount of the contents splashes down on <charDesc ref="Overload">the electric figure</charDesc>; his face strains
                in discomfort as he gulps the water down.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Robin">Robin</spkr>Good idea. <char>Titans</char>! Soak him!</sp>

            <sd><char>Raven</char> exerts her powers over a water fountain and rips it from the wall, and the
                broken pipes start to gush. The cooler bottle is in the hands of the again, <transform class="human">human</transform>
                <char>Beast Boy</char>; he chugs every drop, becomes <transform class="mammal">an elephant</transform>, and uses his trunk as a fire
                hose. Next, <char>Starfire</char> put a few shots on the ceiling-mounted sprinklers, knocking
                them all off to create one shower after another. <char>Robin</char>, meanwhile, has the actual
                fire hose in hand with the nozzle full open. The combined effect of the four
                assaults shrinks <char>Overload</char> and drives him groaning to the floor. Smiling
                triumphantly, the <char>Titans</char> stand over him; <char>Beast Boy</char> is back in <transform class="human">human form</transform>.</sd>

            <sd><directNote kind="dissolve">Dissolve to the exterior of Cook's.</directNote> Out come the heroes; <directNote kind="cut">cut to <stageDesc category="close-up">a close-up of
                <char>Overload</char></stageDesc>, who has been rolled in a thick blanket to protect them from his charge.</directNote>
                <directNote kind="pull">Pull back to frame the entire entrance.</directNote> <char>Starfire</char> is carrying the criminal, while
                <char>Beast Boy</char> has frozen in his tracks and is staring dumbstruck at something o.c. The
                other four head out.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>Soon as we hand <charDesc ref="Overload">Sparky</charDesc> over to the cops...<sd>stops
                    and elbows <char>Beast Boy</char></sd>...how 'bout we swing by the drive-thru?</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr><sd>gestures vaguely</sd>Uh...dude?</sp>

            <sd><char>Cyborg</char> looks ahead and lets off a huge, shocked gasp. <directNote kind="cut">Cut to <stageDesc category="overhead-shot">an overhead view of the
                parking lot</stageDesc></directNote>, with five <char>Titans</char> near the door and no <char>T-Car</char> anywhere in sight. Ground
                level; <char>Cyborg</char> runs across the blacktop in a panic.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>My wheel lock! My car alarm! <charDesc ref="T-Car">My baby!</charDesc><sd>collapses
                    and sobs</sd>Somebody stole <charDesc ref="T-Car">my baby</charDesc>!</sp>

            <sd><stageDesc category="close-up">Close-up of <charDesc ref="T-Car">the baby in question</charDesc>, speeding through the streets, with <char>Cash</char> and <char>Sammy</char>
                hanging out the front windows and whooping it up.</stageDesc> The former is driving the now-hot
                car in this joyride.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cash">Cash</spkr>Yeah!</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Sammy">Sammy</spkr>Make it go faster! Make it go faster!</sp>

            <sd>More shouting and laughter as the car speeds up and disappears over the hill. <directNote kind="fade">Fade
                to black.</directNote></sd>

        </act>
        <act n="2">
            <title>Act Two</title>
            <sd><stageDesc category="open-shot">Opening shot: a close-up of <char>Cyborg</char>, still in the Cook's parking lot, with tears
                streaming down his face.</stageDesc></sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>Noooo!</sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="pull">Pull back.</directNote> The broken wheel lock and ripped-out car alarm are in his hands, and
                <char>Starfire</char> and <char>Robin</char> stand behind him. She has set <char>Overload</char> down.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>No, no, no, no, no...</sp>

            <sd>He hangs his head sadly; the movement exposes <char>Beast Boy</char> directly behind him.
                <char>Starfire</char> steps up and places a hand on his back to console him.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Starfire">Starfire</spkr>I understand your pain, <char>Cyborg</char>. When I was
                small, my favorite zarnik was eaten by a rampaging gloorg. Believe me, after your
                zarnik has been inside a gloorg, you do not want it back.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>My car wasn't eaten. It was stolen!</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>Hey, look on the bright side. At least it
                wasn't my fault.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Robin">Robin</spkr>Not helping.<sd><char>Beast Boy</char> laughs nervously; <char>Robin</char>
                    addresses <char>Cyborg</char>.</sd>We'll help you find your car, I promise. But right now,
                we've gotta take <char>Overload</char> to jail.</sp>

            <sd><charDesc ref="Overload">The soggy villain grumbles wearily inside his blanket.</charDesc> <directNote kind="cut">Cut to all five <char>Titans</char>.</directNote></sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>No! We gotta go now! Every second we wait is a
                second, she could get scratched or dinged or--</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Raven">Raven</spkr>Calm down. It's just a car.</sp>

            <sd><stageDesc category="close-up">Extreme close-up of <charDesc ref="Cyborg">the distressed owner</charDesc>, whose over-shoulder glare shows just what
                he thinks of this remark.</stageDesc> He pivots to put his entire face in view, after which <directNote kind="pull">the
                camera pulls back and he gets in hers</directNote>.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>She's not just a car, she's my car.<sd>stalking
                    away</sd>And I'm gonna find her, whether you guys help me or not!</sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="dissolve">Dissolve to a drive-in restaurant at the height of the evening rush.</directNote> All the stalls
                are filled with customers chowing down. As a waitress fits a tray onto one driver's
                door, <char>Cyborg</char> marches resolutely up and gets funny stares from both of them. <directNote kind="cut">Cut to
                his perspective</directNote>; he advances along the walk in front of the place as everybody stops
                whatever they are doing to stare. <charDesc ref="Boy">At the end of the path is a fellow who, seen from
                the back, looks very much like <char>Cash</char>.</charDesc> After a few seconds, <stageDesc>close-up of him</stageDesc>; he is
                talking to a friend, and <annot>his voice reveals that he is not the car thief</annot>.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Boy">Boy</spkr><sd>gesturing</sd>It had a tailpipe this big!</sp>

            <sd><char>Cyborg</char> comes up behind him; the other youth gets spooked and runs off.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr><sd>hauling <charDesc ref="Boy">the boy up by his jacket lapels</charDesc></sd>I'm
                looking for my car. <charDesc ref="T-Car">Tricked-out hardtop with a growl that'll make your teeth shake.</charDesc>
                Ring any bells?</sp>

            <sd><charDesc ref="Boy">The subject of this up-close interrogation</charDesc> sweats profusely during this line.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Boy">Boy</spkr>Um, yeah, yeah, um-- <char>Sammy</char> and <char>Cash</char> cruised by in a car
                like that. <charDesc ref="T-Car">Looks really cool with those flames painted on it.</charDesc></sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr><sd>shakes him</sd><charDesc ref="T-Car">They painted my baby</charDesc>?!?<sd>sets
                    him down</sd>Where are they?</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Boy">Boy</spkr>Well, they were looking to race, so they headed
                    to...<sd>points</sd>...Crash Alley.</sp>

            <sd><char>Cyborg</char> pushes him to the ground and gives the camera a long, stunned look. <directNote kind="cut">Cut to a
                billboard for the Crash Alley Raceway.</directNote> The distinctive sound of racing engines is
                heard; <directNote kind="pan">pan to bring the track into view nearby</directNote>. At the starting line, the <char>T-Car</char>
                pulls up in front of the packed grandstands. True to the boy's description, <charDesc ref="T-Car">orange
                flames have been painted across the hood and front bumper, spilling back along the
                sides</charDesc>. Next to it, a tiny vehicle rolls up; it almost looks like a circus clown car,
                but with a normal paint job. An antenna sprouts from the rear end, marking it as an
                oversized radio-control car. <char>Sammy</char> rolls down his window so he and <char>Cash</char> can get a
                good look.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Sammy">Sammy</spkr><sd>laughing</sd>Hey, <char>Cash</char>! Check out the cute little
                windup toy!</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cash">Cash</spkr><oneLine>Get out the butter and jam, <char>Sammy</char>, 'cause this dude is
                toast.</oneLine></sp>

            <sd>Both engines rev up. The starting lights drop from red through yellow and finally to
                green, and they are off the line in a wailing screech of smoking rubber. The <char>T-Car</char>
                and the midget racer edge back and forth a few times before <char>Cash</char> and <char>Sammy</char> nudge the
                competition aside and speed ahead. They repeat the performance when it starts to
                pull even again, but the tiny auto drives up onto the banked outer wall of the track
                and zooms on. When it comes back down, it has taken the lead. The fans cheer wildly.
                Now <char>Cash</char> and <char>Sammy</char> find themselves stuck behind the swerving micro-car and unable to
                get out in front.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Sammy">Sammy</spkr>Dude, we're getting smoked!</sp>

            <sd><char>Cash</char> floors the accelerator and gets them ahead.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cash">Cash</spkr>Then we'll smoke him right back.</sp>

            <sd>He presses a button labeled "Smoke," causing thick clouds of it to pour from the
                rear into the path of the other car. They soon part to reveal the vehicle charging
                on; with a small vacuum nozzle deployed under the front bumper, sucking up the
                fumes. Those tiny headlights begin to grow in <char>Cash</char>'s side view mirror; now he goes
                for the "Oil Slick" control, and pipes pop out from the rear bumper and spew copious
                amounts of motor oil. The little car's axles extend to either side, putting the
                tires beyond the edges of the slick, and the body rises a few feet on the slender
                rods to avoid the hazard. It rolls neatly past, and over, the <char>T-Car</char> before reverting
                to its original configuration. Again the fans cheer.</sd>

            <sd><char>Cash</char> is still bent over the wheel. <char>Sammy</char> fixes a bemused stare straight ahead for a
                second or two before looking at the dash.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Sammy">Sammy</spkr>Hey, what's this one do?</sp>

            <sd>He presses a button and gets his answer after a short delay: the <char>T-Car</char> accelerates
                dramatically and tears ahead. It goes crazily up the wall and comes down in front
                before crossing the finish line to take the checkered flag. With the race over, <char>Cash</char>
                and <char>Sammy</char> do a sharp U-turn and come to a stop, then leap out.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Sammy">Sammy</spkr>Dude! That was the bomb!</sp>

            <sd>The other car stops in front of them.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cash">Cash</spkr>The fastest car in town, and she's totally ours.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Gizmo">Gizmo</spkr><sd>from o.c.</sd>Not anymore, <charDesc ref="Sammy and Cash">pit-sniffers</charDesc>!</sp>

            <sd><char>Gizmo</char>, <annot>you may recall, was <charDesc ref="Gizmo">one of the three H.I.V.E. Academy graduates hired by
                <char>Slade</char> to take on the <char>Titans</char> in "Final Exam."</charDesc></annot> There is a brilliant flash; when it
                clears, <charDesc ref="Sammy and Cash">the two juvenile delinquents</charDesc> are caught within a spherical force field
                projected by the little car's headlights. Slowly but surely, they are lifted into
                the air; the surprise leaves them unable to get a coherent word out for a
                moment.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Sammy">Sammy</spkr>Hey!</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cash">Cash</spkr>Huh? Hey, dude, what's going on here, huh?</sp>

            <sd>The lights shut off, and the entire mini-auto rises into the air to expose <char>Gizmo</char>
                himself on all fours. It folds itself away into the central equipment pack on his
                back; he stands up.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Gizmo">Gizmo</spkr>Check out <char>Gizmo</char>'s bonzer new wheels.<sd>He crosses to
                    the <char>T-Car</char>.</sd>Thanks, hogs. I've been needing a faster getaway car.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Sammy">Sammy</spkr>Wait! You can't take it, it's not ours!</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cash">Cash</spkr>Yeah, we were just kind of borrowing it from the
                <char>Titans</char>.</sp>

            <sd><char>Gizmo</char>, in the driver's seat, laughs.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Gizmo">Gizmo</spkr>Even better.</sp>

            <sd>His perspective of the dash; he turns on a viewscreen, which shows the imprisoned
                pair and a set of crosshairs. Next to this are four buttons; "Ignition," "Oil
                Slick," "Proton Cannon," "Smoke." It goes without saying which of these has to do
                with those crosshairs.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Gizmo">Gizmo</spkr>So long, <charDesc ref="Sammy and Cash">snot-munchers</charDesc>!</sp>

            <sd>On the end of this, <directNote kind="cut">cut to <stageDesc category="close-up">a close-up of one screeching tire</stageDesc></directNote> and <directNote kind="pull">pull back</directNote>. He
                brings the <char>T-Car</char> around sharply and is off with a mighty roar of the engine. <directNote kind="tilt">Tilt up
                from the track to <char>Cash</char> and <char>Sammy</char>, who can only watch helplessly from within the
                force field.</directNote></sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cash">Cash</spkr>This is all your fault.</sp>

            <sd>They are yanked out; <directNote kind="cut">cut to <char>Cyborg</char> holding them</directNote>.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cash #Sammy">Cash and Sammy</spkr>Hey!</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cash">Cash</spkr>What's going on, buddy?</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr><sd>icily</sd>I want my car.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Sammy">Sammy</spkr>Yeah, see, um, the thing is, we sort of lost it in a
                race.</sp>

            <sd>Pause.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>You lost my car?!? My car lost a race?!?</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cash">Cash</spkr>No way! We beat him easy. She handled like a
                dream.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr><sd>smiles and starts setting them down</sd>She
                did? How'd she take the curves? 'Cause, you know, I've been working on the
                suspension for a-d-d-d-d-d-d...<sd>angry again</sd>...don't try to distract me. Who
                has her now?</sp>

            <sd>A big drop of sweat pops out on <char>Cash</char>'s temple.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Sammy">Sammy</spkr>Dude named <char>Gizmo</char>. Said something about a getaway car
                and headed downtown.</sp>

            <sd>They are both unceremoniously stuffed back into the force field. <char>Cyborg</char> heads off to
                continue tracking down his beloved <char>T-Car</char>.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cash">Cash</spkr><sd>as he and <char>Sammy</char> pound on field</sd>Hey!</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Sammy">Sammy</spkr>You can't just leave us like this!</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr><sd>now o.c.</sd>You're right.<sd><directNote kind="shift">Shift to frame
                    all three.</directNote></sd>I'll make sure the cops come pick you up.</sp>

            <sd>They trade a very scared look and start crying. <directNote kind="dissolve">Dissolve to a bank, whose drive-up
                window is occupied by the idling stolen vehicle.</directNote> Inside, the sunroof is open and a
                hose leading from the building is blowing cash into the back seat. <directNote kind="pan">Pan from the
                sizable accumulated pile to <char>Gizmo</char> at the wheel</directNote>, waist-mounted control unit in hand
                to work the car's systems.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Gizmo">Gizmo</spkr>This is too easy.<sd><directNote kind="cut">Cut to behind him</directNote>; <charDesc ref="T-Car">he has added
                    fuzzy dice to the rear view mirror</charDesc>.</sd>Wonder if there's a drive-thru jewelry
                store around here.</sp>

            <sd><char>Cyborg</char> drops into view and lands on the hood. The boiling mad visage startles a yell
                out of <char>Gizmo</char>.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>Get <charDesc ref="Gizmo">your tiny butt</charDesc> outta my car!</sp>

            <sd>With another panicked cry, <charDesc ref="Gizmo">the owner of that tiny butt</charDesc> starts punching buttons
                furiously. The <char>T-Car</char> peels out backward.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>Whoa!</sp>

            <sd>Reaching the street, <char>Gizmo</char> puts it in drive and lays rubber.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr><sd>staring at the rear view mirror</sd>Fuzzy dice?
                Aw, now that's just tacky.<sd>A sharp turn into a car wash.</sd>Whoa!</sp>

            <sd><char>Gizmo</char>'s laughter echoes from inside as the <char>T-Car</char> passes through the whirling brushes
                and jets of water. <char>Cyborg</char> yells in fright.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>No! Keep those nasty plastic brushes off my baby!
                She's hand-wash only!</sp>

            <sd>By this time, they have passed the scrubbing area. Suds pour down over a thoroughly
                peeved amateur mechanic; when they are rinsed off, he has bared all his teeth in a
                snarl accentuated by the hot air pouring from the drying nozzles to peel his lips
                back. Ever so slowly, the ride emerges from the car wash, sparkling clean, as is
                <char>Cyborg</char>, glaring through the windshield at <char>Gizmo</char>, who has stuck his tongue out. <charDesc ref="T-Car">The
                flame paint job applied by <char>Cash</char> and <char>Sammy</char> has been scrubbed away.</charDesc> They barrel off
                past a "Construction Zone Ahead" sign.</sd>

            <sd><char>Cyborg</char> yells time and again as <char>Gizmo</char> swerves through a string of cones and the tires
                bounce on the broken road surface. The <char>Titan</char> is doing his best to hang on to that
                hood. Now he is carried up a steep incline; <char>Cyborg</char> groans loudly as the gears start
                to grind.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>The clutch! You gotta use the clutch!</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Gizmo">Gizmo</spkr><sd>grinning</sd>I know, <charDesc ref="Cyborg">you stinking hood
                ornament</charDesc>!</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>Are you even old enough to drive?</sp>

            <sd>He gets a tongue stuck out at him again. The <char>T-Car</char> reaches the top of the hill and
                goes airborne for a few seconds before slamming back onto the road. A too-close
                encounter with a telephone pole leaves a long gouge on the passenger-side panels;
                <char>Cyborg</char> gasps in fright, turns his left hand into a circular buffer, and starts
                working on it.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>That'll buff right out, that'll buff right
                out...</sp>

            <sd>He is swept too close to another pole, which knocks the buffer pad away to clatter
                on the pavement. <stageDesc category="long-shot">Long shot of the hot auto, now paralleling a river</stageDesc>; <directNote kind="pan">pan ahead to a
                drawbridge over the waterway</directNote>. The two halves start to rise as a trash barge
                approaches, and the wheels tear toward the "Bridge Closed Ahead" sign, whose warning
                lights have begun flashing. Crash through a barricade, up the increasingly steeper
                slope, and <char>Cyborg</char> is on the verge of total meltdown.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>Hit the nitro!<sd><stageDesc category="close-up">Close-up of <char>Gizmo</char>, very scared</stageDesc>;
                    he continues o.c.</sd>HIT THE NITRO!!</sp>

            <sd>The proper button is located and punched, a mighty blast pours from the exhaust;
                <annot>this was the button <char>Sammy</char> pushed earlier</annot>, and the <char>T-Car</char> picks up speed as it did
                during the race at Crash Alley. It sails off the end of the bridge, gaining altitude
                as the barge passes beneath and <char>Cyborg</char> finally loses his grip, and touches down on
                the far end. <directNote kind="cut">Cut to him in midair above the river</directNote>; he yells all the way down to the
                barge and lands squarely amid its piled-up cargo, while <stageDesc category="overhead-shot">seagulls circle overhead</stageDesc>. As
                he picks a banana peel off his head, <char>Cyborg</char>'s facial expression shows that he has
                had about three times as much of this as he can take. The bridge lowers again.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr><sd>wearily</sd>Oh, man...</sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="fade">Fade to black.</directNote></sd>

        </act>
        <act n="3">
            <title>Act Three</title>
            <sd><stageDesc category="open-shot">Opening shot: the drive-in restaurant to which Cyborg tracked his wheels in Act One.</stageDesc>
                <stageDesc category="long-shot">It is now framed in a long shot</stageDesc>; he is sitting despondently on the curb, with
                several items scattered around him. A car pulls up, and <stageDesc category="close-up">in close-up these things are
                revealed to be empty milkshake cups</stageDesc>. <char>Raven</char> comes around on the sidewalk behind
                him.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Raven">Raven</spkr>Fourteen milkshakes. Not a good sign.</sp>

            <sd>She sits down next to him.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>What are you doing here?</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Raven">Raven</spkr>Looking for your car. Soon as we turned <char>Overload</char> in
                to the police, we all split up to search the city.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>Might as well stop looking. <char>T-Car</char>'s probably
                halfway to Metropolis by now.<sd>Pause.</sd><charDesc ref="T-Car">From the day I designed her, I knew she
                was gonna be special. And I worked so hard, every fuel injector, every spark plug, I
                made her perfect. I put my heart, soul, and circuits into that car.</charDesc> And now, she's
                gone forever.<sd>Pause.</sd>Maybe you were right. Maybe it was just a car.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Raven">Raven</spkr>Maybe. Maybe not.<sd><directNote kind="zoom">Zoom in slowly on both.</directNote></sd>When
                I use my powers, I have to put a little of my soul into whatever I'm moving. I
                become a part of it, and it becomes a part of me. That's kinda what happened here.
                It wasn't just a car. <charDesc ref="T-Car">It was...your baby.</charDesc></sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr><sd>brightening a bit</sd>Yeah.</sp>

            <sd><stageDesc category="close-up">Close-up of Raven</stageDesc>; she gives him a small smile of her own.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr><sd>from o.c.</sd>Thanks, <charDesc ref="Raven">Rae</charDesc>.</sp>

            <sd>Screech of tires.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Raven">Raven</spkr>And someone's eating onion rings in <charDesc ref="T-Car">your baby</charDesc>.</sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="pan">Pan to <char>Cyborg</char>, who turns to look in the direction of the noise.</directNote> His eyes go wide;
                <directNote kind="cut">cut to the parking lot, where the <char>T-Car</char> is about to peel out with <char>Gizmo</char> still
                driving</directNote>. A waitress rolls up on her skates.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Waitress">Waitress</spkr>Hey! You didn't pay!</sp>

            <sd><char>Gizmo</char> just laughs as he lays rubber away from the place.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>HE'LL GET KETCHUP ON THE SEATS!!</sp>

            <sd><char>Raven</char> looks in a different direction and taps his shoulder to draw his attention.
                Pointing o.c. at something, she moves off after it. Across the parking lot, standing
                by a black convertible with the top down, are <char>Cash</char> and <char>Sammy</char>; they are talking with
                another waitress.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cash">Cash</spkr>So we were stuck. Looked like we'd get busted for
                sure.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Sammy">Sammy</spkr>But then we totally escaped before the cops showed
                up.</sp>

            <sd>They suddenly find themselves on the receiving end of <char>Raven</char>'s powers and are hoisted
                into the air as the waitress stares in total puzzlement.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Raven">Raven</spkr>Escape from that before the cops show up!</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr><sd>looking at the car</sd>Sweet ride.<sd>holds up
                    keys</sd>Mind if we borrow it?</sp>

            <sd><charDesc ref="Sammy and Cash">The two young hoodlums have no response but a pair of very scared smiles.</charDesc> <directNote kind="cut">Cut to a
                stretch of road outside Jump City</directNote>; <charDesc ref="T-Car">the twice-stolen <char>T-Car</char></charDesc> rockets around a curve.
                Inside, we see that <char>Gizmo</char> has connected his waist controller to the steering wheel
                and is operating it remotely. He now has both hands free to enjoy the meal he ripped
                off from the drive-in. The honk of a car horn causes him to spit out a mouthful of
                soda. <stageDesc category="close-up">Close-up of the rear view mirror</stageDesc>; the borrowed convertible is gaining
                fast.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Gizmo">Gizmo</spkr><sd>from o.c.</sd>CRUD!</sp>

            <sd>He speeds around a curve in the mountains, but the black roadster keeps pace easily.
                With a frustrated groan, <char>Gizmo</char> pulls the controller off the wheel to operate it
                himself. A cloud of exhaust and rubber smoke pours back toward the two <char>Titans</char>.
                <char>Cyborg</char> is driving.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>He may have a better car, but I'm a better
                driver!</sp>

            <sd>The chase continues through the serpentine bends of the two-lane blacktop. <directNote kind="pan">Pan ahead
                a bit to show more twists and turns ahead</directNote>, then <directNote kind="cut">cut to the two cars</directNote>. <char>Cyborg</char> and
                <char>Raven</char> start to close in.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Gizmo">Gizmo</spkr>Eat crude, you stinking losers!</sp>

            <sd>He dumps an oil slick into the <char>Titans</char>' path. <char>Cyborg</char> gasps and cuts his wheels
                sharply, and the car flips up onto its passenger-side tires to keep from running
                through the hazard. It drops out of this side wheelie once the oil is past and zooms
                ahead. As the ultra-high-speed pursuit continues, <char>Gizmo</char> works his own control a bit
                before opening his eyes wide with surprise.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Gizmo">Gizmo</spkr>Ooooh, cool!</sp>

            <sd>He leans forward; <stageDesc category="close-up">close-up of the "Proton Cannon" button</stageDesc>, which he presses. Now the
                roof opens up and this particular weapon extends from within to point back along the
                road. It locks into place and warms up; <char>Cyborg</char>'s eyes pop briefly, and the right one
                tears up.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>Boo-yah! Check out <charDesc ref="T-Car">my baby</charDesc>'s proton cannon.</sp>

            <sd><char>Raven</char> gives him an odd look; he sobers up as a big drop of sweat rolls down his
                temple.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>Uh...I mean...oh, no.</sp>

            <sd><char>Gizmo</char> opens fire, forcing <char>Cyborg</char> to swerve from side to side in order to avoid being
                annihilated. One shot hits the road just ahead of the car; he drives straight on
                through the resulting cloud of smoke. Just at <char>Gizmo</char> rode up on the racetrack wall,
                <char>Cyborg</char> now takes his car up the rock face a few feet, still dodging the cannon
                blasts. Gradually, he eases higher and higher, finally settling on a stretch of road
                that is at an increased elevation. The two single-minded drivers continue their mad
                dash on now-parallel courses.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr><sd>banging the dashboard</sd>Come on! Faster,
                faster!</sp>

            <sd><char>Raven</char> stands up in her seat.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Raven">Raven</spkr>Hang on. Azarath Metrion Zinthos!</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>Yo, what are you--?</sp>

            <sd>The car is flung ahead, forcing a terrified scream from his lungs. <directNote kind="pull">Pull back; the
                entire car, under <char>Raven</char>'s influence, goes flying off the edge of a curve and starts
                to drop.</directNote> <char>Gizmo</char>, on the lower part of the road, is still grinning and working his
                controller, but the sight of <char>Cyborg</char> and <char>Raven</char> smoothly descending to his right
                throws a real surprise his way. The car does not touch the road, but instead eases
                over to knock fenders.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>Pull over!</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Gizmo">Gizmo</spkr><sd>grinning again</sd>Make me, <charDesc ref="Cyborg">Robo-Wimp</charDesc>!</sp>

            <sd>He swerves, pushing the convertible against the rock face, and does a quick
                360-degree spin. <char>Cyborg</char> and <char>Raven</char> come up even again.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>I said, pull over!</sp>

            <sd>He reaches toward the <char>T-Car</char> and gets one hand hooked on the passenger-side front
                door, reaching for <char>Gizmo</char> with the other.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Gizmo">Gizmo</spkr>Hey! Let me go, <charDesc ref="Cyborg">you barf-smelling hairball</charDesc>!</sp>

            <sd>He turns in his seat to break wind in <char>Cyborg</char>'s face.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Raven">Raven</spkr>Okay, making it really hard to concentrate.</sp>

            <sd>They continue on, trading paint as if this were the last NASCAR race of the season.
                A third vehicle pulls partly into view, ahead of them and approaching, and its
                headlights flare over the two <char>Titans</char>.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cyborg #Raven">Cyborg and Raven</spkr>Whoa!</sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="cut">Cut to the source, an approaching prison transport van whose horn is blaring.</directNote> <directNote kind="black-screen">Its
                lights wash out the entire view</directNote>, which quickly <directNote kind="snap">snaps to <stageDesc category="close-up">a close-up of <char>Gizmo</char></stageDesc></directNote>. He has
                just enough time for one yell of sheer panic before the van is upon the group.
                <char>Guards</char> jump clear, leaving it to careen driverless toward <char>Gizmo</char>, <char>Cyborg</char>, and <char>Raven</char>.
                The convertible is levitated to a safe height, and <charDesc ref="Gizmo">the pipsqueak</charDesc> bails out thanks to
                the ejector seat <char>Cyborg</char> warned <char>Starfire</char> not to mess with.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr><sd>half speed</sd>NOOOOOOO!!</sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="cut">Cut to a point above the road as he yells this, the camera aimed at the sky.</directNote> The
                borrowed ragtop and <char>Gizmo</char> both rise into view, and a parachute deploys from the
                latter's seat. A colossal explosion occurs at ground level o.c.; <directNote kind="cut">cut to the crash
                site</directNote>. The van has been knocked onto its side, while the smashed <char>T-Car</char> has fetched up
                against the undercarriage. <directNote kind="pan">Pan away a short distance to a clear patch of road.</directNote> <char>Raven</char>
                brings the convertible down for a soft landing to the sound of the o.c. <char>Gizmo</char>'s very
                nasty laughter; he drifts down into view as they jump out.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Gizmo">Gizmo</spkr>Heh! Looks like your stupid car is--</sp>

            <sd><char>Raven</char> hits the parachute with a burst of telekinesis and causes it to wrap him up in
                a very neat bundle.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr><sd>runs toward the wreck</sd>Please be okay,
                please be okay, please be okay...</sp>

            <sd>Sparks crackle over the side of the overturned van and form into a lightning bolt
                that pours itself into the not-even-close-to-okay <char>T-Car</char>; <annot>only <char>Overload</char> could do
                this.</annot> He was in that van.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Overload">Overload</spkr><sd>from inside</sd>Car is better than
                okay.</sp>

            <sd>It turns to face Cyborg; <stageDesc category="close-up">close-up of <charDesc ref="Overload">the villain</charDesc> at the wheel</stageDesc>.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Overload">Overload</spkr>Car is mine!</sp>

            <sd><charDesc ref="Cyborg">The builder</charDesc> recoils in fear with a small gasp; <char>Overload</char> just laughs and pulls out
                the circuit board that had been put into the dash in the prologue. Throwing it out,
                he feeds himself into the slot it had occupied and all the interior lights go red.
                <stageDesc category="close-up">Extreme close-up of a crack in the windshield, which repairs itself</stageDesc>; <directNote kind="pull">pull back as
                the auto is quickly restored to mint condition</directNote>. However, <charDesc ref="Overload/T-Car">the white bodywork is now
                an angry gray, the blue circuit trim has turned red, and the windows and windshield
                are tinted black. The headlights, narrowed into fierce slits, blaze to life as the
                engine revs up.</charDesc></sd>

            <sd><char>Cyborg</char> growls softly; the <char>Overload/T-Car</char> does likewise. They face each other down
                across the empty yards of asphalt.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Overload/T-Car">Overload/T-Car</spkr>Only way to stop <char>Overload</char> is to
                destroy your precious car!</sp>

            <sd>He/it surges forward with a horrid squeal of rubber. <directNote kind="cut">Cut to Cyborg</directNote> and <directNote kind="zoom">zoom in
                slowly</directNote>; he does not move from his spot, but instead brings out his cannon and aims
                it straight ahead.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr><sd>softly</sd>It's not my car anymore.</sp>

            <sd>He fires a blast straight at the camera. <directNote kind="cut">Cut to the charging possessed vehicle,
                which takes the full force of it</directNote>; <charDesc ref="Overload/T-Car">the entire body is blown off, as are the tires,
                leaving the axles and undercarriage a mass of twisted, skidding metal</charDesc>. A piece of
                debris rolls across the ground, past <char>Gizmo</char>'s fuzzy dice, and stops at <char>Cyborg</char>'s foot.
                <char>Overload</char>'s circuit-board face lies there, but the rest of his body has
                dissipated.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Overload">Overload</spkr><sd>groans wearily and loses
                steam</sd><oneLine><char>Overload</char>...overloaded.</oneLine></sp>

            <sd><char>Overload</char> closes his eye. <directNote kind="dissolve">Dissolve to a second prison van</directNote> and <directNote kind="pan">pan past its rear end
                to the sound of <char>Gizmo</char>'s grumbling</directNote>. It is now sunrise. Two guards have cuffed him and
                are hauling him toward the open doors. Inside, <char>Cash</char> and <char>Sammy</char> have also been
                apprehended. <char>Sammy</char> laughs.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cash">Cash</spkr><sd>to the o.c. <char>Gizmo</char></sd>You got busted.</sp>

            <sd><char>Gizmo</char> is put in.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Gizmo">Gizmo</spkr>So did you, <charDesc ref="Sammy and Cash">you brainless stinkbombs</charDesc>!</sp>

            <sd>The core of <char>Overload</char> is tossed in after the three auto thieves, and the doors are
                closed. <directNote kind="cut">Cut to <char>Cyborg</char> and <char>Raven</char></directNote>, standing among the <char>T-Car</char>'s remains, and <directNote kind="zoom">zoom in
                slowly</directNote>.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>She's gone. Gone forever.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="#Raven">Raven</spkr>Maybe. Maybe not. These are just parts.<sd><directNote kind="cut">Cut to
                    him</directNote>; she continues o.c.</sd>The thing you loved about that car, the thing that
                made her special,<sd>Back to her.</sd>that came from inside you.</sp>

            <sd>She points ahead o.c. <directNote kind="pull">Pull back to ground level, a few feet from the two</directNote>; lying
                among the junk is the original circuit board, intact. He gasps, picks it up, and
                smiles.</sd>

            <sd><directNote kind="dissolve">Dissolve to a litter of auto parts and tools on the floor of the Tower's garage,
                just as in the prologue</directNote>, and <directNote kind="pan">pan across them to the sound of work in progress</directNote>. From
                here, <directNote kind="dissolve">the same sequence of shots is seen, but with a dissolve from one to the next
                instead of a cut</directNote>. Spot welding; body panel cut; shock absorber fitted; hubcap bolted
                on; taillight installed; engine lowered; engine secured; finally, we see <char>Cyborg</char>
                working under the hood of the newly rebuilt <char>T-Car</char>. He passes a tool off, to the side
                hidden by the hood, and <stageDesc category="close-up">closes up to reveal <char>Raven</char> standing there</stageDesc>; <charDesc ref="Raven">her grease-smeared
                face and the implement she took from him tell of the help she has been providing</charDesc>. A
                big, exuberant smile stretches beneath that bright red eye implant, and, for the
                first time, at least in the real world; she uncorks one of her own. <directNote kind="fade">Fade to
                black.</directNote></sd>
        </act>
    </body>
</root>