<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../schema_v2.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?><root>
   <head>
      <episode> HOW LONG IS FOREVER?</episode>
      <writer>David Slack</writer>
      <director>Alex Soto</director>
      <storyboard>Mike Goguen, Sam Liu, Irineo Maramba, Chap Yaep</storyboard>
      <animation>Dong Woo Animation Company, Ltd.</animation>
      <source>https://transcripts.fandom.com/wiki/How_Long_Is_Forever%3F</source>
   </head>
   <characterList>
      <charList type="recurring" subtype="titan" id="Starfire">Starfire</charList>
      <charList type="recurring" subtype="titan" id="Cyborg">Cyborg</charList>
      <charList type="recurring" subtype="titan" id="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</charList>
      <charList type="recurring" subtype="titan" id="Raven">Raven</charList>
      <charList type="recurring" subtype="titan" id="Robin">Robin</charList>
      <charList type="nonrecurring" id="Voice">Voice</charList>
      <charList type="recurring" subtype="villain" id="Warp">Warp</charList>
      <charList type="nonrecurring" id="FCyborg">Future Cyborg</charList>
      <charList type="nonrecurring" id="Kid">Kid</charList>
      <charList type="nonrecurring" id="FBeastBoy">Future Beast Boy</charList>
      <charList type="nonrecurring" id="FRaven">Future Raven</charList>
      <charList type="nonrecurring" id="FWarp">Future Warp</charList>
      <charList type="nonrecurring" id="FRobin">Future Robin</charList>
      <charList type="nonrecurring" id="Nightwing">Nightwing</charList>
   </characterList>
   <locationList>
      <locList id="tower">Titans Tower</locList>
      <locList id="muse">Museum</locList>
      <locList id="future">Future</locList>
   </locationList>
   <body>
      <act n="0">
         <title>PROLOGUE</title>
         <sd><setNote shot="yes">Opening shot: the exterior of <location>Titans Tower</location> at
               night.</setNote> As an alarm clock's ticking is heard, the sky pivots about the
            center of the horizon; the dark panorama rotates out of view and is replaced by the
            morning sun against wild blue yonder. The alarm begins to ring, and the camera cuts to
            an extreme close-up of the sleeping <action mrkr="Starfire" with="all" move="1" place="tower"/><char>Starfire</char>'s closed eyes. She opens them
            with a gasp, then squeezes them shut excitedly on the next line.</sd>
         
         <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr>The day has arrived!</sp>
         
         <sd>She looks off to one side; cut to the source of the ringing, an alarm clock shaped like
            <char>the Amazing Mumbo</char> that sits on her dresser. She reaches into view to shut it off, and we
            see a close-up of a drawer, which she opens to reveal a pile of toys and party favors.
            She sweeps up the lot and giggles o.c.; outside in the hall, her door opens and she
            peeks cautiously back and forth. More bubbly little laughs escape her as she zips out
            and starts to ease toward the corner, whisking from one wall to the other as she goes.
            Her armload jingles slightly. One item falls away when she ducks around the bend and out
            of sight, but she reaches back to pick it up.</sd>
         
         <sd>Now she makes her way past the stairs. Cut to inside a closed door; it slides open to
            admit her, and she lowers her goodies to expose her beaming face. Hearts float up around
            it.</sd>
         
         <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr> HAPPY BLORTHOG!! <sd>A question mark pops up by
               her head.</sd> Huh?</sp>
         
         <sd>Her perspective, looking into <location>the operations center</location>. <action mrkr="Raven" with="all" move="1" place="tower"/><char>Raven</char> sits off to one
            side and reads, <action mrkr="Robin" with="all" move="1" place="tower"/><char>Robin</char> stands before a boom box in <location>the kitchen</location>, and
               <action mrkr="BeastBoy" with="all" move="1" place="tower"/><char>Beast Boy</char> and <action mrkr="Cyborg" with="all" move="1" place="tower"/><char>Cyborg</char> are playing GameStation-the racing
            game seen in "Sisters." A thundering hip-hop track drowns out all other sound at this
            point. Close-up of <char>Robin</char>, whose hair is being blown back by the wall of
            sound, then of <char>Cyborg</char> and <char>Beast Boy</char>. They are having a
            tug-of-war over the game controller.</sd>
         
         <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr> Come on, <char>Beast Boy</char>, gimme that thing!</sp>
         <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr> Dude! I'm in the middle of a game,
               <char>Cyborg</char>!</sp>
         <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr> Yeah, my game, 'cause it's my turn!</sp>
         <sd>Cut to the completely unflappable reader.</sd>
         <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>
            <sd>from o.c.</sd> Give me the controller!</sp>
         <sd>To <char>Starfire</char>.</sd>
         <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>
            <sd>from o.c.</sd> No! Let go!</sp>
         <sd>She walks in.</sd>
         <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>
            <sd>from o.c.</sd> It is my turn!</sp>
         <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr> Friends! We must frolic and leap in glorious
            celebration, for today is Blorthog-the Tamaranean festival of friendship!</sp>
         
         <sd>Sight gag: roses bloom all around her head as she says this. When she finishes, she
            grins broadly for several seconds-and then the flowers fall away, to the sound of a
            mental car wreck, as she realizes that no one is paying the least attention.
            Disgruntled, she looks around the place and drops the items she has carried in, except
            for a few strands of jingling bells that hang from her wrists. <char>Cyborg</char> leans
            into view, still struggling with the o.c. <char>Beast Boy</char>, and she turns
            cheerfully to him.</sd>
         
         <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr> Joyous greeting, friend! <sd>as a tentacle snakes
               into view</sd> I, <char>Starfire</char>, give you this tinnabula as a symbol of-</sp>
         <sd>It wraps around his neck; she gasps.</sd>
         <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>
            <sd>as he is yanked o.c.</sd> You're gonna pay for that, you little grass stain!</sp>
         
         <sd>Sight gag: his eye implant hangs in the air a moment after he is pulled back, then zips
            after him. A few seconds later, there is yell and a camera-shaking crash from the two
            boys' direction, and <char>Beast Boy</char> hops into view as a frog, with the
            GameStation controller in his mouth. Reverting to human form, he laughs and starts
            playing again. <char>Starfire</char> holds a string of bells out to him.</sd>
         
         <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr> Many blessings, friend. May your ears be filled
            with sugar candies and-</sp>
         <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>
            <sd>from o.c., on end of previous</sd>
            <char>BEAST BOY</char>!!</sp>
         <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>
            <sd>yelling over shoulder</sd> Look! I'll give you back the controller as soon as
               <char>Raven</char> gives back my nail clippers!</sp>
         
         <sd>There is a loud, furious growl from o.c., and <char>Cyborg</char> reaches into view to
            yank him away. Cut to <char>Raven</char>-still buried in her book, with the
            aforementioned pair of clippers floating nearby under her influence.</sd>
         
         <sp><spkr ref="Raven">Raven</spkr> Not gonna happen. How else am I supposed to keep your
            toenails off the coffee table?</sp>
         <sd><char>Starfire</char> holds the bells out to her.</sd>
         <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr> Happiness and delight, friend. On this wondrous
            day I wish you sunshine and bunny-</sp>
         
         <sd><char>Raven</char>'s eyebrow twitches as a skull pops up by her head;
               <char>Starfire</char> takes the hint and backs off with a nervous little laugh. Now a
            vein starts to throb on <char>Raven</char>'s forehead on her next words.</sd>
         
         <sp><spkr ref="Raven">Raven</spkr>
            <char>Robin</char>, could the music be a little louder? I can still hear myself
            think.</sp>
         
         <sd>Pull back to frame him; <char>Starfire</char> makes as if to offer him the bells. As
            the free-for-all continues from <location>the vicinity of the couch</location>, <char>Robin</char> glares off
            toward it and one vein after another stands out below his hairline. Finally he has had
            enough.</sd>
         
         <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr> I only turned the music up to DROWN OUT ALL THE
            YELLING!!</sp>
         
         <sd>Sight gag: his face goes red on the end of this line, his head swells, and he shouts
            with enough force to blow <char>Starfire</char>'s hair back. Second gag: now she is
            seen, rather tired of this whole idiocy, in close-up against a red background and
            holding her bells. <char>Robin</char>'s throbbing head is at top left,
               <char>Raven</char>'s at top right, and a laughing <char>Beast Boy</char> runs past
            with the controller while <char>Cyborg</char> chases him. Both of these Titans are in
            "Super Deformed" style. A moment later, they back into view; <char>Cyborg</char> has put
               <char>Beast Boy</char> in a headlock with one hand and seized the device with the
            other.</sd>
         
         <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr> Whose turn is it now, tough guy? Whose turn is it
            now?</sp>
         
         <sd>They slide o.c. Sight gag: flames shoot from <char>Robin</char>'s mouth on the next
            line.</sd>
         
         <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>
            <sd>calling after them</sd> Knock it off! I can't work with you two acting like idiots!</sp>
         <sp><spkr ref="Raven">Raven</spkr> Great, <char>Robin</char>. More yelling will definitely
            stop all the yelling.</sp>
         
         <sd>He turns to growl at her as <char>Cyborg</char> runs screaming across the screen; he
            has the controller, but <char>Beast Boy</char> has turned into a bear and is charging
            after him. The former runs back and perches on <char>Starfire</char>'s bells, while the
            latter comes back in human form and tries to catch his breath.</sd>
         
         <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr> Friends, please! <sd><char>Cyborg</char> laughs
               and waves it.</sd> You must not-if we could simply-happy Blor-</sp>
         <sd>The strand breaks.</sd>
         <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>
            <sd>dropping o.c.</sd> Whoa!</sp>
         
         <sd>The bells fall loose and hit the floor in slow motion, bouncing all over the place.
               <char>Starfire</char>'s disbelieving gaze turns down after them as <char>Robin</char>
            and <char>Raven</char> grimace at each other and <char>Beast Boy</char> stays half
            slumped over. The Tamaranean's shock gives way to fist-clenching anger, and she does her
            best to keep from blowing her top-but eventually she loses the struggle, and the other
            three Titans retreat o.c. on her next word.</sd>
         
         <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr> STTTTTOOOOOPPPPP!!</sp>
         
         <sd>All the sight gags end and the music cuts off. Pull back across <location>the operations center</location>
            at ground level; the broken bells lie near the camera, while the Titans are at a
            distance.</sd>
         
         <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr> Friends must never behave this way-and especially
            not on Blorthog! Do you wish to invite the Rekmas?</sp>
         <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr> Gesundheit?</sp>
         <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr>
            <sd>turning away</sd> On my world, "Rekmas" means "the Drifting."</sp>
         
         <sd>Everything but the five teens' images fades to black, and all but <char>Starfire</char>
            slowly float o.c. in different directions.</sd>
         
         <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr> The point at which close friends begin to drift
            apart-and their friendship begins to die.</sp>
         
         <sd>She fades away as well. Snap to <char>Cyborg</char> and <char>Beast Boy</char>.</sd>
         
         <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr> Aw, come on, <char>Starfire</char>.</sp>
         <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr> We are so not Rek-whatever-ing.</sp>
         <sp><spkr ref="Raven">Raven</spkr> We're getting on each other's nerves a little. Big deal.</sp>
         <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr> Yeah. This is just typical roommate stuff. We're not
            going to drift apart, <char ref="Starfire">Star</char>. I promise. We'll all be friends
            forever.</sp>
         <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr> Forever?</sp>
         
         <sd>A beeping starts up and cuts off her pondering. The source is <char>Robin</char>'s
            communicator, which he pulls out of his belt. As its show-theme ringtone goes off, the T
            on its outer casing flashes red.</sd>
         
         <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr> Titans! Trouble!</sp>
         
         <sd>All but <char>Starfire</char> follow him out of <location>the operations
               center</location>. Close-up of her; after a long moment, she flies out after them,
            and the camera tilts down to ground level, where the broken bells lie near a string she
            has dropped. Fade to black.</sd>
         
         <cue>OPENING THEME</cue>
         
      </act>
      <act n="1">
         <title>Act One</title>
         <sd><setNote shot="yes">Opening shot: the exterior of <location>a museum in Jump
                  City</location>.</setNote> The sun has just barely begun to rise here. Inside, the
            camera pans across <location>a gallery</location> filled with ticking clocks from many historical periods,
            and it stops on a particular display case by the far wall to zoom in a bit. Next to
            this, a portal of white light opens up and turns black after a moment as if a second
            hand had just swept across it. <charDesc ref="Warp">Out steps a goateed man in black
               armor, with gold reinforcements at wrists and ankles; he also wears a gold
               breastplate and helmet that leaves his face exposed.</charDesc> This is
               <char>Warp</char>.</sd>
         
         <sd>Close-up of the item in the case-a small clock in a cylindrical gold housing, with a
            glass hemisphere on top. Inside is an assembly of parts that could be a model of a
            galaxy. <char>Warp</char>'s footsteps approach as his shadow falls over the case; pull
            back to frame him in front of it.</sd>
         
         <sp><spkr ref="Voice">Voice</spkr> Hey, stop!</sp>
         
         <sd>The sound of a weapon being cocked is heard with this. The intruder turns toward it,
            showing a small blue lens on the forehead of his helmet, and the camera cuts to behind
            him. The speaker is one of two armed guards who have moved in and are ready to
            fire.</sd>
         
         <sp><spkr ref="Warp">Warp</spkr> Stop yourselves!</sp>
         
         <sd>He waves a hand carelessly at them; an instant later both men are frozen in ice. Cut
            from them to him on the next line. He turns back to the case, showing his breastplate to
            have a larger blue lens set in it.</sd>
         
         <sp><spkr ref="Warp">Warp</spkr> I didn't journey back in time one hundred years to
            squabble, I came to steal. <sd>His perspective of the timepiece.</sd> The Clock of
            Eternity. <sd>Back to him.</sd> Valuable in the past, priceless in the future.</sp>
         
         <sd>He reaches for it, only to have his hand deflected by one of <char>Robin</char>'s
            discs. Pull back to frame the Titans at the balcony railing; the projectile embeds
            itself in the floor near the camera.</sd>
         
         <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr> But for the present- <sd>Close-up of them.</sd> -you'll
            keep your filthy hands off it.</sp>
         <sp><spkr ref="Warp">Warp</spkr> The Teen Titans. This is a treat. <sd>as a laser pops out
               of each shoulder</sd> I read all about you in the historical archives. And now you're
            all history!</sp>
         <sd>He opens fire.</sd>
         <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr> Titans! Go!</sp>
         
         <sd>They are over the railing in a heartbeat to avoid the blasts. <char>Warp</char> pivots
            off to one side and fires again with a shout, aiming at <action mrkr="Robin" with="all" move="2" place="muse"/><char>Robin</char>; the latter
            has his fighting staff out and extended to full length, and he parries the barrage with
            ease. The last shot, however, breaks the weapon in half and forces him to retreat. A
            starbolt blasts across the screen from behind, and <action mrkr="Starfire" with="all" move="2" place="muse"/><char>Starfire</char> flies in to
            take his place, followed by <action mrkr="BeastBoy" with="all" move="2" place="muse"/><char>Beast Boy</char> as a lion. Her beams carve a long
            double groove in the floor, closing in on <char>Warp</char>, but he effortlessly
            deflects when they reach him. One ricochet comes back at her and knocks her out of the
            air.</sd>
         
         <sd>Extreme close-up of his face; he looks incuriously off to one side as <char>Beast
               Boy</char>'s growl is heard. The big green jungle cat is charging, but up comes one
            gold glove, out pops a blaster from the back of it, and off goes a crackling blast. Pull
            back to show that he has immobilized <char>Beast Boy</char> in mid-leap. Cut to
               <action mrkr="Raven" with="all" move="2" place="muse"/><char>Raven</char> in midair on the next line; she is levitating two grandfather
            clocks.</sd>
         
         <sp><spkr ref="Raven">Raven</spkr> Azarath Metrion Zinthos!</sp>
         
         <sd>The fixtures are hurled at him, only to go flying off to the side when he waves his
            arms. Now he fires a beam from his helmet that drives her to the ground. He is in the
            clear for only a moment, though; <action mrkr="Cyborg" with="all" move="2" place="muse"/><char>Cyborg</char>'s sonic cannon blast flashes in,
            connecting dead on and throwing up a cloud of dust. Cut to him.</sd>
         
         <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr> Boo-yah!...Huh?</sp>
         
         <sd>Pull back. As the view clears, we see that <char>Warp</char> has put up a force field
            to absorb the energy and is quite unharmed. Taking it down, he throws something at the
            camera; cut to <char>Cyborg</char> as it lands on his chest and sticks there. It is
            circular, resembling a kitchen timer, and the pointer turns a notch to send up sparks
            from every part of the bionic teen's body.</sd>
         
         <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>
            <sd>groaning in pain</sd> Draining my power cell!</sp>
         <sp><spkr ref="Warp">Warp</spkr>
            <sd>holding up a disc</sd> You cannot defeat <char>Warp</char>. I am from the
            future.</sp>
         
         <sd>He scales it across <location>the gallery</location> toward the charging <char>Robin</char>, who throws a
            handful of his own discs. <char>Warp</char>'s projectile, however, smashes cleanly
            through them, then doubles back and homes in again. <char>Robin</char> and
               <char>Starfire</char> dive aside as it sails the full length of the room and explodes
            at the other end.</sd>
         
         <sp><spkr ref="Warp">Warp</spkr> And you relics are one hundred years out of date.</sp>
         
         <sd>He turns away; close up of the case holding the Clock of Eternity. <char>Warp</char>
            reaches out, his hand passing through the glass, and removes it. Pull back; he takes a
            few steps across <location>the gallery</location>, stops, and presses the blue lens on his breastplate. It
            glows blinding white and emits a beam that forms into a portal identical to the one that
            brought him here. A little adjustment turns the passage black as before.</sd>
         
         <sp><spkr ref="Warp">Warp</spkr> Ta-ta, Titans. I have enjoyed our time together, but I've
            got a very bright future ahead of me.</sp>
         
         <sd>Cut to <char>Starfire</char> and <char>Robin</char> on the end of this, then back to
            him. He turns to make his exit, but before he can clear out, she roars in fury and flies
            straight at him. Surprised, he turns to look back with one foot out the door.</sd>
         
         <sp><spkr ref="Warp">Warp</spkr> What?</sp>
         
         <sd>She plows into him; her momentum carries both of them through the portal, which winks
            out behind them-an instant before <char>Robin</char> hurls himself across the screen in
            attempt to follow. He ends up sprawled on the floor. Long overhead shot of <location>the gallery</location>,
            pulling back slowly-there are four Titans, spread out and looking at the now-empty case,
            and the fifth nowhere in sight. <char>Beast Boy</char> has returned to human form. Pull
            back slowly.</sd>
         
         <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>
            <char>Starfire</char>!</sp>
         
         <sd>Fade to black.</sd>
         
         <sd>The view resolves into the center of a clock face, the point where the hands are
            attached, as the camera pulls back. It is advancing very quickly, and as the camera
            movement continues, other timepieces are seen in the background, all working at high
            speed. <char>Starfire</char> and <char>Warp</char> grapple in midair; pan to keep them
            in view. We are within the portal he opened.</sd>
         
         <sp><spkr ref="Warp">Warp</spkr> Let go!</sp>
         <sd>Close-up.</sd>
         <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr> You have endangered my friends and ruined
            Blorthog!</sp>
         <sp><spkr ref="Warp">Warp</spkr> Stop! If you damage the suit before we reach my future-
               <sd>She gets hold of the chest lens.</sd> No!</sp>
         
         <sd>She rips it away; there is a great flash of white, which clears to leave her floating
            alone. She gasps and covers her eyes as he drops screaming o.c. Cut to just above her;
            he falls away from the camera, the background blacking out as he goes. When he has
            receded from view entirely, a second white flash emanates from the immeasurable depths
            and washes out the screen. This clears to leave a black field and <char>Starfire</char>
            falling toward the camera from above. <setNote shot="no">Fade to black, then immediately
               snap to a deep snowdrift, where she lands very hard and stands up after a moment. It
               is nighttime, and a bitter winter wind whistles over the landscape.</setNote></sd>
         
         <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr> Huh? <sd>shivering</sd> What has happened? Why is
            it cold? And where are my...</sp>
         
         <sd>She turns her eyes upward on the end of this line. Cut to her perspective-looking
            straight at the base of <location>the Tower</location>, whose windows are all dark and
            drifted deep with snow at the sills. She gasps softly; tilt up to follow her gaze to the
            top floor, where the main window is broken. The entire impression is one of a building
            that has fallen into advanced disrepair.</sd>
         
         <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr> ...friends?</sp>
         
         <sd>Dissolve to inside, near the ceiling of the top floor. A hole has been smashed here,
            allowing the snowflakes to enter. Tilt down to the unlit stairs as she mounts them
            slowly. The device she tore from <char>Warp</char>'s armor is clipped to her belt.</sd>
         
         <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr> Friends? Hello? Friends? Hello!</sp>
         
         <sd>Finding a set of closed doors in her path, she strains to push them open. Cut to the
            other side; one door is forced away, then the other, revealing her silhouette in the
            meager light from outside. She gasps in shock and advances slowly; pull back to reveal
            that she has entered the remains of <location>the operations center</location>. Walking
            through <location>the kitchen</location>, she looks left and right, not believing a bit
            of what she sees, and the camera cuts to floor level. Her boots pass the GameStation
            controller that sparked such a furor between <char>Cyborg</char> and <char>Beast
               Boy</char>, and nudge one of the bells she dropped-now badly rusted.</sd>
         
         <sd>Her level again; the jingling causes her to stop and recoil in fear for a moment, and
            she stops and picks up a loose bell. She fixes it with a wide-eyed look of stunned
            sadness for a long second and watches it crumble on her palm. In the darkness off to one
            side, a spot of red light begins to glow as some machinery is heard; she gasps and looks
            toward this.</sd>
         
         <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr>
            <char>Cyborg</char>!</sp>
         
         <sd>The red dot does not move, so she holds up one glowing hand to shed some light.</sd>
         
         <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr> Oh, <char>Cyborg</char>, thank goodness you
            are-</sp>
         
         <sd>The illumination reaches the dark niche and exposes something that has
               <char>Cyborg</char>'s approximate body shape, but is built entirely of mechanical
            parts. The source of the red spot is an electronic brain sitting in one side of the
            head. <action mrkr="Starfire" with="none" move="3" place="future"/><char>Starfire</char> cries out in fear and throws a starbolt that blows the
            collection of circuitry away, only to be confronted by several spider-like robots that
            jump up from behind the shoulders. Each looks like the part she just destroyed. Now she
            tosses one shot after another to knock them out, but is interrupted by the arrival of a
            new figure at the entrance. The voice is that of <char>Cyborg</char>, but considerably
            older, and the outline has some wires hooked to it.</sd>
         
         <sd>*** All lines marked with an asterisk are spoken by the older, future counterparts of
            present-day characters. Stage directions follow this convention as well until further
            notice. *** </sd>
         
         <sp><spkr ref="FCyborg">*Cyborg</spkr> Yo!</sp>
         
         <sd>He walks in, giving the camera a full view of himself. The face is lined, the armored
            panels that cover most of his body are damaged or missing, and the blue lights that used
            to glow in his circuitry have gone out. Thick cables are connected to his back, snaking
            out of view, and he has armed himself with a piece of pipe.</sd>
         
         <sp><spkr ref="FCyborg">*Cyborg</spkr> Who's up here blasting my... <sd>He stops, lowers
               the pipe, and stares dumbfounded.</sd>
            <char ref="Starfire">Star</char>?</sp>
         
         <sd>The bludgeon slides from his fingers and clatters to the floor, and he comes closer to
            look her over from head to toe. We now see that he has had to replace part of one leg
            with some random components.</sd>
         
         <sp><spkr ref="FCyborg">*Cyborg</spkr>
            <char>Starfire</char>. I don't believe it. You...you haven't aged a day!</sp>
         
         <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr>
            <char>Cyborg</char>, what has happened? Why are...you...</sp>
         
         <sp><spkr ref="FCyborg">*Cyborg</spkr> Old? <sd>He smiles gently, then crosses <location>the
               operations center</location>.</sd> Well, that's what happens to folks when you go away for
            twenty years.</sp>
         
         <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr> Twenty years?!</sp>
         
         <sp><spkr ref="FCyborg">*Cyborg</spkr> You disappeared, <char ref="Starfire">Star</char>.
               <sd>He slides some junk aside.</sd> That battle with <char>Warp</char>, that was a
            long time ago. You fell through a wormhole, and...</sp>
         
         <sd>He looks out the cracked window; cut to the view from it. <setNote shot="no">Across the frozen bay, the
            skyline of Jump City huddles under its blanket of snow and the cruel dark sky.</setNote></sd>
         
         <sp><spkr ref="FCyborg">*Cyborg</spkr>
            <sd>from o.c.</sd> Welcome to the future.</sp>
         
         <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr> The future? But...</sp>
         
         <sd>She removes the lens from her belt and holds it up.</sd>
         
         <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr> ...I damaged his technology.</sp>
         <sd>He takes the thing and looks at it.</sd>
         
         <sp><spkr ref="FCyborg">*Cyborg</spkr>
            <char>Warp</char> was planning to jump ahead one hundred years, right? Looks like you
            stopped him at twenty.</sp>
         
         <sd>She takes it back.</sd>
         
         <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr> Still, I am confused. Please, why are you in
            disrepair?</sp>
         
         <sd>He looks down at himself, then turns away.</sd>
         
         <sp><spkr ref="FCyborg">*Cyborg</spkr> Let's just say things haven't gone so well since you
            left.</sp>
         
         <sd>He approaches the windows; she follows.</sd>
         
         <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr> But what of the other Titans? Where are our
            friends?</sp>
         
         <sp><spkr ref="FCyborg">*Cyborg</spkr> The Titans are history, <char ref="Starfire">Star</char>. Your friends aren't friends anymore.</sp>
         
         <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr> No. You are wrong. This...everything is wrong! How
            could such terrible things...</sp>
         
         <sd>She looks at the lens in her hand.</sd>
         
         <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr>
            <char>Warp</char>! His interference in the past must have changed our future.</sp>
         
         <sp><spkr ref="FCyborg">*Cyborg</spkr>
            <char ref="Starfire">Star</char>, I don't think-</sp>
         
         <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr> He caused all this badness to happen. He made this
            technology, and he is the one who can make things right! <sd>She flies over and lands by
               him.</sd> We must find <char>Warp</char>. You will help me?</sp>
         
         <sp><spkr ref="FCyborg">*Cyborg</spkr> I wish I could.</sp>
         
         <sd>He looks off toward one corner; cut to a piece of equipment there. It resembles a
            gasoline-powered electric generator, and his cables are hooked up to it. Zoom in
            slowly.</sd>
         
         <sp><spkr ref="FCyborg">*Cyborg</spkr>
            <sd>from o.c.</sd> My last power cell burned out years ago. <sd>Back to the pair.</sd>
            I've tried adapting this new stuff to my old circuits, but...I can't leave <location>the Tower</location>,
               <char ref="Starfire">Star</char>. I'm obsolete.</sp>
         
         <sd>Silhouette view of them at the windows.</sd>
         
         <sp><spkr ref="FCyborg">*Cyborg</spkr> Maybe one of the others can help.</sp>
         
         <sd>Cut to an extreme close-up of her eye and pull back to show her in flight.</sd>
         <sp><spkr ref="FCyborg">*Cyborg</spkr>
            <sd>voice over</sd> I can tell you how to find <char ref="BeastBoy">BB</char> and
               <char>Raven</char>.</sp>
         
         <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr>
            <sd>voice over</sd> And <char>Robin</char>?</sp>
         
         <sp><spkr ref="FCyborg">*Cyborg</spkr>
            <sd>voice over</sd> We lost touch a long time ago. If you're looking for him- <sd>She
               disappears into the city skyline.</sd> -you're on your own.</sp>
         
         <sd>Fade to black.</sd>
      </act>
      <act n="2">
         <title>Act Two</title>
         <sd><setNote shot="yes">Opening shot: the interior of a stable or similar
               enclosure.</setNote> As a circus calliope plays outside, a green seal pops up into
            view and barks-it can only be <char>Beast Boy</char>. He jumps onto a nearby crate and
            balances a ball on his nose. It bounces up, the camera following, and when we see him
            again, he becomes a frog and balances it again. Cut to two young boys outside, watching
            the exhibition; they are mostly bald except for small spikes of hair, and they wear pink
            visor/sunglasses that hide their eyes completely. One holds an ice cream cone, and
            neither is too impressed by the whole spectacle.</sd>
         
         <sd>The sound of another transformation is heard; cut to behind the two. <char>Beast
               Boy</char>'s enclosure is now revealed as a large cage. He has assumed panda form to
            keep that ball poised just so. Close-up of him, changing into a pig-but a snowball flung
            in knocks him over and sends the ball flying.</sd>
         
         <sp><spkr ref="Kid">Kid</spkr> You stink, pig!</sp>
         
         <sd>Laughing and jeering, both of them start throwing now; <char>Beast Boy</char> pokes his
            head out from behind the crate, but is quickly driven to the floor. Pull back to a long
            shot, revealing the cage to be <location>a circus wagon</location>. After one last
            salvo, the ice cream cone is thrown in and the two kids leave. The green porker sits
            dejectedly as the cone melts on his head; it slides off, and he looks down and
            sighs.</sd>
         
         <sd><char>Starfire</char> lands on the other side of the bars to peer in. <char>Beast
               Boy</char> returns to human form-bald on top, having gained a great deal of weight,
            and not wearing his belt. Defeat permeates every syllable of his voice.</sd>
         
         <sp><spkr ref="FBeastBoy">*Beast Boy</spkr> No way! <sd>He moves to the bars.</sd> It's
            you. But how?</sp>
         
         <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr> I require your help.</sp>
         
         <sp><spkr ref="FBeastBoy">*Beast Boy</spkr> What kinda help?</sp>
         
         <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr> The future is not as it should be. We must find
               <char>Warp</char>. <sd>warming up starbolts</sd> I will free you from this-</sp>
         
         <sp><spkr ref="FBeastBoy">*Beast Boy</spkr>
            <sd>panicked</sd> This cage isn't to keep me in! It's to keep those maniacs out! <sd>She
               winds down and leans in closer.</sd> Look. After the Titans broke up, I tried the
            whole solo-hero thing. Got my butt kicked-a lot. So now, well...</sp>
         
         <sd>He turns briefly into a squawking chicken to make the point.</sd>
         
         <sp><spkr ref="FBeastBoy">*Beast Boy</spkr>
            <sd>smiling weakly, chuckling</sd> Besides, I'm in the showbiz now.</sp>
         
         <sd>Her eyes tell just how false this excuse rings with her. Cut to a long shot of the
            wagon and pan to a banner on lighted poles nearby: "The Amazing One Man Zoo-Freakish
            Wonder," showing a creature with the heads and body parts of many different animals.
            This is what passes for <char>Beast Boy</char>'s life now.</sd>
         
         <sd>Dissolve to <char>Starfire</char>'s perspective, <setNote shot="no">walking along a
               balcony in a broken-down building</setNote>. At the far end, a single fluorescent
            tube flickers and throws its inadequate light onto a steel door. Close-up; she gets a
            hand to the knob and turns. <location>The room</location> inside is pure white, with no
            features of any kind visible. In the far corner, wearing a white cloak with the hood up,
            a short figure stands with its back to the camera and its head bowed. This is still
               <char>Starfire</char>'s point of view.</sd>
         
         <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr>
            <char>Raven</char>? <sd>Close-up.</sd>
            <char>Raven</char>, it is <char>Starfire</char>, your friend.</sp>
         
         <sd>She moves into <location>the room</location>. The white-cloaked figure does not turn from the corner; the
            voice is <char>Raven</char>'s, but sounding as if the past twenty years have broken her
            mind and body entirely.</sd>
         
         <sp><spkr ref="FRaven">*Raven</spkr> No such thing.</sp>
         
         <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr> Please, <char>Raven</char>, I-</sp>
         
         <sp><spkr ref="FRaven">*Raven</spkr> Just another figment. Don't even look.</sp>
         
         <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr> You must listen! I am here because-</sp>
         
         <sd>Camera shift: <char>Raven</char> seen head-on, still facing the wall,
               <char>Starfire</char> behind her.</sd>
         
         <sp><spkr ref="FRaven">*Raven</spkr>
            <sd>suddenly furious</sd> I'm never coming back! Go away!</sp>
         
         <sd>She half-walks, half-floats to another corner of <location>the room</location>.</sd>
         
         <sp><spkr ref="FRaven">*Raven</spkr> It has to go away. Just like before. Just like all the
            others.</sp>
         <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr>
            <sd>from o.c.</sd> Your mind. <sd>Shift: both head-on again, and she approaches.</sd>
            Without friends, you must have-</sp>
         
         <sd>As she is about to touch her former teammate's back, a shield pops up to block her and
            she gasps. Dropping her head, resignedly, she exits and closes the door behind her.
               <char>Raven</char> keeps her face to the wall and that black barrier up.</sd>
         
         <sd><setNote shot="no">Cut to a patch of sky, seen from between several rooftops, and tilt
               down to ground level. <char>Starfire</char> plods through the snow that thickly
               covers the street, but a laser blast from o.c. knocks her backward.</setNote> Cut to
            a long shot of a ledge, where <char>Warp</char> stands with his
            shoulder-mounted weapons deployed. Circuitry is visible through the hole where she
            pulled that lens away, and his voice reveals that he too has aged.</sd>
         
         <sp><spkr ref="FWarp">*Warp</spkr> What's the matter, dear? Have I come at a bad time?</sp>
         
         <sd>Close-up: his face is lined and drawn from the past two decades. He cuts loose with a
            fusillade that peppers the snow all around her; she stands for a moment, pinned down,
            and then gets clear of the ground. Flying past him and over the buildings, she dodges
            his shots and returns fire, but as in <location>the museum</location>, he puts up a force field to stop her
            starbolts. Now she floats down to his level and gets ready to lay a big one on him-but
            he merely waves a hand and encases her in ice, just as he did to those two guards. She
            drops to the street; the frozen layer shatters, and she is left twitching and groaning
            in a crater of snow. <char>Warp</char> steps close to her and soon finds himself on the
            receiving end of her angry glare. However, it gives way to bewilderment once she gets a
            good close look at him.</sd>
         
         <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr> You have also become old.</sp>
         
         <sp><spkr ref="FWarp">*Warp</spkr> That's what happens when someone steals my vortex
            regulator. <sd>holding out hand</sd> The regulator, if you please. I really must get
            back to my future.</sp>
         <sd>She stands and pulls it off her belt.</sd>
         
         <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr>
            <sd>menacingly</sd> If you ever wish to see your future- <sd>warming up a starbolt</sd>
            -you will repair the damage you have done to my past!</sp>
         
         <sp><spkr ref="FWarp">*Warp</spkr> Damage? Silly girl. There's nothing wrong with your
            past. <sd>Cut to her; he continues o.c.</sd> One cannot damage history, because history
            cannot be changed. <sd>Back to him, holding up the Clock, and zoom in slowly.</sd> I
            went back in time to steal this because history says it disappeared. And history says it
            disappeared because I went back to steal it. Past, present, future. It's all written in
            stone, my dear.</sp>
         
         <sd>The minute hand advances, showing the time at 12: 00. <char>Starfire</char> winds down
            the blast she was about to throw; he takes the lens, or regulator, from her hand.</sd>
         
         <sp><spkr ref="FWarp">*Warp</spkr> And nothing you do can ever change it.</sp>
         
         <sd>He raises one arm and extends a blaster from his wrist, ready to fire-but something
            hurtles into view and <setNote shot="no">knocks him into <location>an
               alley</location></setNote>. Standing up, it is a black silhouette with long hair, and
            it throws <char>Warp</char>
            <setNote shot="no">even farther down the way to bounce off a dead-end wall</setNote>.
            The figure produces a couple of discs between its fingers and throws, revealing a gray
            utility belt and wrist guards; they explode in a fireball that engulfs the time
            traveler, and the thrower runs straight toward the blast zone for a jump. Flame and
            smoke clear to show that <char>Warp</char> has once again shielded himself with a force
            field. He lets it down and looks skyward to see this new figure dropping straight toward
            him.</sd>
         
         <sp><spkr ref="FWarp">*Warp</spkr> Another time, perhaps.</sp>
         
         <sd>He drops into the ground an instant before the leaping shadow lands there.
               <char>Starfire</char> moves cautiously into <location>the alley</location> as this
            person straightens up. No features can be seen, but the voice is unmistakable.</sd>
         
         <sp><spkr ref="FRobin">*Robin</spkr> It's good to see you again.</sp>
         <sd>Her eyes pop.</sd>
         
         <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr>
            <char>Robin</char>?</sp>
         <sp><spkr ref="FRobin">*Robin</spkr>
            <sd>in shadow</sd> I haven't used that name in a long time.</sp>
         
         <sd>He advances into the light. <charDesc ref="Nightwing">Skintight black uniform, with a
               large angular design of a blue hawk on the chest; black gloves and matching eye mask
               that angles down to cover his nose as well; the aforementioned long
            hair.</charDesc></sd>
         
         <sp><spkr ref="FRobin">*Robin</spkr> Call me <char>Nightwing</char>.</sp>
         
         <sd>Fade to black.</sd>
      </act>
      <act n="3">
         <title>Act Three</title>
         <sd><setNote shot="yes">Opening shot: a slow pan across the Jump City skyline.</setNote>
            Machinery makes itself heard, and <setNote shot="no">the view dissolves to a group of
               turning gears in a machine room</setNote>. These part to reveal blackness beyond;
            zoom in through them, then fade in to an overhead shot of a large room. A bank of
            computers and control panels is on one side, with a chair in front, and two cylindrical
            storage containers are across from them. A walkway bisects the area.</sd>
         
         <sd>Cut to just behind one of the containers. It is glass, and a part of
            <char>Robin</char>'s old outfit is visible at the edge of the screen.
               <char>Starfire</char> walks into view and stops to look, wrapping her arms around her
            body for warmth; cut to a head-on shot. The costume, mask and all, has been placed on a
            faceless store-window dummy for display purposes. She sighs quietly and gets a blanket
            wrapped around her shoulders by <char>Nightwing</char>-this is <location>his new base of
               operations</location>.</sd>
         
         <sp><spkr ref="Nightwing">Nightwing</spkr> I heard you've been looking for help.</sp>
         <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr> There is nothing you can do. There is nothing
            anyone can do. The past cannot be repaired, the future cannot be altered, no matter how
            wrong it seems.</sp>
         <sp><spkr ref="Nightwing">Nightwing</spkr> So, it's impossible. <sd>walking to
               computers</sd> Good. If memory serves, we've done the impossible before.</sp>
         
         <sd>She cannot find any words for a moment, but her eyes tell enough about the hope that
            has sprung up in her mind.</sd>
         
         <sp><spkr ref="Nightwing">Nightwing</spkr> I held on to this- <sd>Close-up of a panel; he
               presses a button and continues o.c.</sd> -just in case.</sp>
         
         <sd>The panel slides open, and up pops his old communicator. <char>Starfire</char> moves
            closer to make sure her eyes are not deceiving her. He picks it up and presses a button;
            instantly its T starts to flash red, just as in the prologue. She is delighted to find
            that the black stones in her neck piece and wrist guards are coming to life in the same
            manner-an emergency signal built into them.</sd>
         
         <sd>Cut to a long shot of <char>Beast Boy</char>'s cage and zoom in. As a dog, he is up on
            his hind legs and bouncing his ball on his snout; pan from here to his old belt, which
            hangs on a peg in the corner. Its buckle starts to flash, drawing his attention and
            making him forget the bouncing. Close-up of the red signal, then of him in human form;
            his jaw drops slightly open in surprise, then closes as he hangs his head sadly.</sd>
         
         <sd>In <location>the white room</location>, <char>Raven</char> has not turned her face from the wall, though she
            has put down the shield she used to block <char>Starfire</char>. Red pulses issue from
            the area of her throat; close-up of her neck, where the brooch on her cloak is going
            off. She puts a hand up to cover it, revealing that she now wears white wrist guards
            rather than black.</sd>
         
         <sd>Cut to a long shot of <location>the Tower</location>. Inside, <char>Cyborg</char> sits in <location>the operations
            center</location> and ponders the wreck his life has become. Suddenly his eye implant flickers red,
            responding to the call. He gets to his feet and starts out the door, but the cables in
            his back pull taut and stop him. He gasps softly and looks back over his shoulder; pan
            to the power source that anchors him to this place.</sd>
         
         <sd><setNote shot="yes">Cut to the exterior of <location>the former museum</location>, whose sign out front now identifies it as
            <location>Metro Art Technologies</location>.</setNote> Inside, two armed guards stand frozen in ice among the computer
            equipment.</sd>
         
         <sp><spkr ref="FWarp">*Warp</spkr>
            <sd>from o.c.</sd> Tick-tock.</sp>
         
         <sd>Pull back. This used to be <location>the gallery</location> full of clocks; he is at the far end of it.</sd>
         
         <sp><spkr ref="FWarp">*Warp</spkr> Tick-tock. <sd>Close-up; he is welding the regulator
               back onto his chest.</sd> Just a few more seconds, and I shall finally-</sp>
         
         <sd>The sentence is cut off when a short staff flies into view and strikes the tool from
            his hand. Close-up of it in flight, returning nextly to <char>Nightwing</char>'s hand.
            He and <char>Starfire</char> are at the balcony railing, and she has starbolts ready to
            go in both hands.</sd>
         
         <sp><spkr ref="Nightwing">Nightwing</spkr> The future will have to wait. <sd>extending
               staff</sd> You just ran out of time.</sp>
         
         <sd>With a frustrated growl, <char>Warp</char> brings up his shoulder lasers and fires off
            a few rounds that send the two heroes diving away. <char>Nightwing</char> scales a
            handful of explosive discs at him, <char>Starfire</char> unloads a blast, and he uses a
            force field to stop their onslaught. The two come down to ground level as he drops the
            barrier and the smoke clears. Now he gives them both barrels; they rush in closer, and
               <char>Starfire</char> fires off a shot that he deflects just as he did twenty years
            earlier. This time, though, she gets out of the way of the ricochet.</sd>
         
         <sd><char>Nightwing</char>, meanwhile, is charging ahead through <char>Warp</char>'s laser
            blasts. Silhouette view, slow motion: he is in mid-leap, bearing down on the
            time-jumping thief, and the end of his staff shatters one of the two lasers. Normal
            view, normal speed: the former Titan lands behind him, and <char>Warp</char> turns
            around only to get a starbolt in the back that bowls him over. He fires his remaining
            laser at <char>Starfire</char>, who leaps away, and then turns his attention back to
               <char>Nightwing</char>. The latter is jumping in again, staff at the ready, and he
            brings it down in a mighty overhead swing that just misses <char>Warp</char>. One laser
            blast after another is batted away without breaking the shaft this time; next the
            black-clad fighter starts swinging for the fences, forcing <char>Warp</char> to back up
            as he blocks each strike.</sd>
         
         <sd><char>Nightwing</char> fights like a bojutsu master on speed, his staff flashing
            everywhere almost at once. One final roundhouse finds its mark and sends
               <char>Warp</char> to the ground; <char>Nightwing</char> and <char>Starfire</char>
            step up to him as she winds down her starbolts. The villain, however, just grins and
            adjusts the aim of his working laser. A shot goes straight up to the roof and blows a
            hole through it, dumping in a pile of snow and rubble that buries
            <char>Starfire</char>.</sd>
         
         <sp><spkr ref="Nightwing">Nightwing</spkr>
            <char ref="Starfire">Star</char>!</sp>
         
         <sd>He is blasted away; cut to <char>Warp</char>, who has used his wrist weapon to do this
            job. He retracts it and runs across the place to pick up the welding torch that was
            knocked out of his hand. Before he can do any more repair work, though, a mighty blast
            from <char>Cyborg</char>'s cannon connects squarely with his chest and launches him over
            the length of the place to slam down behind a cabinet. <char>Starfire</char>, having
            been dug out of the rubble, and <char>Nightwing</char> look confusedly back toward the
            source, and the camera cuts to the bionic man himself, on the scene and free of the
            wiring that had held him in place. His circuitry glows blue with life as he lowers the
            cannon.</sd>
         
         <sp><spkr ref="FCyborg">*Cyborg</spkr> Boo-yah.</sp>
         
         <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr>
            <char>Cyborg</char>! <sd>She flies over to him.</sd> You are repaired!</sp>
         <sd><char>Nightwing</char> joins her.</sd>
         <sp><spkr ref="Nightwing">Nightwing</spkr> Glad you could make it.</sp>
         
         <sp><spkr ref="FCyborg">*Cyborg</spkr> Wouldn't have missed it. Now who said y'all could
            start without me?</sp>
         
         <sd>Pull back to ground level. <char>Warp</char> steps partway into view near the
            camera.</sd>
         <sp><spkr ref="FWarp">*Warp</spkr>
            <sd>from o.c.</sd> So sorry.</sp>
         
         <sd>Cut to him, holding up a timer device like the one he used to drain
            <char>Cyborg</char>'s power cell back in the day.</sd>
         
         <sp><spkr ref="FWarp">*Warp</spkr> Perhaps I should finish you first!</sp>
         
         <sd><char>Beast Boy</char>, as a lion, charges in and rakes his claws along the gold armor
            to send sparks up from it. <char>Warp</char> raises his arm and brings the blaster up
            from his wrist-but before he can use it, <char>Raven</char>'s powers exert themselves
            over the hand, then the whole body, and he is flung back to the far wall. The four
            heroes look that way, completely at a loss, and see her "soul self" materialize from the
            floor. It rises high into the air, and the black bird outline swirls to become the
            telekinetic former Titan. Under the cloak, her outfit is still black.</sd>
         
         <sp><spkr ref="FRaven">*Raven</spkr> Nobody hurts my friends.</sp>
         
         <sd>She backs up to join the others. <char>Beast Boy</char>, back in human form, looks up
            at <char>Nightwing</char>'s full head of hair and rubs his own bald scalp
            enviously.</sd>
         
         <sp><spkr ref="FBeastBoy">*Beast Boy</spkr> Dude, that is so unfair.</sp>
         
         <sd><char>Warp</char> activates the regulator, now back on his chest, to open a wormhole
            and turn it black.</sd>
         
         <sp><spkr ref="FWarp">*Warp</spkr> It seems my time has come.</sp>
         
         <sd><char>Nightwing</char> hurls something at him; he counters with one of his own.
            Close-up of the first weapon-a compact device with wings folded in by the body; these
            flick out after a moment to show the entire thing similar in design to
               <char>Robin</char>'s birdarangs. <char>Warp</char>'s disc moves into view,
            approaching, but is sliced neatly in half by one wing. The device slams into his
            regulator and cracks it; electricity crackles all over his body as he begins to grow
            younger before our eyes.</sd>
         
         <sp><spkr ref="FWarp">*Warp</spkr> Uh!?! No! Noooo! NOOOOOOO!!</sp>
         
         <sd>As he ages in reverse, his body shrinks and his outfit starts to flap emptily. In
            addition, the pitch of his voice goes higher and higher. Finally the sparks stop
            spitting and the armored suit lies deflated on the floor; no head is visible in the
            helmet. With the other Titans watching, totally mystified, <char>Beast Boy</char>
            reaches down and pulls the breastplate away. Underneath it is <char>Warp</char>, now a
            screaming baby.</sd>
         
         <sp><spkr ref="FBeastBoy">*Beast Boy</spkr> Okay. I am not changing any diapers.</sp>
         
         <sd>Pan from them to the wormhole, which is starting to close.</sd>
         
         <sp><spkr ref="FCyborg">*Cyborg</spkr>
            <sd>to <char>Starfire</char></sd> We gotta get you home. Come on!</sp>
         
         <sd>He pulls the regulator free and fits it to the muzzle of his cannon. A sustained blast
            hits the wormhole, which is nearly closed, and forces it back to its original size.</sd>
         
         <sp><spkr ref="FCyborg">*Cyborg </spkr>I'm redirecting the wormhole. <sd>Cut to
                  <char>Starfire</char> and <char>Nightwing</char>; he continues o.c.</sd>
            <char>Starfire</char>, go!</sp>
         
         <sd>She steps uneasily toward it, but stops to look back pleadingly at her former
            friends.</sd>
         
         <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr> Please, must this really be our future? <sd>No
               answer.</sd> Is there nothing I can do to change it?</sp>
         <sd><char>Nightwing</char> moves up to look her in the eye; close-up of both.</sd>
         <sp><spkr ref="Nightwing">Nightwing</spkr> I'm sorry, <char ref="Starfire">Star</char>.
            There isn't time.</sp>
         
         <sd>He takes her hand and places the Clock in it-the artifact that started this whole mess
            two acts and two decades ago-and she lowers her head for a moment. Raising it as he puts
            a hand on her shoulder, she gives him a tender smile with her eyes full of tears. He
            takes a few steps back to join the rest of the old crew, the last thing she sees as she
            moves into the black gateway. It closes behind her and winks out.</sd>
         
         <sd>A flash of white, and we are back in the time-traveling passage. A single clock,
            running backward, floats toward the camera until the center attachment point for its
            hands fills the screen with black. Now a second flash puts us back in <location>the museum gallery</location>
            at the present time. <char>Warp</char> is about to escape through the wormhole with the
            Clock.</sd>
         
         <sp><spkr ref="Warp">Warp</spkr> Ta-ta, Titans. I have enjoyed our time together, but I've
            got a very bright future ahead of me.</sp>
         
         <sd>Same camera movements and actions as before: he starts through, but she makes her leap
            straight at him.</sd>
         
         <sp><spkr ref="Warp">Warp</spkr> What?</sp>
         
         <sd>She plows into him; both go through the wormhole; <char>Robin</char> jumps after them
            but misses as it closes up. New cut: he lands near the camera, which is at ground level
            and pointing back toward <char>Cyborg</char> and <char>Beast Boy</char>.</sd>
         
         <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>
            <char>Starfire</char>!</sp>
         <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr> Um, where did she-</sp>
         
         <sd>A flash fills <location>the gallery</location>, followed by a second wormhole that opens behind him and
               <char>Cyborg</char>. <action mrkr="Starfire" with="all" move="4" place="muse"/><char>Starfire</char> is dumped out to land in a huddled
            kneeling position, cradling the Clock, and the three boys lean in.</sd>
         
         <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr> Dude!</sp>
         <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr> Whoa!</sp>
         <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>
            <char ref="Starfire">Star</char>! What happened?</sp>
         <sd>The wormhole closes.</sd>
         <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr> History said it disappeared. <sd>She straightens
               up, showing the Clock intact.</sd> But history was wrong!</sp>
         
         <sd>They can only stare thunderstruck at this instant reversal of fortune and recorded
            evens. <setNote shot="yes">Dissolve to the exterior of <location>the Tower</location>.</setNote> It is later in the day-that is, the modern
            day when this episode began.</sd>
         
         <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr>
            <sd>from inside</sd> Then <char>Nightwing</char> handed me the Clock- <sd>Cut to her in
               <location>the operations center</location>.</sd> -and I entered the vortex.</sp>
         
         <sd>Cut to behind her; she is addressing the other four Titans. <action mrkr="BeastBoy" with="all" move="3" place="tower"/><char>Beast Boy</char>'s
            cheeks are streaked with tears. Long silence as they turn over the whole out-there
            account of future events in their minds.</sd>
         
         <sp><spkr ref="Raven">Raven</spkr> Whoa.</sp>
         <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr> Bald?! <sd>tearing out most of his hair</sd>
            You're telling me I'm going to be bald?!</sp>
         <sd>He whines a bit.</sd>
         <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr> Guess you were right about all that Rekmas stuff.</sp>
         <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr> I don't want us to drift apart. Does it all have to
            happen? Isn't there anything we can-</sp>
         <sd>Cut to <action mrkr="Starfire" with="all" move="5" place="tower"/><char>Starfire</char>.</sd>
         <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr> Our friendship has already changed
               <char>Warp</char>'s past. I believe it can also change our future.</sp>
         
         <sd>One by one, the loose bells from the string that broke under <action mrkr="Cyborg" with="all" move="3" place="tower"/><char>Cyborg</char>'s feet
            float up in <action mrkr="Raven" with="all" move="3" place="tower"/><char>Raven</char>'s influence.</sd>
         
         <sp><spkr ref="Raven">Raven</spkr>
            <sd>from o.c.</sd> So... <sd>Cut to her; they are reassembling themselves.</sd> ...is it
            too late to do this festival-of-friendship thing?</sp>
         <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr>
            <sd>ecstatically</sd> Oh, it's never too late!</sp>
         
         <sd><char>Raven</char> levitates strings down around <char>Beast Boy</char>'s and
               <char>Cyborg</char>'s necks; she is already wearing one of her own, and the
            shape-shifter's hairline has fixed itself.</sd>
         
         <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>
            <sd>in <char>Raven</char>'s ear; her bells jingle</sd> HAPPY BLORTHOG!!</sp>
         <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr> I thought it was "Blort-hog."</sp>
         <sp><spkr ref="Raven">Raven</spkr> Okay, I feel like a wind chime.</sp>
         
         <sd><char>Starfire</char> puts a string around <action mrkr="Robin" with="all" move="3" place="tower"/><char>Robin</char>'s neck; tilt up from it
            to his face.</sd>
         
         <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>
            <sd>cocking an eyebrow</sd> So...<char>Nightwing</char>, huh?</sp>
         
         <cue>Dissolve to the exterior of <location>the Tower</location> and fade to black.</cue>
      </act>
   </body>
</root>