<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../schema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?><root>
     <head>
          <episode>NEVERMORE</episode>
          <writer>David Slack</writer>
          <director>Ciro Nieli</director>
          <storyboard>Kalvin Lee, Rafael Rosado, Alan Wan</storyboard>
          <animation>Dong Woo Animation Company, Ltd.</animation>
          <source>https://teentitans.fandom.com/wiki/Nevermore_(Transcript)</source>
          <issueList>
               <issueInfo link="../comic/issue-3.xml"/>
               <issueInfo link="../comic/issue-6.xml"/>
          </issueList>
     </head>
     <characterList>
          <charList type="nonrecurring" id="DoctorLight" subtype="villain">Doctor Light</charList>
          <charList type="recurring" id="Cyborg" subtype="titan">Cyborg</charList>
          <charList type="recurring" id="Raven" subtype="titan">Raven</charList>
          <charList type="recurring" id="Robin" subtype="titan">Robin</charList>
          <charList type="recurring" id="BeastBoy" subtype="titan">Beast Boy</charList>
          <charList type="recurring" id="Starfire" subtype="titan">Starfire</charList>
          <charList type="nonrecurring" id="Voice">Voice</charList>
          <charList type="nonrecurring" id="PinkRaven">Pink Raven</charList>
          <charList type="nonrecurring" id="GrayRaven">Gray Raven</charList>
          <charList type="nonrecurring" id="Chef">Chef</charList>
          <charList type="nonrecurring" id="GreenRaven">Green Raven</charList>
          <charList type="recurring" id="Trigon" subtype="villain">Trigon</charList>
          <charList type="nonrecurring" id="WhiteRaven">White Raven</charList>
          <charList type="nonrecurring" id="YellowRaven">Yellow Raven</charList>
          <charList type="nonrecurring" id="RedRaven">Red Raven</charList>
     </characterList>
     <body>
          <act n="0">
               <title>Prologue</title>
               <sd><stageDesc>Opening shot: the night sky above the buildings of Jump City.</stageDesc> <directNote kind="tilt">Tilt down to point
                    along a street</directNote>, where a vehicle can be seen turned on its side in the distance.
                    A figure stands atop it, and a couple of Titans are facing off with him. In
                    close-up, they are seen as<char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char> <char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char>  and<char ref="Robin">Robin</char>  and the vehicle is an
                    armored car whose back doors have been broken open. Gold bullion spills out to
                    the pavement. <charDesc ref="DoctorLight">The bearded, helmeted male figure perched on it is clad in a
                    skintight black outfit with a light bulb on the chest, and both hands glow very
                    brightly</charDesc>. This is<char ref="DoctorLight">Doctor Light</char>  not to be confused with the character of the
                    same name from the Mega Man game series.</sd>

               <sp><spkr ref="DoctorLight">Doctor Light</spkr>Your pathetic skills can't outshine
                    the brilliance of<char ref="DoctorLight">Doctor Light</char> </sp>

               <sd>He brings his hands together; the Titans scatter as a broad beam shoots toward
                    them.<char ref="Robin">Robin</char> leaps high and flings a birdarang at the supervillain, who jumps
                    down to avoid both it and the thrower's lunge.</sd>

               <sp><spkr ref="DoctorLight">Doctor Light</spkr>You're fast, but I doubt you'll enjoy
                    moving at the speed of light!</sp>

               <sd>He touches the bulb on his chest, causing it to glow and emit a wide-angle blast
                    that propels<char ref="Robin">Robin</char> over the roof of a nearby building.<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> comes around a
                    corner and charges, <transform class="mammal">turning into a wolf</transform> as he runs. The robber easily ducks this
                    rush.</sd>

               <sp><spkr ref="DoctorLight">Doctor Light</spkr>A wolf is no threat when it's blind
                    as a bat!</sp>

               <sd>He throws several glowing globes at the green lupine hero. They explode in a
                    series of brilliant flashes and leave him so dazzled that he reverts to human
                    form and claps both hands to his head woozily. The next one in is<char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char>  who
                    flies overhead and throws a barrage of starbolts;<char ref="DoctorLight">Doctor Light</char> creates a radiant
                    shield around himself to block them. He drops it after she stops firing, then
                    throws a landmine-like device into the street. Its top opens to emit a wall of
                    radiation that envelops<char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char> and blocks her in.</sd>

               <sd>Back to<char ref="DoctorLight">Doctor Light</char> </sd>

               <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr><sd>from o.c.</sd>Watch yourself,
                    lightweight.</sp>

               <sd><directNote kind="pan">Pan to him</directNote> by the armored car. He has half of one axle in hand, tire and all, and
                    he moves in for a swing.</sd>

               <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>Things are about to get heavy!</sp>

               <sd>He swings the axle down over his head, missing the enemy, but creating enough of
                    a tremor upon impact to throw him back a few feet.<char ref="DoctorLight">Doctor Light</char> concentrates his
                    energy in one hand and projects an intense beam that breaks the makeshift club
                    in half. Laughing, he creates a red projectile and directs it at<char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char>  it
                    explodes in a terrific flash and storm of dust. The view clears to show that the
                    Titan is now embedded in stone, with only his head and hands free.</sd>

               <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>Uh! Hey! Let me..</sp>

               <sd><char ref="DoctorLight">Doctor Light</char> approaches.</sd>

               <sp><spkr ref="DoctorLight">Doctor Light</spkr>Now if nobody minds, I'll be taking
                    the gold.</sp>

               <sp><spkr ref="Raven">Raven</spkr><sd>from o.c.</sd>I mind<sd><directNote kind="cut">Cut to her in
                         midair</directNote>.</sd>Azarath Metrion Zin--</sp>

               <sd>Before she can finish the incantation, a beam connects squarely with her and
                    sends her to the street. He walks up behind her as she starts to get up. The
                    brooch on her cloak now shows a raven's head in its gold frame, and it will
                    continue do so throughout this episode.</sd>

               <sp><spkr ref="DoctorLight">Doctor Light</spkr>Bit of advice<sd>warms up</sd>Find
                    shorter magic words.</sp>

               <sd>She gets herself ready again; <directNote kind="pan">pan to a motorcycle</directNote> at the curb. It is levitated
                    and slung at the light-wielding enemy, who easily blows it apart. He nails her
                    with another blast and drives her down the block again. Now he takes his time
                    walking up; she has her back to him.</sd>

               <sp><spkr ref="Raven">Raven</spkr><sd>menacingly</sd>Don't come any closer</sp>

               <sd>He stops.</sd>

               <sp><spkr ref="DoctorLight">Doctor Light</spkr>What's the matter? Afraid of the
                    light?</sp>

               <sd><directNote kind="cut">Cut to behind her</directNote> on the end of this line. Snarling with pure rage, she swirls to
                    her feet. Her eyes are glowing red rather than the usual white when she uses her
                    powers. <directNote kind="pull">Pull back</directNote>; she grows to an impossible height, at least three times as
                    tall as<char ref="DoctorLight">Doctor Light</char>  and thick black tendrils shoot toward him from under her
                    cloak. He cries out in shock.</sd>

               <sp><spkr ref="DoctorLight">Doctor Light</spkr><sd>fearfully, backing up</sd>No! No
                         <sd>He is seized and pulled in; sparks fly from him.</sd>My suit! What are
                    you--? No, stop, you win, I surrender!</sp>

               <sd>Too late. He is dragged toward the billowing blue hem as<char ref="Raven">Raven</char> smiles viciously
                    down at him. When she speaks, the voice sounds as if some demonic thing is
                    saying the words along with her.</sd>

               <sp><spkr ref="Raven">Raven</spkr>What's the matter? Afraid of the dark?</sp>

               <sp><spkr ref="DoctorLight">Doctor Light</spkr>I surrender! NOOOOOO!</sp>

               <sd>He is pulled in;<char ref="Robin">Robin</char> rushes over.</sd>

               <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr><char ref="Raven">RAVEN</char>!! STOP!!</sp>

               <sd>Raven's eyes return to normal in a snap. She gasps sharply and shrinks back to
                    normal size; her cloak recedes to reveal the beaten enemy, curled up in a fetal
                    position on the pavement and shivering in wide-eyed fear.<char ref="Robin">Robin</char> and<char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char> 
                    out of her trap, run to comfort him.</sd>

               <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>It's okay. You're going to be all right.</sp>

               <sp><spkr ref="DoctorLight">Doctor Light</spkr>It was...no...so dark...make it
                    stop...make it stop..</sp>

               <sd><char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> and<char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char>  free of the pavement, approach<char ref="Raven">Raven</char> </sd>

               <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>Dude!<char ref="Raven">Raven</char>  what did you do?</sp>

               <sd>When she turns to face him, her eyes have again gone red and she is snarling as
                    before. He backs up behind<char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char> with a scream; she quickly composes herself
                    and stalks away.</sd>

               <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>What's her deal?</sp>

               <sd>She enters a dark alley and is soon lost to sight. Fade to black.</sd>

               <cue>OPENING THEM (sung in Japanese)</cue>

          </act>
          <act n="1">
               <title>Act One</title>
               <sd><stageDesc category="open-shot">Opening shot: the exterior of Titans Tower</stageDesc>. It is now the following morning.</sd>

               <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr><sd>from inside</sd>Rise and shine,
                    amigos.</sp>

               <sd>Inside, he is cooking at the kitchen counter, while<char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char> <char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char>  and <char ref="Robin">Robin</char>
                    are at the table. He has donned a chef's hat.</sd>

               <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>Breakfast is served</sp>

               <sd>He carries a steaming pan over.</sd>

               <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>Thanks,<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char>  Everything looks great</sp>

               <sd>It is set down.</sd>

               <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr>On my planet, such a feast would mark the
                    arrangement of a marriage. Tell me,<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char>  to whom are you engaged?</sp>

               <sd>Not quite ready to deal with a curveball like that so early in the day, <char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char>
                    shouts in surprise and jumps back. He has to catch his hat in order to keep it
                    from flying across the room.<char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char>  meanwhile, has started wolfing down a
                    plateful of food. When he finishes, he burps loudly and his expression changes
                    to resemble that of a person who has just eaten a skunk. He spits the meal out
                    disgustedly.</sd>

               <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>That's not eggs! That's that tofu stuff!</sp>

               <sd>He drains his glass to get the taste out of his mouth-but instead his whole head
                    ends up looking as if it might explode. The drink goes the way of the food.</sd>

               <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>That's not even real milk!</sp>

               <sd><char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> gives him a reproving frown as the door opens and<char ref="Raven">Raven</char> enters the
                    kitchen. She pays no mind to the breakfast table and heads for the counter.</sd>

               <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>Hey,<char ref="Raven">Raven</char>  Want breakfast?</sp>

               <sd>She picks up the coffeepot and pours a cup.<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> pops up behind her with a
                    full plate.</sd>

               <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>It's good. Wakey-wakey, tofu eggs and
                    bakey.</sp>

               <sp><spkr ref="Raven">Raven</spkr>Herbal tea.</sp>

               <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>Come on, just one little taste. You could
                    use a little food after the way you cooked<char ref="DoctorLight">Doctor Light</char> </sp>

               <sd><stageDesc category="close-up">Close-up of the back of her head</stageDesc> on the end of this. She then whirls to face the
                    camera, her eyes blazing red.</sd>

               <sp><spkr ref="Raven">Raven</spkr>NO!!</sp>

               <sd>The cook gasps in fear as she exerts her powers on the plate he holds. The eggs
                    explode like a volcano, leaving him covered with his own cuisine. He makes a
                    strangled little noise and drops the plate; she turns away and leaves through
                    the side door, which closes behind her.<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> stands there, holding the pan
                    of food, as a vein throbs in his temple and<char ref="Robin">Robin</char> eases over.</sd>

               <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>Maybe you should go apologize.</sp>

               <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>Me? I'm not the one who just turned
                    breakfast into a battlefield</sp>

               <sd><char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char> joins them carrying his dishes.</sd>

               <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>Yeah, but after the weirdness that went down
                    last night, you should know better than to go messing with her</sp>

               <sd>He heads for the sink.</sd>

               <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>I was trying to be nice<sd><char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char> comes
                         over.</sd>But no matter how hard I try, she still treats me like tofu eggs
                         <sd><char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char> washes the dishes.</sd>You know, she's never once laughed at any
                    of my jokes.</sp>

               <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>'Least she listens. I just kinda tune you
                    out.</sp>

               <sd><stageDesc category="gag">Sight gag: a little storm cloud appears briefly over the disgruntled green
                    Titan's head</stageDesc>.</sd>

               <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr><char ref="Raven">Raven</char> is complicated. There is much about
                    her we are not meant to understand.</sp>

               <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>Then how are we supposed to deal with her?
                    How can we even trust her? I mean--</sp>

               <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>She's our friend. What more do we need to
                    know?</sp>

               <sd><stageDesc category="close-up">Close-up of <char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char></stageDesc>, <directNote kind="zoom">zooming in slowly</directNote>; he puts the mental machinery to work
                    trying to sort this one out. <directNote kind="dissolve">Dissolve to him in the hall</directNote>, standing before a
                    closed door and scratching his head. After a few seconds, <directNote kind="cut">cut to a closer shot</directNote>;
                    he gingerly raises one fist, turns his head away as if ready to avoid a sudden
                    explosion, and just barely taps the door.</sd>

               <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr><sd>shrugging</sd>Oh, well, nobody's
                    home.</sp>

               <sd>He starts away, whistling. <directNote kind="pan">Pan to follow him</directNote> until he runs flat into<char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char>  who
                    has come up just behind him, and rubs his hurt nose.</sd>

               <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>Ow</sp>

               <sd><char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char> glares down at him.</sd>

               <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>You might want to knock a little louder.</sp>

               <sd>This is<char ref="Raven">Raven</char>'sroom, then. The big Titan plants a hand on the little one's
                    shoulder, turns him to face the door, and walks him to it. A little shudder of
                    fear comes from<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> <char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char> knocks, much louder than his colleague's
                    feeble attempt; on the third and final knock, snap to black. The view is
                    illuminated the entire door falls in, exposing them in the hall: we are now
                    inside the room, and he has smashed the door off the hinges. Both faces go slack
                    as a big drop of sweat rolls down <char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char>'s temple.</sd>

               <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>Now we both have to apologize.</sp>

               <sd><directNote kind="cut">Cut</directNote> to a pan across the quarters, proving beyond any doubt that <char ref="Raven">Raven</char>'s tastes
                    are about as dark as they come. Shelves filled with old books, four-eyed tragedy
                    and comedy masks on a pedestal, oddly shaped mirror on the wall, chalices and
                    braziers, ancient chests and lamps, a bed partly recessed into the far wall, a
                    large globe in the near corner. The entire place is done in shades of gray and
                    black. <directNote kind="cut">Back to the doorway</directNote>.</sd>

               <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>Uh,<char ref="Raven">Raven</char>  Sorry about the door.<char ref="Raven">Raven</char> </sp>

               <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>Dude, she's not here. Come on.</sp>

               <sd>He walks in and reaches the bookshelves and masks. <directNote kind="pan">Pan to follow him</directNote>.</sd>

               <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>Looks like Halloween came early this
                    year.</sp>

               <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr><sd>from o.c., whispering</sd>We're in <char ref="Raven">Raven</char>'s
                    room <sd>walking into view</sd>We should not be in <char ref="Raven">Raven</char>'s room. She doesn't let
                    anybody in here, ever!</sp>

               <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>So this is our big chance to find out more
                    about her.</sp>

               <sd>He crosses the space. <directNote kind="cut">Cut to him</directNote> at a dresser by the wall.</sd>

               <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>For instance..<sd>He laughs and picks up a
                         hand mirror, studying his image.</sd>...check out this beauty mirror. Who
                    woulda thought<char ref="Raven">Raven</char> spends time sprucing? Ah! Is that a zit?</sp>

               <sd><stageDesc category="close-up">Close-up of the mirror</stageDesc>; he pokes at a spot on his cheek. Suddenly, two pairs of
                    glowing red eyes, one above the other, superimpose themselves on his image. They
                    clear to leave him gasping in shock, and he drops the mirror and backs up with a
                    cry of fear. A red-rimmed swath of black energy shoots straight up from the
                    object, shapes itself into an arm, and grabs him. He is shaken back and forth as
                   <char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char> pays no mind, having reached the doorway and made ready to leave.</sd>

               <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>Come on, <char ref="BeastBoy">B</char>, we should really get out..<sd><char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> is yanked away.</sd>...huh?</sp>

               <sd><directNote kind="cut">Cut to the mirror</directNote>, on the floor, and <directNote kind="tilt">tilt up along the arm's length</directNote>.</sd>

               <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr><sd>from o.c.</sd>Yo!</sp>

               <sd>It starts to drag<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> down, but<char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char> is there in one swift leap to grab
                    an ankle. Both Titans are yanked through the looking glass, which returns to its
                    normal appearance and gives off a small puff of smoke.</sd>

               <sd><directNote kind="dissolve">Dissolve to within a whirlpool of dark-glowing energy</directNote>. Yelling,<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> and
                   <char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char> are swept into view at the far end and careen toward the camera and o.c.
                    <directNote kind="cut">Cut to a patch of outer space</directNote> filled with red stars and a few large asteroids; a
                    vortex opens over one of them and dumps the two Titans onto its surface. They
                    stand up just in time to watch it close.</sd>

               <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>Oh, man</sp>

               <sd><stageDesc category="long-shot">Long shot of the asteroid.</stageDesc></sd>

               <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>I told you we shouldn't have gone in her
                    room <sd><char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char> taps his forearm controls.</sd>Uh...where are we</sp>

               <sd>He walks around.</sd>

               <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>You're asking the wrong robot. My sensors must
                    be on the blink, 'cause they're saying we're in Titans Tower.</sp>

               <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>Riiiight. So how do we get back</sp>

               <sd>Pause.</sd>

               <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>Guess we start walking.</sp>

               <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>Come on. I'm serious. We're on a rock in
                    the middle of--</sp>

               <sd>The sound of something large shifting cuts him off. In the middle of the void,
                    several fragments of rock rearrange themselves to form a winding path.</sd>

               <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>Oh<sd>They set out.</sd>If sending us to
                    Weirdsville's<char ref="Raven">Raven</char>'sidea of a joke, I am so not laughing.</sp>

               <sd><directNote kind="pan">Pan slightly and refocus on a tree</directNote> in the foreground. A raven sits on one
                    branch.</sd>

               <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>Hey, she didn't send us here. You're the one who
                    went snooping in her room and popping zits in her magic mirror.</sp>

               <sd><stageDesc category="close-up">Close-up of the bird</stageDesc> during this line. Like that strange reflection, it has two
                    pairs of red eyes. Back to the two Titans.</sd>

               <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>Who booby-traps a mirror?</sp>

               <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>Maybe it wasn't a trap. Maybe it's <char ref="Raven">Raven</char>'s way
                    home. Maybe this is where she's from.</sp>

               <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>Definitely creepy enough.</sp>

               <sp><spkr ref="Voice">Voice</spkr><sd>feminine and childlike</sd>Turn back.</sp>

               <sd>They pivot for a look behind them, trying to locate the speaker.</sd>

               <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>Like I was saying...</sp>

               <sp><spkr ref="Voice">Voice</spkr>Turn back.</sp>

               <sd><directNote kind="cut">Cut to a rocky arch</directNote> over the path. Perched on it are three small black birds,
                    each of which shows a pair of large red eyes to the camera. One at a time, they
                    repeat the two-word instruction and continue under the next line.</sd>

               <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>Sweet! Betcha they can tell us how to get
                    home</sp>

               <sd><directNote kind="pan">Pan</directNote>; he passes<char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char> </sd>

               <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>Careful. How do we know they're not a
                    threat</sp>

               <sd><char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> reaches the arch.</sd>

               <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>Hel-lo? Remember me?<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char>  If they
                    were dangerous, I'd know.</sp>

               <sd><char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char> is not a bit convinced that this guy knows what he is doing. Said guy
                    turns to the arch and adopts the sort of tone one might use with a small
                    kitten.</sd>

               <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>Hey, little guys. My buddy and I were
                    wondering if--</sp>

               <sd><directNote kind="tilt">Tilt up to the arch</directNote> on the end of this; the birds are gone. When the camera <directNote kind="tilt">tilts
                    down again</directNote>, five of them have gathered at his feet. "Turn back" is repeated over
                    and over during a <directNote kind="pan">pan across them in <stageDesc category="close-up">close-up</stageDesc></directNote>. The beaks suddenly elongate and
                    sprout small sharp teeth, and each eye splits into two smaller ones to match the
                    raven seen earlier. Their snarls are met with a surprised cry from<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> 
                    who turns and runs smack into<char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char>  the former tumbles o.c. while the latter
                    crashes down on the stones.</sd>

               <sd>The birds, now multiplied into a flock of ravens, fly past<char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char> and zero in on
                    the skidding shape-shifter. <transform class="mammal">He turns into a hippopotamus</transform> and opens wide, and
                    three of them perch on his tongue. Snap go the jaws; the prey squirms inside,
                    and after a moment, he has to open his mouth again and shake them off, they have
                    clamped their beaks onto the lingual muscle.<char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char>  faring no better, shouts as
                    he tries to beat off the attackers.</sd>

               <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>Get 'em off me! Get 'em off me<sd>runs o.c.;
                         they follow</sd>Cut it out!</sp>

               <sd>Back and forth they go.<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char>  <transform class="bird">as an ostrich</transform>, followed by<char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char>  then the
                    flock. The flock, dodging a sonic cannon shot, then<char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char> riding <char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> <transform class="mammal">in
                    llama form</transform> and firing away. One dodges a few shots and buzzes past him; he
                    hunches down over his mount and fires another round. We then see the creature
                    fly low, and in response<char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char> growls and blasts straight down at it. Fractured
                    by the energy, the stone path starts to crumble away; the two Titans trade the
                    classic "uh-oh" look and<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char>'sears droop sadly just before they drop out
                    of sight. <directNote kind="cut">Cut to the broken edge</directNote> of the path, seen from below, and <directNote kind="pull">pull back</directNote>.
                   <char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char> has one hand buried in <char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char>'s pelt and the other dug into the broken
                    rock. <stageDesc category="close-up">Close-up</stageDesc>; he starts to haul the green animal up, but a very familiar voice
                    stops him cold, not so much the speaker, but the tone.</sd>

               <sp><spkr ref="Raven">Raven</spkr><sd>from o.c., cheerfully</sd>Hey, guys.</sp>

               <sd><directNote kind="pull">Pull back a bit</directNote>. On the underside of the path, she can be seen from the knees
                    down. <charDesc ref="PinkRaven">However, her boots and cloak are bright pink rather than the usual blue</charDesc>,
                    and the cloak does not hang down as it would if a person stood on his head. <directNote kind="cut">Cut
                    to <char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char>'s perspective</directNote>; she is hanging upside down with no ill effects
                    whatsoever, and she waves. Her wristbands have also gone pink.</sd>

               <sp><spkr ref="PinkRaven">Pink Raven</spkr>What's up</sp>

               <sd><stageDesc category="close-up">Close-up of <char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char> </stageDesc>.</sd>

               <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr><sd>in a small voice</sd>I don't know
                    anymore.</sp>

               <sd><directNote kind="pull">Pull back to frame all three</directNote>. The camera turns 180 degrees to put<char ref="Raven">Raven</char> right
                    side up and the two interlopers upside down.</sd>

               <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>Whoa!</sp>

               <sd>He and<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> slam down onto the path.<char ref="Raven">Raven</char> giggles as the latter stands up,
                    back in human form.</sd>

               <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>Raven?! How did, where are, what
                         just--<sd><stageDesc category="gag">A question mark pops up by his head.</stageDesc></sd>Why are you wearing
                    pink?</sp>

               <sp><spkr ref="PinkRaven">Pink Raven</spkr><sd>giggling</sd>'Cause it's my favorite
                    color.</sp>

               <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>It is</sp>

               <sd><char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char> gets up.</sd>

               <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>Look, I'd love to talk fashion, but I don't
                    suppose you know how to get home.</sp>

               <sp><spkr ref="PinkRaven">Pink Raven</spkr>The Forbidden Door.</sp>

               <sd><directNote kind="pan">Pan slightly</directNote> to put her out of view and frame the rest of the path, which runs
                    under a couple of other arches and stops at a distant asteroid.</sd>

               <sp><spkr ref="PinkRaven">Pink Raven</spkr><sd>from o.c.</sd>It's the only way out,
                    but you don't want to go there<sd>Back to the three.</sd>Not now.</sp>

               <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy Cyborg">Beast Boy and Cyborg</spkr><sd>glance at each
                         other and speak in unison</sd>Uh...yeah, we do.</sp>

               <sp><spkr ref="PinkRaven">Pink Raven</spkr>'Kay, but don't say I didn't warn
                    ya.</sp>

               <sd><directNote kind="cut">Cut to the nearest arch</directNote>. Making airplane sounds and stretching her arms out like
                    wings, she runs through it and down the path.</sd>

               <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr><sd>from o.c.</sd>Have you ever seen her this
                    happy?</sp>

               <sd>He and<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> walk after her.</sd>

               <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>Dude, I didn't even know<char ref="Raven">Raven</char> could do
                    happy.</sp>

               <sd>Their images fade away. <directNote kind="cut">Cut to a peaceful-looking landscape</directNote> under a bright yellow
                    sky; a stone arch springs overhead, and they appear beneath it.</sd>

               <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>Now where are we?</sp>

               <sd><directNote kind="dissolve">Dissolve to a <stageDesc category="long-shot">long</stageDesc><stageDesc category="overhead-shot">overhead shot</stageDesc></directNote> and <directNote kind="pull">pull back slowly</directNote>. A path goes on and on,
                    threading through that arch and bisecting a huge meadow filled with pink grass
                    and trees. <directNote kind="fade">Fade to black</directNote>.</sd>

          </act>
          <act n="2">
               <title>Act Two</title>
               <sd><stageDesc category="open-shot">Opening shot: the serene pink landscape and yellow sky</stageDesc>. A small strawberry floats
                    past the path; follow it over to two extremely bewildered Titans.</sd>

               <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>I think this might be where air fresheners
                    come from.</sp>

               <sd>Giggling from o.c.; <directNote kind="pan">pan to bring <char ref="PinkRaven">Pink Raven</char> into view</directNote> next to them.</sd>

               <sp><spkr ref="PinkRaven">Pink Raven</spkr>Good one!</sp>

               <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>You're laughing?</sp>

               <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>At one of my jokes?</sp>

               <sp><spkr ref="PinkRaven">Pink Raven</spkr>Sure. I've always thought you were funny,
                    BB. But hey, looks aren't everything.</sp>

               <sd>Laughing even harder now, she takes her leave of them. <directNote kind="cut">Cut to the exterior of the
                    Tower</directNote> and <directNote kind="zoom">zoom in toward the roof</directNote>.</sd>

               <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr><sd>from the roof</sd><char ref="Raven">Raven</char> ...</sp>

               <sd><directNote kind="cut">Cut to her</directNote>, meditating up there.</sd>

               <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr><sd>from o.c.</sd>...you okay? We stopped by your
                    room and the door's been knocked down.</sp>

               <sd>He and<char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char> come up behind her on the end of this. <char ref="Raven">Raven</char>'s eyes pop open,
                    wide as saucers, and she laughs uncontrollably for a few seconds. The sound
                    scares the other two Titans out of their wits; she cuts it off by clapping both
                    hands over her mouth.</sd>

               <sp><spkr ref="Raven">Raven</spkr><sd>blushing profusely</sd>Need to be alone.</sp>

               <sd>She stands up and hurries to the door leading to the stairs/elevator. The camera
                    placement makes it almost appear as if she passes through the barrier.</sd>

               <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr><sd>to Robin</sd>Many of your Earthly ways
                    are still strange to me, but that was...just plain freaky. Correct?</sp>

               <sd><directNote kind="cut">Cut to just inside</directNote> the wrecked door of her room. She looks in around the frame,
                    enters, and puts the wall back in order with an easy motion of the hand. Walking
                    in a bit farther, she stops short at the hand mirror on the floor.</sd>

               <sp><spkr ref="Raven">Raven</spkr><sd>horrified</sd>No.</sp>

               <sd><directNote kind="cut">Cut to the pink meadow</directNote>; the camera points down from the treetops, where a few
                    four-eyed ravens have perched. <directNote kind="pan">Pan to bring<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> and<char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char> into view</directNote>,
                    making their way along the path that runs on and on toward an arch that looks
                    very much like the one they started at.</sd>

               <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>She ditched us! I can't believe <char ref="Raven">Raven</char> 
                    ditched us! Next time I see her, it's not gonna be pretty.</sp>

               <sd>As he says this, the <directNote kind="dissolve">scenery dissolves to the outer-space region</directNote> they were in
                    before. They are back on the winding stone path. <directNote kind="cut">Cut</directNote> to a <stageDesc category="long-shot">long shot</stageDesc> and <directNote kind="pull">pull
                    back briefly</directNote>, then back to them.</sd>

               <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>Hey, I know where we are! We're in that place
                    where I didn't know where we were before.</sp>

               <sd><char ref="Raven">Raven</char> pops up in front of them, her back to us, and startles the daylights out of
                    them. <charDesc ref="GrayRaven">Her cloak is now gray</charDesc>; <directNote kind="cut">cut</directNote> to a <stageDesc category="close-up">close-up</stageDesc>, revealing a very sad and fearful
                    facial expression.</sd>

               <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr><sd>furiously</sd>Where were you? Shopping
                    for robes?!</sp>

               <sd><stageDesc category="gag">Sight gag: his head grows a few sizes and flushes an angry red, with a vein
                    standing out on his temple, and she shrinks to midget size in his shadow and
                    starts to cry</stageDesc>. The two quickly return to normal size as her tears stop.</sd>

               <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>Whoa. Easy<sd><directNote kind="cut">Cut to them</directNote>.</sd>I didn't
                    mean it. Please don't--</sp>

               <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr><sd>from o.c.</sd>Hey!</sp>

               <sd><directNote kind="cut">Cut to him</directNote>. He points ahead down the path toward the asteroid at the end; they
                    are closer now.</sd>

               <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>That's that Forbidden Door, right, <char ref="Raven">Raven</char> <sd>She
                         nods worriedly;<char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char> starts to run.</sd>Come on, y'all! We're
                    almost--</sp>

               <sd>A high metal wall springs up from the stone surface to block his rush.</sd>

               <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>Whoa!</sp>

               <sd>More walls emerge to box in the trio. <directNote kind="dissolve">Dissolve to an <stageDesc category="overhead-shot">overhead view</stageDesc></directNote> of the area; a
                    large maze has assembled itself here, and the camera <directNote kind="tilt">tilts up</directNote> to show it filling
                    much of the stretch leading to the asteroid. Inside, <char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> <transform class="bird">turns into a
                    falcon</transform> and flies up toward the open top of the labyrinth. Just as he is about to
                    surmount the walls, a force field crackles to life and sends him crashing to the
                    ground. <transform class="human">He sits up in human form</transform> and rubs his head.</sd>

               <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>Great</sp>

               <sd><char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char> breaks out his cannon.</sd>

               <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>Oh, man, we gotta get outta here!</sp>

               <sd>He fires a few bursts at the walls, but it does not even put a scratch on them.
                    <char ref="GrayRaven">Gray Raven</char> speaks up for the first time; her voice matches her expression
                    perfectly.</sd>

               <sp><spkr ref="GrayRaven">Gray Raven</spkr>It's a maze. You can't get out. You have
                    to go through. I can show you the way, but when we reach the end, you won't like
                    me anymore<sd>looks at <char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> </sd>He already doesn't like me.</sp>

               <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>Come on. That's not...</sp>

               <sd>She has already started down the way. The two boys stare after her with a fair
                    bit of irritation.</sd>

               <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>Gee,<char ref="Raven">Raven</char>  moody much?</sp>

               <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>Yeah, she's like a whole different person.</sp>

               <sd><directNote kind="dissolve">Dissolve to another part</directNote> of the convoluted architecture. <char ref="GrayRaven">Gray Raven</char>'s voice is
                    heard from around a corner shortly before she walks into view.</sd>

               <sp><spkr ref="GrayRaven">Gray Raven</spkr>And...remember the time I called you both
                    immature pinheads? I'm sorry for that, too. And also, the-</sp>

               <sd><char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char> and<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> round the corner.</sd>

               <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>For the hundredth, millionth time...</sp>

               <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy Cyborg">Beast Boy and Cyborg</spkr><sd>lean toward the
                         camera and speak in unison</sd>...we forgive you!</sp>

               <sd><directNote kind="cut">Cut to<char ref="GrayRaven">Gray Raven</char></directNote>, who has stopped at a wall. She waves timidly toward it, and it
                    slides open like a pair of interlocking doors to reveal a short path that leads
                    out of the maze. <directNote kind="tilt">Tilt up</directNote>, putting her out of view, to show two tall stone
                    statues positioned to either side. They wear long cloaks and have faces that
                    match the masks in<char ref="Raven">Raven</char>'sroom. Each has only one arm, on the side toward the
                    wall next to it.</sd>

               <sp><spkr ref="GrayRaven">Gray Raven</spkr><sd>from o.c.</sd>That's the end</sp>

               <sd><directNote kind="cut">Cut to the three</directNote>.</sd>

               <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>Sweet!</sp>

               <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>All right,<char ref="Raven">Raven</char> </sp>

               <sd>They head for the egress, but she does not join them. The eyes of the smiling
                    statue glow red, followed by those of the frowning one, and they slam together
                    back to back. Three quick half-turns put the smile in view, then the frown, then
                    the smile again. <stageDesc category="close-up">Close-up of each hand in turn</stageDesc>; long swords materialize in them,
                    and when the <directNote kind="pull">camera pulls back</directNote>, we see that the double sculpture has now grown a
                    second set of arms.</sd>

               <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>What?</sp>

               <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>No way</sp>

               <sd><char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char> groans.</sd>

               <sp><spkr ref="GrayRaven">Gray Raven</spkr>Told you you wouldn't like me when we got
                    here.</sp>

               <sd>She drops out of sight, but the guys have no time to worry about her; the stone
                    giant is advancing toward them. Suddenly, the screen fills with static and
                    resolves to a view of a screaming man running from a huge green monster. More
                    static, which clears to show a chef working in his kitchen.</sd>

               <sp><spkr ref="Chef">Chef</spkr>Now the salt.</sp>

               <sd><directNote kind="pull">Pull back into the operations center</directNote>; this is a show<char ref="Robin">Robin</char> is watching on the
                    window/screen, as was the previous clip. He lounges on the couch while <char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char>
                    paces behind him.</sd>

               <sp><spkr ref="Chef">Chef</spkr>Stir continuously until thickened.</sp>

               <sd><directNote kind="cut">Cut to<char ref="Robin">Robin</char></directNote>. He works the remote; from the TV's direction, a Western starts
                    up.</sd>

               <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr>May we go see if she is feeling better?</sp>

               <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>She said she wanted to be alone.</sp>

               <sd>Another click, and the screen again fills with static. It clears to give a view
                    of the end of the outer-space path; <directNote kind="tilt">tilt down to<char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char> and<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char></directNote>, who back
                    nervously along it. The sound of swords being drawn is heard, and here comes
                    that sculpture guardian with both blades ready to go. As it bears down on them,
                    <char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> <transform class="bird">becomes a falcon</transform> and flies away, and<char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char> lets loose a blast from
                    his cannon that does no damage. A sword clangs down on the stone next to him.
                    That green falcon swoops down, talons extended, only to be caught in one of the
                    two free hands and squeezed cruelly. <transform class="human">It changes back into</transform><char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> as <char ref="Raven">Raven</char>'s
                    voice is heard once again, but this time, she sounds radically different.</sd>

               <sp><spkr ref="Raven">Raven</spkr><sd>from o.c., spoiling for a fight</sd>Yo!
                    Eight-Eyes!</sp>

               <sd><directNote kind="cut">Cut to her</directNote>, launching a flying kick. Her cloak is now green.</sd>

               <sp><spkr ref="GreenRaven">Green Raven</spkr>Hai-yah!</sp>

               <sd>The kick slashes across the statue's head and sends it toppling to the
                    ground.</sd>

               <sp><spkr ref="GreenRaven">Green Raven</spkr>Whoo-hoo! In your faces!</sp>

               <sd>She leaps at the foe, now back on its feet, and dodges one sword slash after
                    another without changing the little smirk on her face. Up she goes, index and
                    middle fingers of one hand extended together, and brings them straight down the
                    length of the rock body. Smoke billows out to follow the trace; <directNote kind="cut">cut to a
                    <stageDesc category="close-up">close-up</stageDesc> of the surface</directNote>, which breaks apart along the new cleavage. The two
                    halves drop away, leaving<char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char> and<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> staring in pure amazement at this
                    new incarnation of their fellow Titan.</sd>

               <sp><spkr ref="GreenRaven">Green Raven</spkr>Hoo-ah! High fives! Come on!</sp>

               <sd><char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> stares a bit more, his jaw slack, and then shakes his head vigorously
                    to clear it.</sd>

               <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>What is your deal?! First, you nuke
                         breakfast..<sd><directNote kind="cut">Cut to the trees</directNote>, full of red-eyed ravens; he continues
                         o.c.</sd> ...then finally laugh at my jokes..<sd><directNote kind="tilt">Tilt down to the
                         three</directNote>.</sd>...then you're all weepy, and now you're a Marine? Make up your
                    mind. Who are you?</sp>

               <sd><char ref="GreenRaven">Green Raven</char> directs a quizzical look at him as grinning <char ref="PinkRaven">Pink </char>leaps into view and
                    glum <char ref="GrayRaven">Gray</char> slinks up.</sd>

               <sp><spkr ref="GreenRaven GrayRaven PinkRaven">Green, Gray, and Pink
                         Ravens</spkr><sd>all at the same time</sd>I'm Raven</sp>

               <sd>Poleaxed by the sight,<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> faints.</sd>

               <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>Happy...timid...brave.</sp>

               <sp><spkr ref="PinkRaven">Pink Raven</spkr><sd>pointing at<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char>  he gets
                         up</sd> You forgot dopey.</sp>

               <sd>She laughs, but<char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char> is thinking very hard and starting to figure a few things
                    out.</sd>

               <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>Different sides of <char ref="Raven">Raven</char>'s personality. We're
                    not in<char ref="Raven">Raven</char>'shome.</sp>

               <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>We're in her head.</sp>

               <sp><spkr ref="Raven">Raven</spkr><sd>from o.c., normal tone</sd>And I want you
                    out.</sp>

               <sd>The blue-cloaked girl drops into view in front of her three duplicates, who fade
                    away.</sd>

               <sp><spkr ref="Raven">Raven</spkr>The mirror you found is for meditation. It's a
                    portal into my MIND, NOT A TOY!</sp>

               <sd>The last four words are aimed at<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> and spoken through gritted teeth. A
                    big drop of sweat rolls down his face. <directNote kind="pull">Pull back to the treetops</directNote>; the ravens are
                    still watching.</sd>

               <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr><sd>chuckling</sd>My bad.</sp>

               <sd>The birds fly away in a great commotion of squawking and flapping wings.</sd>

               <sp><spkr ref="Raven">Raven</spkr>You have to go, now.</sp>

               <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>Hold up. What's going on here</sp>

               <sd><stageDesc category="close-up">Close-up of her</stageDesc>.</sd>

               <sp><spkr ref="Raven">Raven</spkr>Last night, something...got loose. Something
                    bad.</sp>

               <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr><sd>from o.c.</sd>Oh, no, you don't<sd><directNote kind="pull">Pull
                         back to frame him</directNote>.</sd>I've had it with this mystery-girl routine. I want
                    to know exactly what we're talking about here.</sp>

               <sd>There is an unholy roaring from o.c. <directNote kind="cut">Cut to a gargantuan black vortex</directNote> that has
                    formed over the horizon; the ravens are flying into it. Gradually, this retreats
                    from the top down to expose a <charDesc ref="Trigon">super-king-sized humanoid male with red skin,
                    flowing white hair, and four glowing yellow eyes. He is clad in a black and gray
                    loincloth, steel wristbands, and a belt similar to the one<char ref="Raven">Raven</char> wears, as well
                    as a jewel on his forehead. The belt is silver, set with black stones, and a
                    matching piece is set at the throat to match her brooch. There are short, curved
                    black stripes on the arms and chest.</charDesc> This is <char ref="Raven">Raven</char>'s father, the demon
                    <char ref="Trigon">Trigon</char> .</sd>

               <sp><spkr ref="Trigon">Trigon</spkr>Hatred shall rule.</sp>

               <sd>His voice is the same as the one overlaid with <char ref="Raven">Raven</char>'s when she snared <char ref="DoctorLight">Doctor Light</char> at the beginning of the episode. <directNote kind="tilt">Tilt down to the horizon</directNote>; he also wears
                    shin guards to match his wristbands.<char ref="Raven">Raven</char> and the boys stare up at his sheer
                    size.</sd>

               <sp><spkr ref="Raven">Raven</spkr><sd>as all three back up</sd>Let's just say I have
                    issues with my father.</sp>

               <sd><directNote kind="cut">Cut to<char ref="Trigon">Trigon</char></directNote>, who moves steadily ahead and leans down with a roar, giving the
                    camera an extreme <stageDesc category="close-up">close-up of his face</stageDesc>. <directNote kind="fade">Fade to black</directNote>.</sd>

          </act>
          <act n="3">
               <title>Act Three</title>
               <sd><stageDesc category="open-shot">Opening shot: the three Titans standing before Trigon</stageDesc>. <directNote kind="tilt">Tilt up to his head</directNote>, he
                    roars, throwing a scare into all of them.<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> and<char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char> turn to run, but
                   <char ref="Raven">Raven</char> holds her ground. A quadruple blast from those glowing eyes hits the
                    ground just in front of her, forcing her to jump clear. Those enormous feet
                    stomp down the path after<char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char> and<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char>  who are making a beeline for a
                    portal set into the base of a rock formation: the Forbidden Door. A beam hits
                    just in front of them and brings that plan to a very abrupt halt.<char ref="Raven">Raven</char> drops
                    into view facing<char ref="Trigon">Trigon</char>.</sd>

               <sp><spkr ref="Raven">Raven</spkr>Azarath Metrion Zinthos!</sp>

               <sd>She creates a shield around herself, the boys, and the Door; daddy not-so-dearest
                    unleashes another blast that cuts a long furrow in the stone as it races toward
                    her. So much rock and dust is thrown up that we cannot see whether her barrier
                    is holding. The screen fills with static,<char ref="Robin">Robin</char> is changing channels again. Stop
                    briefly on a tropical waterfall, then flip to a man and a woman about to kiss,
                    then cut to him on the couch, the remote in his hand.<char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char> pops up behind
                    him.</sd>

               <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr>May we now go see if<char ref="Raven">Raven</char> is better?</sp>

               <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>She wants to be alone.</sp>

               <sd>Another flip brings jungle sounds from the TV's direction; irked, she turns away.
                    <directNote kind="cut">Cut to a profile close-up of<char ref="Trigon">Trigon</char></directNote>; he fires another eye beam, and the <directNote kind="pull">camera
                    pulls back</directNote> to a <stageDesc category="long-shot">long</stageDesc> <stageDesc category="overhead-shot">overhead shot</stageDesc> of the area.<char ref="Raven">Raven</char>'sshield is indeed holding
                    up. <stageDesc category="close-up">Close-up of her</stageDesc>.</sd>

               <sp><spkr ref="Raven">Raven</spkr><sd>with great effort</sd>Get out of my mind!
                    Now!</sp>

               <sd><directNote kind="pan">Pan to<char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char> and<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char></directNote>. The Door has now filled with a whirlpool just like
                    the one that carried them into this place to begin with.</sd>

               <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>And leave you alone with that?</sp>

               <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>Not gonna happen.</sp>

               <sp><spkr ref="Raven">Raven</spkr>It's my problem. I'll deal with it. If I lose,
                    you'll be stuck in here forever.</sp>

               <sd>Pulling his hands back,<char ref="Trigon">Trigon</char> produces a ball of energy between them and swings
                    it forward to throw a mighty burst at his daughter. It breaches the shield, and
                    a second shot blows it apart altogether. There is a great cloud of dust, which
                    clears to show her still on her feet, arms crossed to protect her head. She
                    swings one hand behind her in a sudden lash of telekinesis.</sd>

               <sp><spkr ref="Raven">Raven</spkr>Go!</sp>

               <sd><char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> and<char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char> are flung screaming toward the portal, but skid to a stop
                    just short of its mouth. She flies up toward his level and fires a black salvo
                    from her hand, annoying him enough to make him start trying to swat her down.
                    Her evasive maneuvers make this a rather tougher prospect than it might seem at
                    first; his next eye blast also hits nothing. The two fellows watch, then look at
                    the exit, and finally trade a knowing look.</sd>

               <sd>The free-for-all continues.<char ref="Raven">Raven</char> dodges<char ref="Trigon">Trigon</char>'sattempt to crush her between
                    his palms and lands a shot on his chest. She is behind his head in the briefest
                    instant, but he whirls and scores a direct hit that drops her like a rock. He
                    catches her, knocked senseless, in one broad hand.</sd>

               <sp><spkr ref="Trigon">Trigon</spkr>Rage shall consume you.</sp>

               <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr><sd>from o.c.</sd>Yo!</sp>

               <sd><directNote kind="pull">Pull back</directNote>; he is standing on a nearby mountain ledge and has his cannon locked
                    and loaded.</sd>

               <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>Sounds like somebody needs a time-out.</sp>

               <sd>His blast is blocked when the demon raises a forearm, but with the chest left
                    wide open, a second shot finds its mark.<char ref="Trigon">Trigon</char> stumbles backward, letting go of
                   <char ref="Raven">Raven</char>  and topples over the edge of the asteroid into empty space.<char ref="Raven">Raven</char> tumbles
                    helplessly toward a high-speed hello with a granite slab, but <char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char>, <transform class="bird">as a
                    falcon</transform>, is diving down at top speed. <stageDesc category="close-up">Close-up of her</stageDesc>; his talons close on her
                    shoulder, and she starts to come around with a barely audible moan. <directNote kind="pull">Pull back to
                    ground level</directNote>. He sets her down safely, leaving her to fall to her knees with a
                    small groan, and <transform class="human">drops back next to her in human form</transform>.</sd>

               <sp><spkr ref="Raven">Raven</spkr>You stayed? I thought you didn't like me.</sp>

               <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>Thought you didn't like me</sp>

               <sd>She smiles.</sd>

               <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr><sd>from o.c.</sd>Yo, I like both of you<sd><directNote kind="cut">Cut
                         to him</directNote>.</sd>Now get your butts over here!</sp>

               <sd>A growling<char ref="Trigon">Trigon</char> rises slowly over the ridge behind him. <directNote kind="pull">Pull back</directNote> and <directNote kind="tilt">tilt up</directNote>
                    as he gets fully erect and raises his arms.</sd>

               <sp><spkr ref="Trigon">Trigon</spkr>Feel my fury!</sp>

               <sd>A four-pack of eye blasts blows up the ground at<char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char>'sfeet and sends him
                    diving for cover.<char ref="Raven">Raven</char> and<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> both take to the air; <transform class="reptile">he as a pterodactyl</transform>,
                    to continue the offensive and get backup from their partner's cannon. He bobs
                    and weaves through the barren landscape to dodge the blazing bursts and returns
                    fire as he is able. The last round gets<char ref="Trigon">Trigon</char> good and mad; <stageDesc category="close-up">close-up of him</stageDesc> as
                    he leans down to hit the big man point-blank. Before he can deliver that
                    finishing stroke, though, he yells in surprise and his head is pulled backward.
                    <directNote kind="cut">Cut to behind him</directNote>, revealing that<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> has wrapped his talons around that
                    mane of white hair and started hauling back with all his strength.<char ref="Trigon">Trigon</char> is
                    dragged off balance to crash down among the rocky peaks, but is soon sitting up
                    to shoot at<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char>  who flies away.</sd>

               <sd>The screen fills with static and then <directNote kind="cut">cuts to<char ref="Robin">Robin</char> on the couch</directNote>. Once again,
                   <char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char> eases her head up behind him. The sound of a baseball game comes from
                    the TV's direction.</sd>

               <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr>May we now--?</sp>

               <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>No!</sp>

               <sd>She drops out of sight with a groan, and he works the remote again. More static,
                    which resolves to<char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char> on the run from<char ref="Trigon">Trigon</char>'sfusillade.<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> flies
                    overhead and picks him up as<char ref="Raven">Raven</char> passes them both. The scarlet leviathan waves
                    away the dust, looks around a bit, and moves away; <directNote kind="tilt">tilt down to the group</directNote>
                    huddled behind a small ridge. <char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> <transform class="human">is human again</transform>.</sd>

               <sp><spkr ref="Raven">Raven</spkr>He's too strong. Even with your help, I cannot
                    defeat him.</sp>

               <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>So call for backup! What about all those other
                    you's?</sp>

               <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>Yeah, the green one kinda kicked butt.</sp>

               <sp><spkr ref="Raven">Raven</spkr>It still wouldn't be enough. None of my other
                    sides have the kind of power we need.</sp>

               <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>Not alone, but what about together
                         <sd>Trigon's footsteps approach.</sd>They're all part of who you are,
                    right?</sp>

               <sd>The camera shakes as dust floats down around them.<char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char> peeks over the ridge
                    and sees the demonic figure nearby. A couple of eye blasts send the Titan
                    ducking back behind the rocks.</sd>

               <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>Go for it! We got your back.</sp>

               <sd><char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> gives her an encouraging nod and runs after<char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char> to assist in the
                    diversion. A small smile crosses her face and then disappears as she closes her
                    eyes and begins to concentrate. Her hood is down at this point, <directNote kind="dissolve">but a dissolve
                    shows her with it up</directNote>. Opening her eyes, she crosses her arms in front of herself
                    as the <directNote kind="pull">camera pulls back</directNote>; a sudden gust of wind stirs the dust at her feet, and
                    her duplicates rise from the ground. One of them is so close that her cloak
                    blacks out the screen. <directNote kind="fade">Fade in to no fewer than six Ravens</directNote> in cloaks of pink,
                    gray, green, yellow, brown, and lavender.<char ref="YellowRaven">Yellow Raven</char> wears glasses, perhaps
                    representing her cerebral aspect. Well after the arrival of this group, a
                    seventh alter ego pops up, clad in an orange cloak. She digs something out of
                    her ear, opens her eyes sleepily, and burps; <char ref="Raven">Raven</char>'s lazy side.</sd>

               <sd>They scatter; <directNote kind="cut">cut to<char ref="Raven">Raven</char></directNote> as they form a large circle around her. All eight rise
                    into the air and hover several feet above the ground, and the seven doubles
                    start to spin about her center point, faster and faster until they are visible
                    only as colored blurs. The formation gradually turns white, sucking up a little
                    grit due to the airspeed, and the whole screen is washed out from the
                    brilliance, except for <char ref="Raven">Raven</char>'s form, which can be seen fuzzily at the
                    center.</sd>

               <sd>A huge flash puts the camera near<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> and<char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char>  the latter firing his
                    cannon at will.<char ref="Trigon">Trigon</char> counters with a storm of bird apparitions from his hand;
                    <char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> <transform class="reptile">turns into a pterodactyl</transform> again and takes to the air.<char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char> is quickly
                    beset by the flapping things and loses control of his shots. The giant smiles
                    evilly down at him and does not notice<char ref="Raven">Raven</char> rising behind his own head; her
                    <charDesc ref="WhiteRaven">tightly wrapped cloak now pure white</charDesc>. He swivels to look her full in the face,
                    and the wind blows her garment open to reveal that her outfit is also white
                    instead of black.</sd>

               <sd><char ref="WhiteRaven">White Raven</char> hurls a mass of black energy, which forms itself into a band that
                    encircles<char ref="Trigon">Trigon</char> tightly from shoulders to waist. Her next words take on a very
                    deep and terrible tone.</sd>

               <sp><spkr ref="WhiteRaven">White Raven</spkr>You are going back where you
                    belong!</sp>

               <sp><spkr ref="Trigon">Trigon</spkr>Never!</sp>

               <sd>He breaks loose of her binding spell. She rises into the air, arms crossed in
                    front, and her eyes and mouth start to blaze with the same dark force that pours
                    from her hands. <directNote kind="cut">Cut to<char ref="Trigon">Trigon</char></directNote> and <directNote kind="pull">pull back</directNote>; he sends two huge beams from his
                    hands toward her. The two energies meet at a point between them and cancel out;
                    it becomes a tug-of-war, with the balance point shifting back and forth between
                    them. <char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char>,<transform class="human"> back in human form</transform>, and<char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char> have their hands full trying to
                    keep those birds from pecking them to mush, but they suddenly disappear.</sd>

               <sd>The standoff between <char ref="WhiteRaven">White Raven</char> and<char ref="Trigon">Trigon</char> continues, with the former slowly
                    gaining ground. One final groaning effort sends her beam surging into his face;
                    there is an incredible flash when it hits, and the screen clears to show that he
                    has turned into another copy of her, with red eyes and a dark red cloak. <char ref="RedRaven">Red Raven</char> drops to the ground in front of the white-clad real thing, revealing
                    herself to be perhaps a foot tall, and raises her head to expose two pairs of
                    those glowing eyes. Her body disintegrates into a bolt of energy that crackles
                    into <char ref="WhiteRaven">White Raven</char>'s, throwing her into an unbearable rictus.</sd>

               <sd>One final flash leaves the screen filled with smoke, which clears to show only
                    the Titan standing on a rock-back in her normal blue cloak and bowed as if she
                    has just taken the beating of a lifetime. As she straightens up, the wind
                    reveals her black outfit beneath. A moment later, she moans weakly and collapses
                    backward only to be caught by<char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char> and<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> </sd>

               <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>We gotcha.</sp>

               <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>It's okay</sp>

               <sd>They set her on her feet; she blushes.</sd>

               <sp><spkr ref="Raven">Raven</spkr><sd>rubs her head</sd>Thank you...friends.</sp>

               <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>So...we really are friends?</sp>

               <sp><spkr ref="Raven">Raven</spkr><sd>nods, with a small smile</sd>Mmm-hmm.</sp>

               <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>And you really think I'm funny?</sp>

               <sp><spkr ref="Raven">Raven</spkr><sd>her smile fades</sd>Don't push it.</sp>

               <sd><directNote kind="dissolve">Dissolve to the exterior of the Tower</directNote>; it is now nighttime. <stageDesc category="close-up">Close-up of
                    <char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char>'s hand inside</stageDesc>, straining toward a door to knock, with <char ref="Robin">Robin</char>'s fingers
                    wrapped around her arm to pull it back.</sd>

               <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr><sd>from o.c.</sd>Please! Let us
                    simply-</sp>

               <sd>He pulls her back.</sd>

               <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr><sd>from o.c.</sd><char ref="Raven">Raven</char> asked us not to disturb
                    her!</sp>

               <sd><directNote kind="pull">Pull back to frame them</directNote> on the end of this. They are outside the door to <char ref="Raven">Raven</char>'s
                    room.</sd>

               <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr>She could be weeping and--</sp>

               <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>I don't want to bother her</sp>

               <sd><stageDesc category="close-up">Close-up of their hands</stageDesc>.</sd>

               <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr><sd>from o.c.</sd>But if we merely--</sp>

               <sd>The door opens. Head-on view of the two; she relaxes with a gasp and smiles, and
                    he tumbles backward to the floor. <directNote kind="pull">Pull back to frame the entire doorway</directNote>, in
                    which<char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char> <char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char>  and<char ref="Raven">Raven</char> are now standing.<char ref="Robin">Robin</char> gets to his
                    feet.</sd>

               <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>Where have you guys been?</sp>

               <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>Just getting to know each other</sp>

               <sd><char ref="Raven">Raven</char> smiles and blushes.</sd>

               <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr>Come, friends. We shall prepare a new
                    breakfast feast.</sp>

               <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>It's a little late for breakfast, <char ref="Starfire">Star</char>.
                    Maybe just some herbal tea.</sp>

               <sp><spkr ref="Raven">Raven</spkr>Actually, breakfast sounds...nice.</sp>

               <sd><char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> is caught off-guard momentarily by her change of eating habits, but he
                    quickly smiles as stars flash briefly in his eyes.</sd>

               <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>Breakfast for dinner? Coming up</sp>

               <sd>He runs off;<char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char> goes after him.</sd>

               <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>Oh, no! I'm cooking this time!</sp>

               <sd><directNote kind="cut">Cut to the exterior of the Tower</directNote>.</sd>

               <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr><sd>from inside</sd>We're having real eggs!</sp>

               <sd><directNote kind="pull">Pull back slowly</directNote> and <directNote kind="fade">fade to black</directNote>.</sd>
          </act>
     </body>
</root>