<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../schema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?><root>
    <head>
        <episode>FORCES OF NATURE</episode>
        <writer>David Slack</writer>
        <director>Ciro Nieli</director>
        <storyboard>Kalvin Lee, Rafael Rosado, Alan Wan</storyboard>
        <animation>Dong Woo Animation Company, Ltd.</animation>
        <source>https://teentitans.fandom.com/wiki/Forces_of_Nature_(Transcript)</source>
        <issueList>
            <issueInfo link="../comic/issue-32.xml"/>
            <issueInfo link="../comic/issue-36.xml"/>
        </issueList>
    </head>
    <characterList>
        <charList type="recurring" id="BeastBoy" subtype="titan">Beast Boy</charList>
        <charList type="recurring" id="Raven" subtype="titan">Raven</charList>
        <charList type="recurring" id="Cyborg" subtype="titan">Cyborg</charList>
        <charList type="recurring" id="Starfire" subtype="titan">Starfire</charList>
        <charList type="recurring" id="Robin" subtype="titan">Robin</charList>
        <charList type="nonrecurring" id="Thunder" subtype="villain">Thunder</charList>
        <charList type="nonrecurring" id="Lightning" subtype="villain">Lightning</charList>
        <charList type="nonrecurring" id="Sorcerer" subtype="villain">Sorcerer</charList>
        <charList type="nonrecurring" id="Fire">Fire</charList>
        <charList type="recurring" subtype="villain" id="Slade">Slade</charList>
    </characterList>
    <body>
        <act n="0">
            <title>Prologue</title>
            <sd><stageDesc category="open-shot">Opening shot: a night sky filled with dark thunderhead clouds.</stageDesc> Flashes of lightning
                illuminate their contours. <charDesc ref="Thunder">A bulky silhouette stands up among them and begins to
                swing a pair of sticks against the clouds</charDesc>; every time it brings them down, there is
                another strike and accompanying thunderclap. <directNote kind="dissolve">Dissolve to another patch of the sky,
                where even more lightning crackles back and forth.</directNote> <charDesc ref="Lightning">A second silhouette, this one
                much thinner and with spiky upswetpt hair, stands up and directs its hands here and
                there.</charDesc> There is a new flare-up every time it does so.</sd>

            <sd>When the last one clears, <directNote>the camera has moved to a point near the underside of the
                clouds as the flashes continue from within</directNote>. There is a huge strike, and <directNote kind="pull">the camera
                pulls back to put Titans Tower in view</directNote>. Inside, in the hall, <char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> has become <transform class="mammal">a
                buffalo</transform> and is straining mightily at a rubber band looped over his horns, trying to
                catch it on a nearby hook. He succeeds and ducks away, coming up in <transform class="human">human form</transform> with
                a mischievous smile on his face. Now he produces a large, filled water balloon that
                sloshes a bit in his hands, and he lets off a wicked little chuckle.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>This is gonna be so sweet!</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="Raven">Raven</spkr>
                <sd>from o.c.</sd>What are you doing?</sp>

            <sd>Surprised by her words, he lets go of the balloon and completely freaks out as he
                tries desperately to make a safe catch. Finally, he gets hold of it and turns
                around, and <directNote kind="pan">the camera pans to show <char ref="Raven">Raven</char> behind him</directNote>.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Raven">Raven</spkr>Please tell me this isn't another ridiculous
                prank.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>Okay. It's not a ridiculous prank. It's a
                brilliant one!</sp>

            <sd>He laughs. <stageDesc category="close-up">Close-up of her, rolling her eyes wearily.</stageDesc></sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>
                <sd>from o.c.</sd>All right, check it out<sd><directNote kind="pull">Pull back to frame both.</directNote></sd>'Member
                how <char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char> put red dye in my shampoo and I turned brown for two days? Well, sister,
                it's payback time.</sp>

            <sd><stageDesc category="gag">A thought balloon appears above his head as he describes the situation. It shows, in
                "Super Deformed" style, <charDesc ref="BeastBoy">the hapless victim-tinted brown</charDesc>, holding a scrub brush, in
                towel, shower cap, and slippers, standing there while the other  SD Titans  scroll
                past and laugh at him. The balloon disappears as he finishes; now a pull string
                hangs down from the ceiling, and he reaches for it.</stageDesc></sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>I give you...the <char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> Insta-Lube
                9000!</sp>

            <sd>As he says this, he pulls the string and he and <char ref="Raven">Raven</char> back up o.c. <stageDesc category="fullscreen">Down comes a
                blueprint that fills most of the screen; the words "<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> " and "Insta-Lube"
                slide in beneath it, after which "9000" drops from the lower edge and replaces them.
                The diagram shows the rubber band, which is part of a floor-mounted slingshot, held
                back by the hook and with the balloon loaded in. A tripwire in front of the rig runs
                through overhead pulleys and is tied to a lever that is in turn connected to the
                hook.</stageDesc></sd>

            <sd><stageDesc category="lower">The lower portion of the screen <directNote kind="dissolve">dissolves to a shot of the hall</directNote> and <directNote kind="zoom">zooms in on the
                tripwire</directNote></stageDesc>, and <stageDesc category="blueprint">on the blueprint, a rough figure of <char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char> steps up and catches his
                foot there</stageDesc>.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>
                <sd>voice over</sd>See, when <charDesc ref="Cyborg">Chrome-Dome</charDesc> steps around the corner, his foot tugs the
                    string<sd><stageDesc category="lower">Lower portion: follow it to the lever.</stageDesc></sd>The string trips the
                lever...</sp>

            <sd><stageDesc category="blueprint">Blueprint: it moves forward and pops the band loose.</stageDesc> <stageDesc category="lower">Lower portion: zoom in on the
                attachment point.</stageDesc></sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>
                <sd>voice over</sd>...the lever releases the mother of all rubber bands...</sp>

            <sd><stageDesc category="blueprint">Blueprint: the balloon sails toward <char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char> in slow motion.</stageDesc> <stageDesc category="lower">Lower portion: <char ref="Raven">Raven</char>                 walks over to the setup, and <char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> pops into view with the ammo.</stageDesc></sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>
                <sd>loading it in</sd>...which sends a balloon, load of motor oil flying right at
                him, and BOOSH<sd><stageDesc category="blueprint">The blueprint rolls back up on this last word.</stageDesc></sd>Pretty clever,
                huh?</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="Raven">Raven</spkr>You're a genius.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>It's just a little good clean dirty fun.</sp>

            <sd>A door opens o.c.; he perks up his ears to listen.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>Here he comes</sp>

            <sd>He ducks away, then back to whisk her off.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Raven">Raven</spkr>Whoa<sd>They hide around a corner.</sd>I do not
                think--</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>Shhh!</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="Raven">Raven</spkr>But what if--?</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>Shhh</sp>

            <sd>Long silence.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>
                <sd>from o.c., whispering</sd>Why are we hiding?</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>Shhh!</sp>

            <sd>His eyes instantly go as wide as saucers upon realizing that his target is nowhere
                near ground zero, and <directNote kind="pull">the camera pulls back as he flips out for a moment</directNote>. <char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char> is
                hunched down behind both of them.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr><char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char> ?! You can't be <char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char> !</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>I can't?</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>
                <sd>pointing at him, then into hall</sd>If you're you, then who's...?</sp>

            <sd>Footsteps echo out there as all three look out. <directNote kind="cut">Cut to a shot down the way</directNote>, the
                camera positioned just behind the oil-filled balloon, then to <stageDesc category="close-up">an extreme close-up of
                the tripwire</stageDesc>. <charDesc ref="Starfire">A violet boot</charDesc> steps into view and catches it, the string is pulled
                taut, the lever moves, and the hook starts to pull away from the rubber band. <directNote kind="cut">Cut to
                in front of the balloon, which is released as <char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> jumps out in a frantic
                attempt to stop it.</directNote></sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>NOOOOOOOO!!</sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="shift">Audio and video both shift to slow motion as the projectile is propelled forward by
                the tension.</directNote> Just as he is about to run into the camera, <directNote kind="cut">cut to <stageDesc category="long-shot">a long shot of
                Starfire</stageDesc></directNote> and <directNote kind="zoom">zoom in to <stageDesc category="close-up">an extreme close-up of her face</stageDesc></directNote>. She is so taken by surprise
                that she literally cannot see straight.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr>
                <sd>normal speed</sd>Eek!</sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="pull">Pull back to show the balloon right in front of her</directNote>; it collides with her face,
                splattering her with the viscous contents, and knocks her onto her back. Normal
                speed: <char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> runs up.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr><char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char> !</sp>

            <sd>She has propped herself up on her hands, but cannot see him due to all the oil
                covering her eyes. <char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char> and <char ref="Raven">Raven</char> come over.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>You okay</sp>

            <sd>She gets her eyes open.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr>
                <sd>puzzled</sd>This is punishment? I did something wrong</sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="cut">Cut to <char ref="Raven">Raven</char> and <char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char> .</directNote></sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Raven">Raven</spkr>You didn't. He did.</sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="pan">Pan from them to <char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> , who gives a sheepish grin-accompanied by a sheep's
                bleating.</directNote></sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr> Star ! It was..<sd><directNote kind="cut">Cut to her</directNote>; he continues
                    o.c.</sd>...you weren't supposed to...</sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="cut">Back to him on the end of this.</directNote> He starts to say something else, but <directNote kind="cut">when the camera
                cuts to <char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char> and <char ref="Raven">Raven</char> </directNote>, their disapproving stares stop him in his tracks for a
                moment.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>
                <sd>from o.c.</sd>I didn't..<sd><directNote kind="pull">Pull back to frame him</directNote>; he trails off and
                    laughs.</sd>Just remember to change that oil every three thousand miles.</sp>

            <sd>He tries to laugh again, but it dies on his lips. <char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char> stands up and leans over
                him.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr>
                <sd>with steadily building rage</sd>On my planet, we have a name for those who do
                such terrible things. You are a...a...<charDesc ref="BeastBoy">CLORBAG VARBLERNELK</charDesc>!!</sp>

            <sd><stageDesc category="gag">Sight gag: her head grows in stages until it is many times normal size, and he
                shrinks a few notches before it. The oil disappears from her face on the last two
                words. From here, <directNote kind="cut">cut to <stageDesc category="close-up">a close-up of Cyborg</stageDesc>, very worried</directNote>. The sight gag has now
                ended.</stageDesc></sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>
                <sd>from o.c.</sd>I'm a what-bag</sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="tilt">Tilt down to him, in front of <char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char> .</directNote></sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>You heard the <charDesc ref="Starfire">lady</charDesc>.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="Raven">Raven</spkr>
                <sd>shaking her head</sd>You are such <charDesc ref="BeastBoy">a clorbag</charDesc>.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>Come on, you guys. Can't anybody take a
                joke</sp>

            <sd>A flash of lightning interrupts the standoff.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>
                <sd>from o.c.</sd>Titans<sd><directNote kind="cut">Cut to him, silhouetted against the glare.</directNote></sd>
                Trouble!</sp>

            <sd>The next strike illuminates him fully and <directNote kind="black-screen">leaves the screen black when it
                dissipates</directNote>.</sd>

            <cue>OPENING THEME</cue>

        </act>
        <act n="1">
            <title>Act One</title>
            <sd><stageDesc category="open-shot">Opening shot: the bridge across Jump City Bay.</stageDesc> Lighting flashes among the storm
                clouds and finally strikes the roadway. <stageDesc category="overhead-shot">Overhead view of the blast</stageDesc>, then <directNote kind="cut">cut to a
                big rig on the bridge</directNote>. The driver yells in surprise and cuts his wheels sharply to
                the right, braking as he does so; the truck stops just short of the smoking, flaming
                strike point. Many cars slam on their brakes to avoid a collision, creating an
                instant traffic jam.</sd>

            <sd>As the smoke starts to clear, <charDesc ref="Thunder Lightning">the two silhouettes seen among the clouds become
                visible within it</charDesc>. The last wisps evaporate to give a fully detailed view of both;
                <charDesc ref="Thunder Lightning">they wear outfits that look like something like samurai armor, but without the upper
                body protection</charDesc>. <charDesc ref="Thunder">The bulky one has blue skin and black clothing trimmed with blue,
                and he also wears a samurai-style helmet. A thundercloud is emblazoned on his chest,
                and he has long black sideburns.</charDesc> <charDesc ref="Lightning">His thin cohort, on the other hand, has light
                yellow skin and hair, and his outfit is red and yellow, with a lightning bolt on the
                chest. A headband keeps his hair out of the way and has a guard plate stretching
                down on either side to cover his cheeks.</charDesc> <charDesc ref="Thunder Lightning">Both wear armbands and wrist/shin guards.</charDesc>
                <annot>We have just met <char ref="Thunder">Thunder</char> and <char ref="Lightning">Lightning</char> .</annot></sd>

            <sd>The two new arrivals look at each other and smile; <stageDesc category="close-up">close-up of <char ref="Thunder">Thunder</char> </stageDesc>.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Thunder">Thunder</spkr>May we have fun here, <charDesc ref="Lightning">brother</charDesc></sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="pan">Pan to <char ref="Lightning">Lightning</char> .</directNote></sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Lightning">Lightning</spkr>Of course<sd>creating a bolt between his
                    hands</sd>We are <char ref="Thunder">Thunder</char> and <char ref="Lightning">Lightning</char> . We may do whatever we please!</sp>

            <sd>He throws the bolt upward. <directNote kind="cut">Cut to one of the bridge's columns, where the suspension
                cables are connected, seen from roadway level.</directNote> It is struck, and sparks fly
                everywhere.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Lightning">Lightning</spkr>
                <sd>from o.c.</sd>Look, <charDesc ref="Thunder">brother</charDesc>! I command the sparks to dance!</sp>

            <sd>He laughs as the strike dies out and <directNote kind="tilt">the camera tilts down to them</directNote>; the flickering
                remains fall all around in a shower.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Thunder">Thunder</spkr>Amusing. Now listen as I make music!</sp>

            <sd>He claps his hands, creating an intense shock wave, and <directNote kind="pull">the camera pulls back a
                distance to show it radiating outward</directNote>. The bridge cables are jarred loose and begin
                to whipsaw back and forth. <directNote kind="cut">Cut to the semi, which gets a smoking lightning bolt
                traced into its side.</directNote> <directNote kind="pan">Pan to the pair on the next line.</directNote></sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Lightning">Lightning</spkr>Let all who pass this way know <char ref="Lightning">Lightning</char> was
                here!</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="Thunder">Thunder</spkr>And <char ref="Thunder">Thunder</char> , too!</sp>

            <sd>He bangs his fists together, knuckle to knuckle, and creates an earthquake that sets
                the stopped cars and their drivers trembling; all the alarm systems are set off in
                the process. <charDesc ref="Thunder Lightning">The brothers</charDesc> laugh, and <char ref="Thunder">Thunder</char> pats <char ref="Lightning">Lightning</char>'s shoulder.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Lightning">Lightning</spkr>Most amusing.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>
                <sd>from o.c.</sd>Hate to break it to you...</sp>

            <sd>Surprised, they look toward the traffic snarl; <directNote kind="cut">cut to the truck, where the  Titans 
                are standing on the trailer</directNote>.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>...but you guys have a lousy sense of humor! This
                ends now!</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="Lightning">Lightning</spkr>
                <sd>shakes his fist</sd>No one gives orders to <char ref="Thunder">Thunder</char> and <char ref="Lightning">Lightning</char> <sd>warms
                    up</sd>Taste my power!</sp>

            <sd>He throws a bolt at the truck and just misses the  Titans , who scramble in five
                different directions. The trailer gets a big hole blown through it, wiping out his
                graffiti. <char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char> does a U-turn and swoops down on him with starbolts blazing; he
                jumps onto a line of stopped cars, she does likewise, and they run on these parallel
                tracks and trade shots. The firefight continues for several dozen yards until he
                gets in a lucky hit that knocks her down.</sd>

            <sd><charDesc ref="Thunder">His brother</charDesc>, meanwhile, is mixing it up with <char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char> . They block or dodge a few of
                each other's punches and start to grapple. <stageDesc category="close-up">Close-up of <char ref="Thunder">Thunder</char>'s left fist, which he
                pulls back and readies for a powerful strike</stageDesc>, then <stageDesc category="close-up">of <char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char>'s right as he
                reconfigures it into the sonic cannon</stageDesc>. <directNote kind="pull">Pull back to frame both</directNote>; the fists swing and
                connect with each other, and <directNote kind="pull">the camera pulls back farther as the resulting shock
                wave throws them far down the bridge in opposite directions</directNote>. <char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char> lands on his
                back, but <char ref="Thunder">Thunder</char> brings a small cloud to himself and hops onto it to float
                upward.</sd>

            <sd><char ref="Robin">Robin</char> finds <charDesc ref="Thunder">the big blue hooligan</charDesc> bearing down on him and has to dodge a
                thunderclap. He leaps onto a guardrail, but another blast destroys that section and
                he has to move down a bit. The next attack breaks a support cable; he grabs the
                swinging free end and is carried away an instant before <char ref="Thunder">Thunder</char> obliterates that
                section of the rail. <char ref="Robin">Robin</char> is carried high into the air before the cable starts to
                descend. He times his next move carefully and hurls himself over <char ref="Thunder">Thunder</char> , avoiding a
                punch and grabbing the foe's shoulders to throw him across the pavement.</sd>

            <sd><directNote kind="cut">Cut to <char ref="Lightning">Lightning</char> , throwing a bolt.</directNote></sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Lightning">Lightning</spkr>Ha!</sp>

            <sd>Midair; <char ref="Raven">Raven</char> dodges the shot and launches herself downward for a flying kick. <charDesc ref="Lightning">The
                yellow brother</charDesc> throws up his arms to block and is driven backward by her flurry of
                attacks. Finally, he gets clear and shocks her with a bolt that sends her flying. No
                sooner is she down, though, then <char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> , as <transform class="mammal">a giant panda</transform>, lumbers up behind and
                catches him in a bear hug. <char ref="Lightning">Lightning</char> struggles for a moment, then electrifies his
                entire body and gives <charDesc ref="BeastBoy">the shape-shifting Titan</charDesc> a few hundred thousand volts. The
                shock forces him back into <transform class="human">human form</transform> and causes him to let go.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Lightning">Lightning</spkr>
                <sd>laughing</sd>Your powers are strong, but mine are stronger!</sp>

            <sd><char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> , lying against a chunk of debris, groans and rubs his head for several
                seconds. He then gasps as <char ref="Thunder">Thunder</char>'s shadow falls over him; a flash of lightning, and
                <directNote kind="shift">the camera has shifted to <charDesc ref="Thunder">the big blue one</charDesc></directNote>.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Thunder">Thunder</spkr>Your power of the animals is impressive, <charDesc ref="BeastBoy">green
                    one</charDesc><sd>He warms up his fists.</sd>Rise so we may do battle.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>Why are you doing this</sp>

            <sd>He stands up.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Thunder">Thunder</spkr>Because it is not sporting to attack an unready
                opponent.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>No. Why are you wrecking everything?</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="Thunder">Thunder</spkr>
                <sd>puzzled</sd>Uh...because it is amusing.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>
                <sd>gesturing</sd>Do they look amused?</sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="pan">Pan in that direction to show the scared motorists huddling behind their damaged and
                overturned cars.</directNote> <annot>The answer to that question is obvious.</annot> Back to <char ref="Thunder">Thunder</char> and <char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char>.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Thunder">Thunder</spkr>I--</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>This isn't funny! It's wrong!</sp>

            <sd>An attack of conscience makes <char ref="Thunder">Thunder</char> relax his power. Before <char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> can say
                anything more, though, a lightning bolt blasts him away and <charDesc ref="Lightning">its shooter</charDesc> jumps down
                next to <charDesc ref="Thunder">his brother</charDesc>.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Lightning">Lightning</spkr>Ah, the thrill of victory<sd>puts his arm
                    around <char ref="Thunder">Thunder</char>'s shoulders</sd>Come, <char ref="Thunder">Thunder</char> . We shall seek more amusement.</sp>

            <sd>They take to the air. <directNote kind="pan">Pan to a pile of rubble</directNote>, from which <charDesc ref="BeastBoy">the blasted Titan sits up,
                dazed, smoking, disheveled, drooling a bit</charDesc>. He shakes his head to clear it and finds
                <char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char> floating into view behind him. She is clutching her forearm.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>Well, that was a shock</sp>

            <sd>She turns up her nose and floats on.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr>Hmph!</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>So...I'm guessing you're still mad</sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="cut">Cut to the other three</directNote>, <char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char> helps <char ref="Raven">Raven</char> to her feet.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>Okay, team<sd><char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char> arrives, then <char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> .</sd>
                We have to find those guys before they do any more damage. <char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char> , search the west
                side. <char ref="Raven">Raven</char> , the east. I'll take downtown. <char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> , you and  Star  scan from the
                skies.</sp>

            <sd><char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> looks uneasily up at <charDesc ref="Starfire">the partner</charDesc> who has just been assigned to him. She
                has turned her back and crossed her arms.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>Um...maybe <char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char> should come with me
                instead.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr><char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char> can't fly.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>Oh. Yeah.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>
                <sd>pinching his cheek; a big drop of sweat rolls down</sd>Have a nice flight, <charDesc ref="BeastBoy">my
                little clorbag</charDesc>.</sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="dissolve">Dissolve to the open courtyard in front of the museum.</directNote> <stageDesc category="setting">On either side of a central
                open area is a row of vertical concrete slabs; a large metal globe is mounted at the
                end nearest the building.</stageDesc> A couple of fellows make their way across the screen on
                foot and bicycle before there is a mighty blast of lightning. <charDesc ref="Thunder Lightning">The troublemaking
                brothers</charDesc> appear, scaring the men away.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Lightning">Lightning</spkr>Magnificent<sd>warms up</sd>We can make much
                mischief here!</sp>

            <sd>He strikes the globe, which rolls away from its post toward one row of slabs. It
                bangs into the end one, which topples over into the next, and so on like a row of
                falling dominoes. <stageDesc category="long-shot">Long shot of <char ref="Thunder">Thunder</char> , whose expression changes to one of
                trepidation as the last slab comes down.</stageDesc></sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Lightning">Lightning</spkr>
                <sd>walks into view</sd><charDesc ref="Thunder">Brother</charDesc>! Did you see what I...something troubles you?</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="Thunder">Thunder</spkr><charDesc ref="BeastBoy">The green one</charDesc>'s words. He says our fun
                is...wrong.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="Lightning">Lightning</spkr>
                <sd>laughs</sd>Wrong<sd>puts his arm across <char ref="Thunder">Thunder</char>'s shoulders</sd>He speaks
                nonsense, <charDesc ref="Thunder">brother</charDesc>! How could such amusement be wrong? The fun is only
                beginning.</sp>

            <sd>He leads <charDesc ref="Thunder">his brother</charDesc> away. <directNote kind="dissolve">Dissolve to <char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char> in flight, looking intently down
                toward the o.c. Jump City</directNote>; <char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> , as <transform class="bird">a falcon</transform>, glides next to her. Their
                perspective, passing the damaged courtyard of the museum, then <directNote kind="cut">cut to ground level
                as they land</directNote>. <char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> returns to <transform class="human">human form</transform>, and they begin to inspect the smashed
                slabs.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>Well, either they were just here, or this is
                the ugliest modern art I've ever seen.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr>You are not funny. You are <charDesc ref="BeastBoy">a clorbag
                varblernelk</charDesc></sp>

            <sd>She walks o.c.; he follows.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>Come on,  Star <sd><directNote kind="cut">Cut to them</directNote>; he catches
                    up.</sd>You can't stay mad forever. What? Do I have to do the face
                    <sd>smiling</sd>You know you can't resist the face.</sp>

            <sd>Except for a glance out of the corner of her eye, she has not looked his way
                throughout all of this. In no time flat, he has transformed into <transform class="felidae">a small kitten with
                huge, shining eyes</transform>. He meows as endearingly as he can; she looks down at him for a
                long moment.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr>
                <sd>turning her nose up</sd>Hmph!</sp>

            <sd>She walks away and he returns to <transform class="human">human form</transform> with a surprised meow.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>She resisted the face!</sp>

            <sd>She has now reached the point where the globe was anchored. Smoke rises from the
                stump. <char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> runs up again.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>Just talk to me,  Star <sd>kneels</sd>Come on,
                this is no fun!</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="Lightning">Lightning</spkr>
                <sd>from o.c.</sd>Wrong again, <charDesc ref="BeastBoy">green one</charDesc>!</sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="cut">Cut to the stormy sky.</directNote> Laughing, <char ref="Thunder">Thunder</char> floats into view on his cloud and throws a
                beam downward. He is joined by an equally jubilant <char ref="Lightning">Lightning</char> , also firing away. <directNote kind="zoom">The
                camera zooms in on the two off-guard  Titans </directNote> and <directNote kind="pull">then pulls back to frame the whole
                courtyard as <charDesc ref="Thunder Lightning">the brothers</charDesc>' onslaught connects in several places</directNote>. <char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char> runs down
                one side and manages to keep just ahead of <char ref="Thunder">Thunder</char> , also on foot; when she reaches
                the end, she goes straight up the wall and does a long, high backflip to come down
                behind him. She throws a starbolt, but misses him.</sd>

            <sd><directNote kind="cut">Cut to<char ref="Lightning">Lightning</char></directNote>; he gets a bolt ready.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Lightning">Lightning</spkr>Ha!</sp>

            <sd>He flings it at <char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> , who changes into <transform class="mammal">a rabbit</transform> and hops away. <char ref="Lightning">Lightning</char> chases
                him toward the ruins of those slabs and fires again. <charDesc ref="BeastBoy">The startled green bunny</charDesc> runs
                o.c., and when <directNote kind="tilt">the camera tilts up to the sky</directNote>, we see that he has become <transform class="bird">a crane</transform>.
                More lightning comes his way and is just barely dodged; now he drops to the ground
                as <transform class="mammal">a mouse</transform> and runs toward <char ref="Lightning">Lightning</char> . The projectiles are very easy for him to evade
                now. <stageDesc category="close-up">Close-up of the static-electricity master.</stageDesc></sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Lightning">Lightning</spkr>
                <sd>laughing</sd>Your animal forms cannot protect you forever!</sp>

            <sd><char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> , as <transform class="mammal">a bighorn sheep</transform>, barrels into him and sends him flying. <char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char> flips
                and leaps her way to the end of the courtyard as <char ref="Thunder">Thunder</char> closes in. He projects a
                beam toward her, she counters with a mighty starbolt, and the two attacks meet
                between them and cancel out. <stageDesc category="overhead-shot">Overhead view of the two duelists</stageDesc>; her energy starts to
                overwhelm his. <stageDesc category="close-up">Close-up of him.</stageDesc></sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Thunder">Thunder</spkr>Huh?</sp>

            <sd>The starbolt reaches him and knocks him across the open expanse to land squarely on
                the spot where the globe had stood. <char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> , now <transform class="mammal">a giant bear</transform>, moves in on him,
                and <char ref="Lightning">Lightning</char> takes <charDesc ref="Thunder">his fallen brother</charDesc>'s place against <char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char> . <charDesc ref="BeastBoy">The ursine Titan</charDesc>
                gets to his hind legs and plows into <char ref="Thunder">Thunder</char> , driving him to the courtyard wall,
                then runs up in <transform class="human">human form</transform> and grabs his collar.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>I don't want to hurt you. And I don't think
                you want to hurt me.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="Thunder">Thunder</spkr>Pain does not amuse us.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>Could've fooled me. Keep playing rough, and
                innocent people will get hurt.</sp>

            <sd>This makes <charDesc ref="Thunder">the big blue fellow</charDesc> think a bit. <directNote kind="cut">Cut to a fence that separates the
                concrete of the courtyard from the museum lawn.</directNote> <charDesc ref="Sorcerer">There is a sudden puff of smoke,
                which solidifies into a tall figure wearing long red traveling robes and a broad,
                flat-crowned hat. An arm is lowered from the face, revealing long white hair blowing
                about an old but strong male face. The overall impression is vaguely Oriental, and
                is reinforced by the thin mustache and beard. Only one eye, the left, can be seen.
                Under the red robes, the man wears black ones and has hidden an old wooden box on a
                tripod.</charDesc> This has a hand crank in its side, much like an old-style movie camera.</sd>

            <sd> The sorcerer  smiles evilly and begins to turn the crank. The front cover falls away
                to expose a camera lens, which glows red and then white. <char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> and <char ref="Thunder">Thunder</char> are
                caught off guard as the ground trembles.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy Thunder">Beast Boy and Thunder</spkr>Huh?</sp>

            <sd>A broad energy beam shoots past them from the camera and smashes cleanly through the
                intact row of concrete slabs. It just misses <char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char> and <char ref="Lightning">Lightning</char> , who have broken
                off their duel; he sidesteps, but she gasps as a shower of ruined stonework comes
                straight down toward her.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr> Star !</sp>

            <sd>The shadows of the crumbling slabs fall over him. <directNote kind="fade">Fade to black.</directNote></sd>

        </act>
        <act n="2">
            <title>Act Two</title>
            <sd><stageDesc category="open-shot">Opening shot: <charDesc ref="Thunder Lightning">the two brothers</charDesc>, backing up in fear and awe at what this newcomer has
                just brought about.</stageDesc></sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Sorcerer">Sorcerer</spkr>
                <sd>from o.c., echoing</sd>Your gifts are your own. Who are they to tell you how to
                use them?</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="Lightning">Lightning</spkr>And who are you that commands such power?
                Show yourself!</sp>

            <sd>The dust from the destruction of the concrete slabs starts to clear.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Sorcerer">Sorcerer</spkr>
                <sd>from "o.c."</sd>As you wish<sd>The haze parts to reveal him standing
                    within.</sd>I am but a humble old man-<sd>The camera, abandoned, shuts
                    down.</sd>--whose power is drawn from nature, like your own. Come with me, and
                sow as much destruction as you please</sp>

            <sd>He turns away.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Lightning">Lightning</spkr>
                <sd>to <char ref="Thunder">Thunder</char> </sd>Yes! More fun</sp>

            <sd><char ref="Thunder">Thunder</char> restrains him with a hand on his shoulder.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Thunder">Thunder</spkr>Will we harm anyone?</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="Lightning">Lightning</spkr>What? <charDesc ref="BeastBoy">The green one</charDesc> has poisoned your
                mind.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="Thunder">Thunder</spkr>This destruction, will we harm the innocent?</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="Sorcerer">Sorcerer</spkr>Would it matter if you did? <charDesc ref="Thunder Lightning">You are unique.
                Gifted. Better.</charDesc> Why should anything interfere with your enjoyment? I am going.
                Follow, if you wish</sp>

            <sd>He walks out of the courtyard; <char ref="Lightning">Lightning</char> follows.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Lightning">Lightning</spkr>Come, <charDesc ref="Thunder">brother</charDesc>, and leave your foolish
                thoughts behind.</sp>

            <sd><char ref="Thunder">Thunder</char> takes a few steps after them, but stops and looks back at the pile of
                crumbled stone for a moment. He then turns to catch up with the other two, and <directNote kind="pan">the
                camera pans to the wreckage</directNote> and <directNote kind="cut">cuts to <stageDesc category="close-up">a close-up of its surface</stageDesc></directNote>. <transform class="arachnid">A small green
                spider</transform>, <char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> , scuttles out of a hole in the pile and climbs up the side a bit;
                he then returns to <transform class="human">human form</transform>.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr> Star ? <char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char> ? Where are you<sd>climbs
                    down</sd>Come on! Gimme a sign here<sd>He starts to dig.</sd>You have to be all
                right, okay? 'Cause I-it s just a joke, you know? Back at the Tower, and...I'm
                sorry. I never said it, but I'm really, really sorry. It was supposed to be funny.
                And you could've been hurt, and...</sp>

            <sd>He strains to lift a good-sized fragment and manages to get it clear of the
                pile.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>
                <sd>softly</sd>...<charDesc ref="BeastBoy">I'm a total clorbag.</charDesc></sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="cut">Cut to behind him</directNote>; <charDesc ref="Starfire">a tall shadow is thrown across him from near the camera</charDesc>. <directNote kind="pull">Pull
                back to frame its source, <char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char> , with not so much as a scratch on her.</directNote> He turns
                around.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>Huh?</sp>

            <sd>She gives him a warm, forgiving smile that instantly perks him up.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr><char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char> !</sp>

            <sd>Taking <transform class="felidae">kitten form</transform> again, he jumps into her outstretched hands and she cuddles him
                to her chest. Her perspective; he looks up at her and meows happily.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr>
                <sd>laughing</sd>I am glad you are unharmed as well</sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="pull">Pull back from both</directNote>; he takes <transform class="human">human form</transform> and kneels before her.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>I am so sorry. You gotta forgive me.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr>I already have<sd>She helps him up.</sd>Now
                <charDesc ref="Thunder Lightning">those evil brothers</charDesc> must be made to apologize.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>I don't think they are evil. I think they're
                just like me.</sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="dissolve">Dissolve to a clearing in the mountains outside Jump City.</directNote> <stageDesc category="setting">A few scarecrow-like
                dummies have been set up, consisting of two crossed tree limbs with a blanket
                wrapped around them. Some characters have been painted on the cloth.</stageDesc> <directNote kind="pan">Pan across the
                area; more such dummies have been set up, and  the sorcerer  stands among them.</directNote></sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Lightning">Lightning</spkr>
                <sd>from o.c., contemptuously</sd>Sticks and leaves<sd><directNote kind="cut">Cut to him and<char ref="Thunder">Thunder</char> in the
                    clearing.</directNote></sd>Is this a joke? There is no fun in blasting such frail
                targets!</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="Sorcerer">Sorcerer</spkr>Are you certain, <charDesc ref="Lightning">young master</charDesc>? Try. You may
                like what you see.</sp>

            <sd><charDesc ref="Lightning">The young master in question</charDesc> groans and throws a bolt at one of the dummies; it
                instantly catches fire and makes him rethink his opinion of the whole exercise.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Lightning">Lightning</spkr>Dancing lights! Pleasing.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="Thunder">Thunder</spkr>Let <char ref="Thunder">Thunder</char> try his hand.</sp>

            <sd>He steps toward a target and throws a blast, causing the thing to disappear in a
                small explosion and a great clap of sound.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Thunder">Thunder</spkr>Wondrous noise!</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="Lightning">Lightning</spkr>See, <charDesc ref="Thunder">brother</charDesc>? There is no harm in our
                fun.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="Sorcerer">Sorcerer</spkr>And there is so much fun to be had.</sp>

            <sd><charDesc ref="Thunder Lightning">The two thrill-seekers</charDesc> grin at each other. <char ref="Lightning">Lightning</char> flies across the clearing,
                blasting one target after another, and <char ref="Thunder">Thunder</char> leaps high and slams a fist against
                the ground to open a furrow. A target at the end of it lights up, followed by
                several others when he redirects his efforts. Now <charDesc ref="Thunder Lightning">both brothers</charDesc> work in tandem and
                turn one target after another into blazing torches. They finally stop their assault
                and back up to  the sorcerer .</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Lightning">Lightning</spkr>More targets, <charDesc ref="Sorcerer">old one</charDesc>!</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="Thunder">Thunder</spkr>Yes, please, give us more.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="Sorcerer">Sorcerer</spkr>That won't be necessary. You've done quite
                enough.</sp>

            <sd>He produces a metal disc from underneath his robes. <stageDesc category="close-up">Close-up: it bears a character,
                Chinese in appearance, that looks something like a stylized letter S.</stageDesc> <directNote kind="pull">Pull back; he
                scales the object over the clearing as <char ref="Thunder">Thunder</char> and <char ref="Lightning">Lightning</char> watch, totally baffled.</directNote>
                It stops high in the sky and spins in place; electricity crackles around it as it
                picks up speed, culminating in a mighty orange flash. <directNote kind="pull">Pull back to show it suspended
                over the burning target as rays of light shoot down to strike every last one.</directNote> Beams
                of orange light start to play between them and just miss <charDesc ref="Thunder Lightning">the two puzzled
                brothers.</charDesc></sd>

            <sd><directNote kind="pull">Pull back to <stageDesc category="long-shot">a long overhead shot</stageDesc> to reveal that these have traced out <charDesc ref="Fire">a large,
                rough humanoid shape on the ground, with a final wide beam from above touching the
                heart area</charDesc>.</directNote> When the light show stops, the outline starts to burn intensely;  the
                sorcerer  holds up a staff topped with the same character that was on the disc he
                threw.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Sorcerer">Sorcerer</spkr>Rise.</sp>

            <sd><charDesc ref="Fire">The apparition does so with an unearthly screeching noise. It has that character
                engraved on its forehead.</charDesc></sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Sorcerer">Sorcerer</spkr>Burn,  Fire ! Burn it all!</sp>

            <sd>It starts down the mountainside toward the city proper, but stops upon finding the
                 Titans  some distance away.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>Didn't anyone ever tell you<sd><directNote kind="cut">Cut to them.</directNote></sd> <oneLine>Play
                with fire, you're going to get burned.</oneLine></sp>

            <sd><charDesc ref="Fire">The beast swings a flaming forearm at the team</charDesc>, forcing them to scatter. <char ref="Robin">Robin</char> looks
                up from the duck-and-cover position he has assumed and sees  Fire  pushing trees aside
                and making its way toward Jump City. <charDesc ref="Fire">Smoke and flames billow in its wake</charDesc> as <directNote kind="pan">the
                camera pans slightly to put the entire metro area in view, and right in its path</directNote>.
                The sorcerer waves the fumes aside with his staff.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Sorcerer">Sorcerer</spkr>Good. Very good.</sp>

            <sd><char ref="Thunder">Thunder</char> and <char ref="Lightning">Lightning</char> cannot believe what they have just had a hand in
                unleashing.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Thunder">Thunder</spkr><charDesc ref="Lightning">Brother</charDesc>, what have we done?</sp>

            <sd><charDesc ref="Fire">The thing</charDesc> continues down the mountain. <directNote kind="fade">Fade to black.</directNote></sd>

        </act>
        <act n="3">
            <title>Act Three</title>
            <sd><stageDesc category="open-shot">Opening shot: a group of houses built downhill of the newly kindled forest.</stageDesc> <directNote kind="tilt">Tilt up
                to show the extent of the blazes</directNote>, then <directNote kind="cut">cut to  Fire  as it stalks on toward the city</directNote>.
                The  Titans  chase it.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr> Titans ! Go!</sp>

            <sd>He pulls even with the creature on foot while <char ref="Raven">Raven</char> does likewise in the air.
                Pulling a couple of grenades from his belt, he throws them at its feet; <charDesc ref="Fire">they throw
                up a wall of smoke when they blow</charDesc>. <char ref="Raven">Raven</char> flies through it all.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Raven">Raven</spkr><oneLine>Flames can't spread if there's nothing to burn</oneLine>.
                Azarath Metrion Zinthos</sp>

            <sd>Her spell uproots several trees.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>Good idea, <char ref="Raven">Raven</char> . <char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> ! <char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char> ! Help her
                out!</sp>

            <sd>These two put on a burst of speed, and <char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> turns into <transform class="mammal">a buffalo</transform> to deliver a
                crushing headbutt against the base of a tree. It topples into a row of others and
                brings them all down. Meanwhile, <char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char> takes up a position high above the boughs;
                she throws a starbolt that blows another clump of old growth to matchwood. His
                cannon at the ready, <char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char> leaps toward  Fire  and lets go with a terrific blast when
                he lands. It skims the ground and throws up a wall of dirt in <charDesc ref="Fire">the beast</charDesc>'s face; a
                large-scale equivalent of dumping sand on a campfire to put it out.</sd>

            <sd>It takes some time for the view to begin to clear.  Fire  is nowhere in sight among
                the dust clouds. <directNote kind="cut">Cut to the  Titans </directNote>; <char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> is in <transform class="human">human form</transform> again.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>Is he out?</sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="pull">Pull back to frame him in front of the murky air.</directNote> In answer to his question,  Fire 
                stands up, still blazing and now roaring mad.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Raven">Raven</spkr>You had to ask.</sp>

            <sd>As it screeches some more, <char ref="Robin">Robin</char> runs up for a closer look. <directNote kind="cut">Cut to his perspective
                of the flaming creature</directNote> and <directNote kind="zoom">zoom in a bit</directNote>. Up the slope to one side, standing on a
                stone outcropping, is  the sorcerer . <stageDesc category="close-up">Close-up: he grins maliciously.</stageDesc> Back to <char ref="Robin">Robin</char> ,
                who is starting to put it all together, then to <charDesc ref="Sorcerer">the old man</charDesc>. <char ref="Thunder">Thunder</char> and <char ref="Lightning">Lightning</char>                 are behind him.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Sorcerer">Sorcerer</spkr>Go, <charDesc ref="Thunder Lightning">young masters</charDesc>.  Fire  is your creation. They
                have no right to destroy your fun.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="Lightning">Lightning</spkr>Yes! We must fight!</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="Thunder">Thunder</spkr>But, <charDesc ref="Lightning">brother</charDesc>--</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="Lightning">Lightning</spkr>Do not annoy me with your foolish concerns!
                Come!</sp>

            <sd><charDesc ref="Thunder">The blue brother</charDesc> thinks it over for a moment, and both of them disappear in a flash
                of light.  The sorcerer  turns away from the spot where they stood and spreads his
                arms; he starts to laugh in triumph, but it dies on his lips as <char ref="Robin">Robin</char>'s yell is
                heard from o.c. <charDesc ref="Robin">The  Titans ' leader</charDesc> sails across the clearing and lands a flying kick
                that sends the staff spiraling through the air. It sticks in the ground, walking end
                down, and <char ref="Robin">Robin</char> lands next to it. However, the thing pulls loose and sails back into
                <charDesc ref="Sorcerer">the old man</charDesc>'s hand.</sd>

            <sd>The tense seconds pass as the two face off; finally  the sorcerer  breaks the silence,
                his voice starting to take on a tone similar to that used by  Slade .</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Sorcerer">Sorcerer</spkr><char ref="Robin">Robin</char> . We meet at last.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>Who are you?</sp>

            <sd>There is no answer, except for a charge with staff raised for a swing. <char ref="Robin">Robin</char> meets
                it by hurling himself at the enemy as  Fire  moves closer to the city. <directNote kind="cut">Cut to <char ref="Raven">Raven</char> in
                flight.</directNote></sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Raven">Raven</spkr>Azarath Metrion Zinthos!</sp>

            <sd>This time, she has targeted <charDesc ref="Fire">the creature</charDesc> itself. The stream of black energy pouring
                from her hands breaks against <charDesc ref="Fire">the giant</charDesc>'s form and stops it in its tracks. When she
                relents, <charDesc ref="Fire">its flames have gone out, leaving the body black and smoking</charDesc>. <directNote kind="cut">Cut to the
                midsection</directNote> and <directNote kind="tilt">tilt up to the head as the surface begins to crack all over</directNote>; finally,
                <charDesc ref="Fire">the creature</charDesc> lights up again and <char ref="Raven">Raven</char> gasps in shock. It slams its fists together
                and creates a pyrotechnic shock wave that blasts away all the trees within several
                dozen yards. She is thrown back by the overpressure, as is <char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char> .</sd>

            <sd><stageDesc category="lower">Ground level: he slams down, and <char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char> and <char ref="Raven">Raven</char> land and start to help him up.</stageDesc>
                Before they can get him upright, though, a lightning bolt flashes down and knocks
                all three even farther away. <charDesc ref="Thunder Lightning">The brothers</charDesc> descend to the clearing; <char ref="Lightning">Lightning</char> warms
                up his hands and advances, while <char ref="Thunder">Thunder</char> stays put and gets ready to attack. Before
                he can throw that curveball, though, <char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> , as <transform class="mammal">a tiger</transform>, steps into view before
                him.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Thunder">Thunder</spkr>Stand aside, <charDesc ref="BeastBoy">green one</charDesc>!</sp>

            <sd><charDesc ref="BeastBoy">Said green one</charDesc> just roars. They charge at one another, but before any blows can
                land, violet smoke boils up and covers the entire screen. When it clears, we are in
                the middle of a bank of clouds in this color. <char ref="Thunder">Thunder</char> is among them, but <charDesc ref="Thunder">his body is
                largely in shadow and drawn in a somewhat different style now</charDesc>. <directNote kind="cut">The next cut, after
                the following line, will show <char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> in a similar manner.</directNote> <stageDesc category="fullscreen">The entire view
                shimmers and wavers somewhat, and the two voices echo slightly.</stageDesc></sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Thunder">Thunder</spkr>I do not wish to harm you.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>But you want to destroy homes and innocent
                lives?</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="Thunder">Thunder</spkr>No.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>Then what are you fighting for?</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="Thunder">Thunder</spkr><charDesc ref="Lightning">My brother</charDesc> and I...<charDesc ref="Sorcerer">the old one</charDesc> says <charDesc ref="Thunder Lightning">we are
                unique, gifted, better</charDesc>.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr><oneLine>Gifts don't make you better, just different.
                It's how you use them that counts.</oneLine></sp>

            <sd><char ref="Thunder">Thunder</char> turns this over in his mind a bit. <directNote kind="cut">Cut to <stageDesc category="close-up">a close-up of <char ref="Lightning">Lightning</char> </stageDesc>.</directNote></sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Lightning">Lightning</spkr>It seems your power has its limit<sd>holds up
                    a sparking hand</sd>But mine has none.</sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="pull">Pull back.</directNote> He is standing over the unconscious <char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char> and getting ready to light
                her up like a Christmas tree, but before he can do so, a blast from <char ref="Thunder">Thunder</char> plows
                him away. She comes to and looks in the direction of the shot; <directNote kind="shift">shift to frame <charDesc ref="Lightning">both
                brothers</charDesc></directNote>. <char ref="Thunder">Thunder</char> pushes over a charred tree as he steps up, and <char ref="Lightning">Lightning</char> gets to
                his feet.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Lightning">Lightning</spkr>
                <sd>warms up</sd>You betray me?</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="Thunder">Thunder</spkr>We have done wrong, <charDesc ref="Lightning">my brother</charDesc>. Our fun must
                stop.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="Lightning">Lightning</spkr>No one commands <char ref="Lightning">Lightning</char> ..<sd>warming
                    up</sd>...not even <char ref="Thunder">Thunder</char> !</sp>

            <sd>He throws a wide beam; the impact sends <char ref="Thunder">Thunder</char> tumbling among the trees. <char ref="Robin">Robin</char> and
                 the sorcerer , meanwhile, continue their melee as the mountain burns all around them.
                Slowly but steadily, <charDesc ref="Robin">the young Titan</charDesc> retreats downhill before <charDesc ref="Sorcerer">his attacker</charDesc>'s swings.
                Soon, though, he holds his ground and blocks one strike after another, then
                sidesteps when the upper end of the staff is jabbed at him. It hits a tree and sends
                up a wisp of smoke as if it were a red-hot branding iron.  The sorcerer  grimaces down
                at him.</sd>

            <sd><directNote>Cut to the mountainside.</directNote>  Fire  continues its inexorable advance toward the lower
                houses as the other four  Titans  gather to watch. <char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> is back in <transform class="human">human
                form</transform>.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>Those houses go, the whole city could go. We gotta
                stop the fire!</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="Raven">Raven</spkr>How?</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>Any way we can.</sp>

            <sd>They run down the slope. <directNote kind="cut">Cut to <char ref="Lightning">Lightning</char> in flight</directNote>; he throws a bolt out ahead, and
                <directNote kind="shift">the camera shifts to <char ref="Thunder">Thunder</char> , whose face suddenly goes slack-realizing he is the
                target</directNote>. The electricity washes over him and hurls him back against a wall of rock.
                He slides down to a sitting position and groans wearily. Looking up, he finds his
                brother standing over him and ready to unload a king-size shock at point-blank
                range.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Thunder">Thunder</spkr>Tell me, <charDesc ref="Lightning">brother</charDesc>, are we still having fun</sp>

            <sd><char ref="Lightning">Lightning</char>'s conscience gets to him.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Lightning">Lightning</spkr>
                <sd>winding down</sd>No.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="Thunder">Thunder</spkr>
                <sd>pointing</sd>Observe.</sp>

            <sd><directNote>Cut to behind  Fire  as it descends the mountain</directNote>, then <directNote kind="cut">to in front of it</directNote> and <directNote kind="tilt">tilt down
                to the houses</directNote>. It is hit in the face with a sudden torrent of water, accompanied by
                an elephant's trumpeting. <directNote kind="pan">Pan along a street</directNote>; <char ref="Raven">Raven</char> is casting a spell to hold the
                flames back, <char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> , as <transform class="mammal">the pachyderm</transform>, is spraying water from his trunk, and
                <char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char> has opened a fire hydrant. <char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char> descends among them.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Thunder">Thunder</spkr>They also have gifts, but they use them for good,
                while we waste ours on dangerous fun<sd>He puts a hand on <char ref="Lightning">Lightning</char>'s
                shoulder.</sd><oneLine>If we are so special, brother, let us act special.</oneLine> We must help.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="Lightning">Lightning</spkr>But how? Our gifts can only destroy.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="Thunder">Thunder</spkr>True. But together we have another gift.</sp>

            <sd>They are gone in a flash of light, ascending into the cloud cover. When they have
                vanished from sight, a blast of lightning is seen from within. The four  Titans  find
                themselves staring at a mountain in flames and a walking inferno that has not let up
                one bit despite their best efforts. It towers over them and roars.</sd>

            <sd><directNote kind="cut">Cut to the clouds, as seen at the beginning of the episode.</directNote> <char ref="Thunder">Thunder</char> strikes them
                with his sticks and <char ref="Lightning">Lightning</char> directs his hands here and there, producing the same
                effects as before. <directNote kind="shift">The camera shifts to point up at them from foot level as the
                glare plays over both of them and a driving rain begins</directNote>; the result of combining
                their talents. <stageDesc category="lower">At ground level,  Fire  looks up in alarm at the downpour, then screams
                in agony as its flames go out in a thick wall of brown smoke.</stageDesc> When the view clears,
                there is nothing left but a few piles of ashes. <directNote kind="pan">Pan from them to <char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> , <char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char> ,
                <char ref="Raven">Raven</char> , and <char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char> .</directNote> All but <char ref="Raven">Raven</char> cheer wildly; <char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> is in <transform class="human">human form</transform>.</sd>

            <sd>Up on the mountain,  the sorcerer  has caught the front of <char ref="Robin">Robin</char>'s tunic and hoisted
                him up. <annot>The former's tone of voice is now unmistakable.</annot></sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Sorcerer">Sorcerer</spkr><char ref="Robin">Robin</char> . Is that the best you can do?</sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="black-screen">There is a tremendous flash of lightning that whites out the entire screen.</directNote> When it
                subsides, <stageDesc category="lower">the view is at ground level</stageDesc>; <char ref="Robin">Robin</char> drops into a crouch, free of <charDesc ref="Sorcerer">the man</charDesc>'s
                grasp. <directNote kind="cut">Cut to <charDesc ref="Slade">the robed figure, who has thrown up an arm to guard his face</charDesc></directNote>; he
                brings it down after a moment, revealing it to have been only a mask that was
                damaged in the strike. <charDesc ref="Slade">Most of the left side has fallen away, and underneath is a
                smooth expanse of red-orange metal with a narrow slit for the eye. The last
                remaining pieces come loose to fully expose that half of Slade's still-concealed
                face</charDesc>; <annot>the first time that any of it has been seen on camera</annot>. <annot>The colored reflection
                in that part of his silhouette, seen in "Divide and Conquer" and "Final Exam," is
                now fully explained, and he was able to recognize <char ref="Robin">Robin</char> from  Gizmo 's transmission at
                the end of "Final Exam.</annot>"</sd>

            <sd><char ref="Robin">Robin</char> gasps in shock and stares, frozen in place, and after a long moment, <directNote kind="dissolve"><charDesc ref="Slade">the
                mastermind</charDesc> disappears in a blast of smoke that fills the screen</directNote>. <stageDesc category="close-up">The view clears to
                show a close-up of the metal disc he threw into the air to bring  Fire  to life.</stageDesc> <directNote kind="pull">Pull
                back</directNote>; <char ref="Robin">Robin</char> regards it thoughtfully, then picks it up for a very close look.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr> Slade .</sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="dissolve">Dissolve to the street, where the celebration is still going on.</directNote> <char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> has his
                tongue out to catch the raindrops.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>Ah, yeah</sp>

            <sd>He laughs.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>That's what I mean! Very nice!</sp>

            <sd><char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> turns away from the street and sees <char ref="Thunder">Thunder</char> and <char ref="Lightning">Lightning</char> coming down from
                the mountain. He crosses to them. <char ref="Lightning">Lightning</char> looks away, showing very clearly that he
                would rather be doing anything else right now.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Thunder">Thunder</spkr>
                <sd>bows</sd>I am sorry for the trouble we have made</sp>

            <sd>He nudges <char ref="Lightning">Lightning</char> , who faces forward.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Lightning">Lightning</spkr>I am..<sd>also bows</sd>...also sorry</sp>

            <sd><char ref="Thunder">Thunder</char> and <char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> shake hands.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Thunder">Thunder</spkr>You have taught us much, <charDesc ref="BeastBoy">green one</charDesc>. Thank
                you.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>Don't thank me<sd>He gestures at <char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char> ; she
                    steps forward.</sd><oneLine>Thank the person who taught me</oneLine></sp>

            <sd>She and <charDesc ref="Thunder Lightning">the brothers</charDesc> bow to each other.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr>And thank you for helping to defeat <charDesc ref="Fire">the flame
                monster</charDesc>.</sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="cut">Cut to <stageDesc category="overhead-shot">an overhead view of the six</stageDesc></directNote>; <charDesc ref="Thunder Lightning">two brothers</charDesc> and four  Titans , and then <directNote kind="dissolve">dissolve
                to <stageDesc category="long-shot">a long shot of the Tower</stageDesc>, seen from the city proper</directNote>. It is now sunrise of the
                next day, the clouds have broken, and a rainbow stretches up from the horizon behind
                the Tower. <directNote kind="pan">Pan a short distance to the entire team, on a ridge overlooking Jump
                City.</directNote> <char ref="Robin">Robin</char> hands  Slade 's talisman to <char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char> so he can give it a looking over.</sd>

            <cue>Animation goofs: <char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char>'s armband appears and disappears during this final scene,
                and the black stones in her wrist guards turn red.</cue>

            <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>So,  Slade  wants to destroy the city. Question is,
                why?</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>I don't know, but I will find out, and he won't get
                away with it</sp>

            <sd><char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> comes up behind <char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char>.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>So...am I, you know...still <charDesc ref="BeastBoy">a clorbag</charDesc>?</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr>Mmm, no. I believe you are more of a...<charDesc ref="BeastBoy">milnip
                wusserloop</charDesc>.</sp>

            <sd>Not being too fluent in Tamaranean, he does not know what to make of this label for
                a moment. Bewilderment quickly gives way to a big grin, though.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>SWEET<sd>dances</sd>Go, <char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> ! <charDesc ref="BeastBoy">I'm a
                milnip</charDesc>! Who's <charDesc ref="BeastBoy">your wusserloop</charDesc>? Huh?</sp>

            <sd>He stops dancing; for a moment his eyes have stars in them.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>
                <sd>a bit puzzled</sd>That is a good thing...right,  <char ref="Starfire">Star</char> ?</sp>

            <sd>She just giggles and goes airborne to head home. <char ref="Raven">Raven</char> follows her, while <char ref="Robin">Robin</char> and
                <char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char> start running. <charDesc ref="BeastBoy">The green Titan</charDesc> is left standing by himself.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr> Star ?</sp>

            <sd>He hot-foots it after the others. <directNote kind="fade">Fade to black.</directNote></sd>
        </act>
    </body>
</root>