<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../schema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?><root>
    <head>
        <episode>APPRENTICE - PART 2</episode>
        <writer>David Slack</writer>
        <director>Ciro Nieli</director>
        <storyboard>Kalvin Lee, Rafael Rosado, Alan Wan</storyboard>
        <animation>Dong Woo Animation Company, Ltd.</animation>
        <source>https://teentitans.fandom.com/wiki/Apprentice_-_Part_2_(Transcript)</source>
        <issueList>
            <issueInfo link="../comic/issue-10.xml"/>
            <issueInfo link="../comic/issue-34.xml"/>
        </issueList>
    </head>
    <characterList>
        <charList type="recurring" id="Starfire" subtype="titan">Starfire</charList>
        <charList type="recurring" id="Raven" subtype="titan">Raven</charList>
        <charList type="recurring" id="BeastBoy" subtype="titan">Beast Boy</charList>
        <charList type="recurring" id="Cyborg" subtype="titan">Cyborg</charList>
        <charList type="nonrecurring" id="Voice">Voice</charList>
        <charList type="nonrecurring" id="Guard1">Guard 1</charList>
        <charList type="nonrecurring" id="Guard2">Guard 2</charList>
        <charList type="recurring" id="Slade" subtype="villain">Slade</charList>
        <charList type="recurring" id="Robin" subtype="titan">Robin</charList>
    </characterList>
    <body>
        <act n="0">
            <title>Prologue</title>
            <sd><stageDesc category="open-shot">Opening shot: a slow overhead pan across Jump
                    City.</stageDesc> It is sunset.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr><sd>voice over</sd><char ref="Robin">Robin</char>?
                   <char ref="Robin">Robin</char>! Please,<char ref="Robin">Robin</char>, where are you?</sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="dissolve">Dissolve to another area of the urban
                    center</directNote> and <directNote kind="pan">pan slowly</directNote>.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Raven">Raven</spkr><sd>over communicator</sd><char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char>,
                enough. You've been calling for forty-five minutes.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr><sd>voice over</sd>Perhaps if I just try one
                more--</sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="cut">Cut to another group of buildings</directNote>, seen from
                ground level, and <directNote kind="pan">pan slowly</directNote>.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr><sd>over comm</sd>Come on, <charDesc ref="Starfire">Star</charDesc>. If he's gonna pick up, he'd have done it by now.
                'Sides, you're kinda giving me a headache.</sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="cut">Cut to a shot along one street</directNote> and <directNote kind="tilt">tilt down through the layers of pavement and
                earth</directNote>.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr><sd>voice over</sd>But why does he not respond?
                Where could he be?</sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="pan">The screen pans down on<char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char> in the
                    sewer.</directNote></sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr><char ref="Robin">Robin</char> and Cinderblock
                definitely went a few rounds,<sd><directNote kind="pull">Pull back</directNote>;
                       <char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char> is at the site of their battle in Part One.</sd>but I
                can't tell who won, or where they went.</sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="cut">Cut to a computer map of Jump City.</directNote> Three spots
                are flashing on it; one shows a C, one a B, one an S: the positions of the
                others.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Raven">Raven</spkr><sd>from o.c.</sd>No sign of him here, either.</sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="pull">Pull back; she is at a console in the operations center of
                    Titans Tower.</directNote> Night has fallen.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Raven">Raven</spkr>His locator is still offline. I've been monitoring
                all the frequencies, but he hasn't checked in.</sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="cut">Cut to<char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char> in flight.</directNote></sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr>Oh, we are bad
                    friends! We should never have left<char ref="Robin">Robin</char> to do battle
                alone.</sp>

            <sd><char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char>, <transform class="mammal">as a monkey</transform>, jumps
                onto a roof and takes <transform class="human">human form</transform>.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>Yeah, especially since<char ref="Slade">Slade</char>'s
                big doodad was a dud.</sp>

            <sd>He jumps away again. <directNote kind="cut">Cut to a computer schematic of the fake
                    detonator.</directNote></sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Raven">Raven</spkr><sd>from o.c.</sd>The Chronoton Detonator wasn't a
                        dud.<sd><directNote kind="pull">Pull back; she is studying her
                        screen.</directNote></sd>It was a decoy to lure us away from
                   <char ref="Robin">Robin</char>, and we fell for it.</sp>

            <sd><char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char> groans loudly and slams a fist against the wall of the sewer
                tunnel.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>I shoulda known that thing was a fake!</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr>But why? Why did<char ref="Slade">Slade</char> wish to
                separate us from<char ref="Robin">Robin</char>?</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>And if the detonator was a decoy...</sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="dissolve">Dissolve to<char ref="Raven">Raven</char>.</directNote></sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Raven">Raven</spkr>...what was<char ref="Slade">Slade</char>'s real plan?</sp>

            <sd>An urgent alarm starts up as <directNote kind="dissolve">the view dissolves to
                       <char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char>, now running through the sewer</directNote>.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>Titans! Trouble!</sp>

            <sd><stageDesc category="overhead-shot">Overhead view of a tall, circular building with
                    an observation deck set a story or two below its roof; a walkway leads away from
                    this.</stageDesc>
               <char ref="Robin">Robin</char> drops into view, free-falling toward the structure. Inside, the
                top floor is seen to be a darkened laboratory. A panel falls from the ceiling, and
                   <char ref="Robin">Robin</char>'s silhouette drops in after it. He will be seen in this
                fashion until further notice. Something is hurled across the room toward a glass
                storage vessel that holds a piece of equipment. <stageDesc category="close-up">Close-up of it, sticking in the framework; it is a small sphere with two short
                    arms sticking out from opposite sites.</stageDesc> Each arm ends in a curved
                blade, so that the entire device looks like a backwards letter S.
               <char ref="Slade">Slade</char>'s insignia is embossed on the sphere, this is one of his toys,
                given for<char ref="Robin">Robin</char>'s use. One by one, lights wink on around the center
                logo to form a ring; after they are all illuminated, the thing explodes in a
                brilliant flash. <directNote kind="cut">Cut to <stageDesc category="overhead-shot">the overhead exterior view</stageDesc> again as the blast spreads outward
                    from those upper stories.</directNote> When it clears, we see
               <char ref="Robin">Robin</char>'s form near the camera, holding the item that was in the
                vessel.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Voice">Voice</spkr>He's stolen the Thermal Blaster!</sp>

            <sd>On the end of this, <directNote kind="cut">cut to an adjoining tunnel</directNote>.
                The speaker is one of several prison guards who run in with weapons at the
                ready.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Guard1">Guard 1</spkr>Stop him!</sp>

            <sd>They reach the lab, then the observation deck, and open fire against <charDesc ref="Robin">the fleeing thief</charDesc>. He somersaults away; they stop for a
                look around.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Guard2">Guard 2</spkr>Where'd he go?</sp>

            <sd><stageDesc category="overhead-shot">Overhead view of the deck</stageDesc>,
                    <directNote kind="tilt">tilting up slightly</directNote>. He is hanging upside
                down from the roof. After the guards have left the area, he drops down and makes a
                break for it, but<char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char> and<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> pull out to block
                him and<char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char>'s foot lands near the camera to cut off any
                retreat.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr><sd>from o.c.</sd>Freeze!</sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="cut">Cut to him and<char ref="Raven">Raven</char></directNote>, then
                    <directNote kind="pull">pull back to frame all five</directNote>.
                   <char ref="Robin">Robin</char> sprints off along the walkway; they give chase, and he soon
                finds himself nearing the end of the line, with nothing between him and a very long
                drop to the street. He stops and turns to face them, and the light comes up fully on
                him for the first time, giving the others a clear view of <charDesc ref="Robin">his
                    new outfit</charDesc>. They are so paralyzed with shock and confusion, it is as
                if their feet have been nailed to the floor.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>That's not<char ref="Slade">Slade</char>, that's...</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr>...<char ref="Robin">Robin</char>.</sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="fade">Fade to black.</directNote></sd>

            <cue>OPENING THEME</cue>

        </act>
        <act n="1">
            <title>Act One</title>
            <sd><stageDesc category="open-shot">Opening shot:<char ref="Robin">Robin</char>, still ready to
                    throw down at the point where he just stopped running.</stageDesc></sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>Whoa!</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>No way!</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr><char ref="Robin">Robin</char>, why are you--?</sp>

            <sd>He cuts her off with the throw of a <char ref="Slade">Slade</char>-styled flyer that explodes in
                her face, driving her back along the walkway toward the others.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>Yo!</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>What is your deal?</sp>

            <sd><stageDesc category="close-up">Close-up of Robin</stageDesc>,
                    <directNote kind="zoom">zooming in as he turns his head</directNote>. A small
                radio receiver, marked with<char ref="Slade">Slade</char>'s insignia, is plugged into his left
                ear, and <charDesc ref="Slade">the new boss</charDesc>' voice is heard from it.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Slade">Slade</spkr>Not a word,<char ref="Robin">Robin</char>. They're not your friends anymore.</sp>

            <sd>The four close in; he raises the blaster he just stole and fires at the stretch of
                walkway between him and them. The resulting explosion brings them up short and
                forces a yell from<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char>.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>What are you doing?</sp>

            <sd>The smoke begins to clear, revealing that a section has been blown apart entirely.
                   <char ref="Robin">Robin</char>'s outline is visible through the haze, but <directNote kind="fade">it fades away after a few seconds, he is gone</directNote>.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr><sd>crushed</sd><char ref="Robin">Robin</char>...</sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="fade">Fade to black.</directNote></sd>

            <sd><directNote kind="fade">Fade in to<char ref="Robin">Robin</char>, stepping forth from the
                    darkness to hold up the blaster</directNote>, and <directNote kind="pull">pull
                    back</directNote>. He is standing in a single spot of light.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Slade">Slade</spkr><sd>from o.c.</sd>Excellent,<char ref="Robin">Robin</char>. I'm
                pleased. You're already proving to be <charDesc ref="Robin">the perfect
                    apprentice</charDesc>.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>This deal can't last forever.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="Slade">Slade</spkr><sd>from o.c.</sd>It can. And it will.</sp>

            <sd><annot>We are in<char ref="Slade">Slade</char>'s lair, then.</annot> Behind<char ref="Robin">Robin</char>,
                a row of monitors comes to life, all showing blank white screens. He turns to face
                them; one shows static, then an image of the decoy detonator.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Slade">Slade</spkr><sd>from o.c.</sd>The Titans still have
                no idea that my Chronoton Detonator was more than a decoy. Now that my probes are
                inside their bodies, they could remain undetected for years, decades.</sp>

            <sd>During this line, the following clips from Part One play out, with blips of static
                between. The detonator shorting out; the other four staring at the smoking remains
                on the speedboat; the weapon emerging from the prow to strafe them; the four being
                blown off the deck; <directNote kind="pan">a pan across the magnified views of their
                    probe-laden bloodstreams</directNote>. Finally, the monitors go white
                again.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Slade">Slade</spkr><sd>from o.c.</sd>Unless, of course, you disobey
                    me,<sd>He steps into view.</sd>and I decide to destroy your former friends with a push of the button.</sp>

            <sd>He holds up his hand on the end of this line; said button is nestled in it.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>Sooner or later, you'll let your guard down. I will
                get that controller, and the instant they're out of danger, you will pay.</sp>

            <sd><char ref="Slade">Slade</char> steps toward him. <directNote kind="pull">Pull back; both are
                    silhouetted against the monitors.</directNote></sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Slade">Slade</spkr>That sounds like a threat, <charDesc ref="Robin">young man</charDesc>.<sd><stageDesc category="close-up">Close-up; he takes the
                        blaster from<char ref="Robin">Robin</char>.</stageDesc></sd>Quite a good threat,
                actually. Betrayal, destruction, revenge. We really do think alike.</sp>

            <sd><char ref="Robin">Robin</char> grits his teeth in a quiet snarl that quickly builds in intensity
                before he throws himself at<char ref="Slade">Slade</char>. The charge goes bad in a hurry;
                   <char ref="Slade">Slade</char> grabs<char ref="Robin">Robin</char>'s wrist and bends his arm back
                sharply. <annot>From the sound of things, one or more bones are within an inch of
                    breaking.</annot></sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Slade">Slade</spkr>I monitored your vital signs during the mission.
                Elevated heart rate, adrenaline, endorphins.<sd><stageDesc category="close-up">Close-up of<char ref="Robin">Robin</char>'s straining face; he continues
                        o.c.</stageDesc></sd>You won't admit it, but at some level,<sd>Back to
                    him.</sd>you enjoyed stealing for me. It was a thrill, wasn't it?</sp>

            <sd>He releases his hold;<char ref="Robin">Robin</char> stumbles away and rubs his overstressed
                arm.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Slade">Slade</spkr>You're going to keep stealing,
                       <char ref="Robin">Robin</char>.<sd><charDesc ref="Slade">removes his blaster
                        muzzle</charDesc></sd>And you're going to keep getting that
                        thrill.<sd><stageDesc category="close-up">Close-up of<char ref="Robin">Robin</char>; he
                        continues o.c.</stageDesc></sd>And sooner or later,<sd>Back to him.</sd>you
                will see things my way.</sp>

            <sd>He has put the weapon back together now.<char ref="Robin">Robin</char> is still holding up his
                right arm.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Slade">Slade</spkr><sd>walks to him</sd>Who knows? I might even become
                like a father to you.</sp>

            <sd><stageDesc category="close-up">Close-up of the raised wrist on the end of
                    this</stageDesc>; he clamps the blaster onto it, so that <charDesc ref="Robin">the muzzle points out along<char ref="Robin">Robin</char>'s arm</charDesc>. <directNote kind="pan">Pan to the sullen young apprentice, who lowers it.</directNote></sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr><sd>softly</sd>I already have a father.</sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="tilt">Tilt up into <stageDesc category="overhead-shot">the
                        darkness overhead</stageDesc></directNote> and stop at the ceiling of the
                lair. A few bats fly out through the openings between the blades of an enormous
                blower and disappear into the night. <directNote kind="cut">Cut to the exterior of
                    the Tower</directNote> and <directNote kind="zoom">zoom in</directNote>.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr><sd>from inside</sd>Okay. The way I see
                it...</sp>

            <sd>In the operations center, <charDesc ref="BeastBoy">he has donned a cap and long
                    coat similar to those often worn by Sherlock Holmes</charDesc>, and he paces in
                front of<char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char> and<char ref="Raven">Raven</char>. After a couple of passes, he
                stops and turns to them, holding up the sort of pipe smoked by the great sleuth.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>...there are only two logical explanations.
                One...</sp>

            <sd>He holds up a comic book, Weird Shock, whose cover depicts a colossal robot in
                   <char ref="Robin">Robin</char>'s very approximate likeness. It is destroying a city.
                    <directNote kind="zoom">Zoom in on this.</directNote></sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr><sd>from o.c.</sd>...<char ref="Robin">Robin</char>'s been
                replaced by an evil robot double.</sp>

            <sd>The book opens to its first page, showing <stageDesc category="close-up">a close-up
                    of one panel, a spiky-haired silhouette, its back to us, facing a horde of
                    undead corpses</stageDesc>. On the next line, <directNote kind="pan">pan to the
                    second panel; the figure has turned around to show itself as a
                       <char ref="Robin">Robin</char> zombie</directNote>.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>Two...he's another innocent victim of zombie
                mind control.</sp>

            <sd>The background changes to a black and white spiral, then restores itself before the
                book closes again. <directNote kind="cut">Cut to<char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char> and
                       <char ref="Raven">Raven</char>, whose faces indicate just how far round the bend they
                    think<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> has gone.</directNote></sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Raven">Raven</spkr>As logical as that sounds, if anything was
                controlling his mind, I would have sensed it.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr><sd>checks his forearm panel</sd>And my scanners
                confirmed his biometrics. That was the real<char ref="Robin">Robin</char>, our
                   <char ref="Robin">Robin</char>.</sp>

            <sd>Both hang their heads.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr><sd>from o.c.</sd>Lies!<sd><directNote kind="pan">Quick pan to her at the kitchen tables.</directNote></sd>That was
                not<char ref="Robin">Robin</char>! Your scanners are wrong!<char ref="Robin">Robin</char> is our friend,
                and nothing could ever make him betray us!<sd>sadly</sd>Nothing.</sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="cut">Cut to<char ref="Raven">Raven</char> and
                   <char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char>.</directNote></sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Raven">Raven</spkr>But something did.</sp>

            <sd><charDesc ref="BeastBoy">The would-be gumshoe with the overactive
                    imagination</charDesc> pops up. <stageDesc category="gag">He has blanked out the
                    pupils and irises of his eyes, and his head looks as if the top of it has been
                    torn away.</stageDesc></sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>Three words: Disgruntled radioactive
                        clone.<sd><char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char> yanks him away.</sd>Ow!</sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="gag">Sight gag: only the top half of his body is attached to the
                    head, and it looks something like an old store-window dummy.</directNote>
               <char ref="Raven">Raven</char> delivers a spin kick that sends him flying o.c. toward the
                kitchen; a crash of glass is heard from that direction.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Raven">Raven</spkr>No matter what the reason, no matter how much we wish
                it wasn't true, <charDesc ref="Robin">Robin's a criminal
                now</charDesc>. And just like any other criminal--</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>--The Teen Titans have to bring him
                down.</sp>

            <sd><char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char> stifles a sob and turns away, clapping her hands to her face.
                An alarm blares out before she can do anything else; <directNote kind="cut">cut to
                       <char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> at a computer console</directNote>. He is back to
                normal.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>It's him!</sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="fade">Fade to black.</directNote></sd>

            <sd><directNote kind="fade">Fade in to a large open space within a
                    building.</directNote> A set of doors, marked with a large W, is blown inward
                off the hinges, and<char ref="Robin">Robin</char> steps in as the smoke swirls around his
                ankles. He advances across the floor; <directNote kind="cut">cut to behind
                    him</directNote> and <directNote kind="tilt">tilt up to show that the room is
                    empty save for a device suspended within a force field at the
                    center</directNote>. <stageDesc category="close-up">Close-up of this as he
                    approaches it.</stageDesc> He reaches out to seize the item, but the next words
                freeze him in his tracks.</sd>

            <cue>Animation goof: The blaster is on his left wrist, not his right. This error will be
                repeated several times throughout the rest of this act and the start of the
                next.</cue>

            <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr><sd>from o.c.</sd>You're not walking outta here,
                   <char ref="Robin">Robin</char>!</sp>

            <sd>He turns; the other Titans are at the wrecked door.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>Not without a fight.<sd><char ref="Robin">Robin</char> yells
                    and charges.</sd>Titans! Go!</sp>

            <sd>They bolt across the floor,<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> becoming <transform class="mammal">a tiger</transform> as he moves. <directNote kind="cut">Cut to
                       <char ref="Robin">Robin</char> and back to the group</directNote>, then <directNote kind="cut">to<char ref="Robin">Robin</char> once more</directNote>. <stageDesc category="letterbox">Letterbox view, top half of the screen: the five
                    silhouettes hurtle toward one another.</stageDesc>
                <stageDesc category="fullscreen">Fullscreen:<char ref="Robin">Robin</char> dodges both
                       <char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char>'s punch and<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char>'s lunge; the latter
                    returns to <transform class="human">human form</transform> as <charDesc ref="Robin">the new felon</charDesc> vaults overhead.</stageDesc> He sails
                neatly between<char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char> and<char ref="Raven">Raven</char>, tears away a ceiling
                panel, and is away through it before either can react. <directNote kind="cut">Cut to
                    just inside the hole</directNote> and <directNote kind="pull">pull back a bit as
                    the four stare flabbergasted up after him</directNote>.</sd>

            <sd><directNote kind="cut">Cut to <stageDesc category="long-shot">a long overhead shot
                        of the building's front entrance</stageDesc></directNote>, then <directNote kind="tilt">tilt up to the roof</directNote>. A large lighted sign identifies
                this as the headquarters of Wayne Enterprises. A panel pops open, and
                   <char ref="Robin">Robin</char> springs out and races across, his silhouette tiny in the
                glare from the huge white letters.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Slade">Slade</spkr>Not so fast,<char ref="Robin">Robin</char>. You have yet to
                achieve your objective.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>The device was too heavily guarded. I'll have to
                steal it another--</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="Slade">Slade</spkr>No!<sd><char ref="Robin">Robin</char> stops.</sd>Go back. Unless
                you want me to destroy them, go back and fight.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr><sd>from o.c.</sd><char ref="Robin">Robin</char>!</sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="shift">Camera shift: he and the others are at one end of the
                    roof.</directNote>
               <char ref="Robin">Robin</char> turns to face them.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>Look, I don't know what's going on,<sd><directNote kind="cut">Cut to<char ref="Robin">Robin</char>;<char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char> continues
                        o.c.</directNote></sd>but we don't want to fight.<sd><directNote kind="cut">Back to him.</directNote></sd>We just want to talk.</sp>

            <sd><char ref="Robin">Robin</char> lets his feet do the conversing, in the form of a high flying
                kick that drives<char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char> back past the other three.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>Guess there's nothing to talk about.</sp>

            <sd>He cracks his knuckles and turns into <transform class="mammal">an enormous
                    gorilla</transform>, bringing both fists down on the rooftop. <char ref="Robin">Robin</char>
                leaps back to evade the hit and a couple of grabs before perching at the center of
                the A in WAYNE. <charDesc ref="BeastBoy">A huge green hand shoots up after
                    him</charDesc>; he leaps to the A's peak, then down again as <char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> climbs up after him. In midair, he pulls out another of
                   <char ref="Slade">Slade</char>'s flying weapons, the curved blades extending from the
                central orb.<directNote kind="cut"> Cut to<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char></directNote>; a
                line whistles down from o.c.,<char ref="Robin">Robin</char>'s direction, and winds itself
                around one thick wrist.<char ref="Robin">Robin</char> drops down and threads the line through
                the A's center. It is pulled taut, yanking<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> halfway through to
                make him stick fast.</sd>

            <sd><stageDesc category="close-up">Close-up of<char ref="Robin">Robin</char> on the
                    roof</stageDesc>; <directNote kind="pull">pull back to show
                       <char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char>'s feet planted in front</directNote> and <directNote kind="cut">cut to her</directNote>.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr>Please--</sp>

            <sd>She is cut off as he rushes past her, leaps very high, and comes down with a kick
                and a flurry of other strikes aimed at<char ref="Raven">Raven</char>. She shields herself from
                the offensive. <directNote kind="cut">Cut to <stageDesc category="close-up">an
                        extreme close-up of<char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char>'s sonic
                    cannon</stageDesc></directNote> and <directNote kind="tilt">tilt up to his face
                    behind it</directNote>. Even though the weapon is fully charged up, his face
                betrays his extreme uneasiness and reluctance at the prospect of using it in this
                situation. His perspective of the two duelists; a low groan is heard as he steadies
                his aim.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>Don't make me...</sp>

            <sd>Back to him. Giving up the attempt to get a clear shot, he disarms and runs in to do
                things the old-fashioned way. The punch he throws misses<char ref="Robin">Robin</char>, but
                connects against<char ref="Raven">Raven</char>'s shield. High above the roof, <char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> is still struggling to extricate himself from the sign's A. He
                finally succeeds by changing into <transform class="reptile">a snake</transform> and
                slithering down; once he is back on the roof, he assumes the form of <transform class="mammal">a bighorn sheep</transform> and charges. Those curved horns slam
                into<char ref="Robin">Robin</char>'s back and send him rolling away to stop just short of the
                edge.</sd>

            <sd><stageDesc category="open-shot">Opening shot:<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char>,
                       <char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char>, and<char ref="Raven">Raven</char> on the roof.</stageDesc>
               <char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> returns to <transform class="human">human form</transform>
                and runs to the edge, where<char ref="Robin">Robin</char> lies prone.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>Dude! Are you okay?</sp>

            <sd>His answer comes in the form of a savage kick that knocks him into
                   <char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char>; both go down, and<char ref="Robin">Robin</char> sits up. <stageDesc category="close-up">Extreme close-up of his eyes</stageDesc>, <directNote kind="pan">panning to the receiver in his ear</directNote>.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Slade">Slade</spkr>Fight to win,<char ref="Robin">Robin</char>. Use the thermal
                blaster.</sp>

            <sd><char ref="Raven">Raven</char> rises into the air.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Raven">Raven</spkr>Azarath Metrion Zinthos!</sp>

            <sd>The spell lifts<char ref="Robin">Robin</char> up and binds him from neck to knees. His right
                arm is free, however, and he scales a disc at her. It explodes in her face with a
                blinding flash, breaking her hold.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Raven">Raven</spkr>I…can’t…see!</sp>

            <sd>She tumbles down as<char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char> watches.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr>No!</sp>

            <sd><char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char> backs into view, blocking <char ref="Robin">Robin</char>’s punches.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>Come on, man, don’t make me do this! I don’t want
                to do this!</sp>

            <sd>He grabs one arm and gets ready to fire his cannon, but a low foot sweep gets in
                under his guard and dumps him onto his back. The blast goes off when he falls;
                   <char ref="Robin">Robin</char> leaps away and ends up atop the sign’s A. As
                   <char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char> and<char ref="Raven">Raven</char> sit up, rubbing their heads, and
                   <char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> gets to his feet, <charDesc ref="Robin">the former
                    Titan</charDesc> hops from one letter to the next. When he reaches the E, he
                finds a supremely furious<char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char> floating just past its edge, with a
                starbolt ready to go in her outstretched hand.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr>Stop!<sd><char ref="Robin">Robin</char> does so.</sd>Do,
                not, move.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="Slade">Slade</spkr>I thought I told you to use that blaster. Attack!
                Now!</sp>

            <sd><char ref="Robin">Robin</char> raises the weapon and trains it on<char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char>; its
                muzzle glows red. <stageDesc category="close-up">Close-up of her, the green radiance
                    from her palm throwing an unearthly hue onto her icy expression as she steels
                    herself to fire.</stageDesc>
                <directNote kind="cut">Cut to a slow pan across <char ref="Robin">Robin</char>’s expressionless
                    face, bathed in the blaster’s glare</directNote>, then to <stageDesc category="close-up">an extreme close-up of her eye</stageDesc>. It widens,
                showing the struggle between friendship and duty raging in her mind. <directNote kind="pull">Pull back to frame both.</directNote></sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr><sd>voice trembling</sd><char ref="Robin">Robin</char>,
                    <charDesc ref="Robin">you are my best friend</charDesc>. I cannot be in a world
                where we must fight.<sd><stageDesc category="close-up">Close-up.</stageDesc></sd>If
                you are truly evil,<sd>drops her head, cooling down her starbolt</sd>then go
                        ahead.<sd><directNote kind="pull">Pull back; she lowers her
                        arm.</directNote></sd>Do what you must.</sp>

            <sd><char ref="Robin">Robin</char> still has her in his sights, but her words have touched off his
                own inner conflict. After a tense moment, he de-energizes the blaster and lowers his
                arm.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr><char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char>, no! I--</sp>

            <sd>There is a squeal of shrill feedback from the receiver; he claps a hand to his ear
                in pain.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Slade">Slade</spkr>ROBIN!! I gave you an order.</sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="cut">Cut to <stageDesc category="close-up">a close-up of
                        him</stageDesc>.</directNote> On the next words, <directNote kind="tilt">tilt down to the button in his hand</directNote>.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Slade">Slade</spkr>If you won’t attack, my probes will.</sp>

            <sd>His thumb comes down, and he stands watching the other four Titans’
                blood vessels on his monitors. As the probes begin their work, flashes of red light
                play across one after another of the human figures on the vital-sign readouts. The
                last seen is<char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char>, whose readout changes to an orange-glowing,
                red-flecked silhouette of her; around it, the background flashes to the edge of the
                Wayne Enterprises sign. She is still floating just past its edge, groaning in agony
                and unable to move.<char ref="Robin">Robin</char> runs as close to her as he can without going
                overboard. <directNote kind="dissolve">Dissolve to <stageDesc category="close-up">a
                        close-up of her, now twitching and flailing uncontrollably</stageDesc>; she
                    starts to fall, but<char ref="Robin">Robin</char> catches her.</directNote></sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr><char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char>!</sp>

            <sd>He looks down toward the roof, and <directNote kind="cut">the camera cuts to a slow
                    pan across the bases of the five giant letters</directNote>. One by one, the
                other three Titans are similarly afflicted and collapse in unbearable
                pain.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>Stop! Please stop!</sp>

            <sd><stageDesc category="close-up">Close-up of<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char>.</stageDesc></sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Slade">Slade</spkr>Attack,<char ref="Robin">Robin</char>.<sd><stageDesc category="close-up">Close-up of<char ref="Raven">Raven</char>.</stageDesc></sd>It’s the
                only way to save them.<sd><stageDesc category="close-up">Close-up to
                           <char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char>.</stageDesc></sd>Attack with everything you’ve
                got.</sp>

            <sd><char ref="Robin">Robin</char> mulls over the predicament, one that would put Catch-22 to shame,
                and gently sets<char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char> down.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr><sd>weakly</sd>Robin…</sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="cut">Cut to<char ref="Robin">Robin</char>; he points the blaster down at
                    her.</directNote></sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>I’m sorry.</sp>

            <sd>He fires; the entire screen goes red from the glare and <directNote kind="fade">then
                    fades to black</directNote>.</sd>

            <sd><directNote kind="fade">Fade in to him still aiming the weapon</directNote>; but
                now,<char ref="Slade">Slade</char> is standing at a short distance. Smoke drifts up from the
                muzzle.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Slade">Slade</spkr><charDesc ref="Robin">That’s my boy.</charDesc></sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="snap">Snap to black.</directNote></sd>

            <sd><directNote kind="fade">Fade in to <stageDesc category="close-up">a close-up of
                            Starfire</stageDesc>, knocked out on the sign.</directNote>
                She is no longer suffering the effects of<char ref="Slade">Slade</char>'s probes. She moans
                weakly and sits up atop the huge lighted letters.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr>Huh?</sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="pan">Pan from her to <stageDesc category="overhead-shot">an
                        overhead view of the other three</stageDesc>.</directNote> They too are free
                of the probes' onslaught and have begun to come around. <directNote kind="cut">Cut
                    to roof level.</directNote></sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr><sd>as they all gather</sd>Okay. Weirdness.
                What just--?</sp>

            <sd>Before he can finish the sentence,<char ref="Robin">Robin</char> plunges toward them with a
                yell and a fresh blast ready to go. It traces a short distance between the foursome;
                he lands in the middle and slings<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> into<char ref="Raven">Raven</char>'s
                face. A low kick knocks<char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char> away, and<char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char> finds
                herself trying to hit a moving midair target with her starbolts. He somersaults
                across the roof and trains his blaster on her. She gasps, realizing that he has her
                bracketed, but he shifts his aim and fires past her, hitting the Y. The next beams
                come at<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> and<char ref="Raven">Raven</char>; he becomes <transform class="mammal">a monkey</transform> and scampers away, while she puts up a
                shield in front of herself.</sd>

            <sd>Now <charDesc ref="BeastBoy">the little green primate</charDesc> darts in and
                climbs all over the armored arms and legs; it takes a moment for <char ref="Robin">Robin</char>
                to get hold and throw him aside. As he does so, though,<char ref="Raven">Raven</char> exerts
                her powers over the arm with the blaster and causes the thing to dismantle itself.
                What she gets for her trouble is a shove that sends her careening across the roof.
                Next up is<char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char>, who comes up from behind and tries to grab him.
                   <char ref="Robin">Robin</char> ducks away; <directNote kind="cut">cut to him</directNote>
                and swivel quickly to show that all four of the other Titans have
                regrouped to face him.<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> becomes <transform class="mammal">a
                    bear</transform>,<char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char> has his cannon locked and loaded, and the
                girls have their respective powers warmed up.</sd>

            <sd><directNote kind="pull">Pull back slightly</directNote>; he looks over his shoulder
                and finds that he is at the roof's edge. He whips out a handful of discs and throws
                them at the group. <directNote kind="cut">Cut to<char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char> and
                       <char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char>, who duck as the projectiles hurtle past</directNote>,
                and <directNote kind="pan">pan to<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> and<char ref="Raven">Raven</char> as
                    one of them explodes o.c.</directNote>
                <directNote kind="pull">Pull back to show them detonating at the bases of the
                    A.</directNote></sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>Titans! Move!</sp>

            <sd>They clear out,<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> transforming to <transform class="mammal">bat
                    form</transform>, just in time, as the Y topples forward with the A not far
                behind. When the smoke clears,<char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char> is seen in one piece and on his
                feet; <directNote kind="pull">pull back slightly to show him standing in the center
                    of the fallen A</directNote>, the right place at the right time to keep from
                being crushed.<char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char> looks around fearfully as <char ref="Raven">Raven</char>
                lands near her.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Raven">Raven</spkr>He's gone.</sp>

            <sd><char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char> comes over.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>Everybody okay?</sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="cut">Cut to him and<char ref="Raven">Raven</char></directNote>; <char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> lands and takes <transform class="human">human form</transform>.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>Uh, I know where<char ref="Robin">Robin</char> picked up
                that heat ray, but where did he learn that little glowy hurty trick?</sp>

            <sd><stageDesc category="gag">Sight gag: on the end of this line, his eyes briefly turn
                    orange with red spots.</stageDesc></sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr><sd>from o.c.</sd>I do not think that was
                   <char ref="Robin">Robin</char>.<sd><directNote kind="pull">Pull back to frame
                        her.</directNote></sd>Perhaps it is<char ref="Slade">Slade</char> who has learned a new
                trick.</sp>

            <sd><stageDesc category="long-shot">Long overhead shot of the roof.</stageDesc> Smoke
                pours up from the two fallen letters; the three still standing are not in too great
                a shape either. <directNote kind="pull">Pull back slowly for a few
                    seconds</directNote>, then <directNote kind="cut">cut to roof
                level</directNote>. <stageDesc category="overhead-shot">As<char ref="Robin">Robin</char>'s
                    thermal blaster ray comes down from overhead among the
                    Titans</stageDesc>, the picture starts to fast-forward and then
                rewind as if it were a videotaped program. It stops just before the beam is to hit
                the roof, at which point it starts to play at normal speed.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Slade">Slade</spkr><sd>from o.c.</sd>Thrilling.</sp>

            <sd>It rewinds again to the same point and plays as <directNote kind="pull">the camera
                    pulls back very slowly</directNote>. We are looking at one of the monitors in
                   <char ref="Slade">Slade</char>'s lair, on which many clips from the battle are playing at
                the same time. <directNote kind="cut">Cut to him; he leans back in his
                    chair.</directNote></sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Slade">Slade</spkr><charDesc ref="Robin">My apprentice</charDesc> is
                progressing even faster than I had hoped. All he needed was a little
                motivation.</sp>

            <sd><char ref="Robin">Robin</char> reaches into view and grabs a wrist. <directNote kind="cut">Cut
                    to him, fist cocked back.</directNote></sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr><oneLine>Motivate THIS!</oneLine></sp>

        </act>
        <act n="2">
            <title>Act Two</title>
            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr><oneLine>Motivate THIS!</oneLine></sp>

            <sd>He throws the punch, but<char ref="Slade">Slade</char> catches it easily without flinching and
                wrenches the arm to one side<char ref="Robin">Robin</char> is flung toward <stageDesc category="overhead-shot">a set of overhead gears</stageDesc>, but he comes down
                in a crouch across the floor. He stands up;<char ref="Slade">Slade</char> leaves his chair and
                flexes a handful of fingers.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Slade">Slade</spkr><char ref="Robin">Robin</char>.<sd>He crosses the floor.</sd>That
                was vicious, dishonorable, and ruthless. Excellent work. You're becoming more like
                me every second.</sp>

            <sd>He turns away, then whirls to face <charDesc ref="Robin">his apprentice</charDesc>
                with a sudden string of blows;<char ref="Robin">Robin</char> dodges and tries a few
                counterattacks, but<char ref="Slade">Slade</char> gets him in a headlock and lifts him off his
                feet.<char ref="Robin">Robin</char> swings his leg straight ahead and up to kick him in the
                face, forcing him to break the hold. Both retreat a bit, trying to catch their
                breath and clear their heads.</sd>

            <sd><directNote kind="cut">Cut to<char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char> in the Tower's operations
                    center.</directNote> He straightens up.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>Think I found something.</sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="pull">Pull back.</directNote> The four Titans are
                gathered around the couch;<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> wears an assortment of devices
                wired up to the computers. On the window/screen is a readout of his vital
                signs.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>The enhanced sensors are picking up radio
                interference on the nanoscopic scale.</sp>

            <sd>He does a bit of typing; now the screen shows<char ref="Slade">Slade</char>'s probes in fine
                detail, attached to<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char>'s red blood cells.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Raven">Raven</spkr><sd>as<char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char> gasps</sd>Whoa.</sp>

            <sd><charDesc ref="BeastBoy">The test subject</charDesc> looks toward the screen, and
                his eyes pop wide open for a moment.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>Those things are inside me? EWWW!!</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>They're inside all of us. Billions of 'em!</sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="cut">Cut to<char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char>.</directNote></sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr>With such technology at his command,
                   <char ref="Slade">Slade</char> can destroy us whenever he wants.</sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="pan">Pan to<char ref="Raven">Raven</char>.</directNote></sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Raven">Raven</spkr>Unless<char ref="Robin">Robin</char> does whatever he says.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>And you guys thought my zombie idea was
                crazy.</sp>

            <sd>Back to<char ref="Slade">Slade</char> and<char ref="Robin">Robin</char>, still trying to collect
                themselves after the previous skirmish.<char ref="Robin">Robin</char> strikes first, propelling
                himself in a high backward jump that carries him toward <charDesc ref="Slade">the
                    metal face</charDesc>, but<char ref="Slade">Slade</char> grabs his legs, swings him low to
                scrape the floor, and ends by hurling him toward <stageDesc category="overhead-shot">the overhead machinery</stageDesc>. <charDesc ref="Robin">The screaming Boy
                    Wonder</charDesc> hooks a crankshaft to stop himself from flying into the gears.
                    <directNote kind="cut">Cut to a shot of the turning wheels</directNote>, then
                    <directNote kind="cut">another angle</directNote>, and <directNote kind="snap">snap to black</directNote>.</sd>

            <sd><directNote kind="pan">Pan from here to a section of the machine room, the blackness
                    was just a darkened corner, as<char ref="Robin">Robin</char> advances into view and peers
                    warily from one spot to another.</directNote> He makes his way to a bank of
                levers near the edge of this elevated platform and stops for a good look around.
                Steam boils up as a stationary gear begins to turn; <stageDesc category="close-up">close-up of the platform's edge</stageDesc>.<char ref="Slade">Slade</char>'s feet are
                carried down onto it from the rotating wheel.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Slade">Slade</spkr><sd>from o.c.</sd>Good,
                       <char ref="Robin">Robin</char>.<sd><directNote kind="pull">Pull back; he
                        approaches.</directNote></sd>You're doing much better than last time. A few
                more years of training, and you might actually pose a threat.</sp>

            <sd><char ref="Robin">Robin</char> has started to back up by this point; he reaches the levers and
                breaks one loose to use as a club. He twirls it back and forth and gets ready to
                swing, but<char ref="Slade">Slade</char> merely pulls out a fighting staff just like the one
                   <char ref="Robin">Robin</char> used to use and extends it to full length. More steam roils
                around the two enemies before<char ref="Robin">Robin</char> charges in. <char ref="Slade">Slade</char>
                parries his attacks, and the two lean in at each other with their full weight.
                Slowly but surely,<char ref="Slade">Slade</char> overpowers<char ref="Robin">Robin</char> and forces him
                back, then catches him with a high swing to drive him back against a pipe.</sd>

            <sd><char ref="Robin">Robin</char> leaps away, just barely missing<char ref="Slade">Slade</char>'s jabbing
                strike that punctures the pipe to release a flood of steam that envelops both of
                them. The staff has lodged in the metal, and<char ref="Robin">Robin</char> jumps onto it for a
                blind swing of his makeshift club. The sound of metal crashing against metal tells
                that the strike hit its target, but after a moment,<char ref="Slade">Slade</char> stands
                up.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>Huh?</sp>

            <sd><charDesc ref="Slade">The villain</charDesc> delivers a karate chop that breaks the
                end off his own staff.<char ref="Robin">Robin</char> jumps away and <stageDesc category="overhead-shot">high overhead, landing on a bend in the damaged
                    pipe</stageDesc>. A camshaft swings back and forth in front of him like a
                pendulum; he takes a few cautious steps backward, and<char ref="Slade">Slade</char> appears
                suddenly before him once the next swing has gone through.</sd>

            <sd>Another couple of cycles, and he is gone again.<char ref="Robin">Robin</char>'s eyes go wide in
                disbelief; an instant later,<char ref="Slade">Slade</char> barrels across and hits him
                broadside. <charDesc ref="Robin">The young man</charDesc> fetches up on a stationary
                gear mounted horizontally and, dazed a bit, struggles to lift his head. He snaps
                back to full consciousness in a hurry once he sees<char ref="Slade">Slade</char> coming
                straight down toward him. One of those armored fists slams into the platform, just
                missing<char ref="Robin">Robin</char> thanks to his last-second dodge. Withdrawing his hand
                from the hole he has smashed in the deck plate,<char ref="Slade">Slade</char> stands up and
                cracks his knuckles.<char ref="Robin">Robin</char>'s eyes narrow in pure hatred, and he runs
                across for a leap; instead of aiming directly at<char ref="Slade">Slade</char>, though, he goes
                past one shoulder and brings his leg up for a crashing spin kick that staggers the
                man. A second blow knocks<char ref="Slade">Slade</char> over the edge; he tumbles down in front
                of the monitors, which once again show the four Titans' bloodstreams.
                    <charDesc ref="Slade">The left side of his mask has cracked from the force of
                    the kick.</charDesc>
               <char ref="Robin">Robin</char> jumps down to face him.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Slade">Slade</spkr>You're going to wish you hadn't done that.</sp>

            <sd><char ref="Robin">Robin</char> steps closer.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>I only wish I'd done it sooner.</sp>

            <sd>As he says this, <charDesc ref="Robin">he tears the silver S from his
                    chest</charDesc>. He then throws it down to stick in the platform surface just
                in front of the still-kneeling<char ref="Slade">Slade</char>, who voices a low growl and lets
                it build into a full roar as he charges. Now<char ref="Robin">Robin</char> is forced to go on
                the defensive against a sequence of attacks. He goes into a handstand, attempting to
                kick<char ref="Slade">Slade</char> in the face, but <charDesc ref="Slade">the latter</charDesc>
                only catches the approaching foot to immobilize him. After an incurious look back
                and forth,<char ref="Slade">Slade</char> throws<char ref="Robin">Robin</char> across the way; <directNote kind="cut">cut to <charDesc ref="Robin">the former Titan</charDesc>, ground
                    level, as he struggles to stand and <charDesc ref="Slade">the former</charDesc>
                    steps into view near the camera</directNote>.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Slade">Slade</spkr><sd>from o.c.</sd>I have much to teach
                        you.<sd><directNote kind="pull">Pull back to frame
                both.</directNote></sd>But the first thing you need to learn is gratitude.</sp>

            <sd><char ref="Robin">Robin</char> wipes his face, and<char ref="Slade">Slade</char> merely stands there and
                eyes the activity on the monitors. <charDesc ref="Robin">The rebellious
                    apprentice</charDesc> yells in fury and moves in for another go, but
                   <char ref="Slade">Slade</char> seizes his arm and bends it back cruelly past the shoulder
                before dumping him onto his back. <stageDesc category="close-up">Close-up of
                        Robin</stageDesc>; the hold is released, and he starts to roll
                away.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Slade">Slade</spkr><sd>from o.c.</sd>I made you <charDesc ref="Robin">my
                    apprentice</charDesc>. All my knowledge, all my power, all for you.<sd>He leans
                    into view and grabs<char ref="Robin">Robin</char>'s hair.</sd>But the only thing you care
                about is your WORTHLESS, LITTLE FRIENDS!!!</sp>

            <sd><stageDesc category="close-up">Close-up of<char ref="Robin">Robin</char> on this last
                    word</stageDesc>, then <directNote kind="pull">pull back</directNote>.
                   <char ref="Slade">Slade</char> lets go of the hair and takes a couple of steps away before
                   <char ref="Robin">Robin</char> stands.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Slade">Slade</spkr>If the Titans are so distracting, maybe
                I should just get rid of them.</sp>

            <sd>As casually as if he were looking at a wristwatch, he brings up the button and gets
                ready to set the probes off again.<char ref="Robin">Robin</char> steels himself for another
                charge, then loses his resolve, knowing what another act of defiance could bring
                down on his friends.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>Don't. I'll do whatever you say.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="Slade">Slade</spkr>Good boy. And, from now on, I'd like you to call me
                master.</sp>

            <sd>A starbolt flashes across the screen and blasts him away to land right in front of
                the monitors. <directNote kind="cut">Cut to the other four Titans, now
                    in the lair and gathered in front of his favorite chair.</directNote>
               <char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char> has a double-barreled blast all ready to go with his name on
                it.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr>Leave. Him. Alone!</sp>

            <sd><char ref="Slade">Slade</char> is getting up from the shot<char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char> laid on
                him.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Slade">Slade</spkr><char ref="Robin">Robin</char>! Attack!</sp>

            <sd><char ref="Robin">Robin</char> is now close to a piece of equipment at one end of the row of
                monitors. It is the same device that blasted the other four Titans off
                the speedboat and implanted the probes in Part One. As he speaks, he gestures toward
                it.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>Get out of here! Go! You don't know what those beams
                did to--</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>Dude...</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="Raven">Raven</spkr>...We know...</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>...And we don't care.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr>We are your
                    friends,<char ref="Robin">Robin</char>. We are not leaving without you.</sp>

            <sd>They tense for battle;<char ref="Slade">Slade</char> steps up.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Slade">Slade</spkr>How very touching.<sd>puts his finger on the
                    button</sd>But<char ref="Robin">Robin</char> doesn't need any friends.</sp>

            <sd>He presses it, bringing the rapparatus to life; red energy bolts blaze out across
                the space. <directNote kind="cut">Cut to<char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char>, who is first to
                    succumb to the probes</directNote>, and <directNote kind="pull">pull back as he
                    and<char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char> both collapse in torment</directNote>. <directNote kind="pan">Pan to<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char>, whose knees buckle next</directNote>;
                   <char ref="Raven">Raven</char> drops to the ground next to him. <directNote kind="pull">Pull
                    back across the platform to put<char ref="Robin">Robin</char> in view, watching them, and
                       <char ref="Slade">Slade</char> just behind him.</directNote></sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Slade">Slade</spkr>This is the price for your disobedience,
                   <char ref="Robin">Robin</char>. Now do as I command. Attack!</sp>

            <sd>With a Herculean effort,<char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char> lifts her head and aims a pleading
                gaze at<char ref="Robin">Robin</char>. <charDesc ref="Starfire">Even though her eyes are whited
                    out by the glare of the energy surging through her body, they and the tears
                    running down her cheeks broadcast the quartet's agony loud and clear.</charDesc>
               <char ref="Robin">Robin</char>'s jaw drops open as he gasps softly; he looks off in the
                direction of the device, and <directNote kind="pan">the camera pans quickly to
                    it</directNote>. Back to <stageDesc category="close-up">an extreme close-up of
                    his eyes</stageDesc>, now narrowed in pure, righteous determination.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>No.</sp>

            <sd>He dashes off.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Slade">Slade</spkr><char ref="Robin">Robin</char>!</sp>

            <sd>A few more steps and a great leap carry <charDesc ref="Robin">the roaring
                    apprentice</charDesc> over the last few yards, and he plants his hand on the
                rig. Now bathed in its glow, he brings his other palm around to touch it as well.
                The groans that escape through his tight-locked teeth betray the unendurable
                physical strain he has put on himself. <directNote kind="cut">Cut to <stageDesc category="close-up">a close-up of his face</stageDesc></directNote> and
                    <directNote kind="zoom">zoom in</directNote>, <directNote kind="dissolve">dissolving to a sequence of internal shots just like those that showed the
                    entry of the probes into<char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char>'s body in Part One</directNote>.
                Muscle tissue, artery, devices latching onto blood cells, they are invading his
                body, and a flash of white subsides to put us back in the lair and him still at the
                system's core. He is thrown backward as the entire rig explodes; <directNote kind="fade">fade to black as the glare dies away</directNote>.</sd>

            <sd><directNote kind="fade">Fade in to <stageDesc category="long-shot">a long shot of
                        him, supine near the monitors with smoke rising from his
                    body</stageDesc>.</directNote>
                <directNote kind="pan">Pan to<char ref="Slade">Slade</char>, watching the four
                        Titans' bloodstreams with great surprise</directNote>, and, as
                he does, a fifth screen pops up with<char ref="Robin">Robin</char>'s name on it. Groaning with
                the strain, <charDesc ref="Robin">this new victim</charDesc> hauls himself to his
                feet;<char ref="Slade">Slade</char> regards his control button with some trepidation now, and
                the orange-glowing boots advance toward him, step by labored step. <directNote kind="pan">Pan to follow him</directNote>, then <directNote kind="cut">cut to
                       <char ref="Slade">Slade</char> as he stops for a little face time</directNote>.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>New deal,<char ref="Slade">Slade</char>. If I lose my friends, you lose <charDesc ref="Robin">your
                    apprentice</charDesc>.<sd><stageDesc category="close-up">Extreme close-up of
                           <char ref="Slade">Slade</char>'s eye, narrowing, then back to
                him.</stageDesc></sd>And I know how you hate to lose.</sp>

            <sd>He collapses.<char ref="Slade">Slade</char> gives this proposition a long moment's thought, his
                thumb ready to bring<char ref="Robin">Robin</char>'s existence to a grinding halt, and then
                tears the controller off his wrist and tosses it away. A few sparks flash up from
                it, after which the probes cease their destructive work on <charDesc ref="Robin">the
                    Boy Wonder</charDesc>. Not about to let the matter drop so easily,
                   <char ref="Slade">Slade</char> raises one foot to stomp <charDesc ref="Robin">the
                    spiky-haired head</charDesc> flat; before he can bring it down, though,
                   <char ref="Robin">Robin</char> is up and grabbing at it. He smirks at<char ref="Slade">Slade</char>,
                whose eye goes very wide, and a smashing punch sends <charDesc ref="Slade">the evil
                    genius</charDesc> flying to the other end of the platform.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>Titans! Go!</sp>

            <sd>The others, also back in good health, charge at<char ref="Slade">Slade</char>. <char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char>, <transform class="mammal">now a tiger</transform>, is first to do
                damage with a clawed swipe that pierces the armor.<char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char> and
                   <char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char> move in next, starbolts and cannon going full throttle to
                blast<char ref="Slade">Slade</char> backward. As he tumbles,<char ref="Raven">Raven</char> casts a spell
                to bind his feet and sling him hard onto the platform. Only now does
                   <char ref="Robin">Robin</char> go on the attack, delivering a flying kick that pastes a boot
                sole across that masked face. <stageDesc category="close-up">Close-up of
                       <char ref="Slade">Slade</char>, seen from behind</stageDesc>; <charDesc ref="Slade">glowing cracks spread across the back of his head as the steel
                    fractures</charDesc>.</sd>

            <sd><directNote kind="pull">Pull back.</directNote>
               <char ref="Robin">Robin</char> lands in a crouch as<char ref="Slade">Slade</char> falls to his knees near
                the camera, <annot>the left side of his face turned to us</annot>. <charDesc ref="Slade">The right half of his mask drops away and skids across the floor,
                    and he now stands up with one big hand covering the exposed portion of his
                    visage. Nothing can be seen but a fringe of unruly hair above the fingers, and
                    his eye looks as if it might pop out of his head.</charDesc> He turns and runs
                off, dropping his hand as he does so; <annot>we never see that part of his
                    face</annot>.</sd>

            <sd><directNote kind="cut">Cut to another part of the lair.</directNote> He runs into
                view and fiddles briefly with a large piece of equipment, then turns to the camera.
                The light does not shine on the exposed side.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Slade">Slade</spkr>Another day,<char ref="Robin">Robin</char>.</sp>

            <sd><stageDesc category="close-up">Close-up of a dial on the end of this.</stageDesc> He
                has slotted his fingers into holes bored for a better grip, similar to a bowling
                ball, and he turns it. Lines of red light emanate along the surface of the device;
                    <directNote kind="pull">pull back to show rings of light flicking on down the
                    body of the rig</directNote>.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Slade">Slade</spkr>Another day.</sp>

            <sd>All five Titans stand dumbfounded near the monitors, which have all
                gone blank;<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> returns to <transform class="human">human
                    form</transform>. The light goes red and <directNote kind="fade">begins to fade
                    in and out</directNote>, <directNote kind="black-screen">blacking out the screen
                    every time it goes</directNote>.<char ref="Robin">Robin</char> runs forward as the entire
                place starts to shake and crumble,<char ref="Slade">Slade</char> has set off a self-destruct
                sequence. Gears start to fall off their axles, first one and then many more. The
                biggest tumbles toward<char ref="Robin">Robin</char>. He runs at top speed to stay ahead as it
                rolls along and tears up the platform; finally,<char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char> flies past and
                carries him off.<char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char> strains at the core of the probe system and
                tears it loose. <stageDesc category="overhead-shot">Overhead view:
                       <char ref="Raven">Raven</char> flies up, towing<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char>, as
                       <char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char> makes a mad dash along the crumbling deck plates and is
                    thrown into the air when one flips.</stageDesc></sd>

            <sd><directNote kind="black-screen">After the screen blacks out following this last
                    shot</directNote>, a door opens and white light pours in from outside.
                   <char ref="Robin">Robin</char> is there, having opened it.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>Let's go home.</sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="black-screen">A gear wheel falls into view near the camera to
                    black out the screen.</directNote></sd>

            <sd><directNote kind="fade">Fade in to the exterior of the Tower</directNote> and
                    <directNote kind="zoom">zoom in slowly</directNote>. It is now the following
                morning. <directNote kind="dissolve">Dissolve to <stageDesc category="close-up">a
                        close-up of a computer console</stageDesc> in the operations
                    center.</directNote> On its screen, a bar graph is quickly filling up;
                    <directNote kind="pull">pull back to show that the core of<char ref="Slade">Slade</char>'s
                    probe system has been wired up</directNote>. <directNote kind="pan">Pan to put
                       <char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> in view-seated</directNote>, tubes and cables hooked
                to every square inch of him, a mask clamped over his face.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr><sd>muffled, annoyed</sd>Am I done yet?</sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="pull">Pull back.</directNote>
               <char ref="Robin">Robin</char>, <charDesc ref="Robin">dressed in his proper outfit</charDesc>,
                and the other three Titans are watching a magnified view of <char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char>'s blood on the window/screen. Not a probe in sight.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>That's it, y'all. The Teen Titans are
                officially probe-free.</sp>

            <sd>Back to<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> on the end of this. He jumps out of the chair with a
                boisterous laugh and starts to dance, with assorted hardware still connected to his
                body.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>Go,<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char>! You're probe-less!
                No probes now! Go,<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char>! Go,<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char>! Get fun-kay!
                Uh! Yeah! Uh, uh, that's right.</sp>

            <sd>He moonwalks o.c. on he end of this.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Raven">Raven</spkr>Um...I know this isn't my style, but we just kicked
                   <char ref="Slade">Slade</char>'s butt. Shouldn't we celebrate or something?</sp>

            <sd><char ref="Robin">Robin</char> and<char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char> stare incredulously at her, but
                   <char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> jumps into view and lands on<char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char>'s
                shoulders. <charDesc ref="BeastBoy">The green goofball</charDesc> has shed all the
                equipment he pulled along with him.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>Yeah!</sp>

            <sd>He leans forward to stare<char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char> upside-down in the face.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>All-you-can-eat...</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>...free-form...</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy Cyborg">Beast Boy and Cyborg</spkr>...breakfast
                explosion!</sp>

            <sd><stageDesc category="gag">Sight gag: on the last two words, they pull apart and a
                    shower of breakfast foods flies out from behind them.</stageDesc></sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Raven">Raven</spkr>Sorry I asked.</sp>

            <sd><charDesc ref="BeastBoy Cyborg">The two laughing cooks</charDesc> run past and
                haul her toward the kitchen, leaving<char ref="Robin">Robin</char> and <char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char>
                alone at the couch. Some bacon and a couple of eggs fly back into view. He sits down
                next to her; she cannot raise her eyes to him.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>Everything okay?</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr>I am sorry.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>You're sorry? For what?</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr>When things were bad, there was a moment where
                I truly believed that you were...like<char ref="Slade">Slade</char>. I doubted you. And for
                that, I am sorry.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>I doubted myself, Star. <charDesc ref="Robin">Focused, serious, determined</charDesc>...as much as I hate to admit
                it, he and I are kind of alike. But there's one big difference between me and
                   <char ref="Slade">Slade</char>.<sd>smiles</sd><charDesc ref="Slade">He doesn't have any
                    friends.</charDesc></sp>

            <sd>This lifts her spirits in an instant. Both look toward the kitchen; <directNote kind="cut">cut to a truly irked<char ref="Raven">Raven</char> at the counter</directNote>.
                Behind her, on its other side, the o.c.<char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char> is flinging food every
                which way.<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> pops up; one hand a crab claw and the other a
                tentacle, with a waffle in each.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>Who wants tofu waffles?</sp>

            <sd><char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char> stops throwing and leans in his face; throbbing vein on temple.
                   <char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> drops the waffles and returns his hands to normal.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>Man, nobody wants tofu waffles.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>I do. Pass me the soy milk!</sp>

            <sd><stageDesc category="long-shot">Long shot of the counter.</stageDesc>
               <char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char> is out of view,<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> jumps after him, and a
                scuffle breaks out as<char ref="Robin">Robin</char> and<char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char> cross to
                   <char ref="Raven">Raven</char>.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr><sd>from o.c.</sd>I'm telling you, you're not
                getting anywhere near the soy milk.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr><sd>from o.c.</sd>Man, pass me the soy
                milk!</sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="cut">Cut to the exterior of the Tower</directNote>, <directNote kind="zoom">zoomed in on the top floor</directNote>, and <directNote kind="pull">pull back slowly</directNote>.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr><sd>from inside</sd>Is there any meat in the
                tofu?</sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="dissolve">Dissolve to <stageDesc category="long-shot">a longer
                        shot</stageDesc></directNote> and <directNote kind="pull">keep pulling
                    back</directNote>.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr><sd>from inside</sd>No, there's no meat in the
                tofu, it's tofu!</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr><sd>from inside</sd>Nobody wants it.</sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="fade">Fade to black.</directNote></sd>
        </act>
    </body>
</root>