<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../schema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?><root>
    <head>
        <episode>DIVIDE AND CONQUER</episode>
        <writer>David Slack</writer>
        <director>Ciro Nieli</director>
        <storyboard>Kalvin Lee, Rafael Rosado, Alan Wan</storyboard>
        <animation>Dong Woo Animation Company, Ltd.</animation>
        <source>https://teentitans.fandom.com/wiki/Final_Exam_(Transcript)</source>
        <issueList>
            <issueInfo none="y"/>
        </issueList>
    </head>
    <characterList>
        <charList type="recurring" id="Narrator">Narrator</charList>
        <charList type="recurring" id="Headmistress" subtype="villain">Headmistress</charList>
        <charList type="recurring" id="Slade" subtype="villain">Slade</charList>
        <charList type="recurring" id="Cyborg" subtype="titan">Cyborg</charList>
        <charList type="recurring" id="BeastBoy" subtype="titan">BeastBoy</charList>
        <charList type="recurring" id="Raven" subtype="titan">Raven</charList>
        <charList type="recurring" id="Starfire" subtype="titan">Starfire</charList>
        <charList type="recurring" id="Robin" subtype="titan">Robin</charList>
        <charList type="recurring" id="Gizmo" subtype="villain">Gizmo</charList>
        <charList type="recurring" id="Mammoth" subtype="villain">Mammoth</charList>
        <charList type="recurring" id="Jinx" subtype="villain">Jinx</charList>
    </characterList>
    <body>
        <act n="0">
            <title>Prologue</title>
            <sd>Opening shot: a screenful of static, which resolves into a school crest. The field
                is hexagonal, black-and-white checkered within a gold border. A large H is
                superimposed on it in gold script; across the bottom is a white banner bearing the
                letters "H.A.E.Y.P." Behind the crest, a square corridor can be seen, with yellow
                walls, ceiling, and floor marked in a honeycomb pattern. A cool female voice begins
                to narrate.</sd>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="Narrator">Narrator</spkr>The H.I.V.E. Academy for Extraordinary Young
                People is proud to introduce...</sp>

            <sd>A platform rises into view in front of the crest, carrying three young individuals
                on it to block the crest. One is a very short, bald boy in a jumpsuit; a pair of
                goggles is propped on his forehead, and assorted controls are mounted at chest and
                waist level. Behind him is a very tall, beefy fellow with collar-length brown hair
                and a small beard. His sleeveless shirt and pants are black, and studded gold bands
                cross his chest and run around his shoulders. Off to the right of these two, our
                left, is a slim girl in an off-the-shoulder black dress trimmed with blue ruffles,
                black-and-blue striped stockings, and black platform boots with blue soles. Her
                lavender hair is bound into two large horn-like tufts that stick up above her ears,
                her catlike eyes are the same color, and her skin is an odd shade of bluish-pink. A
                small pendant hangs from a black ribbon that encircles her throat.</sd>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="Narrator">Narrator</spkr>...this year's top graduates.</sp>

            <sd>They leap from the platform; the big one and the girl drop out of the frame, and the
                camera zooms in on the runt. The big one's motion reveals studded gold
                wristbands.</sd>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="Narrator">Narrator</spkr>Gizmo, the boy genius whose intellect can
                conquer any problem with an inventive solution.</sp>

            <sd>During this line, cut to an extreme close-up of his chest control; he presses a
                button, and the camera pulls back as a pair of large metal wings sprouts from his
                back. He takes hold of the device at his waist, and the wings respond and carry him
                into the air. Lasers pop out from the wall panels and open fire against him, but he
                easily avoids all the shots and goes for another button. Now a small missile
                launcher comes up between the wings and unleashes a salvo that destroys all the guns
                with remarkable efficiency.</sd>

            <sd>
                <char ref="Gizmo">Gizmo</char> lands on the platform he and his classmates originally stood on, then glides
                away as two large robots step in from portals that open up in the walls. The girl
                takes his place.</sd>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="Narrator">Narrator</spkr>Jinx, the enchanting sorceress whose powerful
                hexes mean bad luck for her enemies.</sp>

            <sd>During this line, she extends her arms to both sides and does a 360-degree twirl,
                throwing off a wave of energy that causes a couple of wall panels to fall away. She
                leaps high off the platform, and the panels crash down on the robots' heads. Two
                others have moved in during this sequence and meet the same fate. She backflips down
                the corridor a short dittance.</sd>

            <sd>Three large laser cannons emerge from recessed panels in the floor, but the giant
                drops into view and bends its the barrel of one of them as if it were a piece of
                taffy.</sd>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="Narrator">Narrator</spkr>And<char ref="Mammoth">Mammoth</char>, the genetically enhanced giant
                whose unstoppable strength speaks for itself.</sp>

            <sd>During this line, he tears the cannon from its moorings and does an Olympic-style
                hammer throw to sling it away. It skids across the floor and wrecks the other two.
                Close-up of him, looking very pleased with himself; a robot looms up behind the
                strongman and catches him in its huge hands.<char ref="Gizmo">Gizmo</char> jumps onto its back and attaches
                a small unit. Close-up of this as it screws itself down, sending up a small puff of
                smoke, then pull back. During the next line,<char ref="Gizmo">Gizmo</char> jumps free and sparks start to
                fly from the head; he has hot-wired the thing to put it out of action.</sd>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="Narrator">Narrator</spkr>Well-organized, highly trained, and
                combat-equipped...</sp>

            <sd>
                <char ref="Mammoth">Mammoth</char> throws off the robot, which collapses, and<char ref="Gizmo">Gizmo</char> lands in a crouch near the
                camera before running off again. As the narration continues,<char ref="Jinx">Jinx</char> runs to Mammoth
                and springs up just before reaching him; he catches one foot and boosts her into a
                series of flips that carries her down the corridor.</sd>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="Narrator">Narrator</spkr>...these new H.I.V.E. agents are the perfect
                fighting force.</sp>

            <sd>She pronounces the acronym like the word "hype." Batteries of lasers emerge from
                behind the walls and cut loose against<char ref="Jinx">Jinx</char>, who continues her gymnastic advance.
                Not one shot hits her, but the positioning of the turrets on opposite walls results
                in their blowing each other to bits by the time she has reached the end of the
                gauntlet. She lands with her back to the camera, surveying her triumph, then turns
                to face front.</sd>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="Narrator">Narrator</spkr>And for the right price..<sd>
                    <char ref="Gizmo">Gizmo</char> and Mammoth
                    slide up on either side; pull back slightly.</sd>...this ideal team can be
                yours.</sp>

            <sd>The image gives way to static, which resolves into the H.I.V.E. Academy's crest
                against a dark field. A gray-haired woman steps into view; severe dark outfit with a
                hexagonal gold patch on one sleeve. This is the school's headmistress.</sd>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="Headmistress">Headmistress</spkr>Well, Mr.<char ref="Slade">Slade</char>?</sp>

            <sd>Cut to just behind her.<char ref="Slade">Slade</char>'s shadowy form stands behind a railing on a slightly
                elevated platform across the area-the same industrial machine room seen in "Divide
                and Conquer." Wisps of steam rise from the floor. This has been a sort of highlight
                reel and sales pitch that was displayed on the monitor, and her words mark the first
                time someone refers to<char ref="Slade">Slade</char> by name.</sd>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="Slade">Slade</spkr>Impressive. Truly. However, robots and obstacle
                courses only prove so much.</sp>

            <sd>Extreme close-up of his eye on the end of this, then pull back across the space to
                give a good view of it for the first time. The monitor is one of several in a row,
                and the platform on which the headmistress stands stops short of them in an
                overhang.<char ref="Slade">Slade</char>'s vantage point is at the other end. He leads her away from the
                screen and deeper into the machinery; pan to follow.</sd>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="Slade">Slade</spkr>My plans demand operatives who can function in the
                real world<sd>They step onto a catwalk.</sd>If your students are going to serve
                me...</sp>

            <sd>They reach a darkened area with two spotlights shining down from above. One pool of
                light is occupied by the three graduates; she steps into the other while he sits in
                the blackness.</sd>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="Slade">Slade</spkr>...they'll have to pass one final exam<sd>Extreme
                    close-up of his eye.</sd>Destroy the Teen Titans<sd>Pull back to frame
                all.</sd>and then we'll talk.</sp>

            <sd>The light on the trio goes out, and the headmistress bows before hers is
                extinguished as well. Only the outline of<char ref="Slade">Slade</char>'s figure and his eye are visible
                now. The remaining light source is switched off to black out the screen.</sd>


            <cue>OPENING THEME</cue>

        </act>
        <act n="1">
            <title>Act One</title>
            <sd>Opening shot: the exterior of Titans Tower during the day.</sd>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>
                <sd>from inside</sd>Aw, man, come on!</sp>

            <sd>Cut to a slow pan across the kitchen. The sink and counter are piled high with dirty
                dishes, and the floor is strewn with garbage.</sd>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>
                <sd>from o.c.</sd>It's gotta be around here someplace!</sp>

            <sd>
                <char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char>, as a bloodhound, sniffs at some of the trash as a frustrated groan is
                heard from<char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char>'s direction.</sd>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>
                <sd>from o.c.</sd>I don't believe this!</sp>

            <sd>Pull back to frame the entire operations center, in total disarray.<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> keeps
                nosing around on the floor while<char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char> hoists the couch and shakes it in search of
                whatever has been lost.<char ref="Raven">Raven</char> is reading a book at the kitchen table.</sd>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>How could you lose the remote</sp>

            <sd>
                <char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> returns to human form.</sd>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>
                <sd>rummaging</sd>What makes you so sure I lost it</sp>

            <sd>They lean into each other's faces.</sd>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>Uh...'cause you're you.</sp>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>Hey! Just because I lost that video
                game--</sp>

            <sd>Sight gag: a new shot swings into view showing both in "Super Deformed" style
                against a red field. A thought balloon is above their heads; as<char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char> mentions each
                of the next three items, it rolls by as if on a stock ticker, is marked with a red
                X, and disappears.<char ref="Raven">Raven</char> also appears sitting on the couch.</sd>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>--And the toothpaste, and my football, and the
                waffle iron-</sp>

            <sd>Sight gag ends; close-up of<char ref="Raven">Raven</char>.</sd>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>
                <sd>from o.c.</sd>Things disappear. How am I supposed to know where they go?</sp>

            <sd>She lowers her book on this line to give the camera a good look at the annoyance in
                her eyes. During the next one, a vein starts to throb in her temple.</sd>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>
                <sd>from o.c.</sd>Well, how am I supposed to watch TV without a remote</sp>

            <sd>
                <char ref="Raven">Raven</char> slams her book shut and stands up.</sd>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="Raven">Raven</spkr>
                <sd>icily</sd>Simple. You just get up and change the channel.</sp>

            <sd>The two squabbling boys give her and each other a very long and puzzled look.</sd>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>Don't even joke like that</sp>

            <sd>Back to<char ref="Raven">Raven</char>.</sd>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="Raven">Raven</spkr>I wasn't joking.</sp>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>
                <sd>from o.c.</sd>Good, 'cause it wasn't funny! Now either help us look for the
                    remote<sd>She grimaces; angry spark by her head.</sd>or go back to your nasty
                old book and--</sp>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="Raven">Raven</spkr>
                <sd>over end of previous line, face flushing</sd>This is a pointless argument over a
                useless device.</sp>

            <sd>A big drop of sweat appears on her temple briefly as she says this. Her face returns
                to its normal color as she walks o.c.</sd>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="Raven">Raven</spkr>
                <sd>from o.c.</sd>You are wasting your energy and disrupting my concentration</sp>

            <sd>The side door behind her opens to show<char ref="Robin">Robin</char> and<char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char>.</sd>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>
                <sd>from o.c.</sd>I'm telling you, I didn't lose it! You were the one watching TV
                last!</sp>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr>
                <sd>to<char ref="Robin">Robin</char>, over the previous line</sd>And that is the secret to traveling faster
                than light.</sp>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>
                <sd>from o.c.</sd>So if you want to blame someone<sd>
                    <char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char> gasps; Robin
                    stares.</sd>look in the mirror, buddy!</sp>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>
                <sd>over the end of the previous line</sd>Whoa! Take it easy, Titans! Combat
                practice is this afternoon!</sp>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr>We must mend your dispute by the sharing of
                unhealthy junk foods. I shall fetch them</sp>

            <sd>Both cross the room.</sd>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>
                <sd>from o.c.</sd>I don't need food, what I need is a time machine, I didn't--</sp>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>Back me up here,<char ref="Robin">Robin</char>!! Have I ever lost
                any--?</sp>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>
                <sd>from o.c</sd>Okay! Okay</sp>

            <sd>whistles</sd>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>To stop him from taking the REMOTE!!!</sp>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>
                <sd>from o.c</sd>Hey! Come on!! Settle down! ENOUGH!!!</sp>

            <sd>Snap to black, accompanied by louder arguing from all but<char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char>. The view
                resolves into the inside of the refrigerator as she opens it to look in. There is a
                jumble of half-eaten leftovers, all covered with a thick layer of blue mold; this
                thing has not been cleaned out in who knows how long. Her perspective of the mess,
                tilting down from top shelf to bottom. The growth on a wheel of cheese starts to
                move and screech. Pull back out of the fridge;<char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char> shrieks in alarm and throws
                a starbolt, blowing up everything inside and splattering blue crud throughout the
                operations center. Tilt down from the ceiling to four Titans who have just had the
                living daylights scared out of them, not to mention a healthy dose of the mold
                dripped on their heads.</sd>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>Maybe we should just go out for pizza.</sp>

            <sd>Wipe to an overhead view of a pizza joint in the heart of Jump City. It is built at
                the intersection of two streets at an acute angle, with a second-story patio that
                takes advantage of this detail. The floor's coloring and the placement of tables
                makes this entire affair look like a huge slice of pepperoni. Zoom in slowly to the
                sound of arguing from four Titans, then cut to the group's table; all have cleaned
                up from the fridge blowout.<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> squats on his stool instead of sitting. When
                the dispute over toppings finally stops,<char ref="Raven">Raven</char> speaks up; she is the only one who
                did not take part in it.</sd>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="Raven">Raven</spkr>Can we please just order something?</sp>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>As long as it's vegetarian.</sp>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>Come on, man, how can you deny me the all-meat
                experience?</sp>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>
                <sd>offended</sd>Dude, I've been most of those animals!</sp>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr>I suggest a large pizza with pickles, bananas,
                and mint frosting.</sp>

            <sd>She beams at her suggestion, but<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> is visibly repulsed by the combination,
                and<char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char> and<char ref="Raven">Raven</char> think just as little of it, as we see when they slide into view
                next to him.<char ref="Robin">Robin</char> leans over to her.</sd>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>Uh,<char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char>? Not everything on the menu is a pizza
                topping.</sp>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr>Oh!</sp>

            <sd>She blushes over the gaffe she has made. Cut to an overhead view of the table, seen
                through a set of green lenses.</sd>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>Double pepperoni!</sp>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>I'm not eating meat!</sp>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>There's no meat in pepperoni!</sp>

            <sd>The argument begins anew as crosshairs appear on each Titan's head. At the bottom of
                the view, the words "INITIATE MISSION" flash red.<char ref="Gizmo">Gizmo</char>'s voice is heard; this is
                his perspective, spying on the group.</sd>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="Gizmo">Gizmo</spkr>Gizmo to<char ref="Jinx">Jinx</char>.</sp>

            <sd>Cut to her, standing next to a parked bus and with a hand cupped to her ear: she is
                receiving his transmission on a hidden radio.</sd>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="Gizmo">Gizmo</spkr>
                <sd>over the radio</sd>Begin Phase One.</sp>

            <sd>She carelessly tosses a spell at the bus, causing it to start rolling downhill. Back
                to the pizza joint; as the vehicle's horn blares from down the street, the Titans
                stand up from the table. The sound of a baby crying from ground level elicits a
                shocked gasp from<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char>. Cut to the source, a carriage in the crosswalk, and
                tilt up to show the bus on a collision course.</sd>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>Titans! Go!</sp>

            <sd>They immediately spring into action while the bus keeps bearing down on the
                crosswalk.<char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char> pushes the carriage out of the way, and<char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char> and<char ref="Raven">Raven</char> plant
                themselves in the vehicle's path. When the bus reaches him, he pushes back against
                the front fender to slow it down. Close-up of his feet grinding against the
                pavement, then of<char ref="Raven">Raven</char> as she casts a spell, then of the bus' gearshift lever. It
                is in neutral, but under her influence it slides into park. From here, cut to a
                close-up of one tire, which stops spinning and goes into a tearing skid, then pull
                back.<char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char> has finally brought the thing to a stop with only a foot or two to
                spare between him and<char ref="Raven">Raven</char>. The doors have come open, revealing an empty driver's
                seat. He straightens himself up.</sd>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>Um...don't buses normally have drivers?</sp>

            <sd>Pull back.<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> and<char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char> look on, while<char ref="Robin">Robin</char> is peering into the carriage,
                whose back is to the camera. He too straightens up.</sd>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>And don't baby carriages normally have babies?</sp>

            <sd>The two Titans near him look in as well. His perspective: he is holding a teddy bear
                that had been taking the place of the typical occupant. Its eyes are green, the same
                color as the lenses of<char ref="Gizmo">Gizmo</char>'s goggles, and his voice is heard next. This was the
                source of the crying as well.</sd>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="Gizmo">Gizmo</spkr>
                <sd>over a hidden speaker</sd>Are you pit-sniffers normally this stupid?</sp>

            <sd>The bear's head swivels slightly toward the camera on the end of this, and the eyes
                suddenly glow and fire laser beams. Pull back;<char ref="Robin">Robin</char>,<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char>, and<char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char> are
                projected screaming through the air as a result of the hit, with smoke trailing
                behind them. Tilt down to<char ref="Raven">Raven</char> and<char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char>, still standing in front of the bus,
                which suddenly seems to tilt back onto its rear wheels of its own volition. They
                look up, completely flabbergasted as the shadow falls over them, and the camera
                pulls back to show the reason for the spontaneous wheelie.<char ref="Mammoth">Mammoth</char> has seized the
                rear bumper and levered the mode of mass transit into the air, and he brings it down
                on top of the two. As the dust clears, he walks forward and brushes dust from his
                hands, and<char ref="Gizmo">Gizmo</char>'s nasty laughter is heard. He and<char ref="Jinx">Jinx</char> step into view just in front
                of the camera, which has backed up to ground level.</sd>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="Gizmo">Gizmo</spkr>
                <sd>from o.c.</sd>That was too easy<sd>Cut to these two.</sd>What a buncha
                cludge-heads. You guys want to get pizza?</sp>

            <sd>Quick pan to<char ref="Robin">Robin</char>,<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char>, and<char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char>, who have ended up in an alley, on the
                next line.<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> is in a trash can, with a banana peel on his head.</sd>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>This isn't over!</sp>

            <sd>He dusts himself off a bit. Back to<char ref="Mammoth">Mammoth</char> and the bus, which, without warning,
                gets blasted to one side.<char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char>'s sonic cannon, protruding from a hole in the
                ground, is revealed as the driving force.</sd>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>
                <sd>standing up from the hole</sd>We're just getting started!</sp>

            <sd>A bird-shaped shadow looms up behind him. It resolves into<char ref="Raven">Raven</char> as she brings her
                arms back in and wraps her cloak around herself.</sd>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>Who are these guys<sd>A question mark appears
                    by his head.</sd>And what's a cludge-head?</sp>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="Gizmo">Gizmo</spkr>We are the H.I.V.E.!</sp>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="Mammoth">Mammoth</spkr>Your worst nightmare!</sp>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="Jinx">Jinx</spkr>And this is Attack Pattern Alpha!</sp>

            <sd>She and<char ref="Mammoth">Mammoth</char> scramble, and a jet pack on<char ref="Gizmo">Gizmo</char>'s back carries him into the air.
                He fires a volley of laser shots at the alley, chipping loose large hunks of masonry
                so that they fall on the three Titans. Cut to<char ref="Raven">Raven</char> and<char ref="Jinx">Jinx</char> in close quarters
                spell-to-spell combat, then pan to the grappling<char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char> and<char ref="Mammoth">Mammoth</char>. The H.I.V.E.
                alumnus is pushed back down the street at<char ref="Robin">Robin</char> and company emerge from the
                rockslide<char ref="Gizmo">Gizmo</char> set off.</sd>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="Mammoth">Mammoth</spkr>What do you call an idiot with a rocket on his
                back?</sp>

            <sd>
                <char ref="Gizmo">Gizmo</char> zooms over and sticks one between<char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char>'s shoulder blades.</sd>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>Huh?</sp>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="Gizmo">Gizmo</spkr>Doomed!</sp>

            <sd>He gets clear and touches a control; igniting the rocket and sending<char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char> veering
                crazily over the buildings.<char ref="Robin">Robin</char>,<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char>, and<char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char> watch from the alley as
                his yells of panic drift down to them. She gasps.</sd>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr>Cyborg!</sp>

            <sd>She takes off to catch up with him, but a sudden change in direction throws her off.
                Tilt down from the sky to<char ref="Raven">Raven</char>;<char ref="Jinx">Jinx</char> comes at her with a jumping spin kick, but she
                ducks away and gets behind the funny-haired sorceress. Dodging two more strikes,
               <char ref="Raven">Raven</char> counters with a backhand. Close-up of<char ref="Jinx">Jinx</char> as she blocks it.</sd>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="Jinx">Jinx</spkr>You fight like a boy</sp>

            <sd>Tilt up;<char ref="Gizmo">Gizmo</char> is overhead, now balanced on four tall spider-like legs.</sd>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="Gizmo">Gizmo</spkr>And you're gonna croak like a frog!</sp>

            <sd>The contraption fires a blast that hurls her down the street and squarely into the
                charging<char ref="Robin">Robin</char>.<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> passes them both; close-up of him.</sd>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>Hah!</sp>

            <sd>He turns into an elephant ad continues his rush, but stops short suddenly at the
                sound of grunting from<char ref="Mammoth">Mammoth</char>. Pull back to show that the big lummox has lifted him
                clean off his feet; his fellow graduates are watching.</sd>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="Mammoth">Mammoth</spkr>Mammoth's gonna make you extinct</sp>

            <sd>Back to<char ref="Robin">Robin</char> and<char ref="Raven">Raven</char>, on the ground.</sd>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>
                <sd>getting up and charging</sd>Beast Boy! Hang on!</sp>

            <sd>
                <char ref="Mammoth">Mammoth</char> throws the green elephant straight up into the air and hits it with a
                jumping punch on the way down.<char ref="Robin">Robin</char> suddenly finds himself directly in the path of
                his teammate, who changes back to human form just before slamming into him. They
                skid to a stop near<char ref="Raven">Raven</char>.</sd>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>Is it me, or are we getting our butts
                kicked</sp>

            <sd>The others stand up.</sd>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="Robin Raven">Robin and Raven</spkr>
                <sd>in unison</sd>It's just you.</sp>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>Listen up, team. I have a plan.</sp>

            <sd>Two of<char ref="Gizmo">Gizmo</char>'s shots flash into view and send<char ref="Raven">Raven</char> and<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> flying. Robin
                manages to get out of the way; they end up almost a block away.</sd>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="Gizmo">Gizmo</spkr>
                <sd>from o.c.</sd>Gee, scrum-buffer<sd>Cut to the H.I.V.E. team; he is back on the
                    ground.</sd>Sure hope your fancy plan includes getting fried!</sp>

            <sd>The weapon that fired those shots is poking over his shoulder. It levels itself at
               <char ref="Robin">Robin</char>, who stands his ground.</sd>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>You'll just have to find out the hard way.</sp>

            <sd>He takes up a fighting stance, holding one hand out with its back to the trio, and
                flicks the fingers toward himself: "bring it on." The shoulder-mounted laser zeroes
                in and fires a shot, and the camera cuts to the point of impact on the street and
                starts to pull back quickly. A long crack opens in the asphalt ahead of the strike;
               <char ref="Jinx">Jinx</char> leaps backward into view, landing on her knees, and throws a spell that breaks
                the fissure wider. Tilt up from her to<char ref="Mammoth">Mammoth</char>, who leaps in with a mighty yell and
                brings all his weight down on the fault line. Pull back to an overhead view to
                reveal that the net effect of this three-way combo has been to open a very wide
                chasm, which runs straight down the middle of the road toward<char ref="Robin">Robin</char>. Cut to this; he
                tumbles screaming into the darkness beneath Jump City and is lost to our eyes.</sd>

            <sd>Shift to just beneath the road surface, looking out past the edge of the massive
                fracture zone.<char ref="Raven">Raven</char> and<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> arrive at the scene, and the camera dissolves to
                a longer shot of them while pulling back slowly to the surface of the murky tide
                that flows down here. The Titans' leader is nowhere to be seen in the murky tide.
                Close-up of the two.</sd>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>Robin!</sp>

            <sd>Fade to black.</sd>

        </act>
        <act n="2">
            <title>Act Two</title>
            <sd>Opening shot: the exterior of the Tower. A door is heard moving; inside, on the
                ground floor, the main entrance is opening. Tilt down from the upper threshold to
                show two figures entering, silhouetted against the sunlight;<char ref="Raven">Raven</char> and<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char>. He
                is limping somewhat and leaning against her for support. Cut to them and pan to
                follow their movement as the door is heard closing. The entrance hall has armchairs
                along both walls.</sd>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>That didn't just happen<sd>She helps him into
                    a chair; he rubs his leg.</sd>Tell me that didn't just happen.</sp>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="Raven">Raven</spkr>It did happen. We cannot change the truth, no matter
                how much we dislike it.</sp>

            <sd>She holds her hands near the injured leg; a brief glow of healing energy envelops
                them.</sd>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>
                <sd>smiling</sd>Who knew we had a doctor in the house? Thanks.</sp>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="Raven">Raven</spkr>No problem.</sp>

            <sd>The door has closed, but it now opens again, and the two trade a very nervous look
                before<char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char> and<char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char> walk in with ear-to-ear smiles. He no longer has Gizmo's
                rocket stuck to his back. The door closes on his next line.</sd>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>Maybe y'all should call me Flyborg. I was halfway
                to Gotham City before Star zapped that thing off my back. So what'd I miss?</sp>

            <sd>
                <char ref="Raven">Raven</char> cannot meet his eyes; neither can<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> when the camera pans to him.</sd>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>Tell me how we kicked their butts. Come on, I gotta
                have the play-by-play.</sp>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr>Where is Robin</sp>

            <sd>Cut to<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char>.</sd>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>Um, Star? We're not sure.</sp>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr>
                <sd>from o.c.</sd>Not sure<sd>Back to her.</sd>Why are you not--?</sp>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="Raven">Raven</spkr>We searched everywhere<sd>Cut to her waist
                    level.</sd>And all we found was this.</sp>

            <sd>She produces his utility belt from beneath her cloak.<char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char> gasps in horror;
               <char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char> groans and claps both hands to his forehead.</sd>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>I shoulda been there. I let that kid sneak up on me
                and, what was I--? It was a trap, and I-- I shoulda known.</sp>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr>I do not understand<sd>Cut to<char ref="Raven">Raven</char> and Beast
                    Boy; she continues o.c.</sd>How could you not find him<sd>Pull back; she looks
                    straight at<char ref="Raven">Raven</char>.</sd>People do not just vanish! He has to be someplace, so go
                there and look!</sp>

            <sd>
                <char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> puts himself between the two girls to keep things from getting ugly.</sd>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>Easy, Star. Come on. This is<char ref="Robin">Robin</char> we're
                talking about. I'm sure he's fine. He'll probably turn up any second.</sp>

            <sd>Pull back to frame the entire group; the door mechanism kicks into gear once
                more.</sd>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>Awesome timing.</sp>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr>Robin!</sp>

            <sd>She flies toward the door; cut to it as she lands there. It has not yet opened, and
                she walks toward the threshold to see who has arrived. A moment later, the whole
                entrance disappears in a mighty crash that throws her backward. The dust clears to
                show the H.I.V.E. team walking in;<char ref="Gizmo">Gizmo</char> is back up on his mechanical spider
                legs.</sd>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>Oh, no</sp>

            <sd>
                <char ref="Mammoth">Mammoth</char> cracks his knuckles.</sd>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="Jinx">Jinx</spkr>Oh, yes</sp>

            <sd>The four Titans get ready to fight.</sd>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>You guys got lucky last time, but you're in our
                house now</sp>

            <sd>The trio advances.</sd>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="Gizmo">Gizmo</spkr>Yeah, nice place. We'll take it!</sp>

            <sd>By now, they have moved close enough to the camera to frame<char ref="Jinx">Jinx</char>'s face in extreme
                close-up. From here, cut to a corner of the hall, which is promptly lost under the
                glare and dust cloud of a large o.c. explosion. When the view clears,<char ref="Raven">Raven</char> is
                levitating chairs and sending them in the H.I.V.E.'s direction, while Starfire
                tosses off some starbolts from overhead.<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> tumbles into view and clambers
                away to make room for<char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char>; tilt up to his head level as he backs up again, firing
                his cannon.</sd>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>Split up!</sp>

            <sd>
                <char ref="Raven">Raven</char> flies to a landing on the stairs and, after<char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char> passes her, projects a
                couple of nearby fire extinguishers toward<char ref="Mammoth">Mammoth</char> at the bottom. He merely swats
                them away and charges. Cut to a hall, where<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> runs into view from around a
                corner and dodges the collapse of several wall panels. Emerging fro the dust and
                debris as a bobcat, he runs o.c; when the view clears,<char ref="Jinx">Jinx</char> steps unhurriedly after
                him, she caused the panels to fall.</sd>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="Jinx">Jinx</spkr>Here, kitty, kitty. What's the matter<sd>More panels
                    blow out.</sd>Afraid of a little bad luck?</sp>

            <sd>Cut to inside the gym.<char ref="Raven">Raven</char> and<char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char> burst through the closed doors and slam
                them shut again. A starbolt is fired against the frame and traced along the doors'
                outer edges to weld them closed. The two girls then back up a bit and trade a very
                nervous look, wondering whether the barricade will hold. It proves to be a moot
                point when the wall behind them blows out, throwing them to the floor. They look
                back toward it and find<char ref="Mammoth">Mammoth</char>'s head protruding from a fresh hole: he just
                delivered a mother of a headbutt.</sd>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="Mammoth">Mammoth</spkr>Hello, ladies.</sp>

            <sd>The stairs again.<char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char> retreats upward as one of<char ref="Gizmo">Gizmo</char>'s long metal legs swings
                into view near the camera. Cut to a hall in which the runt's spidery shadow advances
                into view against the far wall, followed by the runt himself. He turns and
                approaches the camera; cut to inside a door, which opens to admit him.<char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char> peeks
                out from a corner across the hall, nips over, and peers in carefully after<char ref="Gizmo">Gizmo</char>.
                Pull back; he steps in boldly. Except for the light spilling from the hall, the
                place is completely dark. The blackness becomes total when the door slides shut
                without warning.</sd>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>Hey!</sp>

            <sd>A wall of TV screens comes to life, every one showing a close-up of<char ref="Gizmo">Gizmo</char>'s grinning
                visage.</sd>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="Gizmo">Gizmo</spkr>
                <sd>from all screens</sd>So, Tin Man, you got a heart under all that outdated
                crud-ware?</sp>

            <sd>He turns away, but a single giant screen, also showing<char ref="Gizmo">Gizmo</char>, comes on next to
                him.</sd>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="Gizmo">Gizmo</spkr>Not telling<sd>Pull back to frame them all.</sd>
                Guess I'll have to take you apart and find out!</sp>

            <sd>Tilt up to the ceiling on the end of this. The whiz kid's spider legs carry him into
                the light from those screens and lower him steadily toward<char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char>, who can only
                stare in complete shock. Cut to yet another hall;<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char>, back in human form,
                races around the corner and into view. Seeing no one behind him, he stops to catch
                his breath.</sd>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>Lost her.</sp>

            <sd>He is, of course, referring to<char ref="Jinx">Jinx</char>, and he has spoken too soon. A couple of her
                spells pass just over his head, and the camera tilts up to show them hitting the
                ceiling there. A panel swings loose and cracks him dead in the face. His head
                rattles on his neck for a moment before he collapses; she walks up behind him.</sd>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="Jinx">Jinx</spkr>This just isn't your lucky day.</sp>

            <sd>He sits rubbing his head for a second before transforming into a tyrannosaurus rex
                and roaring with enough force to shake the entire building.<char ref="Jinx">Jinx</char> does a few
                backflips to get out of range, then stops and fixes a glowing stare on him. Around
                the green reptile, a ring of pink fire flares up briefly and floats toward his head
                before disappearing. There is a loud crackling from the floor, followed by the
                collapse of the section on which<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> is standing due to her hex; he drops from
                sight. Cut to below floor level, the camera pointing up out of the hole, as she
                walks up to it and smiles.</sd>

            <sd>Now we see a storage area of the Tower, with a large circular hatchway in the back
                wall. This is smashed off its hinges by<char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char>, who emerges into this place
                unscathed. He is not alone; however;<char ref="Gizmo">Gizmo</char> comes out of the dust clouds and moves in
                on him.<char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char> steadily backs up before the advance; one of the metal legs swings at
                him, but he catches the end in both hands.</sd>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>Gotcha!</sp>

            <sd>
                <char ref="Gizmo">Gizmo</char> just grins and swings another leg.<char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char> shifts his grip to free up one hand
                and catch this one as well. A good strong wrenching motion throws the little jerk
                off balance and sends him to the floor; when he hits, sparks fly from the central
                unit on his back. He is quickly yanked free of the legs and held aloft by the
                chuckling Titan. The unit is still on his back, but it is soon pulled off.</sd>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="Gizmo">Gizmo</spkr>Let me go, you scuzz-munching zit!</sp>

            <sd>During this line,<char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char> puts him down so he can run away and then crushes the
                device. The big guy tosses the remains aside like a candy wrapper.<char ref="Gizmo">Gizmo</char> runs off
                among the crates and boxes; now<char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char> walks after him at a leisurely pace.</sd>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>How you gonna fight me without your tech?</sp>

            <sd>A small, shadowy figure passes in front of him, and he goes after it. Close-up of
               <char ref="Gizmo">Gizmo</char>, peeking out from behind a panel; he gasps as it is lifted away. Cut to a very
                pleased<char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char>, who suddenly looks down with surprise at the sound of a crunch.</sd>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>Huh?</sp>

            <sd>Cut to floor level. His foot has come down on a flashlight-like unit and damaged it
                somewhat. Looking up again, he sees<char ref="Gizmo">Gizmo</char>'s image grin and then flicker out; it was
                merely a hologram projected by that unit.<char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char> backs cautiously away; the real
               <char ref="Gizmo">Gizmo</char> is perched on a piece of equipment behind him, and he jumps down onto the back
                and pulls out a tool. Sparks fly.</sd>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>Yo, what are you--?</sp>

            <sd>Close-up of his back. The gadget genius pops open a panel and goes to work on the
                circuitry.</sd>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>
                <sd>strained</sd>Get out of my systems! Nobody hacks my systems!</sp>

            <sd>He runs back and forth, clearly against his will due to the hotwiring, then stops as
                his limbs start to flail randomly. His right arm is raised.</sd>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="Gizmo">Gizmo</spkr>Ooh, ejector arm. Cool!</sp>

            <sd>He makes it pop off-hand, forearm, and half the upper arm. Close-up: it rolls
                uselessly away across the floor. Tilt up to the shadows of the two combatants
                projected against the far wall.</sd>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>
                <sd>from o.c.</sd>My arm!</sp>

            <sd>Cut to the exterior of the Tower, which shakes and bends as the fight inside
                continues. It is now later in the day.</sd>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>
                <sd>from inside</sd>Get off! Get off me! Stop!</sp>

            <sd>He flies screaming off the roof as if shot from a cannon, and the camera pulls back
                a distance as he comes down in the middle of Jump City Bay. Another set of yells and
                three more splashes mark the forcible eviction of<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char>,<char ref="Raven">Raven</char>, and<char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char>.
                Back to the long shot of the Tower and zoom in; the H.I.V.E. team can be seen
                looking out from the top-floor window of the operations center. Zoom in and cut to
                them.</sd>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="Gizmo">Gizmo</spkr>Have a nice afterlife, you snot-eating losers!</sp>

            <sd>
                <char ref="Jinx">Jinx</char> casts a spell; cut to the Tower exterior and tilt down to the water level as it
                radiates over the island. The hex stirs up a huge tidal wave that leaves the
                foursome too scared to move as its shadow falls over them. Down comes the wall of
                water, and back goes the camera to the H.I.V.E. operatives, who smile smugly and
                walk away.</sd>

            <sd>Dissolve to the sky and tilt down to the bridge across the bay. Two seagulls are
                perched on pilings near the camera. The next ten lines, all delivered in voice over,
                echo slightly.</sd>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>That didn't just happen. Tell me that didn't
                just happen.</sp>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>Get out of my systems<sd>The seagulls fly
                    away.</sd>Get off me.</sp>

            <sd>Dissolve to a close-up of a soda can washing up on the shore. Now the spoken words
                start to overlap.</sd>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr>Robin. Where is<char ref="Robin">Robin</char>? I do not
                understand.</sp>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>Gotta go out for the others</sp>

            <sd>Long shot of the Tower and the bridge.</sd>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="Raven">Raven</spkr>We searched everywhere</sp>

            <sd>Tilt down slowly to the shore.</sd>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr>How could you not find him?</sp>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="Raven">Raven</spkr>All we found was this</sp>

            <sd>
                <char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char> makes his way up the slope.</sd>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr>People do not just vanish.</sp>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>Oh, no.</sp>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>I shoulda been there. I shoulda known.</sp>

            <sd>Pull back from him to put the other three Titans in view as they approach.</sd>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>So, uh...who else never wants to go surfing
                again?</sp>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>
                <sd>really annoyed</sd>Not now, man.</sp>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>Hey, I was just trying to--</sp>

            <sd>
                <char ref="Raven">Raven</char> puts a hand on his shoulder to cut him off.<char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char> extends a small acetylene
                torch from his left forefinger. The panel on his thigh opens, revealing a plethora
                of sparks and short circuits. Pull back to behind him;<char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char> approaches as he
                bends down to the self-repair work.</sd>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr>Perhaps I could be of some assistance.</sp>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>I got it.</sp>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr>But you are so damaged and--</sp>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>
                <sd>rounding on her; she gasps</sd>I got it!</sp>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>Hey! She only wanted to help! What is your
                problem?</sp>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>What do you think<sd>Long shot of them and the
                    Tower.</sd>We got kicked out of our house, a pint-size Poindexter took me for a
                joyride, and in case you haven't noticed, I just became left-handed!</sp>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="Raven">Raven</spkr>Enough! We need to control our emotions.</sp>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>Or what? Our bad vibes will keep you from
                meditating</sp>

            <sd>Cut to<char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char>.</sd>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr>I wish<char ref="Robin">Robin</char> were here.</sp>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>
                <sd>from o.c.</sd>Well, he's not<sd>Pull back to frame them all.</sd>Don't you guys
                get it? They won, we lost. IT"S OVER!!</sp>

            <sd>Cut to a patch of water and pan slowly to the shore. The four heroes stand slumped
                in defeat.</sd>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>Then...the Teen Titans are finished?</sp>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>
                <sd>from o.c.</sd>Not yet.</sp>

            <sd>His voice draws four very surprised glances over four assorted pairs of shoulders.
                Pan quickly in that direction to show him standing in front of some bushes; arms
                crossed, confident smile, cape waving in the breeze. Except for his missing belt,
                everything is in proper order. Dissolve to a close-up of his chest and tilt up to
                his face.</sd>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>Not if I can help it.</sp>

            <sd>Fade to black.</sd>

        </act>
        <act n="3">
            <title>Act Three</title>
            <sd>Opening shot: the exterior of the Tower that night. The new occupants have started
                extensive renovations to the place, as follows. One, the vertical bar of the T has
                been extended. Two, the lights in one half of the crossbar top floor have been put
                out. Three, a second vertical portion has been built to join with the half that is
                still lit; it reaches the same height as the central extension. The entire effect is
                to make the lighted Tower portions and new construction look like a giant H for
                H.I.V.E., and the honeycomb pattern has been applied to the add-ons.</sd>

            <sd>Zoom in on the Tower, then cut to inside.<char ref="Gizmo">Gizmo</char>'s hands reach into view, thumbs and
                forefingers extended to make a box in which he is framing a patch of blank wall.
                This is his perspective. Two small robots whiz into view, carrying<char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char>'s detached
                arm-mounted as if it were a stuffed fish, between them, and follow his instructions
                as they hang it up.</sd>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="Gizmo">Gizmo</spkr>Higher...a little to the left...a little
                    more...and..<sd>take his hands down and gives a thumbs-up</sd>...perfect!</sp>

            <sd>Pull back across the room and down to ground level to put him in view. The arm is
                mounted high on the wall.</sd>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="Gizmo">Gizmo</spkr>
                <sd>walking away</sd>Slade's gonna have kittens when he hears we whipped the Titans
                and took their stinking Tower!</sp>

            <sd>On the end of this, cut to the kitchen as he passes it.<char ref="Mammoth">Mammoth</char> looks in the fridge,
                while<char ref="Jinx">Jinx</char> comes down the stairs. Close-up of her; she has donned<char ref="Robin">Robin</char>'s belt,
                which sits askew on her hips similar to the way<char ref="Raven">Raven</char> wears hers, and has one of the
                latter's spare cloaks over her arm.</sd>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="Jinx">Jinx</spkr>Not to mention<char ref="Robin">Robin</char>'s favorite fashion
                    statement<sd>She eyes the cloak and sighs with contempt.</sd>But that's the only
                thing fashionable around here</sp>

            <sd>Pull back to put<char ref="Mammoth">Mammoth</char> in view.</sd>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="Mammoth">Mammoth</spkr>Tell me about it<sd>He pulls a moldy hamburger
                    from the fridge.</sd>Hmph. All their food is way out of date.</sp>

            <sd>This does not stop him from downing the burger in one gulp.</sd>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="Gizmo">Gizmo</spkr>
                <sd>from o.c.</sd>You think that stuff's rotten<sd>Cut to him in the operations
                    center; he holds up a CD.</sd>Wait 'til you see their music<sd>tossing it aside,
                    then another</sd>Crud...snot...</sp>

            <sd>Dissolve to the mounted arm and zoom in slowly, then dissolve to an extreme close-up
                of the middle finger and keep zooming in.</sd>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="Gizmo">Gizmo</spkr>
                <sd>from o.c., sighing</sd>...mega-crud...snot...</sp>

            <sd>The fingertip pulls loose of the hand, remaining connected to it by two thin jointed
                armatures. It swivels to point its open and at us and reveals a tiny camera lens
                inside. A brief change in focus, and it turns to point elsewhere. Camera eye: it is
                zooming in on<char ref="Jinx">Jinx</char>, who has put on<char ref="Raven">Raven</char>'s cloak.</sd>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="Jinx">Jinx</spkr>Does she have anything that's not blue?</sp>

            <sd>Pan to<char ref="Mammoth">Mammoth</char>, now gorging himself on the spoiled food in the fridge, then move
                quickly to<char ref="Gizmo">Gizmo</char> at the CD rack in the operations center. The ones he hated are
                strewn about the floor behind him. The tiny camera roves on, stopping at one of the
                computer consoles.</sd>

            <sd>Normal view:<char ref="Jinx">Jinx</char> inspecting herself with a hand mirror. The arm scuttles into view,
                walking on its fingers with the camera still active, and turns here and there to
                scope out the place. Finally, it moves toward us; cut to an extreme close-up of
               <char ref="Mammoth">Mammoth</char> as he eagerly lifts a moldy chicken drumstick to his mouth and licks it. The
                arm makes is way along a ledge on the far side of the kitchen while he eats the meat
                off the bone.</sd>

            <sd>Back to<char ref="Gizmo">Gizmo</char>, who has yet another CD in hand.</sd>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="Gizmo">Gizmo</spkr>
                <sd>throwing it and the next one away</sd>Ugh. Crud...snot...</sp>

            <sd>The arm moves along the ledge behind him and is not noticed. It stops near one of
                the consoles and points its camera around the area before jumping down into the
                seat. Close-up of it, then pull back; thin tentacles fly out from the joint where
                the limb connected to the stump of<char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char>'s natural arm. They press several keys,
                and the view cuts to an overhead shot of the keyboard as they go to work and the
                screen lights up with a schematic of the Tower. Piece by piece, the diagram goes
                red. When it has all turned this color, the screen winks out and alarms and buzzers
                start to sound, accompanied by red flashing lights throughout the operations center.
                The security systems have been triggered.</sd>

            <sd>
                <char ref="Jinx">Jinx</char> gasps and throws the cloak aside, and<char ref="Mammoth">Mammoth</char> stands up from the fridge. All
                the cabinet doors in the kitchen start opening and closing at random. Next, Gizmo
                stands up from the CD rack; without warning, one disc after another is ejected past
                him at high speed.</sd>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="Gizmo">Gizmo</spkr>Hey!</sp>

            <sd>This is the only intelligible word he gets out before trailing off into surprised
                yells and losing his balance to tumble on the floor. He slides backward as the rack
                continues its impression of a skeet-shooting target launcher.</sd>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="Gizmo">Gizmo</spkr>What the hairball?</sp>

            <sd>The chair of the nearest console swivels to give him a good look at the arm
                occupying it; he cries out in surprise and fear. The tentacles have retracted, but
                now, they shoot forth again and wrap around his arms and legs. The bionic limb jumps
                down and speeds across the floor, dragging one very surprised pipsqueak, and pops a
                couple of small jet thrusters out from the forearm. These ignite and carry it into
                the air; the hand balls into a fist as the thing aims itself toward the ceiling and
                carries<char ref="Gizmo">Gizmo</char> up with it.</sd>

            <sd>Long shot of a ceiling air vent. The arm closes in on it and punches through; cut to
                inside the ductwork as it races along and takes<char ref="Gizmo">Gizmo</char> for one very wild ride and out
                of sight around a bend. Back in the kitchen, a large shadowy hand reaches down
                behind<char ref="Jinx">Jinx</char> and seizes her. She has time for one startled cry before it recedes into
                the ceiling and takes her with it; the sort of thing only<char ref="Raven">Raven</char> could do. The big
                lug is left standing by himself; the side door opens on its own, and a starbolt
                rockets into view from the left side of the screen to knock him through it. Starfire
                has made it into the Tower. The door closes.</sd>

            <sd>Cut to the exterior of the Tower, at roof level, and zoom in before dissolving to
                the surface. A large black raven emerges from the surface and rises o.c., leaving
               <char ref="Jinx">Jinx</char> there to drop to her knees. We have just witnessed<char ref="Raven">Raven</char>'s "soul-self" at work;
                a projection that can carry individuals from one place to another. Behind<char ref="Jinx">Jinx</char>,
               <char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char>'s arm bursts out of a vent pipe and carries the screaming<char ref="Gizmo">Gizmo</char> higher and
                higher before veering back toward his classmate. Zoom in to an extreme close-up of
                her face as she gasps in shock and her eyes widen-just before she is hit head-on and
                both roll halfway across the roof. Having released<char ref="Gizmo">Gizmo</char>, the arm flies away, and
                the closed door of the stairs or elevator leading up here slide open. A green flash
                of a starbolt plays across the screen, and<char ref="Mammoth">Mammoth</char> is blasted out onto the roof. He
                ends up next to the other two H.I.V.E. agents.</sd>

            <sd>Close-up of<char ref="Robin">Robin</char>'s upraised hand; his belt lands neatly in it.</sd>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>
                <sd>from o.c.</sd>Sorry to interrupt the victory celebration<sd>Cut to his waist
                    level; he fastens it.</sd>But like I said..<sd>Head level.</sd>...this isn't
                over.</sp>

            <sd>Pull back.<char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char> is there, reattaching his arm, and the other three Titans soon
                arrive.</sd>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>It's just getting started</sp>

            <sd>The trio stands up.</sd>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="Jinx">Jinx</spkr>Attack Pattern Alpha!</sp>

            <sd>
                <char ref="Gizmo">Gizmo</char> and<char ref="Mammoth">Mammoth</char> scatter while she shouts and throws a spell. The Titans scramble
                to avoid it; when it hits the rooftop, a panel swells and explodes.<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> comes
                down from his jump only to find<char ref="Mammoth">Mammoth</char> coming straight at him. He jumps away again
                and turns into a falcon as the giant slams his fist down on the roof and sends a
                shock wave toward<char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char>.<char ref="Jinx">Jinx</char> lands behind the latter and vaults high over his
                shoulders, hurling a spell down at him as she sails through the air. It knocks out
                the base of a water tank and causes the while thing to topple toward<char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char>, who
                gets out of the way just in time before a second tank collapses nearby.</sd>

            <sd>Cut to<char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char> in midair, throwing a few Tamaranean fastballs, then to<char ref="Jinx">Jinx</char> as she
                nimbly dodges them and ducks out of sight behind part of the new construction.
               <char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char> flies in after her.<char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char>, meanwhile, looks around himself a bit. All
                clear, but that changes in an instant when<char ref="Gizmo">Gizmo</char> jumps down from the fallen water
                tanks and lands on his back.</sd>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="Gizmo">Gizmo</spkr>Hey, Robo-Wimp<sd>He pulls out his tool.</sd>Feel
                like getting hacked?</sp>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>Nope. How 'bout you?<char ref="Robin">Robin</char>! Now!</sp>

            <sd>Cut to<char ref="Robin">Robin</char> in mid-leap; he throws a small device, and the camera follows it over
                to<char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char> and<char ref="Gizmo">Gizmo</char>. It attaches itself to the machinery on the latter's back, and
                sparks fly as he yells in pain and frustration. Long shot:<char ref="Robin">Robin</char> drops back to the
                roof.</sd>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="Gizmo">Gizmo</spkr>
                <sd>runs around, trying to pull the thing off</sd>Cut it out! It's gonna crash my
                whole system<sd>He rips off his shoulder-mounted laser.</sd>Get it off me! Get it
                off me!</sp>

            <sd>
                <char ref="Robin">Robin</char>'s device triggers the jet pack, carrying him off the roof.<char ref="Jinx">Jinx</char> runs like mad
                to avoid getting fried by<char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char>'s bombardment.</sd>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr>Beast Boy! Go!</sp>

            <sd>
                <char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> is back in human form and crouching on an overhead girder to watch<char ref="Jinx">Jinx</char>.
                Flipping<char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char> a hand sign to acknowledge, he dives from his perch and transforms
                into a monkey to come down squarely on the face of the fleeing girl. She has made
                her way into a framework of pipes. Unable to see, she fires spells in all directions
                in an attempt to get him off; finally, she gets all ten fingers into the game, yanks
                him away, and throws him across the roof. He reverts to human form before touching
                down.</sd>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>Your luck just ran out!</sp>

            <sd>Getting a running start, he again becomes a falcon and flies into the open sky
                Close-up of a very puzzled<char ref="Jinx">Jinx</char>.</sd>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="Jinx">Jinx</spkr>Huh?</sp>

            <sd>Creaks and groans from the o.c. pipework draw her attention; cut to a view of the
                overhead lines from the ground and pan to follow them. One after another, the joints
                start to pop, having been hit by the spells she was casting every which way. Tilt
                down to ground level just in time to see one pipe burst and start spewing water and
                steam. The sound of a nervous little shudder is she can manage as more lines rupture
                and collapse around her.</sd>

            <sd>From here, cut to<char ref="Mammoth">Mammoth</char>, running like sixty, and pull back to show him advancing
                on<char ref="Raven">Raven</char>. He aims a colossal punch at her, but she flies up to avoid it and comes
                down behind him. When he turns to charge again,<char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char> rams a shoulder into him. It
                takes some time for him to touch down on the roof and stop skidding; when he does,
                the view shifts to letterbox, in the top third of the screen. Pan ahead of Mammoth
                just a bit to show<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char>, as a T-rex, waiting for him. One snarl is all it takes
                to make the overgrown villain completely freak out and run for his life. Fullscreen:
               <char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char> gathers all her strength for a starbolt and lets it go, hitting Mammoth
                dead center in the gut. The hit leaves him spinning in the air as<char ref="Robin">Robin</char> dashes over.
                One mighty flying kick drives him back into<char ref="Gizmo">Gizmo</char> and<char ref="Jinx">Jinx</char> and leaves all three in a
                weary, groaning pile. Tilt down to<char ref="Gizmo">Gizmo</char> at the bottom of it; he has a transmitter
                in hand.</sd>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="Gizmo">Gizmo</spkr>Cram it. I'm calling Slade</sp>

            <sd>
                <char ref="Robin">Robin</char> yanks him up to eye level as he switches it on.</sd>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>Who is<char ref="Slade">Slade</char>?</sp>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="Gizmo">Gizmo</spkr>Wouldn't you like to know, barf-brain?</sp>

            <sd>Snap to black and pan until the long shot of<char ref="Slade">Slade</char>'s lair, as seen in the prologue,
                comes into view. The H.I.V.E. Academy's headmistress speaks during this movement and
                comes into view at the edge of the platform.</sd>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="Headmistress">Headmistress</spkr>I assure you, such failures are not
                tolerated within the H.I.V.E<sd>Close-up of her.</sd>Once the agents have been
                retrieved from the authorities, they will be disciplined<sd>Cut to waist level; she
                    socks a fist into her palm.</sd>Strictly disciplined.</sp>

            <sd>Cut to another part of the platform.<char ref="Slade">Slade</char> steps out from among the pipes; the
               <char ref="Headmistress">Headmistress</char> has been addressing herself to him. The light glinting off his figure
                shows the colors from "Divide and Conquer", gray on the right side of his head,
                red-orange on the left.</sd>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="Slade">Slade</spkr>Actually, your agents served my plans quite well. I
                never expected them to succeed<sd>Extreme close-up of his eye; light shines on
                    it.</sd>They were merely messengers. And the message has been received.</sp>

            <sd>On the end of this, pan slightly to a transmitter in his raised left hand, a
                counterpart of the one<char ref="Gizmo">Gizmo</char> carried. He activates it, and on the monitor behind the
                headmistress, an image of<char ref="Robin">Robin</char> appears; caught on film by<char ref="Gizmo">Gizmo</char> and asking "Who is
               <char ref="Slade">Slade</char>?" over and over. Pull back slowly as more images of different sizes appear to
                fill the screen, then back to the long shot of the lair as they pop up on the entire
                row of screens. That three-word question is repeated countless times by all of them.
                If<char ref="Slade">Slade</char>'s intent was to bring his name to the Titans' attention, the H.I.V.E. crew
                did indeed meet his expectations.</sd>

            <sd>Cut to the exterior of the Tower. The original architecture has been restored.</sd>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>
                <sd>from inside</sd>NOOOO!! This is the worst thing that could ever happen!</sp>

            <sd>Close-up of him. He is in human form, with hands to head and ready to pull his green
                hair out.</sd>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>My tunes! They've been..<sd>He steps
                    back.</sd>...alphabetized.</sp>

            <sd>Pull back again. He tosses CDs around the operations center as<char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char> looks high and
                low, much as he did at the start of Act One.<char ref="Robin">Robin</char> stands behind the couch and
                watches the two.</sd>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>How am I ever gonna find anything?</sp>

            <sd>
                <char ref="Raven">Raven</char> comes downstairs, carrying the cloak<char ref="Jinx">Jinx</char> borrowed.</sd>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="Raven">Raven</spkr>
                <sd>icily</sd>They went into my room. No one should ever go into my room</sp>

            <sd>
                <char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char> gasps and pops up from under the kitchen counter.</sd>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr>Someone has disposed of all our blue furry
                food!</sp>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>
                <sd>lifting the couch</sd>You gotta be kidding me! The whole place gets cleaned and
                I still can't find the--</sp>

            <sd>A whistle from o.c. stops him short; cut to<char ref="Robin">Robin</char>, who points down toward the couch.
                Close-up of the coffee table, with the missing remote lying on it in plain
                sight.</sd>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>Ha!</sp>

            <sd>He drops the couch and sits down on it with<char ref="Robin">Robin</char>, who has started to flip
                channels.</sd>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>I guess we really oughta be training for battles,
                tracking down clues, and trying to figure out who<char ref="Slade">Slade</char> is, huh</sp>

            <sd>Pull back as the other three gather around the couch on this line.</sd>

            <sp>
                <spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>We will. But right now, I'm just happy to be part of
                the team.</sp>

            <sd>Pull back past the coffee table.<char ref="Robin">Robin</char> points the remote at the camera and clicks,
                and the whole screen winks out.</sd>
        </act>
    </body>
</root>