<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../schema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?><root>
    <head>
        <episode>SISTERS</episode>
        <writer>David Slack</writer>
        <director>Ciro Nieli</director>
        <storyboard>Kalvin Lee, Rafael Rosado, Alan Wan</storyboard>
        <animation>Dong Woo Animation Company, Ltd.</animation>
        <source>https://teentitans.fandom.com/wiki/Sisters_(Transcript)</source>
        <issueList>
            <issueInfo link="../comic/issue-23.xml"/>
        </issueList>
    </head>
    <characterList>
        <charList type="recurring" id="Starfire">Starfire</charList>
        <charList type="recurring" id="Robin">Robin</charList>
        <charList type="recurring" id="Cyborg">Cyborg</charList>
        <charList type="recurring" id="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</charList>
        <charList type="recurring" id="Raven">Raven</charList>
        <charList type="nonrecurring" id="Voice">Voice</charList>
        <charList type="nonrecurring" id="Blackfire">Blackfire</charList>
        <charList type="nonrecurring" id="Crewman1">Crewman 1</charList>
        <charList type="nonrecurring" id="Crewman2">Crewman 2</charList>
        <charList type="nonrecurring" id="GothBoy">Goth Boy</charList>
        <charList type="nonrecurring" id="Slacker">Slacker</charList>
        <charList type="nonrecurring" id="Centauri1">Centauri 1</charList>
        <charList type="nonrecurring" id="Centauri2">Centauri 2</charList>
        <charList type="nonrecurring" id="Centauri">Centauri</charList>
    </characterList>
    <body>
        <act n="0">
            <title>PROLOGUE</title>
            <sd><stageDesc>Opening shot: outer space.</stageDesc> There is a distant flash of light,
                from which four glowing objects emerge and approach the camera; <directNote kind="pan">pan to follow them across the cosmos</directNote>. As they home in on
                Earth, three peel off while the fourth heads straight for the planet. <directNote kind="shift">A camera shift reveals it to be <charDesc ref="Centauri">long and
                        cylindrical, something like a missile in shape, with several trailing
                        tentacles</charDesc>.</directNote></sd>

            <sd><directNote kind="cut">Cut to the night sky, where a fireworks show is in full
                    swing.</directNote>
                <directNote kind="pull">Pull back to show the area as the waterfront</directNote>;
                the craft’s brilliant streak descends past the display and below the horizon.
                    <directNote kind="pan">Pan to a nearby carnival-Ferris wheel, roller coaster,
                    games, the usual.</directNote>
                <stageDesc category="close-up">Close-up of one of the wheel’s cars, which holds
                        <char ref="Robin">Robin</char>  and <char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char> .</stageDesc> She watches the
                pyrotechnics with complete awe and sighs blissfully.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr>Beautiful. Tell me again what they are
                called.</sp>
            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>Fireworks.</sp>
            <sd>A few more go off.</sd>
            <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr>
                <sd>suddenly concerned</sd>On my home planet, such explosions would mean the
                Gordanians were attacking. You are certain Earth is not under attack?</sp>
            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>Positive. Cotton candy?</sp>
            <sd>He holds the pink stuff out to her.</sd>
            <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr>The last time I ate a ball of cotton, it was
                white. And it did not taste very-</sp>
            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>This is different.</sp>
            <sd>He pulls off a wad and pops it into his mouth; cautiously, she follows suit and
                realizes it is indeed different from the cotton ball.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr>Mmmm...<sd>A yelp of surprise.</sd>It
                vanished!</sp>
            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>
                <sd>chuckling</sd>Yeah. It’ll do that.</sp>
            <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr>
                <sd>sighing again</sd>When I first came to this planet, I did not think I would ever
                fit in. Earth was full of strange things. But now I see that-</sp>
            <sd>Big glare from fireworks.</sd>
            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>Here comes the finale! Yes!</sp>
            <sd>In the sky, the display has turned into a fusillade of redoubled intensity.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>Whoo-hoo-hoo! Amazing!</sp>
            <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr>Earth is full of amazing things too.</sp>
            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>Best planet I’ve ever been to.</sp>
            <sd>The craft seen in space sweeps past the Ferris wheel and yanks <char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char> 
                from her seat in <charDesc ref="Centauri">its tentacles</charDesc>; she is carried
                screaming into the sky.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>STARFIRE!!</sp>
            <sd><directNote kind="fade">Fade to white</directNote>, then <directNote kind="snap">snap to black</directNote>.</sd>

            <cue>OPENING THEME</cue>

        </act>
        <act n="1">
            <title>Act 1</title>
            <sd><stageDesc category="open-shot">Opening shot: the craft streaking toward the camera
                    over the bay.</stageDesc> The carnival is now in the distant background.
                    <char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char>  struggles against the hold on her.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr>Wherever you are taking me, I do not wish to
                go!</sp>
            <sd>She fires a starbolt at <charDesc ref="Centauri">the tentacles’ base; the craft
                    stops in midair, crackling all over with the energy of the shot</charDesc>, and
                she extricates herself and bugs out. The device goes after her. From here,
                    <directNote kind="cut">cut to <stageDesc category="overhead-shot">an overhead
                        shot of the carnival game booths</stageDesc></directNote>, then to
                    <stageDesc category="close-up">a close-up of several bottles set up for the old
                    ring-toss game</stageDesc>. A ring is thrown into view, bouncing off the neck of
                a bottle as a near miss; the next one rattles down on target. <directNote kind="tilt">Tilt up to the counter</directNote>, to the sound of <char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char>’s laughter. He and <char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char>  have been playing.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>Boo-yah!</sp>
            <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>Sweet!</sp>
            <sd>They trade a high five. <directNote kind="cut">Cut to outside the booth as
                        <char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char>  is handed his prize, a huge stuffed
                    chicken.</directNote>
                <char ref="Raven">Raven</char>  leans against a post, her arms crossed and her expression showing
                her low opinion of the whole exercise.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>Told you we’d win you a prize.</sp>
            <sd>He gives her the toy.</sd>
            <sp><spkr ref="Raven">Raven</spkr>A giant chicken. I must be the luckiest girl in the
                world.</sp>
            <sd><char ref="Robin">Robin</char>  lands nearby, in a crouch.</sd>
            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>
                <sd>standing up</sd> Titans ! Trouble!</sp>
            <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>Where’s <char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char> ?</sp>
            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>That’s the trouble.</sp>
            <sd>He runs off; <char ref="Raven">Raven</char>  tosses the chicken aside and all three follow him.
                Reaching the end of the pier, they look over the bay and see <charDesc ref="Centauri">a scintillating object</charDesc> plummet straight toward the
                waves. <directNote kind="resolve">It resolves into <char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char>  as she
                    pulls up sharply to skim the surface</directNote>, leaving a broad wake behind
                herself. <charDesc ref="Centauri">The craft</charDesc> is hot on her tail. She looks
                back over her shoulder, gasps, and sidesteps to avoid <charDesc ref="Centauri">a
                    lashing tentacle</charDesc>; turning onto her back, she throws a couple of
                starbolts that hit the nose without effect.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr>No more chasing now, please!</sp>
            <sd>A flip to face forward again, and she is off like a shot. She angles herself toward
                the pier and flies neatly through the other four  Titans ; <charDesc ref="Centauri">the pursuer</charDesc> does likewise.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>Who’s her new best friend?</sp>
            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>Don’t know-<sd>socking fist against palm</sd>-but I
                can’t wait to meet him.</sp>
            <sd>The chase loops around the Ferris wheel and back to the pier, where
                    <char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char>  stops just behind the rest of the team. <char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> is first to attack, leaping high and turning into <transform class="reptile">an alligator</transform> to bite at <charDesc ref="Centauri">the
                    tentacles’ bases</charDesc>-just barely missing. <char ref="Raven">Raven</char>  levitates a
                nearby hot dog cart and heaves it at the oncoming vehicle, which crashes right
                through it. As the thing races past <char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char> , he grabs <charDesc ref="Centauri">the tentacles</charDesc> and hauls on them with all his strength.
                Ever so slowly, he is dragged forward a few feet before bringing <charDesc ref="Centauri">the craft</charDesc> to a stop.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>Don’t know what you did to make this thing mad,
                     Star , but it couldn’t hurt to apologize!</sp>
            <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr>I am… sorry?</sp>
            <sd><charDesc ref="Centauri">The tentacles</charDesc> yank themselves out of his grip.
                    <char ref="Robin">Robin</char>  whips out his staff, extends it, and goes on the offensive; a
                mighty swing reverberates against the nose and drives <charDesc ref="Centauri">the
                    craft</charDesc> back. It tumbles over the guardrails as he lands and puts the
                weapon away. <char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> , back in <transform class="human">human
                    form</transform>, looks down after it; a loud splash is heard from down
                o.c.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>
                <sd>bewildered</sd>So, did we just win?</sp>
            <sd><charDesc ref="Centauri">The thing</charDesc> crashes up through the planks at the
                     Titans ’ feet <annot>to answer that one with a big fat no</annot>.
                    <char ref="Robin">Robin</char>  vaults onto the nose.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr><oneLine>Don’t see an OFF switch. Guess I’ll have to
                    make one.</oneLine></sp>
            <sd><stageDesc category="close-up">Close-up of a panel</stageDesc>; his fist flies down
                and smashes through it, and he pulls out a handful of wiring underneath. Sparks fly
                from the broken connections; <directNote kind="pull">pull back as he jumps
                    free</directNote>. <charDesc ref="Centauri">The craft</charDesc> veers
                hopelessly out of control, rising higher and higher toward the stratosphere, and
                finally explodes in a mighty conflagration among the fireworks that are still going
                off. <char ref="Robin">Robin</char>  lands next to <char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char> .</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>Whatever that thing was, it can’t hurt you now.</sp>
            <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr>But…why did it wish to hurt me at all?</sp>
            <sd>Animation goof: In this shot, her armband is on the left side rather than the
                right.</sd>
            <sd><directNote kind="dissolve">Dissolve to <stageDesc category="setting">the exterior
                        of Titans Tower</stageDesc></directNote>, then <directNote kind="cut">cut to
                    just inside the operations center door</directNote>. <char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char> ,
                positively ecstatic, enters first while her teammates stand at the doorway.
                    <directNote kind="pan">Pan to follow her.</directNote></sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr>Come, friends.<sd><stageDesc category="setting">The background changes to flowers</stageDesc> and bathes her in
                light.</sd>I shall thank you for my rescue by reciting the Poem of Gratitude-all six
                thousand verses.</sp>
            <sd><stageDesc category="setting">Normal background resumes</stageDesc>, and <directNote kind="cut">the camera cuts to the other four, now inside the operations
                    center</directNote>. <annot>This segue, to them, is as subtle as a car wreck-and
                    their eyes and the accompanying sound effect reinforce the point.</annot>
                <directNote kind="pull">Pull back to put <char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char>  in view, facing
                    them.</directNote>
                <charDesc ref="Voice">The next voice, from o.c., catches her by surprise-young,
                    female, perhaps a bit cocky, and very smooth.</charDesc></sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Voice">Voice</spkr>I see you haven’t changed a bit.</sp>
            <sd><directNote kind="cut">Cut to the speaker</directNote>, <charDesc ref="Blackfire">a
                    teenage girl similar in appearance to <char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char> , but whose clothing
                    is black rather than violet</charDesc>. <charDesc ref="Blackfire">Her hair is
                    this same color, her eyes narrow and blue, and she wears metallic full-body
                    armor beneath her clothes. In addition, her wrist guards and neck piece are
                    metal-colored.</charDesc> This is <char ref="Blackfire">Blackfire</char> . She leans against the
                back of the couch, but pushes off from it on her next line.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Blackfire">Blackfire</spkr>When we were little, I was always rescuing
                    <char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char> .</sp>
            <sd>Laughing, she opens her arms wide as <char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char>  squeals with delight and
                runs over to hug her.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr><charDesc ref="Blackfire">Sister</charDesc>!</sp>
            <sp><spkr ref="Blackfire">Blackfire</spkr>
                <sd>holding up a necklace with a large green gem</sd>Brought you a present.</sp>
            <sd><char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char>  gasps deeply and her eyes pop at the sight of this
                bauble.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr>A Centauri moon diamond?!? Where did you
                get-</sp>
            <sp><spkr ref="Blackfire">Blackfire</spkr>On the Centauri moons, of course.<sd>She
                    fastens it around <char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char> ’s neck.</sd>Oh, look, it matches your
                eyes.</sp>
            <sd><charDesc ref="Starfire">The recipient</charDesc> beams for a moment, then
                    <stageDesc category="fullscreen">opens her eyes wide to give the camera a full
                    view</stageDesc>. <directNote kind="gag">Sight gag: they have become diamonds as
                    well, and they grow a little bigger as a cash register is heard going off. This
                    ends after a moment.</directNote></sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr>You must meet my friends!</sp>
            <sd><char ref="Blackfire">Blackfire</char>  is yanked across the operations center before she can say a
                word.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr>I wish to introduce my <charDesc ref="Blackfire">big sister</charDesc>.</sp>
            <sd><char ref="Blackfire">Blackfire</char>  steps forward.</sd>
            <sp><spkr ref="Blackfire">Blackfire</spkr><char ref="Blackfire">Blackfire</char> .<sd><char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char>  is caught
                    out at her boldness.</sd>And since  Star  told me all about the
                     Titans  in her transmissions, let me guess.<sd>She points
                    to…</sd><char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char> .</sp>
            <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>
                <sd>holding out hand to shake</sd>Pleased to meet you, <charDesc ref="Blackfire">little lady</charDesc>.</sp>
            <sd>There is a loud grinding of metal as she takes the hand; after letting go, he finds
                his fingers to have been squeezed temporarily out of alignment.</sd>
            <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr><charDesc ref="Blackfire">Little lady, big
                    handshake.</charDesc> Well, all right.</sp>
            <sd>She goes on to…</sd>
            <sp><spkr ref="Blackfire">Blackfire</spkr><char ref="Raven">Raven</char> . I like <charDesc ref="Raven">that gemstone on your Ajna chakra</charDesc>.</sp>
            <sp><spkr ref="Raven">Raven</spkr>
                <sd>impressed</sd>You…know about chakras?</sp>
            <sp><spkr ref="Blackfire">Blackfire</spkr>I got way into meditation on Altara Prime.
                    <sd>She moves on to…</sd><char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> ! What’s up?</sp>
            <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>Nothing but the ceiling, baby.</sp>
            <sp><spkr ref="Blackfire">Blackfire</spkr>
                <sd>laughing</sd>Good one!</sp>
            <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>
                <sd>to <char ref="Raven">Raven</char> </sd>See? She thinks I’m funny.</sp>
            <sp><spkr ref="Raven">Raven</spkr>Statistically, I suppose someone has to.</sp>
            <sd>This deflates him a bit. Finally <char ref="Blackfire">Blackfire</char>  makes her way to <charDesc ref="Robin">the leader</charDesc>.</sd>
            <sd><annot>Note: In yoga, chakras are points in the body at which spiritual energy is
                    concentrated. There are seven, ranging from the top of the head to the base of
                    the tailbone, and the Ajna chakra-centered on the forehead-is the second one
                    down.</annot></sd>
            <sp><spkr ref="Blackfire">Blackfire</spkr>And you must be <char ref="Robin">Robin</char> .<sd>She
                    zips behind him and fingers <charDesc ref="Robin">his cape</charDesc>.</sd>Oh, I
                am loving this cape. It’s positively luscious!</sp>
            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>Thanks. It’s a high-density polymerized titanium, ten
                times stronger than steel.</sp>
            <sp><spkr ref="Blackfire">Blackfire</spkr>Fascinating.</sp>
            <sd><directNote kind="cut">Cut to just behind him-her perspective.</directNote> He
                directs an appreciative glance over his shoulder as <char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char>  slides
                into view and gasps, completely shocked by this exchange. Back to him and <charDesc ref="Blackfire">the big sister</charDesc>; she has leaned in even closer.</sd>
            <sp><spkr ref="Blackfire">Blackfire</spkr>And <charDesc ref="Robin">this mask makes you
                    look very mysterious</charDesc>.</sp>
            <sd><char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char>  inserts herself between them.</sd>
            <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr>So, <charDesc ref="Blackfire">beloved
                    sister</charDesc>, what brings you to Earth?</sp>
            <sd><char ref="Blackfire">Blackfire</char>  crosses to the couch.</sd>
            <sp><spkr ref="Blackfire">Blackfire</spkr>I was in the quadrant. Thought I’d see if
                Earthlings like to party.<sd>She hops over the back and sits.</sd>Besides, I needed
                a rest. Nearly got sucked into a black hole on the way here.</sp>
            <sd>The three boys are at the couch in an eyeblink, leaving <char ref="Raven">Raven</char>  by
                herself at the kitchen counter.</sd>
            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>Black hole?</sp>
            <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>No way!</sp>
            <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>Cool!</sp>
            <sp><spkr ref="Blackfire">Blackfire</spkr>Okay. I’m cruising through the Draconis
                Nebula, and-</sp>
            <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr>Sister! That nebula is full of black holes! You
                know travel there is forbidden.</sp>
            <sd>This remark is met with dead silence, except for a cricket chirping outside, and
                very funny looks from the four at the couch.</sd>
            <sp><spkr ref="Blackfire">Blackfire</spkr>Most fun things in life are. Now be a sweetie
                and bring me one of those sodas I’ve heard so much about.<sd>turning to the
                    boys</sd>So anyway, I’m zooming over an event horizon, approaching light speed,
                when all of a sudden-</sp>
            <sd><char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char>walks toward the kitchen on the end of this. <directNote kind="snap">Snap
                    to black</directNote>, which <directNote kind="resolve">resolves into the
                    interior of the refrigerator as the door opens and she looks in</directNote>. It
                is an under-the-counter model, <annot>the sort that might be found in a college dorm
                    room</annot>. A can of soda is on the top shelf.</sd>
            <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr>
                <sd>disgruntled, to herself</sd>I see you have not changed either.</sp>
            <sd>She gets the soda and closes the door. The view blacks out again, then <directNote kind="snap">snaps to outer space</directNote>. <stageDesc>One by one, three
                    bright streaks flash across the screen</stageDesc>; <directNote kind="tilt">tilt
                    up slightly to show them approaching a large hovering vessel</directNote>.
                    <directNote kind="cut">Cut to a bank of four docking tubes inside as the three
                    objects-duplicates of <charDesc ref="Centauri">the craft <char ref="Robin">Robin</char> 
                        destroyed at the pier</charDesc>, the ones that peeled off from Earth-slide
                    into place within them and stop.</directNote> A light on each occupied tube goes
                green, but that on the empty fourth one flashes red. <directNote kind="cut">Cut to
                    an alien crewman in a shadowy nook.</directNote></sd>
            <sp><spkr ref="Crewman1">Crewman 1</spkr>Our target was not located. The drones have
                failed.</sp>
            <sd><directNote kind="pan">Pan slightly</directNote>; <charDesc ref="Crewman2">a second
                    crewman</charDesc> is next to him.</sd>
            <sp><spkr ref="Crewman2">Crewman 2</spkr>Have they?</sp>
            <sd>He looks down; <directNote kind="cut">cut to a control panel that shows outlines of
                        <charDesc ref="Centauri">the four craft, or drones</charDesc>.</directNote>
                <charDesc ref="Centauri">Three glow green, while the last one is red, matching the
                    status lights on the docking tubes.</charDesc> One clawed hand reaches into view
                and presses the red outline, and the four give way to a view of Earth.</sd>
            <sp><spkr ref="Crewman2">Crewman 2</spkr>
                <sd>from o.c.</sd>The one that probed Earth did not return.<sd><directNote kind="pull">Pull back; both look at Earth on the main
                    viewer.</directNote></sd>That is where we will find the girl.</sp>
            <sd><directNote kind="dissolve">Dissolve to the exterior of the Tower.</directNote> It
                is now the next day.</sd>
            <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr>
                <sd>from inside</sd><charDesc ref="Blackfire">Sister</charDesc>?</sp>
            <sd><directNote kind="cut">Cut to her, walking down the hall.</directNote> She is still
                wearing the necklace and will continue to do so until further notice.</sd>
            <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr><charDesc ref="Blackfire">Sister</charDesc>?<sd>She looks around a bit.</sd>
                <charDesc ref="Blackfire">Sister</charDesc>, I seek your companionship.</sp>
            <sd><stageDesc category="close-up">Close-up of a racing video game in
                    progress.</stageDesc> Two vehicles, one green and one white, speed along a
                twisting elevated track, and the green one gets out in front and blocks attempts by
                the white to pass. <directNote kind="cut">Cut to <char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char>  and <char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> on the couch; they are playing GameStation on the
                    window/screen</directNote>, and their respective expressions tell right away who
                is winning.</sd>
            <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>You want to pass me, but you can’t pass me. You
                can’t pa-<sd>surprised; <char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char>  grins</sd>You passed me!</sp>
            <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>Tighten the turn…jets…and nitro!</sp>
            <sd>He jumps up and does a laughing victory dance as <char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char>  slumps over; a
                moment later, he is back on the couch. <char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char>  walks up behind
                them.</sd>
            <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr>Tell me, have either of you seen
                    <char ref="Blackfire">Blackfire</char> ?</sp>
            <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr><charDesc ref="Blackfire">Blazin’
                    B</charDesc>? She was here just a second ago.</sp>
            <sd>His face goes slack as <char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char>  grins; back to the screen. The white
                vehicle hugs the guardrail, then knocks the green one aside and zooms on.</sd>
            <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>
                <sd>from o.c.</sd>Aw, yeah! Back in the lead!</sp>
            <sd>Back to the couch; he laughs heartily.</sd>
            <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr>What fun! May I join your game?</sp>
            <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>Winner plays <char ref="Blackfire">Blackfire</char> .</sp>
            <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>
                <sd>as hearts float up from him</sd>Yeah. She rules at this game.</sp>
            <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr>
                <sd>deflated</sd>I see.</sp>
            <sd>She walks away. <directNote kind="cut">Cut to <stageDesc category="close-up">a
                        close-up of a door</stageDesc></directNote>; she reaches into view and
                knocks. It slides open a small amount and reveals <char ref="Raven">Raven</char>  peering
                out-this is her room.</sd>
            <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr>Is…<charDesc ref="Blackfire">my
                    sister</charDesc> in there?</sp>
            <sp><spkr ref="Raven">Raven</spkr>No.</sp>
            <sd>She starts to close the door; <directNote kind="cut">cut to her side</directNote>.
                The lights are out.</sd>
            <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr>Oh…Might you wish to hang out with me? We could
                visit your favorite depressing cafe.</sp>
            <sd>Outside again.</sd>
            <sp><spkr ref="Raven">Raven</spkr>Already been. It was open mic and
                    <char ref="Blackfire">Blackfire</char>  wanted to share. <charDesc ref="Blackfire">Your
                    sister</charDesc>’s poetry is surprisingly dark.</sp>
            <sd>She closes the door; <char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char>  heads off down the hall and sighs
                heavily. Through the open door to the gym, the shadows of <char ref="Blackfire">Blackfire</char>  and
                    <char ref="Robin">Robin</char>  can be seen on the wall. They are close enough to touch, and
                they do so on the next line.</sd>
            <sp><spkr ref="Blackfire">Blackfire</spkr>
                <sd>from inside gym</sd>That’s perfect, <char ref="Robin">Robin</char> .</sp>
            <sd><stageDesc category="close-up">Close-up of <charDesc ref="Starfire">the little
                        sister</charDesc>, who gasps sharply as her eyes bug out.</stageDesc></sd>
            <sp><spkr ref="Blackfire">Blackfire</spkr>
                <sd>from inside gym</sd>Hold me just like that, and…</sp>
            <sd><directNote kind="cut">Cut to the gym.</directNote> She throws him the full width of
                the room; he spins in the air a bit before coming down on top of a rack of
                dumbbells. <char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char>  is positively aghast at the sight. Inside again;
                when <char ref="Robin">Robin</char>  peels himself up from the floor, he is seen to be badly
                dazed from the impact.</sd>
            <sp><spkr ref="Blackfire">Blackfire</spkr>Learned that move from a Ven-Zo master on
                Tyrus Three.</sp>
            <sd>He comes to.</sd>
            <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr>
                <sd>from o.c.</sd>Hello, <char ref="Robin">Robin</char> …<sd><directNote kind="shift">Shift to
                        frame all three</directNote>; she enters.</sd> …and…<charDesc ref="Blackfire">my sister</charDesc>. Am I interrupting?</sp>
            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>Not at all. <char ref="Blackfire">Blackfire</char>  was just showing
                me some alien martial arts. How come you never taught me these cool moves?</sp>
            <sd><directNote kind="cut">Cut to a close-up of <char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char> </directNote>, who
                has no good answer, then <directNote kind="cut">back to <char ref="Blackfire">Blackfire</char>  and
                        <char ref="Robin">Robin</char>  on the start of the next line</directNote>.</sd>
            <sp><spkr ref="Blackfire">Blackfire</spkr>Probably because she doesn’t know them. I
                always was the better fighter.<sd>leading him away</sd>Come on. I’ll show you the
                technique I once used to stop a raging orthax.</sp>
            <sd><charDesc ref="Starfire">The little sister</charDesc> stares bug-eyed after them for
                a moment and then hangs her head sadly. <directNote kind="dissolve">Dissolve to the
                    exterior of the Tower.</directNote> Inside, all the  Titans  except
                    <char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char>  are lounging on the couch in the operations center;
                    <char ref="Raven">Raven</char>  is reading a book.</sd>
            <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr>
                <sd>from o.c., cheerfully</sd>Friends!</sp>
            <sd>She comes in, balancing buckets of popcorn and candy along with stacks of DVDs.</sd>
            <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr>I invite you to join me in the togetherness of
                a stay-home movie night. I bring you popcorn and non-cotton candies. Tell me, what
                sort of movie shall we view?</sp>
            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>Action.</sp>
            <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>Comedy.</sp>
            <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>Sci-fi.</sp>
            <sp><spkr ref="Raven">Raven</spkr>Horror.</sp>
            <sd>Caught off guard,<char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char> drops her load of goodies.</sd>
            <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr>Perhaps a double feature?</sp>
            <sd><directNote kind="gag">Sight gag: a little drop of nervous sweat springs from her
                    head and falls.</directNote></sd>
            <sp><spkr ref="Blackfire">Blackfire</spkr>
                <sd>from o.c.</sd>Forget the flicks, kids.</sp>
            <sd>She turns to look; <directNote kind="cut">cut to the side door</directNote> and
                    <directNote kind="tilt">tilt up from ground level</directNote>.
                    <char ref="Blackfire">Blackfire</char>  stands there, <charDesc ref="Blackfire">dressed in one of
                    <char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char>’s spare outfits, and has dispensed with the armor</charDesc>.</sd>
            <sp><spkr ref="Blackfire">Blackfire</spkr>We’re going out!</sp>
            <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr>
                <sd>puzzled</sd>We are?<sd><char ref="Blackfire">Blackfire</char>  passes her.</sd>Where did you-?
                Are those my-?</sp>
            <sp><spkr ref="Blackfire">Blackfire</spkr>
                <sd>to the other  Titans </sd>Heard about a party downtown. Cool crowd,
                hot music.</sp>
            <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>Yeah!</sp>
            <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>I’m in.</sp>
            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>Why not?</sp>
            <sd><stageDesc category="close-up">Close-up of <char ref="Raven">Raven</char> , nose still in her
                    book.</stageDesc></sd>
            <sp><spkr ref="Blackfire">Blackfire</spkr>
                <sd>from o.c.</sd>And it’s in a creepy run-down warehouse.</sp>
            <sd>This gets her attention. One by one, <char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char> ’s comrades file out.</sd>
            <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>Whoo!</sp>
            <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>I am a party animal.</sp>
            <sd>He turns into a gorilla.</sd>
            <sd><char ref="Robin">Robin</char>  and <char ref="Raven">Raven</char>  pass <char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char>  without saying
                anything; <char ref="Blackfire">Blackfire</char>  is the last one out.</sd>
            <sp><spkr ref="Blackfire">Blackfire</spkr>Hey, sweetie, raided your closet. Hope you
                don’t mind me borrowing your look.</sp>
            <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr>
                <sd>sadly, looking after her</sd>Why not? You have already borrowed my friends.</sp>
            <sd><charDesc ref="Blackfire">Big sister</charDesc> departs, leaving <charDesc ref="Starfire">little sister</charDesc> standing among the snacks and movies she
                dropped-the scattered remains of her plan to spend time with the gang. <directNote kind="fade">Fade to black.</directNote></sd>

        </act>
        <act n="2">
            <title>Act 2</title>
            <sd><stageDesc category="open-shot">Opening shot: the exterior of the creepy run-down
                    warehouse <char ref="Blackfire">Blackfire</char>  mentioned.</stageDesc> It is nighttime. A
                thumping dance beat can be heard within as multicolored lights pulse at the windows.
                    <directNote kind="cut">Cut to inside</directNote> and <directNote kind="pan">pan
                    across the space</directNote>, which is packed with partying teens, then
                    <directNote kind="pull">pull back to <stageDesc category="overhead-shot">an
                        overhead view</stageDesc></directNote>. <char ref="Blackfire">Blackfire</char>  makes her way
                among the crowd, with all  Titans  except <char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char>  close
                behind. <char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char>  has returned to <transform class="human">human
                    form</transform>.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Blackfire">Blackfire</spkr>Step aside, Earthlings, the queen of the
                galaxy has arrived!</sp>

            <sd><char ref="Raven">Raven</char>  looks back the way they came and sees <char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char> 
                standing at a distance now. The fifth  Titan  moves hesitantly through
                the dancers and gets jostled back and forth.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr>Oh…excuse…oh…uh…<sd>Her foot is trod on.</sd>
                Ow! You really should apologize after stepping on someone’s foot.</sp>

            <sd><char ref="Raven">Raven</char>  shakes her head-"this is a lost cause"-and moves further into the
                crowd. <directNote>Cut to <char ref="Blackfire">Blackfire</char> , already getting
                down.</directNote></sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Blackfire">Blackfire</spkr>
                <sd>laughing</sd>Now don’t tell me you big tough superheroes are afraid of a little
                dancing.</sp>
            <sd><directNote kind="cut">Cut to<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> and<char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char>.</directNote></sd>
            <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>Betcha <char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char>  can do the
                Robot.</sp>

            <sd>He does a little bit of that old dance and gets a very unappreciative glare from the
                    <charDesc ref="Cyborg">big bionic man</charDesc> standing next to him.
                    <char ref="Blackfire">Blackfire</char>  dances across the screen in front of the pair, after
                which they and <char ref="Robin">Robin</char>  start to get into the spirit of things.
                    <char ref="Raven">Raven</char>  and <char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char>  watch, the former with the same
                posture and expression she wore at the carnival game booths.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Raven">Raven</spkr>This party is pointless.</sp>
            <sd><charDesc ref="GothBoy">A goth-looking boy</charDesc> comes up next to her.</sd>
            <sp><spkr ref="GothBoy">Goth boy</spkr>Everything’s pointless. Wanna go talk about
                it?</sp>

            <sd>She looks sidewise at him and shrugs, and both walk away to leave
                    <char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char>  by herself. She makes as if to follow them but does not. A
                couple of slacker types pass behind her and back up for a closer look after moving
                o.c.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Slacker">Slacker</spkr>Hey, <charDesc ref="Starfire">hot alien
                    girl</charDesc>. You digging the scene?</sp>
            <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr>
                <sd>nervously, blushing</sd>I…did not know we were supposed to bring shovels.</sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="gag">Sight gag: she appears in "Super Deformed" style, mortified
                    under a solitary spotlight, as the two slackers laugh themselves silly and the
                    merriment of everyone else is heard from o.c.</directNote>
                <directNote kind="snap">Snap to black.</directNote></sd>

            <sd><directNote kind="fade">Fade in to a view of Earth from outer space.</directNote>
                The ship that launched those four probes drifts slowly into view; inside, the two
                crewmen are still watching the planet on the main viewer.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Crewman2">Crewman 2</spkr>The girl may have defeated one probe-
                        <sd><directNote>Cut to the three docked drone, or probes</directNote>; he
                    continues o.c.</sd>-but she will not fare so well against three.</sp>

            <sd>They are launched, one by one, and <directNote kind="cut">when the camera cuts to
                    outer space</directNote> again, they rocket toward Earth. <directNote kind="cut">Cut to the night sky</directNote> and <directNote kind="tilt">tilt down to the
                    roof of the warehouse</directNote> as the three bright trails disappear into the
                Jump City skyline. <char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char>  sits on a ledge, head in hands. <stageDesc category="close-up">Close-up: she is utterly dejected, and she heaves a
                    sigh.</stageDesc></sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr>Perhaps I do not belong here after all.</sp>
            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>
                <sd>from o.c.</sd>Of course you don’t.</sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="cut">Cut to him, holding open the door at the top of the stairs
                    that lead up to the roof.</directNote></sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>You belong down there, having fun with the rest of
                    us.<sd>closing door, stepping out</sd>What’s wrong?</sp>
            <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr>
                <sd>with a false smile</sd>Nothing is wrong. Everything is wonderful.<sd>He sits by
                    her.</sd>The pounding music and blinding lights are quite enjoyable.</sp>

            <sd>The words are barely out of her mouth before her real mood rearranges her face.
                    <char ref="Robin">Robin</char>  looks on with concern.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr>Everything is not wonderful. I am happy to see
                her, but <char ref="Blackfire">Blackfire</char>  rules the video games, and she is able to share very
                depressing poems, and she knows the cool moves-<sd><directNote kind="cut">Cut to
                            <char ref="Robin">Robin</char> </directNote>; she continues o.c.</sd>-and she always
                knows when people are not talking about shovels.<sd><directNote kind="pull">Pull
                        back to frame both</directNote>; she sighs.</sd>And I am nothing like
                her.</sp>
            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>
                <sd>putting a hand on her shoulder</sd>No, you’re not. And I think-</sp>

            <sd>They are interrupted by a creak of hinges. <directNote kind="cut">Cut to the
                    skylights</directNote>, one of which <char ref="Blackfire">Blackfire</char>  has opened to let
                herself out. She holds it propped open; <charDesc ref="Blackfire">her hair is now
                    shorter and bright pink</charDesc>.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Blackfire">Blackfire</spkr>How do I look?</sp>
            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>Pink. Look, can you give us a minute here?</sp>

            <sd>This response is not quite what she expected. However, her demeanor changes in an
                instant with the music.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Blackfire">Blackfire</spkr>
                <sd>gasping happily</sd>Oh, I love this song!</sp>

            <sd>She flies over, grabs <char ref="Robin">Robin</char> ’s arm, and yanks him down through the
                skylight. It swings shut to leave <char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char>  alone on the roof again. She
                sighs wearily and stands up from the ledge as the sound of something in flight is
                heard from o.c.; now she looks up.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr>Huh?</sp>

            <sd>From between the letters of the lighted sign on the roof, a glare can be seen fading
                away. Its source, one of the three launched probes, pokes out and charges at her. A
                shocked gasp escapes her before <directNote kind="cut">the camera cuts back to the
                    party</directNote>. <char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char>  and <char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char>  are dancing
                to beat the band now, but <charDesc ref="BeastBoy">the little green
                    goofball</charDesc> stops short and looks up. His perspective:
                    <char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char>  and <charDesc ref="Centauri">the probe</charDesc>, visible
                only as silhouettes, are fighting it out on the skylight panes. It finally seizes
                her in <charDesc ref="Centauri">its tentacles</charDesc> and darts away.</sd>

            <sd>Floor level; <char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char>  runs across the room to track <charDesc ref="Centauri">the alien craft</charDesc>. Losing sight of it near the wall, he
                turns back to call in a little help.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr> Cy !  Star ’s in
                trouble!</sp>

            <sd><char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char>  stops dancing and turns to look, just as <char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> 
                is grabbed by <charDesc ref="Centauri">the tentacles of a second probe</charDesc>
                and dragged toward the door.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>Whoa! Help!</sp>

            <sd><char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char>  runs after him, but is broadsided by <charDesc ref="Centauri">the third probe</charDesc>; he fetches up against the wall, and <charDesc ref="Centauri">the craft</charDesc> closes in. From here, <directNote kind="cut">cut to <char ref="Raven">Raven</char>  and <charDesc ref="GothBoy">the goth teen</charDesc>
                    she followed away from the dance floor</directNote>. They are in a dark corner
                of the warehouse.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="GothBoy">Goth boy</spkr>So, do you like show tunes?</sp>

            <sd><charDesc ref="Centauri">The probe</charDesc> hauling <char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char>  passes
                before she can answer. <charDesc ref="GothBoy">Her companion</charDesc> beats feet
                out of there, and she flies to lend a hand. Two crates are promptly levitated and
                projected at the craft; their impact jars <char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char>  out of its grip,
                and he falls to skid across the floor. Through the skylight, <char ref="Raven">Raven</char> 
                spots <charDesc ref="Centauri">the one that has caught
                    <char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char> </charDesc>-it gains altitude and then goes into a
                screaming dive to crash through the glass and into a pile of crates. She moves back
                to avoid the impact. <char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char>  lands a punch against <charDesc ref="Centauri">the probe that struck him</charDesc>, after which
                    <char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char>  and the one that seized her break out of the crates. She
                blasts it back with a starbolt.</sd>

            <sd><char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> , momentarily in the clear, suddenly yelps and jumps back a
                bit to get out of the way of <charDesc ref="Centauri">the one that tried to tow him
                    in</charDesc>. Transforming into <transform class="mammal">a tiger</transform>
                during his backflip, he lunges at <charDesc ref="Centauri">the alien
                    craft</charDesc> and drives it across the room with a swipe of his paw. It stops
                beneath <char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char> ; in no time, it and the other two have closed in on
                her. She gasps and flies around and around to shake them, finally getting a breather
                thanks to <char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char> ’s flying tackle that brings down all of them. Looking
                down as his grunts rise to her, she sees him taking on <charDesc ref="Centauri">the
                    three craft</charDesc>. <charDesc ref="Centauri">One is punched away, another
                    slung out by its tentacles; the third, however, spins like a high-speed flail
                    and sends him tumbling.</charDesc></sd>

            <sd><directNote kind="cut">Cut to <char ref="Robin">Robin</char>  and <char ref="Blackfire">Blackfire</char>  on the
                    stairs.</directNote> His attention drawn by the commotion on the other side of
                the wall, he turns toward it as <char ref="Blackfire">Blackfire</char>  tries to pull him away.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Blackfire">Blackfire</spkr>Where are you going? Stay and talk to
                me.</sp>
            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>Look, I just want to make sure that
                    <char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char> ’s okay.</sp>

            <sd><char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char>  comes crashing through the wall. As he stands up, rubbing his
                head and grumbling, <char ref="Robin">Robin</char>  runs over to him.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>What’s going on?</sp>
            <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>Remember <charDesc ref="Centauri">that
                    thing</charDesc> that attacked  Star ? It had friends.</sp>

            <sd>He rushes back into the melee, leaving <char ref="Blackfire">Blackfire</char>  alone at the top of
                the stairs. <char ref="Robin">Robin</char>  starts to follow, but stops upon seeing her
                there.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>Didn’t you hear him? <charDesc ref="Starfire">Your
                    sister</charDesc> needs help!</sp>
            <sd>Pause.</sd>
            <sp><spkr ref="Blackfire">Blackfire</spkr>
                <sd>smiling</sd>Right. Of course.</sp>

            <sd>She pulls off her pink hair and drops it-it is only a wig she had been wearing over
                her natural hair. Now she runs down the stairs. <directNote kind="cut">Cut to the
                    alley behind the warehouse</directNote>; <char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char>  crashes out
                through the wall, hits the one opposite, and drops into a nearby Dumpster. <charDesc ref="Centauri">The three probes</charDesc> float out as she opens the lid for a
                peek. One of them slams it down on her head and starts to hoist the entire container
                skyward; her screams are heard from inside as all three take off.</sd>

            <sd><char ref="Robin">Robin</char> ’s birdarang flashes into view and severs two of the tentacles
                holding the Dumpster, causing it to fall to the ground. It returns to his hand;
                    <directNote kind="pull">pull back to frame all the  Titans  except
                        <char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char> </directNote>. <char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char>  is back in
                    <transform class="human">human form</transform>.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Robin Cyborg">Robin, Cyborg</spkr> Teen Titans ! Go!</sp>

            <sd>Before they can move, <char ref="Blackfire">Blackfire</char>  flies over their heads and straight
                toward <charDesc ref="Centauri">the three probes</charDesc>, which move to
                intercept. Beams of energy shoot forth from her eyes and blow them all away;
                fragments of hulls and tentacles rain down as she lands in the alley.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>
                <sd>from o.c.</sd>Aw, yeah!<sd><directNote kind="pan">Pan slightly</directNote>, the
                    four  Titans  run/fly to her.</sd> Good times!</sp>
            <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>Nice shooting, <charDesc ref="Blackfire">Tex</charDesc>.</sp>
            <sp><spkr ref="Raven">Raven</spkr>Very nice.</sp>
            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>How did you know where to hit them?</sp>
            <sp><spkr ref="Blackfire">Blackfire</spkr>
                <sd>shrugging</sd>Lucky guess.</sp>
            <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>We could use luck like that. Maybe you oughta join
                the team.</sp>
            <sp><spkr ref="Blackfire">Blackfire</spkr>Me? A  Teen Titan ?</sp>

            <sd>The Dumpster lid swings open, and <char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char>  pokes her head up and gasps
                in undiluted shock. A banana peel has fallen on her head. <directNote kind="fade">Fade to black.</directNote></sd>

        </act>
        <act n="3">
            <title>Act 3</title>
            <sd><stageDesc category="open-shot">Opening shot: an overhead view of the
                    Tower.</stageDesc> It is later that night, and waves break loudly against the
                island’s shores. <directNote kind="cut">Cut to the roof</directNote>;
                    <char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char>  walks slowly to the edge, away from the camera, to
                silhouette herself against the full moon. She carries a backpack by the shoulder
                straps. <stageDesc category="close-up">Close-up as she looks back-her face tells the
                    story</stageDesc>: she is ready to throw in the towel once and for all.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr>
                <sd>slinging up pack</sd>She will be a better  Titan  than I ever
                was.</sp>

            <sd>She lifts off from the roof. <directNote kind="pull">Pull back</directNote>;
                    <char ref="Robin">Robin</char>  steps out, and his words stop her from heading into the great
                wide open.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>Were you just going to leave without saying
                goodbye?</sp>

            <sd>Having been called out in this manner, she cannot look him in the eye, but instead
                dips her head and descends back to the roof, her knees half-buckled. The backpack
                slides from her shoulders; finally she looks up at him.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr><char ref="Robin">Robin</char> , I-</sp>

            <sd>The sound of an approaching <charDesc ref="Centauri">craft</charDesc> draws a gasp
                from her and an over-shoulder look from him. <directNote kind="pull">Pull back to
                    put it in view</directNote>: the same ship that launched the four probes in the
                first place. One of the two crewmen is standing on its flat top deck. It turns 90
                degrees to present one side to the  Titans, and the standing man lashes out a long tentacle from his right arm that
                pushes <char ref="Robin">Robin</char>  back and then snares <char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char> . The left arm has the claws seen earlier aboard ship.
                The tentacle’s end wraps itself around her mouth before she can put up any sort of
                resistance, and the ship begins to haul her away.</sd>

            <sd><char ref="Robin">Robin</char>  gets to his feet and sprints most of the length of the roof,
                finally leaping over the edge toward the alien vessel. Slowly but surely, his
                momentum carries him closer to <char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char> ; <stageDesc category="close-up">extreme close-up of one of her feet, with his hand straining toward
                    it</stageDesc>. The effort falls short, however, and she is lifted toward outer
                space as her muffled cries ring in the air.</sd>

            <sd><directNote kind="dissolve">Dissolve to the moon, now partially obscured by drifting
                    clouds.</directNote> The ship flies into view; now the other crewman is on the
                top deck, handling the navigational duties. <directNote kind="cut">A cut to a
                    control button at deck level shows an arm reaching down to it and
                        <char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char> ’s feet just in front of him.</directNote>
                <directNote kind="pull">Pull back as the button is pressed</directNote>; a force
                field appears around the still-bound girl.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Crewman1">Crewman 1</spkr>Prepare to leave Earth orbit. We have
                    <charDesc ref="Starfire">the Tamaranean girl</charDesc>.</sp>
            <sp><spkr ref="Crewman2">Crewman 2</spkr>
                <sd>to Starfire</sd>Once we return to Centauri, you will pay for what you have
                done.</sp>

            <sd>Now we know what race these creatures are. She can only struggle and grunt through
                her bonds. <directNote kind="pull">Pull back to a side view of the ship</directNote>
                and <directNote kind="tilt">pan/tilt down to its underside</directNote>.
                    <char ref="Robin">Robin</char>  is hanging on upside down.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>Nobody’s taking her away.</sp>

            <sd>He vaults to the deck and lands facing the crewman at the force-field holding
                cell.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr><charDesc ref="Starfire">My friend</charDesc> stays
                here!</sp>

            <sd> The <char ref="Centauri">Centauri </char> roars and charges at him with a swing of that right arm,
                but he easily dodges this. A roundhouse also misses <charDesc ref="Robin">the Boy
                    Wonder</charDesc>; the alien’s next attack consists of a series of right-handed
                laser blasts-<charDesc ref="Centauri">the thing on his arm is a multi-purpose
                    weapon</charDesc>. <char ref="Robin">Robin</char>  leaps away from the shots, several of
                which hit the force field holding <char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char>  and bounce off, and the
                     <char ref="Centauri">Centauri </char> charges toward him. An overhead swing crackles upon impact
                with the field and leaves his underarm exposed for <char ref="Robin">Robin</char> ’s
                counter-punch. This blow sends sparks up from the armor and pushes <charDesc ref="Centauri">the aggressor</charDesc> back a bit.</sd>

            <sd>Now <charDesc ref="Robin">the young man</charDesc> retreats to a spot near one of
                the ship’s engines, on the side. Out comes that tentacle, which he barely dodges; it
                hits the edge of his cape and deflects into the engine, causing it to flame
                out.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Centauri1">Centauri 1</spkr>No!</sp>

            <sd>The craft begins to lose altitude, throwing <charDesc ref="Centauri2">his
                    colleague</charDesc> off balance and putting the brawl on hold for the time
                being. It plunges through the clouds and just barely skims a riverbank.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Centauri1">Centauri 1</spkr>I cannot control it!</sp>

            <sd><char ref="Robin">Robin</char>  scrambles across the deck to the control button and deactivates
                the force field. The ship descends ever closer to the river as he peels the
                tentacles away from her body.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr>Robin!</sp>
            <sd><directNote kind="cut">Cut to a point between them.</directNote></sd>
            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>
                <sd>from o.c.</sd>Come on!</sp>

            <sd>They reach into view and join hands; <directNote kind="pull">pull back as they leap
                    from the deck</directNote>. The ship turns down nose first and grinds into the
                riverbank, skidding a considerable distance before finally stopping and tumbling
                forward to land on its top deck. <char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char>  lowers <char ref="Robin">Robin</char> 
                safely to the ground and lands beside him.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>
                <sd>from o.c.</sd>Star!<char ref="Robin">Robin</char>!</sp>
            <sd>He,<char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char>, and<char ref="Raven">Raven</char> run up.</sd>
            <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>You guys okay?</sp>

            <sd>The two  Centauri  crewmen stand up amid the clouds of smoke pouring up
                from their wrecked craft. All five  Titans  brace for action.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>Titans! Get ready!</sp>
            <sd>The  Centauri  approach.</sd>
            <sp><spkr ref="Centauri2">Centauri 2</spkr>In the name of the Grand Centauri Empire,
                you are all under arrest.</sp>

            <sd>He shows a badge, the sight of which leaves the entire team momentarily
                stunned.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>Uh…you can’t be the good guys. We’re the good
                guys.</sp>
            <sd><stageDesc category="close-up">Close-up of the two.</stageDesc></sd>
            <sp><spkr ref="Centauri2">Centauri 2</spkr>And we are  Centauri 
                police.</sp>
            <sp><spkr ref="Centauri1">Centauri 1</spkr><charDesc ref="Blackfire">The Tamaranean
                    girl is a liar and a thief.</charDesc>
                <sd>pointing</sd><charDesc ref="Blackfire">She’s committed high crimes throughout
                    the entire Centauri system.</charDesc></sp>

            <sd>On the end of this, <directNote kind="cut">cut to <char ref="Robin">Robin</char>  and
                        <char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char> </directNote>; she is on the receiving end of the
                gesture.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr>I have never even been to the Centauri
                moons!</sp>
            <sd>She and <char ref="Robin">Robin</char>  both look at her necklace.</sd>
            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>
                <sd>removing it, holding it up</sd>But I know someone who has.</sp>

            <sd>Gazing into the large green gem <charDesc ref="Blackfire">her sister</charDesc> gave
                to her, <char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char>  gasps as the pieces of the frame-up fall together in
                her brain. <directNote kind="pull">Pull back</directNote>; <char ref="Robin">Robin</char>  turns
                to address the o.c.  Centauri  cops.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>You’ve been chasing the wrong girl.<sd>He throws the
                    necklace away and turns to the team.</sd>Where’s <char ref="Blackfire">Blackfire</char> ?</sp>

            <sd><char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char>  is the first to provide an answer, pointing up at a tiny
                black shape zooming among the clouds and away from the area.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>Uh…</sp>
            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>Don’t worry,  Star . She won’t get away
                with this.</sp>
            <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr>
                <sd>with sudden ice-cold fury</sd>No, she will not!</sp>

            <sd>She takes off. <directNote kind="cut">Cut to a long shot of her sister, headed
                    toward space</directNote>; <charDesc ref="Blackfire">she has changed back into
                    her own clothes and put the armored undergarment back on.</charDesc>
                <char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char>  flies up to intercept.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr>Hello, <charDesc ref="Blackfire">sister</charDesc>.</sp>
            <sp><spkr ref="Blackfire">Blackfire</spkr>Aww, you’re mad. I know, I should have told
                you I was leaving, but you know how I hate goodbyes and-</sp>
            <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr>You are a criminal, and you were going to let
                me take your place in jail!</sp>
            <sp><spkr ref="Blackfire">Blackfire</spkr>Oh…well…yeah.</sp>
            <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr>
                <sd>leaning into her face</sd>You will give back what you have stolen and turn
                yourself over to the police!</sp>
            <sp><spkr ref="Blackfire">Blackfire</spkr>
                <sd>leaning right back</sd>And what will you do if I don’t?</sp>

            <sd><char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char>  has no immediate answer here. <char ref="Blackfire">Blackfire</char>  warms up
                a starbolt and lets her have it in the kisser to send her tumbling.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Blackfire">Blackfire</spkr>I always was the better fighter.</sp>

            <sd><charDesc ref="Starfire">Her little sister</charDesc> rights herself after touching
                down on the ground and floats back up.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr>Not anymore!</sp>

            <sd><char ref="Blackfire">Blackfire</char>  unloads a machine-gun barrage of starbolts;
                    <char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char>  flies through them all without so much as getting her hair
                singed and gathers herself for a crushing counterstrike. This shot connects with
                    <char ref="Blackfire">Blackfire</char> ’s hand and makes the one she was about to throw fizzle
                out. <charDesc ref="Starfire">One very angry little sister</charDesc> rises to stare
                her down; both hands are lost in the dazzling radiance of the starbolts she is
                holding in check. <char ref="Blackfire">Blackfire</char>  merely laughs in her face, but trails off
                into surprised yells as a Centauri tentacle whips in from behind to tie her up.
                    <char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char>  turns to look toward the source; <directNote kind="cut">cut to him, standing on the deck of the righted ship</directNote>.</sd>

            <sd>Animation goof: The armor on <char ref="Blackfire">Blackfire</char> ’s legs disappears briefly during
                this sequence.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Centauri2">Centauri 2</spkr><char ref="Blackfire">Blackfire</char>  of Tamaran, you are
                under arrest.</sp>
            <sd><directNote kind="cut">Back to the two girls; she is slowly reeled
                in.</directNote></sd>
            <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr>
                <sd>waving</sd>Farewell, <charDesc ref="Blackfire">sister</charDesc>! Although you
                did betray and attack me, it was…still very nice to see you.</sp>
            <sp><spkr ref="Blackfire">Blackfire</spkr>Next time it won’t be so nice. I will get out
                of jail, <charDesc ref="Starfire">little sister</charDesc>, and I will get
                even!</sp>

            <sd>Said <charDesc ref="Starfire">little sister</charDesc> looks down at her worriedly.
                    <directNote kind="dissolve">Dissolve to the roof of the Tower; it is now sunrise
                    of the next day.</directNote>
                <char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char>  sits at the edge, bathed in light and lost in thought, and
                looks out over the sparkling bay as the wind blows her hair where it will.
                    <char ref="Robin">Robin</char>  comes up.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>Hey. How are you doing?</sp>
            <sd>He sits by her.</sd>
            <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr>I am…sad for <charDesc ref="Blackfire">my
                    sister</charDesc>.</sp>
            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>And for yourself?</sp>
            <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr>I am just glad that the truth was discovered
                before I was replaced.</sp>
            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>What are you talking about?</sp>
            <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr>Well, you…everyone was having such fun with
                her, and then <char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char>  said-</sp>
            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>Look. <charDesc ref="Blackfire">Your
                    sister</charDesc> was interesting, but she could never take your
                    place.<sd>smiling</sd>No one could ever take your place.</sp>

            <sd>Her answering smile shows that she has heard him loud and clear. <directNote kind="cut">Cut to <stageDesc category="long-shot">a long shot of them from
                        behind-two seated silhouettes watching the sun come
                    up</stageDesc></directNote>, their long shadows stretching back across the roof.
                    <directNote kind="fade">Fade to black.</directNote></sd>

            <cue>End</cue>
        </act>
    </body>
</root>