<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../schema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?><root>
   <head>
       <episode>MAD MOD</episode>
       <writer>David Slack</writer>
       <director>Ciro Nieli</director>
       <storyboard>Kalvin Lee, Rafael Rosado, Alan Wan</storyboard>
       <animation>Dong Woo Animation Company, Ltd.</animation>
       <source>https://teentitans.fandom.com/wiki/Mad_Mod_Transcript</source>
       <issueList>
            <issueInfo none="y"/>
       </issueList>
   </head>
   <characterList>
       <charList type="recurring" id="Robin" subtype="titan">Robin</charList>
       <charList type="recurring" id="Cyborg" subtype="titan">Cyborg</charList>
       <charList type="recurring" id="BeastBoy" subtype="titan">Beast Boy</charList>
       <charList type="nonrecurring" id="Voice">Voice</charList>
       <charList type="nonrecurring" id="MadMod" subtype="villain">Mad Mod</charList>
       <charList type="recurring" id="Starfire" subtype="titan">Starfire</charList>
       <charList type="recurring" id="Raven" subtype="titan">Raven</charList>
       <charList type="nonrecurring" id="Blackboard" subtype="villain">Blackboard</charList>
   </characterList>
   <body>
       <act n="0">
           <title>Prologue</title>
           <sd><stageDesc category="open-shot">Opening shot: a brown screen</stageDesc>.<char ref="Robin">Robin</char>  sits up after a moment with a huge gasp, giving
                the camera an <stageDesc category="close-up">extreme close-up of his face</stageDesc>.</sd>

           <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>Huh?</sp>

           <sd><directNote kind="pull">Pull back</directNote>. This place is a large, partially lit atrium with several balconies
                running around the walls, as well as paintings hung everywhere. The brown is the
                polished wood back of the chair he is sitting in. Wrists and ankles are securely
                bound to it;<char ref="Robin">Robin</char>  struggles against the restraints, but cannot get loose. Near him
                is the shadowy outline of<char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char>  in a chair of her own. <stageDesc category="close-up">Close-up</stageDesc>, <directNote kind="pan">panning slowly
                across</directNote>. Now the lights have fully come up to show one Titan after another also
                clamped into chairs. They are all half-unconscious, but come around with assorted
                groans, and each has an additional binding: red energy rings at<char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char> 's wrists,
                steel straps over<char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char> 's chest, a white energy band encircling<char ref="Raven">Raven</char> 's, and giant
                rubber bands on<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> 's.</sd>

           <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr><sd>during the previous</sd>What?</sp>

           <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>Huh? Am I the only one who has no idea where
                we are?</sp>

           <sp><spkr ref="Voice">Voice</spkr><sd>male, Cockney accent</sd>Why, you're right where
                you belong, my duckies.</sp>

           <sd><char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> gasps upon hearing these words. <directNote kind="cut">Cut to the speaker</directNote>, a man standing at an
                open set of double doors on one balcony. Light from the other side obscures him for
                the moment, but a cane can be seen in one hand. This is <char ref="MadMod">Mad Mod</char> </sd>

           <sp><spkr ref="MadMod">Mad Mod</spkr>You're in school!</sp>

           <sd>He leaps onto the banister of a nearby staircase and slides down it, giving the
                camera a full view of himself. <charDesc ref="MadMod">Early forties; red hair in a Beatle cut with
                muttonchop sideburns; small rectangular sunglasses; sportcoat with the design of the
                British Union Jack flag; black shirt; white kerchief tied at the neck; white pants;
                brown shoes with black socks. The cane is topped with a large ruby</charDesc>. Landing near
                <char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char>  he twirls it in one hand.</sd>

           <sp><spkr ref="MadMod">Mad Mod</spkr>That's right, lads and loveys. You're the only
                students at<char ref="MadMod">Mad Mod</char> 's Institute for Bratty Teenage Do-Gooders.<sd>He tosses the cane
                    high, to his other hand, and holds it out.</sd>And it's high time someone taught
                you sprogs a lesson.</sp>

           <sd>During this last sequence, the floor is seen to be tiled in a black and white
                checkerboard pattern. White light flares from the ruby as<char ref="MadMod">Mad Mod</char>  finishes. <directNote kind="cut">Cut to</directNote> a
                <directNote kind="pan">pan across the scared, straining Titans</directNote>, from<char ref="Robin">Robin</char>  to <char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> </sd>

           <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>Uh-oh.</sp>

           <sd><directNote kind="fade">Fade to black</directNote>.</sd>

           <cue>OPENING THEME (sung in Japanese)</cue>

       </act>
       <act n="1">
           <title>Act One</title>
           <sd><stageDesc category="open-shot">Opening shot:<char ref="MadMod">Mad Mod</char>  strolling leisurely toward the camera</stageDesc>, the ruby on his cane is
                blazing. As he nears the Titans, he raises the stick for a swing.</sd>

           <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>Titans! Move!</sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="pan">Pan across the others</directNote>, who are unable to break their bonds; <char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> <transform class="reptile">cycles through
                lizard and cobra forms</transform> as he strains against his.<char ref="MadMod">Mad Mod</char>  is now prancing around at
                the foot of the stairs and twirling the cane.</sd>

           <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr>My starbolts are useless!</sp>

           <sp><spkr ref="MadMod">Mad Mod</spkr>Specially designed chairs, love.<sd><stageDesc category="close-up">Close-up</stageDesc>; he
                    leans into her face.</sd>Can't have those nasty superpowers disrupting my
                lecture now, can I?</sp>

           <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr><sd>from o.c.</sd>Get away from her!</sp>

           <sd>The bizarre Brit straightens up, glances over at <char ref="Robin">Robin</char>  and thrusts the cane into
                his face. Its ruby flares up anew, more intensely, and<char ref="Robin">Robin</char>  recoils from the glare
                as far as he can.</sd>

           <sp><spkr ref="MadMod">Mad Mod</spkr>Now don't get your knickers in a twist, my little
                    snot.<sd>He backs off.</sd>I didn't go to all the trouble of building this
                school and filling your tower with knockout gas just to finish you off
                lickety-split.</sp>

           <sp><spkr ref="Raven">Raven</spkr>Then what do you want?</sp>

           <sp><spkr ref="MadMod">Mad Mod</spkr>Just what I said, dearie.<sd>leans into her
                    face</sd>To teach you lot a lesson!<sd>turns away and scratches himself</sd>Yes,
                I've been watching you children misbehave. And I hate misbehaving children.</sp>

           <sd>He points the cane off to one side; <directNote kind="pan">quick pan to that wall</directNote>. A picture of him, done
                in the style of Andy Warhol, turns around to show<char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char>  and<char ref="Raven">Raven</char>  beating on
                Thunder and Lightning.</sd>

           <sp><spkr ref="MadMod">Mad Mod</spkr><sd>from o.c.</sd>Fighting crime.</sp>

           <sd><directNote kind="pan">Pan to a second such painting</directNote>, which swivels to show<char ref="Robin">Robin</char>  and<char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char>  cradling
                kittens they have rescued from a blazing fire behind them.</sd>

           <sp><spkr ref="MadMod">Mad Mod</spkr><sd>from o.c.</sd>Saving lives.</sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="pan">Pan to a third picture</directNote>; this one turns to show <char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char>  <transform class="mammal">as a dog</transform>, pulling down
                Plasmus' shorts.</sd>

           <sp><spkr ref="MadMod">Mad Mod</spkr><sd>from o.c.</sd>Interfering with the plans of
                hardworking villains.<sd>Back to him and the Titans.</sd>Why, you lot are nothing
                but a bunch of troublemakers!</sp>

           <sd>His perspective, <directNote kind="pan">panning across the five captives</directNote>. As he points the cane around,
                each in turn reacts with varied expressions of fury.</sd>

           <sp><spkr ref="MadMod">Mad Mod</spkr>But you'll learn your place soon enough.<sd>Back
                    to him.</sd>You see, I'm older than you, so I'm bigger, badder, and better.</sp>

           <sd><directNote kind="zoom">Zoom in on each of the last two adjectives</directNote> to an <stageDesc category="close-up">extreme close-up</stageDesc>, then <directNote kind="cut">cut to
               <char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char> </directNote>.</sd>

           <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>Say wh--?!<sd><char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char> is bashed with the
                cane.</sd>OW!!</sp>

           <sp><spkr ref="MadMod">Mad Mod</spkr>You're in my world now. And you won't be getting
                out 'til you've learned some proper respect.</sp>

           <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>We will get out. And when we do--</sp>

           <sd>A gesture of the cane is followed by the ringing of a school bell.</sd>

           <sp><spkr ref="MadMod">Mad Mod</spkr>Oh, dear, there's the bell, my
                    duckies.<sd>salutes</sd>Off to class!</sp>

           <sd><directNote kind="pan">Pan across the row</directNote>, from<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char>  to <char ref="Robin">Robin</char>  the floor tile under each chair opens
                like a trapdoor, dumping chair and Titan out of sight. <directNote kind="cut">Cut to another area</directNote>, the
                camera pointing at the checkerboard ceiling.<char ref="Robin">Robin</char>  drops into view and makes a
                perfect four-point landing in the middle of the floor. Chair and camera rotate until
                both are facing a large blackboard. <directNote kind="pull">Pull back</directNote>; the side walls are blank, the board
                is on the end wall, and two busts of<char ref="MadMod">Mad Mod</char>  flank it. The man's face is quickly
                drawn on in chalk as the board speaks with his voice.</sd>

           <sp><spkr ref="Blackboard">Blackboard</spkr>Now how can I teach you anything if you
                won't sit still and listen?</sp>

           <sd>A wooden hand extends from the chair's top edge and grabs<char ref="Robin">Robin</char> 's head.</sd>

           <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>Huh?</sp>

           <sd>He tries to wriggle out of the grasp, but with no luck; it is pulling back on his
                scalp, forcing his eyes wide open.</sd>

           <sp><spkr ref="Blackboard">Blackboard</spkr>One of my hypnoscreens ought to get your
                attention and it'll erase everything in your brain as well.</sp>

           <sd>On the end of this, the chalk face swirls away and the board is replaced by a
                pulsating pattern of concentric black and white rings. His laughter rings in the
                room.</sd>

           <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr><sd>straining on every word</sd>Can't let him
                hypnotize me...got to stay focused...</sp>

           <sd><directNote kind="zoom">Zoom in slowly on his face</directNote>; his eyes are pulled even wider open, and the pattern
                starts to affect him. <directNote kind="pull">Pull back across the room</directNote> to show the rings flashing across
                every wall. With great effort,<char ref="Robin">Robin</char>  manages to tip the chair onto its side,
                breaking some of the wood from one of its arms. Underneath, his wrist is held down
                with a metal clamp. He flicks a small lockpick out from one finger of that glove,
                uses it to free that arm in short order, and tears the wooden hand from the chair
                top. One hard throw cracks the hypnoscreen wall and puts it out of business; now he
                sets about freeing his other three limbs. The other walls have returned to normal,
                and<char ref="MadMod">Mad Mod</char> 's voice makes itself heard over a hidden speaker.</sd>

           <sp><spkr ref="MadMod">Mad Mod</spkr>Naughty snotty. If you're gonna destroy school
                property, school property's gonna destroy you.</sp>

           <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>Whoa.</sp>

           <sd><directNote kind="cut">Cut to the ruined wall</directNote>. Something very large starts to push through; it is a fabric
                screen, and the <directNote kind="pull">camera pulls back to frame this</directNote>: an enormous missile ready to
                launch.</sd>

           <sp><spkr ref="MadMod">Mad Mod</spkr>Right, then. Count along with <char ref="MadMod">Moddy</char>.</sp>

           <sd>One of the two busts extends laser muzzles from its eyes and spinning blades on
                jointed arms from its ears.</sd>

           <sp><spkr ref="MadMod">Mad
                Mod</spkr>Ten...nine...eight...seven...six...five...four...three...two...one!</sp>

           <sd>The following things occur during the countdown. On "ten," the bust and its
                identically aimed counterpart move in and fire at <char ref="Robin">Robin</char>  On "eight," he rolls across
                the floor and hurls himself at them. On "six," he hides behind one and ducks as the
                other fires and blows its head off. On "four," he pushes the remains aside, gives
                the missile a good long look, and bolts to the ruined wall. Finally, on "one," he
                dives through the cloth to make his escape.</sd>

           <sd>Ignition. <directNote kind="cut">Cut to a head-on view of<char ref="Robin">Robin</char> </directNote>, now going full tilt down a tunnel done out
                in the checkerboard pattern. The weapon roars up behind him, entering through a
                trick black panel, and detonates with a blast that throws him against the wall. He
                stands up and dusts himself off before polishing the R on his tunic.</sd>

           <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>There goes my shot at perfect attendance.</sp>

           <sp><spkr ref="MadMod">Mad Mod</spkr><sd>from o.c.</sd>Don't be so sure, my little
                duckie.</sp>

           <sd>Shift to point down the tunnel. Sure enough, there he is down the way, now wearing a
                dark suit. This will be his basic outfit for the rest of the episode.</sd>

           <sp><spkr ref="MadMod">Mad Mod</spkr>You may be out of the classroom, but class is
                never dismissed.</sp>

           <sd>He goes up the side, so that he is standing upside down on the top surface, and runs
                at the camera. Side view: he passes overhead as<char ref="Robin">Robin</char>  jumps up in a vain attempt to
                grab him.</sd>

           <sp><spkr ref="MadMod">Mad Mod</spkr>Next lesson: physics!</sp>

           <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>Huh?</sp>

           <sp><spkr ref="MadMod">Mad Mod</spkr>What goes up, stays up!</sp>

           <sd>He laughs and runs off.</sd>

           <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>Until I take it down!</sp>

           <sd>The chase begins, ranging through a network of staircases and arches that connect
                floor to floor. <directNote kind="tilt">Tilt up to follow them</directNote>; through a trick of perspective and design,
                the checkerboard ceiling has more stairs coming down from it. M. C. Escher would be
                proud of the overall effect. Now they move into a region of black and white cubes,
               <char ref="Robin">Robin</char>  right side up and<char ref="MadMod">Mad Mod</char>  upside down, approaching from opposite directions.
                The camera turns 180 degrees to reverse their positions, and the Titan tumbles to
                his enemy's level with a yell and a thud.<char ref="MadMod">Mad Mod</char>  hops over him and runs off.</sd>

           <sd>The chase resumes, now against a field partially filled with checkerboard tiling.
                The upper portion is filled with vertical black and white stripes; the overall
                effect is of a half-woven basket.<char ref="MadMod">Mad Mod</char>  and<char ref="Robin">Robin</char>  dash along the interface between
                the two regions, disappearing briefly behind each black stripe. Suddenly, the
                redhead doubles back and descends a staircase hidden among the squares, and<char ref="Robin">Robin</char> 
                stays hot on his heels. Now they move into an area consisting of two side-by-side
                sets of concentric squares.<char ref="MadMod">Mad Mod</char>  runs into the left set, a tunnel, and does a
                sharp turn into one of the white bands. When<char ref="Robin">Robin</char>  tries to follow, he runs flat
                into a wall.</sd>

           <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>How did he--?</sp>

           <sd><char ref="MadMod">Mad Mod</char> emerges on the right and runs o.c. while blowing a raspberry back at him.
               <char ref="Robin">Robin</char>  gives chase. <directNote kind="cut">Cut to a closed door</directNote> and <directNote kind="pull">pull back as he opens it</directNote> and enters. A
                loud whistle from o.c. draws his attention; he sees the crazed Englishman at the top
                of that long staircase seen in the prologue. They are back in the main atrium.</sd>

           <sp><spkr ref="MadMod">Mad Mod</spkr><sd>twirling his cane</sd>You may as well chuck in
                the sponge, laddie! You can't catch the likes of me!</sp>

           <sd>Determined to prove him wrong,<char ref="Robin">Robin</char>  charges toward the stairs and bounds up the
                banisters. A wave of the cane, and we see a <stageDesc category="close-up">close-up of him</stageDesc>, running full tilt, then
                his feet pounding up the steps. <directNote kind="pull">Pull back slightly to frame all of him</directNote>, then back
                farther to show that the staircases have become long escalators; he is on the down
                one and getting nowhere fast.<char ref="MadMod">Mad Mod</char>  stands at the top, against a black-and-white
                sunburst, but this soon gives way to the normal wall.</sd>

           <sp><spkr ref="MadMod">Mad Mod</spkr>Now what did I tell you? Children today won't
                listen to their betters! Have to learn everything the hard--</sp>

           <sd>On the end of this, <directNote kind="cut">cut to a <stageDesc category="close-up">close-up</stageDesc> of a birdarang</directNote> thrown by <char ref="Robin">Robin</char>  whirling
                through the air, then pull back. It ricochets off the railing in front of the
                Cockney crackpot.</sd>

           <sp><spkr ref="MadMod">Mad Mod</spkr>Hey, oy! No throwing things while teacher is
                talking!</sp>

           <sd>The "miscreant" fires a grappling hook that embeds itself in the wall above the
                doorway as<char ref="MadMod">Mad Mod</char>  runs out, then reels himself up to the landing. <directNote kind="cut">Cut to the other
                side of the doors</directNote>; he bursts through and stands up for a look around. One eyebrow
                jumps in complete surprise, and the camera <directNote kind="cut">cuts to behind him</directNote> and <directNote kind="tilt">tilts up slowly to
                show the whole place</directNote>. He has come out in an atrium that looks exactly like the one
                he just left.</sd>

           <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>What?!?<sd>Back to him.</sd>You've gotta be kidding
                me!</sp>

           <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr><sd>from o.c.</sd>NOOOO!!</sp>

           <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr><char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char> </sp>

           <sd><directNote kind="cut">Cut to a set of very tall library shelves</directNote>, with a ladder set up to reach the topmost
                levels of one of them.<char ref="Robin">Robin</char>  climbs this; <directNote kind="tilt">tilt up slightly to frame this area</directNote>, a
                maze of shelves stretching as far as the eye can see, and a checkerboard ceiling
                over the lot.</sd>

           <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr><sd>from o.c.</sd>NOOOOOOOOO!!</sp>

           <sd><directNote kind="pan">Pan across the library</directNote> to show that another hypnoscreen has been set up among the
                stacks. <directNote kind="cut">Cut to it</directNote>; the display is shaped like a giant book, propped up and open, and
                rows of desks have been set up before it.<char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char>  is at the rear center, thrashing
                from side to side with her eyes tightly shut, but two thin arms reach from the top
                of her chair.</sd>

           <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr>I will not read your book of meanness and
                swirls!</sp>

           <sd>The arms grab her head and force her to face front.</sd>

           <sp><spkr ref="MadMod">Mad Mod</spkr>Now, now, love, it's for your own good.<sd>She
                    begins to succumb.</sd>Nothing teaches discipline and respect like a
                brain-erasing trance.</sp>

           <sd>She closes her eyes on the end of this, but the wooden fingers soon pry them back
                open; she gasps in shock and looks upward. <directNote kind="tilt">Tilt up to the ceiling</directNote>, where a large
                section of tiling opens to reveal a giant rubber "OVERDUE" stamp. The letters are
                shaped backwards, right to left, so that the word can be properly read after
                use.</sd>

           <sp><spkr ref="MadMod">Mad Mod</spkr>Besides, if you won't stop squirming...</sp>

           <sd>It pistons down and stamps the floor, crushing a few desks to splinters.</sd>

           <sp><spkr ref="MadMod">Mad Mod</spkr>...I won't stop squashing!</sp>

           <sd>The stamp moves closer and cycles again. Gasping in sheer terror,<char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char>  renews
                her efforts to get out of that chair; her head has been released. Now it comes down
                right in front of her, throwing bits of wood in her face. As she stares, horrified,
                the string of huge rubber letters positions itself directly over her head and
                hurtles down. <stageDesc category="overhead-shot">Overhead </stageDesc><stageDesc category="close-up">close-up of her</stageDesc>; as the oblong shadow falls across her face,
                she lets go with a scream of abject fear. <directNote kind="fade">Fade to black</directNote>.</sd>

       </act>
       <act n="2">
           <title>Act Two</title>
           <sd><stageDesc category="open-shot">Opening shot</stageDesc>: a slightly longer <stageDesc category="overhead-shot">overhead view of<char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char> </stageDesc>. The shadow of that rubber
                stamp falls on her, and she screams much longer and louder than before.<char ref="Robin">Robin</char>  dives
                across the floor and plows her out of the way a split second before OVERDUE is
                stamped into the tiles. <directNote kind="pan">Pan to them</directNote>; the chair has been knocked onto its back, and
               <char ref="Robin">Robin</char>  pulls out a tiny welding torch to attack the energy restraints that have been
                neutralizing her starbolts.</sd>

           <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr>Are all the schools on your planet this
                horrible?</sp>

           <sd>He frees her. New problem: books come off the shelves and start flapping toward the
                two Titans like giant bats.</sd>

           <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>Come on!</sp>

           <sd>She is yanked up and o.c. with a gasp; a moment later, some of the books hit her
                chair and explode, blowing it to bits. They reach a set of shelves and head straight
                up;<char ref="Robin">Robin</char>  climbing,<char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char>  flying, as more volumes hit and detonate all around
                them.<char ref="Robin">Robin</char>  is jarred loose by the blasts and falls screaming back toward the
                attacking literature, but<char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char>  makes a last-second grab and hauls him up.</sd>

           <sd>They leap along the tops of the shelves, avoiding the oncoming books while<char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char> 
                shoots one or two down, and the <directNote kind="pan">camera pans to follow</directNote>. <directNote kind="cut">Cut to a closed door</directNote>,
                "Library: Quiet Please", set in a wall that is tiled with concentric squares.
               <char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char>  and<char ref="Robin">Robin</char>  burst out, slam it shut, and lean on it with their full weight; a
                final, hefty explosion from the other side nearly pushes it open again. Smoke drifts
                out through the cracks as<char ref="Robin">Robin</char>  strides away and she follows.</sd>

           <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr><char ref="Robin">Robin</char>  I wish to thank you for rescuing me
                from-</sp>

           <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>Don't thank me yet.<sd>They stop.</sd><char ref="MadMod">Mad Mod</char> still
                has us right where he wants us. I know we could take him if we could just get our
                hands on him.<sd>Busts roll up behind them.</sd>But every time we get out of one
                trap...</sp>

           <sd><char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char> turns to look behind and gasps upon seeing them. <stageDesc category="close-up">Close-up of the
                sculptures</stageDesc>, <directNote kind="pan">panning slowly across</directNote>. The sunglasses on one slide up the forehead and a
                missile pops out of the nose; spinning blades emerge from another's ears; a third's
                jaw opens to reveal a stun gun; the hair of the last rises to show a cannon inside
                the head. <directNote kind="gag">Sight gag:<char ref="Robin">Robin</char> 's head has grown a few sizes, a vein throbs on his
                temple, and he looks something like a very annoyed caveman</directNote>.</sd>

           <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr><sd>through gritted teeth</sd>...there's another one
                waiting.</sp>

           <sd>The gag ends. He gets ready for a little kung fu action, but<char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char>  thinks better
                of it when a cannon shot lands too close for comfort. She yanks him off into one of
                the square patterns.</sd>

           <sp><spkr ref="MadMod">Mad Mod</spkr>Run, my duckies!<sd><stageDesc category="overhead-shot">Overhead view of them</stageDesc>, heading
                    left to right.</sd>Run all you like, but you'll never get out!</sp>

           <sd>On the end of this the camera turns 90 degrees to frame them now moving from bottom
                to top, then moves ahead to show a spiraling pattern of concentric squares just
                ahead. They reach it and tumble screaming toward its center-gravity has just
                hiccuped again. <directNote kind="cut">Cut to inside another room</directNote>, near ceiling level; the tiles are all
                white here and marked with the symbols of the periodic table. Some giant models of
                molecules have been set up as well. As the yells grow louder, the tile marked for
                Zirconium flips open and the two teens drop out.<char ref="Robin">Robin</char>  tumbles along the floor while
               <char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char>  brings herself to a midair stop above him; <directNote kind="pan">pan to follow them across</directNote>. Giant
                beakers and test tubes filled with solutions line the walls, along with a microscope
                and a Bunsen burner, we have just reached the chemistry lab. They now head further
                into the room; as they pass behind each container of chemicals, their image distorts
                in a different way.</sd>

           <sp><spkr ref="MadMod">Mad Mod</spkr>It's no good procrastinating, really, because
                sooner or later, you'll both end up like him.</sp>

           <sd><char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char> gasps.</sd>

           <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr><sd>as the <directNote kind="pan">camera pans ahead</directNote></sd><char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> </sp>

           <sd>Stop on the end of the lab, where a few desks have been set up. A head can just be
                seen over the top of a chair that is front and center, positioned for a full view of
                the overhead projector screen that hangs down from the ceiling at an angle. The
                hypnotic pattern is playing across it. Head-on view of the chair; it is indeed <char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char>, wearing a dunce cap, fully under the screen's spell, drool running down his
                chin, babbling incoherently.<char ref="Robin">Robin</char>  and<char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char>  move in for a look.</sd>

           <sp><spkr ref="MadMod">Mad Mod</spkr>Ah, yeah. A model student, that one. Lovely. Sits
                there, quietly, never thinks about misbehaving, matter of fact, he never thinks at
                all!</sp>

           <sd>Laughter.</sd>

           <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr><char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char>  Awaken!<sd>waves in his face and
                    removes the cap;<char ref="Robin">Robin</char>  uses his torch</sd>Your friends are here! <char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> </sp>

           <sd>She snaps her fingers; no good. Now she steps to the screen and warms up a starbolt
                to knock it out, but<char ref="Robin">Robin</char>  stops her before she can fire.</sd>

           <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>Wait! Trust me.</sp>

           <sd><directNote kind="pan">Pan back along the length of the room</directNote>. The test tubes blow their stoppers and all
                the chemicals in the place boil over. Colorful toxic slop spreads across the floor,
                dissolving desks as it reaches them.<char ref="Robin">Robin</char>  frees<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char>  from the chair and hands
                him to <char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char> </sd>

           <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>Here's your hall pass. Meet you outside.</sp>

           <sd>She flies away, and he leapfrogs along the disintegrating desks to traverse the lab.
                Riding one like a surfboard, he approaches the door, where<char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char>  has already made
                it out, and vaults to one of the molecular models and then over to her. He ducks
                through the door and slams it shut. <directNote kind="fade">Fade to black</directNote>.</sd>

           <sd><directNote kind="fade">Fade in to the hypnoscreen pattern</directNote> and <directNote kind="pull">pull back to show it still playing in <char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char>'s eyes</directNote>. He is back in the main atrium.</sd>

           <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr><char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> </sp>

           <sd><directNote kind="pull">Pull back</directNote>. He sits crumpled on the floor, with<char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char>  and<char ref="Robin">Robin</char>  looking down
                concernedly, and he is now drooling all over his clothes.</sd>

           <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr>It is I, <char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char>  your friend. Please! Speak
                to me!<sd>louder</sd><char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char>  <char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> </sp>

           <sd>She knocks on his head a couple of times, then sucks in a huge breath. <directNote kind="gag">Sight gag:
                her head grows too many times normal size, and her next words are delivered with
                enough force to push the boys' faces back on their skulls</directNote>.<char ref="Robin">Robin</char>  shoves his fingers
                in his ears.</sd>

           <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr>BEEEEEEAAAAAASSSSSSTTTTTT
                BOOOOOOYYYYYY!!!!!!!!!!!</sp>

           <sd><stageDesc category="close-up">Close-up of him and<char ref="Robin">Robin</char>  on the end of this</stageDesc>. The gag ends.<char ref="Robin">Robin</char>  is left a bit
                stunned when the yell finally dies away, but<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char>  just drools and babbles some
                more before keeling over.</sd>

           <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>Ah, Star? I don't think that's working.</sp>

           <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr>But we must do something or he will remain this
                way forever.</sp>

           <sd><char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> sits up, wavers a bit, and tumbles against her midsection. A door is heard
                opening; she pushes him away.</sd>

           <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr><char ref="MadMod">Mad Mod</char>  Come on!</sp>

           <sd>He hustles away <char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char>  not quite sure of the proper hygiene protocol to follow
                here, yanks<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char>  after him; the three end up huddled behind the staircase. The
                next two lines are delivered sotto voce.</sd>

           <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>We'll hide here and then take him by surprise.</sp>

           <sd><stageDesc category="close-up">Close-up of him</stageDesc>. A little bit of random mumbling gets on his nerves very
                quickly.</sd>

           <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>Any way to keep him quiet?</sp>

           <sd><directNote kind="pan">Pan to the other two</directNote>.<char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char>  claps a hand over the slack mouth and shudders
                mightily as drool oozes through her fingers. <directNote kind="cut">Cut to just in front of the bottom
                stairs</directNote>;<char ref="Robin">Robin</char>  peeks out, sees a shadow approaching, then ducks back briefly and
                leaps out with<char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char>  right behind him. <stageDesc category="close-up">Extreme close-ups of the following</stageDesc>: his
                foot extended for a kick, her hands ready to fire a starbolt,<char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char> 's sonic cannon,
                a large black hand projected by <char ref="Raven">Raven</char>  There is a white flash, which clears to leave
                the four Titans ready to unload on each other;<char ref="Raven">Raven</char>  has suspended<char ref="Robin">Robin</char>  in
                midair.</sd>

           <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr><char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char>  <char ref="Raven">Raven</char> <sd>She winds down.</sd>Oh, how
                glad we are to see you!</sp>

           <sd><char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char> disarms;<char ref="Robin">Robin</char>  is set down.</sd>

           <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>This place is making me crazy!</sp>

           <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>Tell me about it.<char ref="MadMod">Mad Mod</char> 's wacked-out computer lab
                nearly crashed my hard drive.</sp>

           <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr><sd>to<char ref="Raven">Raven</char> </sd>Where did our captor send
                you?</sp>

           <sd><char ref="Raven">Raven</char> opens her cloak partially and reveals, instead of her usual black outfit, a
                white jersey with a large zero on its front. The sound of a basketball game is
                heard, complete with referee's whistle.</sd>

           <sp><spkr ref="Raven">Raven</spkr>Gym.</sp>

           <sd><directNote kind="tilt">Tilt down to her feet</directNote> as she exposes her clothing fully. Her usual blue wristbands
                have been replaced with white ones, the jersey has<char ref="MadMod">Mad Mod</char> 's name along with the
                zero, and she wears shorts, knee pads, and athletic shoes. The next time her cloak
                is seen open, she will be back in her normal clothing.</sd>

           <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>Anybody seen BB?</sp>

           <sd>Babbling from o.c.; they all look down toward the floor, and the <directNote kind="cut">camera cuts to him</directNote>
                there. He is slithering along like an inchworm, with copious amounts of saliva
                lubricating the path.</sd>

           <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr><char ref="MadMod">Mad Mod</char>'s hypnoscreens. We can't snap him out of it.
                We've tried everything.</sp>

           <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>Did you try this?</sp>

           <sd><stageDesc category="close-up">Close-up of the unfortunate Titan</stageDesc>, now on his feet.<char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char>  leans down, pulls one ear
                wide open, and fires a major-league belch directly into it.<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char>  laughs, shaken
                out of his trance.</sd>

           <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>Nice one!<sd>His laughter dies.</sd>Uh...how
                did I get here and why am I covered in drool?</sp>

           <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr>Wonderful! Now we need only to locate an
                exit.</sp>

           <sd><char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char> breaks out his cannon.</sd>

           <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>Or just keep blasting 'til we make one.</sp>

           <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>Easy.<sd>Close-up.</sd>Last thing I smashed tried to
                smash me back. I'm sure this whole place is booby-trapped.</sp>

           <sd><char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> pops up nearby and wipes himself clean.</sd>

           <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>Then how are we supposed to get out?</sp>

           <sp><spkr ref="Raven">Raven</spkr><sd>from o.c.</sd>We're not.<sd><directNote kind="cut">Cut to her and<char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char> </directNote>
                    and <directNote kind="zoom">zoom in.</directNote></sd>Don't you get it?<char ref="MadMod">Mad Mod</char> 's just gonna keep messing with us
                until--</sp>

           <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>--We mess with him. That cane of his controls
                everything in here. We take the cane--</sp>

           <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>--We take control--</sp>

           <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>--And take him down!<sd>He crosses the floor;
                    <directNote kind="pan">pan to follow</directNote>.</sd>Oh, I'll find him. That demented doofus is never hypnotizing
                me again!</sp>

           <sd>A painting on the wall pops out and swings to face him, showing that hypnotic ring
                pattern. In no time flat, he is salivating, gurgling, and stumbling to the floor.
               <char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char>  catches him.</sd>

           <sp><spkr ref="MadMod">Mad Mod</spkr><sd>from o.c.</sd>Come on.</sp>

           <sd><directNote kind="cut">Cut to a corner</directNote>. He rises into view through a trick black tile in the floor.</sd>

           <sp><spkr ref="MadMod">Mad Mod</spkr>Won't you lot ever learn?<sd>balancing cane on one
                    finger, then twirling it</sd>You're in my world, my duckies.<sd>He presses the
                    ruby; the doors behind him open.</sd>You can't win.</sp>

           <sd>He is off in a heartbeat.</sd>

           <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr><sd>leading<char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char>  and<char ref="Raven">Raven</char>  away</sd>Titans!
                Go!</sp>

           <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr>But how do I--?</sp>

           <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr><sd>talks over his shoulder</sd>Make him
                laugh!</sp>

           <sd>She finds herself standing alone, supporting the hypnotized Titan by his armpits.
                After a moment, she hoists him up to look him in the eye and smiles broadly.</sd>

           <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr>How many Okaarans does it take to hoegee a
                morflark? Finbarr!</sp>

           <sd>No change in his mumbling and driveling; apparently, the joke loses something if the
                listener is not conversant in Tamaranean.<char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char>  thinks for a second.</sd>

           <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr>Um...boo-gers?</sp>

           <sd>That does the trick.</sd>

           <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr><sd>laughing</sd>Boogers!<sd>He realizes <char ref="MadMod">Mad Mod</char> got him again.</sd>Aw, man!</sp>

           <sd>He is yanked off with a shout to join the chase. <annot>Music cue: "K2G" by Puffy AmiYumi:
                a light, energetic tune reminiscent of the "two-tone" ska style that emerged in
                Britain during the late 1970s. The lyrics, which are in Japanese, are not reproduced
                here</annot>. <directNote kind="cut">Cut to a hall lined with various pictures of<char ref="MadMod">Mad Mod</char> </directNote>; the real McCoy, wearing
                goggles and with a sheepskin coat and helmet over his suit, zooms along and o.c. on
                a motor scooter. He will wear these extra items whenever he is on the vehicle. The
                Titans go after him, passing a picture of him in his original outfit. A bunch of
                bananas hides the face, but the painting pulls them away and glares after the team;
                he has pulled a quick change and given them the slip.</sd>

           <sd>The camera shifts to point down the hall; a statue resembling Michelangelo's David
                is in the fore, but with<char ref="MadMod">Mad Mod</char> 's head and a round Union Jack patch covering the
                waist. The bananas are thrown after the Titans, who are at the far end, and the
                lunatic jumps out of the frame and runs off; they charge after him. Now back in his
                suit and reclining on his scooter's seat, he motors down the hall and off-camera The
                five heroes do likewise, but a mighty flash from that direction sends them back the
                way they came.<char ref="MadMod">Mad Mod</char>  is after them, having ditched the coat in favor of an
                enormous bazooka which he fires time after time.</sd>

           <sd><directNote kind="cut">Cut to a long, wide room</directNote> whose white floor and ceiling are marked with a lattice of
                large holes.<char ref="MadMod">Mad Mod</char>  rolls in and drops out of sight; the Titans try to follow, but
                the hole has solidified to block them. As<char ref="Robin">Robin</char>  drums his fingers on the floor, the
                nutcase pops back up two spots over, without his scooter. The team leader runs to
                grab him, but suddenly drops through the hole between him and <char ref="MadMod">Mad Mod</char>  who rises
                through the ceiling. <char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> <transform class="mammal">briefly becomes a tiger</transform> and jumps after the villain;
                the other three start poking their heads in everywhere, and out in all sorts of
                impossible places.<char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char>  even picks up one hole, holds it sideways, and steps
                through; it falls flat like a manhole cover, and<char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char>  jumps on it for a moment
                and shrugs before plummeting out of sight.<char ref="Raven">Raven</char>  is left floating by herself in the
                middle of the screen as the other four heads start popping up all around her like a
                Whack-a-Mole game gone haywire. She is scared into a hole when<char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char>  peeks up with
                his head much larger than normal. A moment later, all five reappear, with musical
                instruments and dressed in the sort of garish clothes often used by British bands of
                the 1960s. Guitar: <char ref="Robin">Robin</char>  Bass: <char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char>  Keyboard: <char ref="Raven">Raven</char>  Drums: <char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> 
                Tambourine: <char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char> <char ref="MadMod">Mad Mod</char>  drives past, once again leaning back on the seat, and
                the Titans zip out of their new threads to give chase.</sd>

           <sd><directNote kind="cut">Cut to a long, winding staircase</directNote>.<char ref="MadMod">Mad Mod</char>  is powering his scooter up the incline,
                they race along for all they are worth, and he reaches a door at the top and stops.
                A press of the cane's ruby turns the stairs into a slide, sending the three boys
                down and off-camera;<char ref="Raven">Raven</char>  and <char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char>  floating above the surface, watch them go.
                At the bottom, a hatch opens and a short stretch of stairs emerges, turning itself
                into a set of snapping jaws. <char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> screams and <transform class="fish">becomes an octopus</transform>. As he nears
                the floor,<char ref="Raven">Raven</char>  and<char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char>  make it down; he stops his slide by wrapping two
                tentacles around the former while the latter grabs two others.<char ref="Robin">Robin</char>  thumps into
                him, then starts to panic just in time to get four hundred pounds of bionic Titan
                plowed into his face, but the makeshift safety net holds.<char ref="Robin">Robin</char>  sits up, dazed and
                with his teeth momentarily knocked out of alignment, and the girls haul them and
               <char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char>  toward the camera.<char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char>  gives<char ref="Robin">Robin</char>  a shrug and a sheepish grin.</sd>

           <sd>They are carried up and o.c., and the view changes behind them to show a hall with
                many doors on either side, seen from one end. A<char ref="MadMod">Mad Mod</char>  bust stands at the other. He
                rides in and, as the Titans slide through in a heap, exits through a far door. <char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> <transform class="human">reverts to human form</transform> and stands there, slightly dazed, while the other four
                bolt to the other end. The Limey runs across the hall and soon has <transform class="mammal">a green dog</transform>
                nipping at his heels. Now<char ref="Robin">Robin</char>  peeks out, catches sight of him, and runs that way
                while<char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char>  crosses the hall. <char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char>  <transform class="mammal">as a gorilla</transform>, shambles through and just
                misses<char ref="MadMod">Mad Mod</char>  riding a "penny-farthing" bicycle;<char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char>  chases him as<char ref="Raven">Raven</char>  goes
                the other way. One door flips up to the ceiling, the opposite one down onto the
                floor, and<char ref="MadMod">Mad Mod</char>  drives across in an old-style roadster. Here comes<char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char>  from a
                near door; he heads back and through a farther one, but his image does not shrink as
                one might expect due to perspective, and he has to crawl out. Now<char ref="Robin">Robin</char>  dashes out
                close to the back wall and toward a near door; the perspective trick is reversed,
                and he comes up very small and has to jump to it. However, he gets the hinges
                instead of the knob and the door swings open the wrong way. Out he goes.</sd>

            <sd><char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char> charges across, riding <char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> <transform class="bird">as an ostrich</transform>, and <char ref="MadMod">Mad Mod</char>  now wearing a
                coonskin cap atop his suit, paddles a canoe across the floor.<char ref="Raven">Raven</char>  flies out and
                 hangs for just a moment before <char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char>  <transform class="mammal">as a gargantuan gerbil</transform>, runs across; her
                eyes pop in surprise and she follows him out. Now<char ref="Robin">Robin</char>  runs into the hall and
                watches as the other four Titans go everywhere;<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char>  now seems to be switching
                forms almost at random - a whale, a pygmy elephant, a penguin, a monkey. Doors open
                and close just as randomly; against their hinges, from lower panels. the Titans
                dashing through as perspective-tricked miniatures, by swinging towards the ceiling
                and floors. Finally, all the Titans gather in one place, and<char ref="Robin">Robin</char>  points furiously
                in several directions. They fan out to five different doors, and at a signal from
                <char ref="Robin">Robin</char>  pull them open all at once. Nothing behind any of them, so as the music
                disintegrates into random notes, they tiptoe to the door nearest the camera, which
                no one tried.<char ref="Robin">Robin</char>  smirks at his comrades and yanks the knob, and all scream as the
                head of a colossal reptilian creature pokes through and roars at them.</sd>

           <sd>The music resumes at this point. <char ref="MadMod">Mad Mod</char>  meanwhile, steps leisurely from a far door
                and waves to them before walking back out. The bust moves slightly; <stageDesc category="close-up">close-up of it</stageDesc>.
                The Titans run up, <char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> <transform class="human">back in human form</transform>, and<char ref="Robin">Robin</char>  flips the head back to
                expose a knob. A quick twist, and the music stops. <directNote kind="snap">Snap to black</directNote>, then <directNote kind="wipe">wipe to the
                five</directNote>; this is the other side of a door that has just opened. The faces go slack with
                surprise, and the camera <directNote kind="cut">cuts to behind them</directNote> to show that the entire end wall has
                opened up to expose a peaceful meadow beyond it.</sd>

           <sp><spkr ref="Raven">Raven</spkr>No way!</sp>

           <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>Is that what I think it is?</sp>

           <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>One way to find out.</sp>

           <sd>They start walking towards the meadow and pass into it.</sd>

           <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>Looks like the real deal.</sp>

           <sd><char ref="Robin">Robin</char> holds up one hand and waves it around. <directNote kind="cut">Cut to a white patch of wall</directNote>, which
                bulges out at its center-a fabric screen, with them on the other side. It tears
                open, dumping them onto the floor.<char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char>  gasps.</sd>

           <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>No!</sp>

           <sd><char ref="Robin">Robin</char> grunts in disgust. <directNote kind="fade">Fade to black</directNote>.</sd>

       </act>
       <act n="3">
           <title>Act Three</title>
           <sd><stageDesc category="open-shot">Opening shot: the Titans in the atrium where all this began</stageDesc>, or at least one
                identical to it.</sd>

           <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>Right back where we started!</sp>

           <sd>A section of the floor flips over, bringing<char ref="MadMod">Mad Mod</char>  into the room.</sd>

           <sp><spkr ref="MadMod">Mad Mod</spkr>Of course you are, my duckies.</sp>

           <sd>He taps the tiles with his cane and is promptly carried high into the air.</sd>

           <sp><spkr ref="MadMod">Mad Mod</spkr>Class is over, and you lot haven't learned a
                thing. That's a failing grade for each blooming one of you.</sp>

           <sd>A big, red F appears on the underside of the platform on the end of this. <directNote kind="cut">Cut to the
                very angry Titans</directNote>.</sd>

           <sp><spkr ref="MadMod">Mad Mod</spkr><sd>from o.c.</sd>There's only one thing for
                    it.<sd>Doors swing shut in front of the torn fabric; <directNote kind="cut">cut to him</directNote>.</sd>You'll have
                to repeat the entire lesson!</sp>

           <sd>The stairs retract up to the first balcony as he says this, after which all the
                walls fall outward to expose a curving black-and-white sunburst pattern all around.
                It is broken only by the doors and paintings, which remain exactly where they were.
                Many more busts move in, sporting a nasty variety of weapons. <stageDesc category="close-up">Close-up of him</stageDesc>,
                laughing maniacally, and <directNote kind="pull">pull back to show this scene playing across<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> 's
                corneas;</directNote> his figure fades away. Standing in the middle of the others, the newly
                re-hypnotized Titan starts to babble and drivel as he crumples slowly toward the
                ground.<char ref="Raven">Raven</char>  catches him. Here come the statues.</sd>

           <sp><spkr ref="MadMod">Mad Mod</spkr>Time for class, my duckies. Everyone back to your
                seats!</sp>

           <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>Titans! Get that cane!</sp>

           <sd><char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char>  <char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char>  and<char ref="Robin">Robin</char>  in turn give a hearty yell and charge. <directNote kind="wipe">Wipe to a visibly
                disgusted<char ref="Raven">Raven</char> </directNote>, who is still trying to figure out what to do with <char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> </sd>

           <sp><spkr ref="Raven">Raven</spkr>Um...</sp>

           <sd>The fronts of several busts open up to reveal small missile launchers that fire off
                a heavy salvo.<char ref="Raven">Raven</char>  creates a shield to protect herself and her charge. She is lost
                beneath the glare of the explosions, but<char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char>  runs through them, catches up to
                <char ref="Robin">Robin</char>  and links his hands.<char ref="Robin">Robin</char>  jumps up onto the palms and gets a hefty upward
                boost; now a bust flies in and<char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char>  wheels to face it. A single punch crushes it
                to gravel.</sd>

           <sd><char ref="Robin">Robin</char> has begun hopping from one airborne stone head to another, dodging the
                occasional laser blast along the way, and finally hurls himself through space. A
                bust flies in and starts to fire, but is blown apart by a starbolt. The shooter
                flies past the cloud of dust she has just created.</sd>

           <sp><spkr ref="MadMod">Mad Mod</spkr>Oy, no roughhousing! Do I have to separate you
                lot?</sp>

           <sd>He presses the ruby on his cane and causes the floor tiles to rise up as square
                columns.<char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char>  is on a collision course with<char ref="MadMod">Mad Mod</char>  and ready to shoot him full
                of holes, but a column rises in front of him without warning.</sd>

           <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr>Eek!</sp>

           <sd>She stops just barely short of the obstacle and tries to swerve around it, only to
                have that path cut off as well. Now the tile that was under her feet has reached her
                level and begun to carry her up; she gasps in shock as she rises against her will.
                Higher and higher she goes, with a forest of columns forming around her.</sd>

           <sd><char ref="Robin">Robin</char> has resumed his game of leapfrog on the busts' heads, and they in turn have
                gone back to using him for target practice. He goes for one huge leap and gets clear
                of them, but his face soon registers surprise.</sd>

           <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>Huh?</sp>

           <sd>He collides head-on with a column.<char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char>  is quickly hemmed in and carried toward
                the ceiling.</sd>

           <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>Yo!</sp>

           <sd>When the motion stops, we see that a staggered pyramid of steps has formed; think of
                the playfield layout for the arcade game Q*bert and you have the idea.<char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char>  and
               <char ref="Robin">Robin</char>  are on different levels of the structure, but<char ref="Robin">Robin</char>  has no time to ponder the
                geometry; laser shots from above force him to start jumping from one level to the
                next. He works his way up and seizes a passing bust, which carries him yelling
                toward a floating door. Working up a little momentum, he flips clear just before the
                sculpture crashes into it and explodes. He throws a birdarang at <char ref="MadMod">Mad Mod</char>  who leaps
                straight up to avoid it and passes him in midair.</sd>

           <sd>A bust flies by and strafes, just missing<char ref="Raven">Raven</char>  and <char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char>  then doubles back for
                another pass as two others join it.</sd>

           <sp><spkr ref="Raven">Raven</spkr>Azarath Metrion Zinthos!</sp>

           <sd>Three floor tiles, standing vertical, hurtle through the air and hit the attacking
                stoneworks edge on to slice them in half. The pieces tumble down around <char ref="Raven">Raven</char> 
                followed by a yelling <char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char>  who has been blown off his high perch.</sd>

           <sp><spkr ref="Raven">Raven</spkr>Little help here?<sd><stageDesc category="close-up">Close-up of<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> </stageDesc>; she
                    continues o.c.</sd>I don't do funny.</sp>

           <sd><char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char> stands up.</sd>

           <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>You asked for it.</sp>

           <sd>Her hood is up at this point, but<char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char>  pulls it back before she knows what is
                going on. Next, he licks his finger, depositing plenty of saliva on the tip, and
                shoves it into her ear; the classic "wet willie" torture. Her whole face looks as if
                it will split in half as her hair flies everywhere, but<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char>  snaps out of his
                trance and laughs.</sd>

           <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>Awesome!<sd>He realizes<char ref="MadMod">Mad Mod</char>  got him once
                    more.</sd>Aw, not again!</sp>

           <sd>With an angry spark flaring on her temple,<char ref="Raven">Raven</char>  puts her hood back up. A loud thump
                is heard from o.c.; the three turn toward it, and the <directNote kind="cut">camera cuts to the source</directNote>;
                busts with metal spider legs, jumping down from their high levels. <char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> <transform class="mammal">turns
                into a rhinoceros</transform> and charges, smashing a couple to bits, and<char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char>  shoots down a
                few flying ones. Having flipped onto her back to pull this off, she does not see one
                moving in with two thin metal arms extended from its shoulders. These grab her
                wrists.</sd>

           <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr>Huh?</sp>

           <sd><char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char> is hauled up with a scream and put into a half-spreadeagle; now a bust
                approaches and extends a laser chainsaw from its base. A swing of her legs knocks it
                away to slice a long gash through the cloth of the giant hypnoscreen that forms the
                wall.</sd>

           <cue>Animation goof: As she is carried up, her armband disappears briefly.</cue>

           <sd><char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char> watches this one explode as it falls behind the columns he is standing on,
                but the moment is short-lived. More busts, these on tall pedestals and tank treads,
                are coming down the vertical surfaces and up from a trapdoor to form an advancing
                line. He leaps down, incapacitates one with a kick, and seizes it. With a heave that
                would make any Olympic javelin thrower very proud, he sends it flying straight at
                the oncoming busts and destroys every one of them. Behind him, one more pops out,
                stun gun extended from the mouth, and rolls toward his back. He turns around just in
                time to get a hair-raising jolt, or it would be, if he had any hair, that drops him
                in his tracks.</sd>

           <sd>The place begins to rearrange itself; doors and paintings change locations, and the
                row of tiles he is lying on moves like a conveyor belt to carry him away. <directNote kind="pan">Pan from
                him to<char ref="Raven">Raven</char> </directNote>, who has been seized by a chair just like the one she was in at the
                start and is being dragged in.</sd>

           <sp><spkr ref="Raven">Raven</spkr>No!</sp>

           <sd>Her arms and legs are clamped down, and the white energy band fastens itself around
                her midsection. <directNote kind="pull">Pull back to show<char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char> </directNote> being hauled in by his own chair and put
               <char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char>  in view, still a rhino. A hypnoscreen pops up right in front of him;
                <transform class="human">reverting to human form</transform>, he turns his head and squeezes his eyes shut as a long
                metal arm reaches up.</sd>

           <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>Don't look at the screen, don't look at the
                    screen--<sd><char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> is grabbed by the head and he turned toward the
                    screen</sd>--don't look at the screen, don't look at the screen--</sp>

           <sd>For the fourth time this episode, he surrenders to the mind-numbing effects and
                starts burbling and drooling. <directNote kind="cut">Cut to<char ref="Robin">Robin</char> </directNote>, making his way quickly up toward <char ref="MadMod">Mad Mod</char>'s platform. Once he reaches it, he throws a kick that hits a big bunch of
                nothing as the villain easily sidesteps.<char ref="MadMod">Mad Mod</char>  plants his cane upright and
                balances on its end.</sd>

           <sp><spkr ref="MadMod">Mad Mod</spkr>Oh, give it a rest, snotty.<sd>gestured with his
                    cane, stays in midair</sd>You've already lost!</sp>

           <sd><char ref="Robin">Robin</char> looks down, sees<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char>  sitting before his screen and the other three
                Titans secured in chairs, then rushes at<char ref="MadMod">Mad Mod</char>  and leaps. <stageDesc category="close-up">Close-up of his hand</stageDesc>,
                reaching out toward the cane, but when the fingers reach the wooden shaft and close,
                they simply go right through it. <directNote kind="pull">Pull back a bit to frame his face</directNote>.</sd>

           <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>Huh?</sp>

           <sd>He passes through the cane and tumbles to the edge of the platform to look at his
                hand and figure out what has just happened.<char ref="MadMod">Mad Mod</char>  hops to his feet and does a
                little brandishing and twirling; close-up of the stick.</sd>

           <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr><sd>from o.c.</sd>The cane isn't real!<sd>Cut to
                    him.</sd>Which means<char ref="MadMod">Mad Mod</char>  is just as fake as everything else in here!</sp>

           <sd>He leaps straight at the Brit's image and runs right through it.</sd>

           <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>Time for a reality check!</sp>

           <sd>He flings himself off the edge with a yell; the holographic<char ref="MadMod">Mad Mod</char>  swings the cane
                and sends two busts out after him. <stageDesc category="close-up">Close-up of one base</stageDesc>, which opens to expose
                missiles locked on target, then <directNote kind="pull">pull back to frame both</directNote>, missiles and ear lasers
                ready to go. <directNote kind="cut">Cut to behind<char ref="Robin">Robin</char> </directNote> as he sails toward the rip made by the laser
                chainsaw, then to the busts as they fire their salvos. Now we see the room from just
                inside a small service duct; he tumbles in through the opening, with the ordnance
                exploding all around him. One mighty blast wipes out the entire screen.</sd>

           <sd><directNote kind="cut">Cut to a view of some machinery</directNote> and <directNote kind="pan">pan across on the next line</directNote>. The voice is that
                of <char ref="MadMod">Mad Mod</char>  but <charDesc ref="MadMod">the gray-haired figure that comes into view is very different from
                the dapper redheaded fellow who has been terrorizing the Titans all the way through.
                Seen from the back, he appears to be at least twenty years older and has lost all
                the hair on top</charDesc>. He is sitting in front of a bank of monitors, which show the team
                from many different angles, and working a complex array of controls. This is the
                actual, flesh-and-blood wacko and his real-life command center. One screen, however,
                displays only static.</sd>

           <sp><spkr ref="MadMod">Mad Mod</spkr>Yeah, this should teach those saucy little
                ankle-biters some respect.</sp>

           <sd>Head-on view. <charDesc ref="MadMod">He wears the same rectangular sunglasses, but his clothing is the sort
                you might expect on an old man of retirement age-plain, nondescript shirt and
                suit</charDesc>.</sd>

           <sp><spkr ref="MadMod">Mad Mod</spkr>Just a tick. I've lost <char ref="Robin">Robin</char> </sp>

           <sd>He is referring to the static-filled monitor. One by one, the other side screens
                wink out to leave only the large central one still working. He gasps; <directNote kind="cut">cut to the
                reason</directNote>, <char ref="Robin">Robin</char>  crawls around in the duct and rips out every handful of wiring he can
                find. In the crazed room, the three Titans in chairs struggle against their bonds as
                the fourth keeps slobbering all over the floor. The hypnotic pattern starts to
                waver, and the<char ref="MadMod">Mad Mod</char>  image steps into view.</sd>

           <sp><spkr ref="MadMod">Hologram Mad Mod</spkr>Uh...minor technical hitch, my
                    duckies.<sd>tugs his collar</sd>Pay no mind, I'll have it fixed in a--</sp>

           <sd>Before he can finish the sentence, he de-resolves and disappears. As the pattern
                shuts itself off, <char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char>  <char ref="Raven">Raven</char>  and<char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char>  break out of their chairs; the first
                with a loud "boo-yah", but<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char>  just stays on the floor, still mesmerized and
                salivating to beat the band. One after another, the pictures of<char ref="MadMod">Mad Mod</char>  fade away in
                their frames and crash to the floor; the surviving busts are knocked down as well.
                Now the fabric walls reel up like window shades, exposing the machinery that made
                all this insanity possible, and a forgotten door swings across on its support rope.
               <char ref="MadMod">Mad Mod</char>  yells and stumbles backward as his systems short out in a plume of smoke;
                <directNote kind="pan">pan to follow him</directNote>.</sd>

           <sp><spkr ref="MadMod">Mad Mod</spkr>My machines! That meddling little snot will pay
                for--</sp>

           <sd>A small cry of fear escapes him as he discovers<char ref="Robin">Robin</char>  waiting at the back of the
                room. He is promptly dragged forward by his lapels and cannot find his tongue for a
                second.</sd>

           <sp><spkr ref="MadMod">Mad Mod</spkr><sd>clearing his throat</sd>Hello, guv'nor.</sp>

           <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>School's out, <char ref="MadMod">Mod</char>. And you're looking at about twenty
                years of detention.</sp>

           <sd>The elderly Englishman recoils a bit at the prospect. <directNote kind="fade">Fade to black</directNote>.</sd>

           <sd>A shaft of light falls across the screen and illuminates <char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char>  who is opening an
                overhead hatch to see the sky above. <directNote kind="cut">Cut to outside it</directNote>; he puts his head up above a
                steel platform.</sd>

           <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>Ha!</sp>

           <sd>He climbs out, then <char ref="Raven">Raven</char>  and a properly trussed-up<char ref="MadMod">Mad Mod</char>  is thrown out after
                them.</sd>

           <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr><sd>stretches, as<char ref="Robin">Robin</char>  climbs up</sd>Oh, yeah,
                this is definitely the real deal.</sp>

           <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>School always seems smaller after you graduate,
                doesn't it?</sp>

           <sd><directNote kind="cut">Cut to inside the hatch</directNote>; the three peer down into it.</sd>

           <sp><spkr ref="Raven">Raven</spkr>Just don't expect me to go to any reunions.</sp>

           <sd>A moan from the o.c. <char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char>  <directNote kind="cut">cut to the platform</directNote> as she struggles up, carrying the
                fifth member of the team, and sets him down.</sd>

           <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr>I cannot awaken <char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char>  I have tried the
                tickling, all manner of bodily noises, and the word "underpants." I fear that this
                time his brain is gone forever.</sp>

           <sp><spkr ref="Raven">Raven</spkr><char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> had a brain?</sp>

           <sd>After a long moment, he sits up laughing; her sardonic remark has broken the
                trance.</sd>

           <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>Good one!</sp>

           <sd>Her meaning sinks in, wiping the smile off his face in a hurry. Everyone else heads
                away,<char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char>  carries <char ref="MadMod">Mad Mod</char> </sd>

           <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>Dude! That's not funny! I totally have a
                brain!</sp>

           <sd>Steam shoots from his ears, and he follows the group. <directNote kind="dissolve">Dissolve to a <stageDesc category="long-shot">long shot</stageDesc> of the
                platform</directNote> to show it in full detail; an offshore oil rig, and <directNote kind="pull">pull back slowly</directNote>. He
                cannot be seen at this distance.</sd>

           <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr><sd>from the platform</sd>I just don't use it
                much.</sp>

           <sd><directNote kind="fade">Fade to black</directNote>.</sd>
       </act>
   </body>
</root>