<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../schema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?><root>
    <head>
        <episode>APPRENTICE - PART 1</episode>
        <writer>David Slack</writer>
        <director>Ciro Nieli</director>
        <storyboard>Kalvin Lee, Rafael Rosado, Alan Wan</storyboard>
        <animation>Dong Woo Animation Company, Ltd.</animation>
        <source>https://teentitans.fandom.com/wiki/Apprentice_-_Part_1_(Transcript)</source>
        <issueList>
            <issueInfo link="../comic/issue-10.xml"/>
            <issueInfo link="../comic/issue-34.xml"/>
        </issueList>
    </head>
    <characterList>
        <charList type="recurring" id="Slade" subtype="villain">Slade</charList>
        <charList type="recurring" id="Robin" subtype="titan">Robin</charList>
        <charList type="recurring" id="Cyborg" subtype="titan">Cyborg</charList>
        <charList type="recurring" id="BeastBoy" subtype="titan">Beast Boy</charList>
        <charList type="recurring" id="Raven" subtype="titan">Raven</charList>
        <charList type="recurring" id="Starfire" subtype="titan">Starfire</charList>
        <charList type="nonrecurring" id="Man">Man</charList>
        <charList type="nonrecurring" id="Computer">Computer</charList>
        <charList type="recurring" id="Cinderblock">Cinderblock</charList>
    </characterList>
    <body>
        <act n="0">
            <title>Prologue</title>
            <sd><stageDesc category="open-shot">Opening shot: a pure white field, which resolves into <char ref="Robin">Robin</char>'s eye as <directNote kind="pull">the camera
                pulls back to frame him running flat out</directNote>.</stageDesc> <directNote kind="pull">Pull back again; he is chasing <char ref="Slade">Slade</char>
                across a rocky landscape under the starry night sky.</directNote> <directNote kind="pan">Pan across the area as <charDesc ref="Slade">the
                masked villain</charDesc> leaps across a deep crevasse, then to a rock formation that
                completely blocks the view.</directNote> When the camera passes the far edge, it has moved to <stageDesc category="close-up">a
                close-up of the two runners</stageDesc>. With<char ref="Robin">Robin</char> still close behind him,<char ref="Slade">Slade</char> bounds over
                another fissure and drops over <stageDesc category="setting">the edge of a mesa before making a beeline for a
                high, flat peninsula studded with several tower-like formations</stageDesc>. There is a narrow
                path leading to it, but he forgoes this in favor of a single long, high jump. <char ref="Robin">Robin</char>
                does likewise, landing in a crouch, and comes up for a wary look around.<char ref="Slade">Slade</char> steps
                out from behind a rock.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Slade">Slade</spkr>Dangerous behavior,<char ref="Robin">Robin</char>. You must be very eager to
                see me. I'm flattered.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>I'm not here to see you. I'm here to stop you.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="Slade">Slade</spkr>
                <sd>stepping closer; they circle</sd>Hmm. But how can you stop me, when you don't
                even know what I'm planning?</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>Like this.</sp>

            <sd>He rushes in with a savage kick;<char ref="Slade">Slade</char> dodges easily, and the follow-up punch only
                smashes a chunk from one of the towers. The two spare a bit, after which<char ref="Robin">Robin</char> finds
                himself on the defensive and tries a charging punch.<char ref="Slade">Slade</char> catches his fist and
                hurls him against a tower, but<char ref="Robin">Robin</char> rebounds quickly and tries a punch that
                pulverizes more rock. One strike after another misses its mark but sends up clouds
                of stone dust. <charDesc ref="Slade"><char ref="Slade">Slade</char>'s eye glows briefly during this string of attacks</charDesc>; at the end
                of it, he lands a powerful kick that staggers <charDesc ref="Robin">the Titan</charDesc> very badly. He is soon on
                his feet and fighting back, but his punches are blocked and he takes one that bowls
                him over again.</sd>

            <sd>When he gets up this time, he has a birdarang in each hand and lets them fly. <char ref="Slade">Slade</char>
                stands his ground, arms crossed in front of himself; there is a quick flash and
                clang of metal on metal, and we see each weapon in turn smash into a tower. The
                formations begin to crumble, and <directNote kind="pull">the camera pulls back to <stageDesc category="overhead-shot">an overhead view to show
                them all toppling in a cloud of dust that covers the entire area</stageDesc></directNote>. <stageDesc category="close-up">Close-up; <char ref="Robin">Robin</char>'s
                silhouette appears within the haze, and he steps into the open to survey the place.</stageDesc>
                His eyes pop when he looks off to his right; the dust clears as he sidles off that
                way.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Slade">Slade</spkr>
                <sd>from o.c.</sd>Excellent,<char ref="Robin">Robin</char>.<sd>passing crumbled formations behind him</sd>
                We appear to be evenly matched and equally ruthless.</sp>

            <sd>Back to<char ref="Robin">Robin</char>, now easing around within the dust, on the end of this.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Slade">Slade</spkr>
                <sd>off-screen</sd>Not surprising. You and I are so very much alike.</sp>

            <sd>As he finishes this line, the dust clears to show him standing behind<char ref="Robin">Robin</char>; the
                latter whirls to face him.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>I'm nothing like you!</sp>

            <sd>He throws an uppercut that connects squarely with the metal-covered jaw and sends
               <char ref="Slade">Slade</char> crashing to the ground.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>
                <sd>pulling him up</sd><charDesc ref="Slade">You're a criminal, a psychopath! All you care about is
                destruction!</charDesc></sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="Slade">Slade</spkr>And all you care about, you destroy.</sp>

            <sd>He gestures off to one side;<char ref="Robin">Robin</char> looks in that direction and sees the shattered
                debris left from the brawl. The base of one smashed pinnacle is shaped like <char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char>'s
                head, and <directNote kind="pan">as the camera pans across the rest of the rubble, broken likenesses of the
                other three Titans are seen</directNote>.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>
                <sd>horrified</sd>No!<sd>to Slade</sd>Who are you?!</sp>

            <sd>He reaches toward the face. <directNote kind="cut">Cut to an empty patch of sky</directNote>; the mask is flung up and
                away, and <directNote kind="cut">the camera cuts to <stageDesc category="close-up">a close-up of him</stageDesc></directNote> and <directNote kind="zoom">zooms in</directNote>. He is staring in
                bug-eyed shock, and <directNote kind="shift">a shift to just behind him shows why the face behind that smooth
                expanse of steel is his own</directNote>. The duplicate laughs heartily in <char ref="Slade">Slade</char>'s voice as <directNote kind="dissolve">the
                camera dissolves to <stageDesc category="overhead-shot">a long overhead shot of the ruined peninsula</stageDesc></directNote> and <directNote kind="pull">pulls back
                slowly</directNote>.</sd>

            <sd>A flash of white, and we are in <char ref="Robin">Robin</char>'s room. He is asleep at his worktable, but
                sits bolt upright with a gasp of terror-the entire proceedings up to this point were
                his very bad dream. His face runs with sweat as he tries to catch his breath. The
                door is heard opening.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>
                <sd>from o.c.</sd>It's him.<sd><directNote kind="pan">Pan to the door; he is there.</directNote></sd>It's<char ref="Slade">Slade</char>.</sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="snap">Snap to black.</directNote></sd>

            <cue>OPENING THEME</cue>

        </act>
        <act n="1">
            <title>Act One</title>
            <sd><stageDesc category="open-shot">Opening shot: the operations center.</stageDesc> It is just before daybreak. The Titans are
                gathered before the window/screen, which shows <char ref="Slade">Slade</char>'s face. He is in some sort of
                industrial area.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Slade">Slade</spkr>Good morning, Teen Titans.<sd><directNote kind="cut">Cut to<char ref="Robin">Robin</char>,<char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char>,
                    and <char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char></directNote>; he is heard on speaker.</sd>I do hope I didn't wake you.</sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="pan">Pan to<char ref="Raven">Raven</char> and<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char>.</directNote></sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>
                <sd>yawning</sd>What are you, <charDesc ref="Slade">an insomniac</charDesc>? Who calls at five in the morning--?</sp>

            <sd><char ref="Raven">Raven</char> elbows him in the side to cut him off.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>What do you want?</sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="cut">The scene cuts to the screen again</directNote></sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Slade">Slade</spkr>Well, that's precisely what you've been trying to
                find out, isn't it? And in spite of all your efforts, you're still in the dark about
                my intentions.<sd><stageDesc category="close-up">Close-up of Robin</stageDesc>; he is heard on speaker.</sd>Disappointing,
               <char ref="Robin">Robin</char>. I expected a little more from you.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>Like I care what you--</sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="cut">The scene cuts to the screen again</directNote></sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Slade">Slade</spkr>But since you've been unable to discover my plan, I
                suppose I'll just have to reveal it myself.</sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="pan">Pan away from him on the end of this line.</directNote> Two of his commando robots are standing
                next to a large object covered with a tarp.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Slade">Slade</spkr>
                <sd>from o.c.</sd>I'm sure you're all familiar with the concept of a Chronoton
                Detonator.</sp>

            <sd>The tarp is pulled away as he says this. Underneath it is a large, egg-like piece of
                machinery with a couple of red lights set into its surface. The upper portion
                telescopes toward the ceiling, giving a view of the circuitry inside and more sets
                of lights. <directNote kind="cut">Cut to<char ref="Robin">Robin</char> and <char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char></directNote>, then <directNote kind="pan">pan to each of the others in turn during
                the next two lines</directNote>.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>No!</sp>

            <sd><char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char> gasps.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Raven">Raven</spkr>Uh-oh.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>No way!<sd><directNote kind="pull">Pull back; he turns to
                   <char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char>.</directNote></sd>Um, what's a crouton detonator?</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr>It eradicates all chronotons within a localized
                area, utterly destroying the temporal component of the space-time continuum.</sp>

            <sd><stageDesc category="gag">A question mark pops up by his head.</stageDesc></sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>Hmm?</sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="pan">Pan to<char ref="Raven">Raven</char>.</directNote></sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Raven">Raven</spkr>It stops time. Permanently.</sp>

            <sd><char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> cries out and faints.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>If he triggers that thing downtown, it'll
                freeze-frame the entire city.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>
                <sd>to<char ref="Slade">Slade</char> on the screen</sd>Tell me where!</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="Slade">Slade</spkr>You're a clever boy,<char ref="Robin">Robin</char>.<sd><directNote kind="cut">Cut to <char ref="Robin">Robin</char></directNote>; he is
                    heard on speaker.</sd>I'm sure you and your little friends can figure it
                    out.<sd>The screen again; he holds up a transmitter.</sd>However, since I
                control the detonation, time is not on your side.</sp>

            <sd>The screen fills with static, and<char ref="Robin">Robin</char> slams a fist down on the computer keyboard
                with a frustrated grunt. Now the window has cleared.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>Fan out! Find it! Shut it down!</sp>

            <sd>He storms toward the door, but<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> and<char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char> move to block his path.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>
                <sd>tugging his collar</sd>Hey, uh, maybe you should stay here and coordinate the
                search.</sp>

            <sd>A big drop of sweat rolls down his temple on the end of this; <directNote kind="cut">cut to <char ref="Robin">Robin</char></directNote>.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>What?</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>
                <sd>from o.c.</sd><char ref="Man">Man</char>, when it comes to<char ref="Slade">Slade</char>, you've got issues.</sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="shift">Shift to frame all three boys on the end of the line</directNote>; <directNote kind="gag"><char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char> has pointed a finger at
                <char ref="Robin">Robin</char>'s temple and is twirling it in the classic "this guy has a screw loose"
                gesture</directNote>.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>Might be better for the team if you sit this one
                out.</sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="cut">Back to<char ref="Robin">Robin</char> on the end of this.</directNote></sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>No.</sp>

            <sd><stageDesc category="letterbox">Letterbox, top third of screen; the three and<char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char> appear as silhouettes.</stageDesc></sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>
                <sd>heading out</sd>There's too much at stake for me to--</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr><char ref="Robin">Robin</char>...</sp>

            <sd>He stops at her mention of his name. <stageDesc category="fullscreen">Fullscreen, normal view.</stageDesc></sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr>We have not forgotten the last time you
                faced--</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>I made a mistake,<char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char>. It won't happen
                    again.<sd>heads out again</sd>I can handle it. I promise.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="Raven">Raven</spkr>
                <sd>from o.c.; the computer is heard</sd>Would you at least like to know where to
                look?</sp>

            <sd>Everyone turns to look at her. She is at the keyboard, and <directNote kind="tilt">the camera tilts up to
                show a freeze frame from <char ref="Slade">Slade</char>'s message, the robots and the detonator, on the
                window/screen</directNote>.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Raven">Raven</spkr><char ref="Slade">Slade</char> gave us more information than he realized.</sp>

            <sd>The image fills the screen. <directNote kind="zoom">Zoom in on a patch of it as a set of gridlines is
                superimposed</directNote>; a small blurry image on the metal surface stands out.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Raven">Raven</spkr>
                <sd>from o.c.; <directNote kind="zoom">zoom in closer</directNote></sd>Here, in this reflection.</sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="cut">Cut to her and<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char>.</directNote></sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>Ooh, squiggly lines. Way informative.</sp>

            <sd>Back to the image. As more keystrokes are heard, it refines and can be clearly seen
                as backward text: "PIER 41." This is turned around to read normally. <directNote kind="cut">Cut to
               <char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char>.</directNote></sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr>Pier Forty-One!</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>
                <sd>stepping closer</sd>The docks!</sp>

            <sd><char ref="Raven">Raven</char> glares at <charDesc ref="BeastBoy">her detractor</charDesc>, who grins and chuckles nervously at having been shown
                up. <directNote kind="dissolve">Dissolve to a sign marking that location</directNote> and <directNote kind="pan">pan to one of the warehouses at the
                waterfront</directNote>. It is now closer to sunup.<char ref="Robin">Robin</char> runs to the doors, followed by <char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char>, <transform class="mammal">as a cheetah</transform>, returning to <transform class="human">human form</transform>, and then the rest of the group. <char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char>
                whips out his sonic cannon and lets it speak; <directNote kind="cut">cut to inside</directNote>. The doors are blasted
                away, and<char ref="Robin">Robin</char> dashes in with his fighting staff in hand. He extends it to as the
                others follow him, ready to slug it out. Their perspective, <directNote kind="pan">panning across the
                interior-no detonator, no<char ref="Slade">Slade</char>, no commandos, no nothing</directNote>.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr>Empty?</sp>

            <sd><stageDesc category="overhead-shot">Overhead view of them.</stageDesc></sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>Oh, man!</sp>

            <sd>Ground level.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>I don't believe this!</sp>

            <sd>To add injury to insult, those robotic strongmen show up out of nowhere, standing on
                the overhead beams as well as all over the floor. A few even move to block the
                exit.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>Great. Now what do we do?</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>We fight.</sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="pull">Pull back from the group</directNote>, then <directNote kind="dissolve">dissolve to <stageDesc category="long-shot">a longer shot</stageDesc></directNote> and <directNote kind="pull">keep pulling back to
                show just how badly outnumbered our heroes really are</directNote>. The opposing forces start to
                close in.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>Titans! Go!</sp>

            <sd>They do so. He moves so fast that he almost seems to be everywhere at once, knocking
                out one robot after another before they have time to react. A couple back up before
                <char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char>'s headlong dash; he gets ready to deliver a real haymaker, but<char ref="Robin">Robin</char> moves in
                first and dispatches them.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>Hey! I was gonna do that!</sp>

            <sd>Elsewhere,<char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char> skids backward a bit and is quickly surrounded by the metallic
                musclemen. She warms up her starbolts and rises into the air to do a spinning
                strafe, but again<char ref="Robin">Robin</char> zips in and wipes out the lot. She stares incredulously
                after him once he has gone. Now<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> is hemmed in and gives a surprised little
                yelp; the enemies dog-pile on him, whereupon he turns into <transform class="mammal">a bull</transform> and bucks them
                away. More close in, and he snorts in preparation to charge, but once again, <charDesc ref="Robin">the Boy
                Wonder</charDesc> leaps into the fray and puts them all down for the count.</sd>

            <sd><directNote kind="cut">Cut to<char ref="Raven">Raven</char> in midair.</directNote></sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Raven">Raven</spkr>Azarath Metrion Zin--</sp>

            <sd>She has no chance to finish the spell; <charDesc ref="Robin">the overactive Titan</charDesc> is there in a flash to
                beat the stuffing out of the commandos menacing her. She just looks around, deadpan
                but slightly bewildered, and sees him leap across the warehouse to engage another
                group. <stageDesc category="gag">Sight gag: the other Titans, as infants up against the wall, watch in sheer
                confusion while the shadows of the battle play back and forth across them.</stageDesc> A piece
                of a head tumbles past, followed by a beaten attacker and<char ref="Robin">Robin</char> himself; <directNote kind="zoom">zoom in on
                the four, who wince as the pounding gets louder</directNote>.</sd>

            <sd>The sight gag ends, and<char ref="Robin">Robin</char> jumps onto the fallen robot whose head was partially
                smashed away. He starts bashing the remains of the metal skull with his staff; <directNote kind="pan">pan
                to the other Titans</directNote>.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>Uh,<char ref="Robin">Robin</char>? I think you got him.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr>Yes, please.<sd><directNote kind="cut">Cut to <char ref="Robin">Robin</char></directNote>; she continues
                    o.c.</sd>You may stop now.</sp>

            <sd>Only her hands on his bring the walloping to a close.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr>We are victorious.</sp>

            <sd>He stands up.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr><char ref="Slade">Slade</char>'s got his finger on the button, and we've got
                    nothing!<sd>He retracts his staff.</sd>Does that sound like a victory to
                you?</sp>

            <sd>He stalks away, leaving the others staring after him and trying to figure out what
                could have turned him into a one-man wrecking crew. <directNote kind="dissolve">Dissolve to outside the
                warehouse, just above the doors<char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char> blew out</directNote>, and <directNote kind="tilt">tilt down to him and <char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char></directNote>.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>Okay. We know the Chronoton Detonator was here. Now
                we just have to figure out where it went.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>No problem. We should split up and--</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="Raven">Raven</spkr>
                <sd>walks into view</sd>--Waste hours searching only to come up empty-handed?</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>Well, when you say it like that--?</sp>

            <sd><char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char> lands by them.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr><char ref="Raven">Raven</char> is right. We must find some way to track
                the device.</sp>

            <sd><char ref="Robin">Robin</char> approaches on the end of this line, then cocks an eyebrow quizzically at the
                sound of echoing footsteps. At a distance, <charDesc ref="Man">a man is walking between two of the
                warehouses</charDesc>; a large shadow is cast on the wall behind him.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>Freeze!</sp>

            <sd>He is off like a shot; <charDesc ref="Man">the spooked fellow</charDesc> races along the way, but a birdarang
                flashes into view and embeds itself in the concrete, bringing him up short. <char ref="Robin">Robin</char>
                follows it down, throws him against the wall, and holds up a small crest with
                <char ref="Slade">Slade</char>'s S insignia on it, taken from one of the robots.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>Tell me everything you know about this!</sp>

            <sd><charDesc ref="Man">The frightened chap</charDesc> can only stutter and mumble inarticulately.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>Answer me! Now!</sp>

            <sd>He shoves the man to the wall, harder.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Man">Man</spkr>I've never seen it before! I don't know anything!
                Honest!</sp>

            <sd>As he says this, <char ref="Raven">Raven</char>'s powers spread over <char ref="Robin">Robin</char>'s torso. <charDesc ref="Robin">The
                Titan-turned-Dirty-Harry</charDesc> is then slung across to the wall of the opposite warehouse
                and pinned to it as she maintains her hold, the other three approach.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Raven">Raven</spkr>You said you could handle it.</sp>

            <sd>She releases him.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr>You promised.</sp>

            <sd>He slides down.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>We're wasting time.</sp>

            <sd>He strides off.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>
                <sd>calling after him</sd>You know, just 'cause we're trying to catch<char ref="Slade">Slade</char> doesn't
                mean you have to act like him!</sp>

            <sd><char ref="Robin">Robin</char> stops in his tracks, <annot>as we have already seen, being compared to this man hits
                him in all the wrong spots</annot>.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>
                <sd>whirling around</sd>Don't you ever compare me to him!<sd>He walks back.</sd>
                He's trying to destroy the city. I'm trying to save it!</sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="pull">Pull back briefly to <stageDesc category="long-shot">a long shot of the group</stageDesc></directNote>, then <directNote kind="cut">cut to them again</directNote>. The rest of
                the Titans are, to borrow a line from Dr. Seuss, puzzling until their puzzlers are
                sore. Suddenly,<char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char> lets off a violent sneeze, accompanied by a starbolt that
                shoots from her nose. When the glare clears out, all four of the others are stunned
                and smoking from the blast. Her next three lines sound rather congested, as if
                spoken by someone with hay fever.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Raven">Raven</spkr>Gesundheit.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr>
                <sd>flushed, sniffling</sd>Forgive me. I am allergic to metallic chromium. There
                must be a source near--</sp>

            <sd>She gets ready to sneeze again; everyone bails out, and <directNote kind="pull">the camera pulls back to <stageDesc category="long-shot">a
                long shot of the waterfront</stageDesc> as she lets it rip with another nasal starbolt</directNote>. At the
                scene, the smoke clears to expose her, standing alone. <directNote kind="pull">Pull back as she sniffles,
                wipes her nose, and groans.</directNote></sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr>Sorry.</sp>

            <sd>The other four return,<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> from behind a trash can,<char ref="Robin">Robin</char> rappelling down from
                the warehouse roof,<char ref="Raven">Raven</char> passing through the wall.<char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char> is the only one to simply
                walk up; he looks down at his forearm.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>Interesting.</sp>

            <sd>His perspective, <stageDesc category="display">looking at a graph readout on his panel</stageDesc>. She wipes her nose
                again.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr>
                <sd>sniffling and groaning a bit</sd>Not really. On my world, chromium allergies are
                quite common.</sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="cut">Cut to him.</directNote></sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>No. The key component of a Chronoton Detonator is a
                metallic chromium core, which means--</sp>

            <sd>He closes the panel; <directNote kind="pull">pull back to show<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> next to him</directNote>.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>--<char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char> can track it!</sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="cut">Cut to her</directNote> and <directNote kind="zoom">zoom in slightly as she sniffles</directNote>, then <directNote kind="fade">fade to black</directNote>.</sd>

            <cue>Animation goof: In this last shot, her armband is on the wrong side.</cue>

        </act>
        <act n="2">
            <title>Act Two</title>
            <sd><stageDesc category="open-shot">Opening shot: the inside wall of a sewer tunnel.</stageDesc> The camera rotates to point down
                the way; from around a bend,<char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char> unloads another high-powered sneeze. <directNote kind="cut">Cut to
                her, slogging through the water and wiping her nose with a groan.</directNote></sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr>
                <sd>congested</sd>I believe it is this way.</sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="pan">Pan to the others, who have thrown up their arms to protect themselves from the
                blast.</directNote> After a moment, they move out with<char ref="Robin">Robin</char> bringing up the rear.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>Look, guys, uh-- about earlier.</sp>

            <sd>They stop.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Raven">Raven</spkr>It'll have to wait.</sp>

            <sd>She points ahead, <directNote kind="pan">pan in that direction to show a small speedboat in the tunnel,
                with the detonator, back in its original compact form--loaded in the back</directNote>. A
                commando guarding the rig catches sight of the group.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>Titans! Go!</sp>

            <sd><char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> becomes <transform class="bird">a falcon</transform> as they charge. The robot moves to the instrument panel
                and hits the throttle, speeding off down the tunnel.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>Quick! We can't let him get away!</sp>

            <sd>A section of the wall smashes out next to him, and <charDesc ref="Cinderblock">a large stone hand reaches
                through and drags him away</charDesc>.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr><char ref="Robin">Robin</char>!</sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="cut">Cut to the other side of the hole, pointing in at the sewer.</directNote> As the other four wade
                past, the sound of a fight is heard. They stop to watch; <directNote kind="cut">cut to their side</directNote>.<char ref="Robin">Robin</char> is
                mixing it up with Cinderblock.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>Get the detonator! Go!</sp>

            <sd>All but<char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char> follow orders; <directNote kind="cut">cut to her, still watching</directNote>.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>
                <sd>from o.c.</sd><charDesc ref="Starfire">Star</charDesc>! You heard the man!</sp>

            <sd>Reluctantly, she sets off after them.<char ref="Robin">Robin</char> leaps from one support column to another
                and stays just ahead of Cinderblock, who destroys each one with a single blow.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>Only fair to warn you: <oneLine>you caught me on a bad
                day</oneLine>!</sp>

            <sd><charDesc ref="Cinderblock">The stone behemoth growls and charges.</charDesc><char ref="Robin">Robin</char> moves in as well; <directNote kind="cut">cut to <stageDesc category="close-up">a close-up of
                each pair of pounding feet</stageDesc></directNote>, then <directNote kind="pull">pull back as <charDesc ref="Robin">the Titan</charDesc> vaults high over Cinderblock
                and hurls a pair of bolas-weighted balls connected with a rope</directNote>. These land on the
                head and tangle up around it, and<char ref="Robin">Robin</char> follows with a flying spin kick. <directNote kind="cut">Cut to the
                tunnel</directNote>; the speedboat zooms ahead.<char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char>, carrying<char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char>, flies after it, and
               <char ref="Raven">Raven</char> and<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> are right behind her. The robot presses one of a row of buttons
                on the control panel.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Computer">Computer</spkr>Defense mode activated.</sp>

            <sd>These words appear on a small screen above the buttons. Now two lasers on the stern
                open up with a barrage of shots that forces everyone to swerve back and forth. The
                chase moves around a junction;<char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char> keeps dodging the shots.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>
                <sd>breaks out his cannon</sd>I will not be having attitude from a boat!</sp>

            <sd>He keeps getting it, though, in the form of a new fusillade. <directNote kind="cut">Back to<char ref="Robin">Robin</char> and
                Cinderblock</directNote>; the former lands in a crouch, then pushes off from the ground for a
                flying roundhouse kick that staggers the latter. Another kick, a crushing left hook,
                and<char ref="Robin">Robin</char> touches down in front of the dazed enemy and seizes him. Cinderblock is
                thrown down onto his back, and<char ref="Robin">Robin</char> climbs atop his chest.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>Where is he?<sd><stageDesc category="close-up">Close-up.</stageDesc></sd>Where's-- huh?</sp>

            <sd>His attention is drawn by a beeping from o.c. <directNote kind="cut">Cut to the source-a small tracking
                device in Cinderblock's open hand.</directNote><char ref="Robin">Robin</char> climbs down and picks up the item; <directNote kind="cut">cut to
                it</directNote>. The screen shows a map of the area with two flashing dots. <directNote kind="zoom">Zoom in</directNote>, then <directNote kind="cut">cut to
                <stageDesc category="close-up">a close-up</stageDesc></directNote>. One dot is an arrow, and the camera follows it to the other; <char ref="Slade">Slade</char>'s
                mark. <stageDesc category="close-up">Extreme close-up of <char ref="Robin">Robin</char>'s wide, wondering eyes</stageDesc>, then <stageDesc category="close-up">of the flashing S</stageDesc>, then
                <stageDesc category="close-up">of him</stageDesc>. A cold smile spreads across his face-now he knows exactly where to find <charDesc ref="Slade">his
                archenemy</charDesc>.</sd>

            <sd>The sewer again. The Titans continue their pursuit of the speedboat. On the next
                line, <directNote kind="pull">pull back to show this as the view on one of the large monitors in <char ref="Slade">Slade</char>'s
                lair; he is watching the chase from different angles</directNote>.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Slade">Slade</spkr>Hurry, young Titans. Your time is running out.</sp>

            <sd>On a high catwalk behind him, a door is blown out but he does not even flinch. The
                smoke clears to show <char ref="Robin">Robin</char>'s silhouette in the light from outside.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr><oneLine>Actually...<sd><stageDesc category="close-up">Close-up.</stageDesc></sd>...we just went into
                overtime.</oneLine></sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="Slade">Slade</spkr><char ref="Robin">Robin</char>. Welcome. I've been expecting you for some
                    time.<sd>as<char ref="Robin">Robin</char> drops to the platform</sd>I was beginning to wonder if
                Cinderblock was too much of a challenge.</sp>

            <sd>He turns around and holds up the transmitter seen during his earlier message.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Slade">Slade</spkr>Looking for this?</sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="cut">Cut to just behind and to one side</directNote>; he holds the device at <char ref="Robin">Robin</char>'s eye level and
                waves it around.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Slade">Slade</spkr>
                <sd>from o.c.</sd>Well...<sd><directNote kind="cut">Cut to a spotlighted patch of floor</directNote>; he sets it
                    down.</sd>...here it is.</sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="pull">Pull back to frame both, on opposite sides of the transmitter.</directNote></sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Slade">Slade</spkr>If you want it, come and take it.</sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="cut">Cut to</directNote> <directNote kind="pan">a slow pan across each determined face, first <char ref="Robin">Robin</char>'s, then <char ref="Slade">Slade</char>'s, then
                back to<char ref="Robin">Robin</char>.</directNote> His teeth bared in a silent snarl, he charges straight at the camera
                and goes into a mighty somersaulting leap. As he sails closer, he pulls his right
                fist back and lets out one cry of pure rage. After the screen has filled with the
                white of his eye, <directNote kind="snap">snap to black</directNote>.</sd>

        </act>
        <act n="3">
            <title>Act Three</title>
            <sd><stageDesc category="open-shot">Opening shot: the wake of the speedboat.</stageDesc> It pulls away from the camera and races
                down the sewer tunnel, unleashing a burst of laser shots at the other four Titans.
               <char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char> returns fire with his cannon, then is whisked off by<char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char>; one shot from
                the boat sends<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> tumbling for a moment. He rights himself and falls in
                behind<char ref="Raven">Raven</char>. Now that cannon is blazing steadily away, and it puts both of the
                speedboat's guns out of action in short order. The commando at the helm opens up the
                throttle and zooms ahead, but<char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char> gradually pulls even to hold<char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char> over the
                deck.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>Thanks for the lift!</sp>

            <sd>She lets go of him and backs off. As soon as his feet hit the deck, he is running
                toward the commando, who starts punching buttons furiously. The screen above them is
                now blank.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Computer">Computer</spkr>Auto pilot engaged.</sp>

            <sd>These words appear. <char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char>'s hand clamps onto the robot's shoulder; <directNote kind="pan">it looks that
                way at he camera pans to <charDesc ref="Cyborg">the grinning Titan</charDesc></directNote>. <directNote kind="pull">Pull back; as the others fly after the
                watercraft, a punch lands and the driver is flung over the stern.</directNote> On the deck, the
                wheel is turning itself under the control of the automatic pilot program; <char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char>
                seizes it and tries to steer manually, but only succeeds in tearing it out. <char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char>
                lands on the deck as he stares popeyed at it. Now he hammers several buttons.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Computer">Computer</spkr>Invalid code.</sp>

            <sd><stageDesc category="display">The display changes to show these two words.</stageDesc> The speedboat begins to swerve back and
                forth, giving the two yelling Titans quite a ride.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr>
                <sd>under <char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char>'s yells</sd>How does one halt this vehicle?</sp>

            <sd>His idea: by seizing the computer panel and ripping it out entirely. The speedboat
                emerges into a large open chamber and comes to a stop.<char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char> smiles placidly as
               <char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char> regards the ruined hardware, and<char ref="Raven">Raven</char> and<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> land on the deck. <charDesc ref="BeastBoy">The
                green falcon</charDesc> returns to <transform class="human">human form</transform>.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Raven">Raven</spkr>Please tell me that's not how you're planning to stop
                the detonator.</sp>

            <sd>Surprised, he blushes a bit as a big drop of sweat rolls down his temple.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>Uh...</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>You do know how to stop it, don't you?</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>How hard could it be?</sp>

            <sd>He throws the panel overboard and crosses the deck to the detonator. Kneeling next
                it, he reaches toward the surface and is surprised when the housing telescopes
                upward as it did in <char ref="Slade">Slade</char>'s message. He falls backward with a grunt; <directNote kind="pan">pan to frame
                the entire device</directNote>, then <directNote kind="cut">cut to <stageDesc category="close-up">a close-up of its red lights</stageDesc></directNote> and <directNote kind="tilt">tilt down slowly to
                the central area</directNote>.<char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char> looks as if he has just realized how far he is in over his
                head.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>Ooh.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="Raven">Raven</spkr>Whatever we're gonna do, we should do it before <char ref="Slade">Slade</char>
                decides to trigger this thing.</sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="cut">Cut to <stageDesc category="overhead-shot">a set of overhead gears</stageDesc> in <char ref="Slade">Slade</char>'s lair</directNote> and <directNote kind="tilt">tilt down to the ground</directNote>. The
                transmitter sits near the camera.<char ref="Robin">Robin</char> tumbles into view at a distance, gets
                himself upright, and runs toward it. A huge leap carries him closer, but<char ref="Slade">Slade</char> hits
                him broadside with a flying kick. The two land facing each other.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Slade">Slade</spkr>Come now,<char ref="Robin">Robin</char>. You'll have to do better than that.
                I haven't even broken a sweat.</sp>

            <sd>He rushes, leaps, and does a midair backflip leading into a roundhouse kick that
                sends<char ref="Robin">Robin</char> reeling. The melee moves across the floor, with each landing blows in
                turn, and<char ref="Slade">Slade</char> plants another steel boot across <char ref="Robin">Robin</char>'s chest. Snarling in rage,
                <charDesc ref="Robin">the Titan</charDesc> gets his head clear, and the two spar again until<char ref="Slade">Slade</char> catches <char ref="Robin">Robin</char>'s
                fist.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Slade">Slade</spkr>Good technique.</sp>

            <sd>He bends the arm sharply at the elbow; we hear bones grinding against each other as
               <char ref="Robin">Robin</char> yells in pain. The hold turns into a throw that sends the hero skidding across
                the floor to slam into a wall. As he gets woozily to his feet, <stageDesc category="lower">seen from ground
                level, <char ref="Slade">Slade</char>'s foot steps into view near the camera</stageDesc>.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Slade">Slade</spkr>
                <sd>from o.c.</sd>Good,<sd><directNote kind="cut">Cut to him.</directNote></sd>but not perfect.</sp>

            <sd>His head clear again, another yell of pure fury in his throat,<char ref="Robin">Robin</char> charges across
                the floor. He launches himself into the air, but one of those steel-gloved fists
                whistles out and hits home in the breadbasket. <stageDesc category="close-up">Close-up of <char ref="Robin">Robin</char>'s stunned
                countenance</stageDesc>, then <stageDesc category="close-up">of <char ref="Slade">Slade</char>'s quietly cruel one</stageDesc>, then <directNote kind="pull">pull back to frame both</directNote>. The
                young man hangs in the air for a moment, supported by the fist that has just stopped
                him cold, and then slowly collapses. <stageDesc category="close-up">Extreme close-up of <char ref="Slade">Slade</char>'s eye; he chuckles to
                himself.</stageDesc></sd>

            <sd><directNote kind="cut">Cut to <stageDesc category="close-up">a close-up of the detonator core</stageDesc>.</directNote> A small square panel is at the heart of it,
                held in place by a screw at each corner. These are pulled out via <char ref="Raven">Raven</char>'s
                telekinesis, and<char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char> reaches into view to remove the panel; this is his
                perspective. Behind it is a rotating, glowing red sphere. The next three lines are
                spoken in whispers.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>The chromium core.<sd><directNote kind="cut">Cut to him and the
                    others.</directNote></sd>Very unstable. No sudden moves.</sp>

            <sd>He holds up the panel;<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> quickly turns into <transform class="mollusca">an octopus</transform>, takes it from him,
                and sets it aside gingerly. As<char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char> reaches toward the machinery,<char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char> gets
                ready to sneeze, her allergy exacerbated by being this close to that much chromium,
                and throws everyone into a panic.<char ref="Raven">Raven</char> creates a shield around <charDesc ref="Starfire">the Tamaranean</charDesc>'s
                head to contain the force of the coming blast; it holds, but just barely, and her
                hair is blown wildly out of place. She sniffles after the shield is taken down.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr>
                <sd>congested</sd>Please continue.</sp>

            <sd>She shakes her hair back into place and grins widely with an embarrassed little
                giggle. <directNote kind="cut">Cut to <char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char>'s perspective</directNote>; he holds up his forearm, <stageDesc category="display">which now shows a
                panel with a circuit diagram of the device</stageDesc>. Three lights come on underneath it. <directNote kind="cut">Back
                to the group</directNote>;<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> resumes <transform class="human">human form</transform>.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>Okay.<sd>extends an acetylene torch from his
                    forefinger</sd>Now all we have to do is decouple the--</sp>

            <sd>His perspective on the end of this; he uses the torch to sever one of the cables
                running to the core. It begins to beep and rotate very quickly. <directNote kind="cut">Back to the
                group.</directNote></sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>Well, that doesn't sound good.</sp>

            <sd>A flash, and we are back in <char ref="Slade">Slade</char>'s lair.<char ref="Robin">Robin</char> tumbles across the floor and stays
                down for a few seconds, pounding his fist against the tiles with a loud groan. <char ref="Slade">Slade</char>
                steps into view near him; <directNote kind="tilt">tilt up from feet to head</directNote>.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Slade">Slade</spkr>I understand your frustration,<char ref="Robin">Robin</char>. You hate losing
                as much as I do.<sd><stageDesc category="long-shot">Long shot, panning slowly across the place.</stageDesc></sd>One of the many
                qualities we have in common.</sp>

            <sd><stageDesc category="close-up">Close-up of<char ref="Robin">Robin</char>.</stageDesc> Once again, his sorest spot has been poked too hard, and he comes
                up into an uppercut that lifts<char ref="Slade">Slade</char> clear off his feet. Two more punches send <charDesc ref="Slade">the
                armored criminal genius</charDesc> to the floor, but he lands in a crouch and runs off. Giving
                him no quarter,<char ref="Robin">Robin</char> lands a string of savage blows to drop him flat on his back.
                <stageDesc category="close-up">Close-up of the transmitter; <charDesc ref="Robin">the Boy Wonder</charDesc> steps into view nearby and picks it
                up.</stageDesc></sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>It's over,<char ref="Slade">Slade</char>!</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="Slade">Slade</spkr>
                <sd>from o.c.</sd>On the contrary,<char ref="Robin">Robin</char>.</sp>

            <sd>The thing starts to spark.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>Huh?</sp>

            <sd>It breaks apart in his hand with a small crackle of electricity. He stares down in
                total confusion; <directNote kind="cut">cut to<char ref="Slade">Slade</char>, stepping out from a dark recess among the
                machinery</directNote>.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Slade">Slade</spkr>This is only the beginning.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>Where's the real trigger?</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="Slade">Slade</spkr>Trigger? There is no trigger, because there is no
                detonator.</sp>

            <sd><char ref="Robin">Robin</char>'s eyes widen even more. <directNote kind="cut">Cut to the detonator core, still beeping and spinning
                like mad.</directNote> <char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char>'s teeth are chattering a mile a minute as the two girls stare
                over <char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char>'s shoulders.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>
                <sd>whispers</sd>Moment of truth, y'all.<sd>holds up his finger torch</sd> Everybody
                ready?</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>I can't watch!</sp>

            <sd>He covers his eyes, but parts his fingers to give one of them a clear field of
                vision.<char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char> rakes his flame across a couple of other cables to cut them, and the
                core stops its activity entirely. The red glow fades to leave the sphere looking
                like an ordinary metal ball.<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char>,<char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char>, and<char ref="Raven">Raven</char> sigh loudly and visibly
                with relief as<char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char> smiles; the moment is short-lived, though, as a loud, urgent
                alarm goes off and elicits gasps and wide-eyed stares from all four. The core starts
                to spin and glow again, and red light spreads from it along the cables that have not
                been broken. Now the alarm slows down a bit as the red lights on the detonator's
                housing start to pulsate, and the topmost section retracts slightly. <char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char>
                screams shrilly.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>We blew it! We'll be frozen in time
                forever!</sp>

            <sd>The alarm gives way to a steady drone, and the whole device shorts out and crumbles
                into a pile of junk.<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> is ready to have a fit, but stops when the rig falls
                silent.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>Um...why are we not frozen in time
                forever?</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>Because this wasn't a Chronoton Detonator. It was a
                fake!</sp>

            <sd>Behind them, at the prow, a weapon pops out and sweeps back and forth, strafing all
                four Titans and knocking them overboard. One by one, their heads break the surface;
                no apparent damage from the assault.<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> shakes off the water with a cry of
                revulsion.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>So aside from the nasty taste of sewer water
                in my mouth, I think I'm okay.</sp>

            <sd><char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char> checks his forearm panel.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>Diagnostic sensors say I'm just fine.</sp>

            <sd>He knocks water out of his ears.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Raven">Raven</spkr>Whatever that beam was supposed to do, it didn't do
                it.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr>Then...we are victorious?</sp>

            <sd><directNote>Her image starts to rotate</directNote>, <directNote kind="zoom">zooms in</directNote>, and <directNote kind="dissolve">then goes into a series of dissolves</directNote>.
                First, we see the tissues within her body, <stageDesc category="close-up">then a closer view of these</stageDesc>, then
                individual blood cells moving in an artery. The next transition shows tiny metal
                spheres, marked with <char ref="Slade">Slade</char>'s S, attaching themselves to these cells, deposited by
                the beam that hit the Titans. <directNote kind="dissolve">One final dissolve shows a row of four monitors, each
                marked with the name of one of these four Titans, showing a picture of the blood
                vessels and a readout of vital signs.</directNote> Every cell is carrying a device along with it.
                <directNote kind="tilt">Tilt down slightly as<char ref="Slade">Slade</char> steps into view; we are back in his lair, and these are
                his monitors.</directNote></sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Slade">Slade</spkr>Nanoscopic probes. The Chronoton Detonator was merely
                the bait for a much larger trap.</sp>

            <sd>As he continues, a small push-button device extends itself from the inside of his
                wrist and settles in his hand.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Slade">Slade</spkr>You see, with the push of a button...</sp>

            <sd><stageDesc category="close-up">Close-up of it</stageDesc>, his thumb poised above, and <directNote kind="pan">pan slightly to show<char ref="Robin">Robin</char> glaring at
                it</directNote>.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Slade">Slade</spkr>
                <sd>from o.c.</sd>...my probes will destroy your friends from the inside out.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>You can't control them. No matter what you threaten,
                they'll never obey you.</sp>

            <sd>Back to<char ref="Slade">Slade</char>; he paces around<char ref="Robin">Robin</char>.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Slade">Slade</spkr>This isn't about your friends,<char ref="Robin">Robin</char>. It's about you.
                It's always been about you.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>What?</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="Slade">Slade</spkr>Sending trouble your way. Leaving cryptic clues for
                you to unravel. I was testing you. For some time now, I have been searching for an
                apprentice. Someone to follow in my footsteps.<sd>leans into <char ref="Robin">Robin</char>'s face</sd>And,
               <char ref="Robin">Robin</char>, I've chosen you. Congratulations.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>No way would I ever work for--</sp>

            <sd><char ref="Slade">Slade</char> holds up the button, thumb just barely clearing it, and he falls silent.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Slade">Slade</spkr>If you join me, if you swear to serve me,<sd><stageDesc category="close-up">Close-up
                    of his face.</stageDesc></sd>if you never speak to your friends again,<sd><stageDesc category="close-up">Extreme close-up
                    of his eye</stageDesc>.</sd>I will allow them to live.</sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="cut">Cut to <char ref="Robin">Robin</char></directNote>, staring in mute fear, and <directNote kind="zoom">zoom in slowly</directNote>.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Slade">Slade</spkr>
                <sd>from o.c.</sd>But...<sd>The monitors; he steps into view.</sd>...if you disobey
                even the smallest request, I will annihilate them,<char ref="Robin">Robin</char>. And I'll make you
                    watch.<sd><directNote kind="cut">Cut to<char ref="Robin">Robin</char>; he continues o.c.</directNote></sd>So, do we have a deal?</sp>

            <sd>Long, tense silence from <charDesc ref="Robin">the Titan</charDesc>, after which <directNote kind="tilt">the camera tilts up to <stageDesc category="overhead-shot">the overhead
                gears</stageDesc></directNote> and <directNote kind="black-screen">into the blackness past them</directNote>. <directNote kind="resolve">This resolves into a street in Jump City.</directNote> It
                is now nighttime. The rest of the Titans are far down the block.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr><char ref="Robin">Robin</char>?</sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="cut">Cut to them.</directNote><char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char> helps<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> up from a manhole;<char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char> has her communicator
                out and is speaking into it.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr><char ref="Robin">Robin</char>?<char ref="Robin">Robin</char>, please respond!<sd>lowers it and
                    looks at the others</sd>Why does he not answer?</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>His locator's been deactivated.<sd><char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char>
                    brushes himself off.</sd>We have no way to find him.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>Not good.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr>
                <sd>into the communicator</sd><char ref="Robin">Robin</char>, please. You must answer.<char ref="Robin">Robin</char>!</sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="fade">Fade to black.</directNote></sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr>
                <sd>over comm</sd>Please respond!</sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="fade">Fade in to <stageDesc category="close-up">a close-up of his outfit</stageDesc>, draped over a pipe in <char ref="Slade">Slade</char>'s lair</directNote>, and <directNote kind="pan">pan to
                a pool of light cast from above</directNote>. A tiny red dot glows through the utility belt, an
                incoming call signal from the communicator in its pouch. A hazy figure can be seen
                in the harsh glare.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr>
                <sd>over comm</sd><char ref="Robin">Robin</char>, where are you?</sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="zoom">Zoom in on the figure</directNote>, then <directNote kind="cut">cut to <stageDesc category="close-up">close-ups of the following</stageDesc></directNote>. A black glove being
                pulled on; a steel wrist guard being snapped into place; a belt being buckled under
                a chest that is yellow on the left side and black on the right; a neck piece
                fastened under <char ref="Robin">Robin</char>'s chin. He takes his hands away after this last action to
                reveal a silver S emblazoned over his heart, and <directNote kind="tilt">the camera tilts up to his sullen,
                defeated face</directNote>. <directNote kind="pull">Pull back to frame all of him</directNote>; <annot>if the abandoned clothing did not show
                his renunciation clearly enough, this shot gets the point across beyond all doubt</annot>.
               <char ref="Robin">Robin</char> wears steel reinforcements just like those of<char ref="Slade">Slade</char>, who steps into the light
                behind him.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Slade">Slade</spkr>I know it seems bad now. But trust me,<sd>He moves
                    away; <stageDesc category="close-up">close-up</stageDesc>.</sd>you'll learn to like it.</sp>

            <sd><stageDesc category="overhead-shot">Head-on view of <charDesc ref="Robin">the former leader of the Titans</charDesc>, standing motionless in the white
                light from overhead.</stageDesc> His expression has not changed one bit, nor does it do so as
               <char ref="Slade">Slade</char> passes in front of him. <directNote kind="pull">Pull back across the space</directNote>; <charDesc ref="Slade">the new boss</charDesc> passes into
                the darkness, leaving him alone, and the camera backs up slowly. <directNote kind="black-screen">The light is shut
                off to black out the screen.</directNote></sd>

            <cue>Continued in Part Two</cue>
        </act>
    </body>
</root>