<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../schema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?><root>
    <head>
        <episode>MASKS</episode>
        <writer>David Slack</writer>
        <director>Ciro Nieli</director>
        <storyboard>Kalvin Lee, Rafael Rosado, Alan Wan</storyboard>
        <animation>Dong Woo Animation Company, Ltd.</animation>
        <source>https://teentitans.fandom.com/wiki/Masks_(Transcript)</source>
        <issueList>
            <issueInfo link="../comic/issue-10.xml"/>
            <issueInfo link="../comic/issue-34.xml"/>
        </issueList>
    </head>
    <characterList>
        <charList type="recurring" id="Robin" subtype="titan">Robin</charList>
        <charList type="recurring" id="Cyborg" subtype="titan">Cyborg</charList>
        <charList type="recurring" id="BeastBoy" subtype="titan">Beast Boy</charList>
        <charList type="recurring" id="Starfire" subtype="titan">Starfire</charList>
        <charList type="recurring" id="Slade" subtype="villain">Slade</charList>
        <charList type="recurring" id="Raven" subtype="titan">Raven</charList>
        <charList type="nonrecurring" id="Guard1">Guard 1</charList>
        <charList type="nonrecurring" id="Guard2">Guard 2</charList>
        <charList type="nonrecurring" id="RedX" subtype="villain">Red X</charList>
    </characterList>
    <body>
        <act n="0">
            <title>Prologue</title>
            <sd><stageDesc category="open-shot">Opening shot: a pure white screen</stageDesc>. After a moment, an image appears at its center
                and resolves into a red microchip rotating slowly in the light. <directNote kind="pull">Pull back a bit</directNote> and
                <directNote kind="pan">pan to one side</directNote> to show darkness beyond this spot. A large figure stands up into
                view; it is clad in black armor, with additional steel plating to reinforce key
                areas, and wears a mask that hides the entire face. This is black, with a red-orange
                circle in the center whose edges touch both eyes. The figure reaches toward the
                chip, revealing a steel-gloved hand, and cocks one eyebrow in surprise. <directNote kind="cut">Cut to the
                other side of the suspension field</directNote>.<char ref="Robin">Robin</char> is hanging upside down.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>Tell<char ref="Slade">Slade</char> if he wants this, he can come get it
                himself!</sp>

            <sd>He drops from his perch and delivers a kick that sends the thief tumbling across the
                darkened area. All the lights now come on; <directNote kind="cut">cut to a <stageDesc category="close-up">close-up of<char ref="Robin">Robin</char> </stageDesc></directNote> and <directNote kind="dissolve">dissolve
                to a <stageDesc category="long-shot">longer shot</stageDesc></directNote>, <directNote kind="pull">pulling back to put the rest of the Titans in frame as well</directNote>. The
                place is a chamber stuffed with supercomputers. A laser beam lances down from above,
                forcing<char ref="Robin">Robin</char> to jump out of its way; <directNote kind="cut">cut to the ceiling</directNote>, where a section is being
                cut away from above. The piece falls in a cloud of dust, and several more intruders
                leap in.</sd>

            <sd><char ref="Robin">Robin</char>  does a few backflips to stay ahead of the next laser blast and soon has one of
                the new arrivals coming right for him. He blocks or dodges several blows, then tries
                a counter-kick that is deflected. The masked figure whips out a blaster, something
                like a set of brass knuckles with a muzzle on the front edge, and opens fire. A few
                acrobatic tricks carry<char ref="Robin">Robin</char> out of danger; he retaliates with a jumping roundhouse
                kick that sends the attacker crashing into the far wall.</sd>

            <sd><char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char>  just above, backs quickly across the screen to evade the shots from a
                squad member who jumps up after her. She gathers herself and puts a starbolt right
                where it belongs; her attacker is sent skidding across the floor. The next one jumps
                even higher, up to the level of the large ceiling-mounted spotlights that illuminate
                the place, and blasts at her. The lens of one light is struck and begins to fall
                loose; she is directly underneath and about to be crushed, but<char ref="Robin">Robin</char> leaps across
                and plows her away just in time. The lens crashes to the ground.</sd>

            <sd>The dust thrown up from the impact clears to give a <stageDesc category="close-up">close-up of <char ref="Robin">Robin</char> </stageDesc> who has set
               <char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char>  down. She is a bit dazed, but soon snaps to with a gasp.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>Huh?</sp>

            <sd>Across the room, several squad members level their weapons, but before they can
                shoot, a computer cabinet slides across and bulldozes them. Loud crash from o.c.
                after it has passed; <directNote kind="pan">pan quickly in the opposite direction to<char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char> </directNote>, who is wiping
                his hands; he pushed it at them.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>Amazing what you can do with computers these
                days.</sp>

            <sd>He runs toward the heart of the battle as<char ref="Raven">Raven</char>  floats backward into view, staying
                just ahead of a laser beam. Another one is fired from midair; she creates a shield
                around herself, and both it and the beam disintegrate when they make contact. The
                enemy runs toward her and starts throwing punches, which she stops by forming small
                barriers in front of herself as she slowly backs up. A low kick cuts her legs out
                from under her; the blaster is aimed at point-blank range, but before it can be
                fired, <char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char>  <transform class="mammal">as a bighorn sheep</transform>, rams its wielder into the wall. <directNote kind="cut">Cut to <char ref="Raven">Raven</char> 
                standing and staring in genuine surprise</directNote>, then to <char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> <transform class="human">in human form</transform>. The
                knocked-out commando lies crumpled in a heap.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr><sd>taunting</sd>You owe me big time, you owe
                me big--</sp>

            <sd>On the end of this, another one jumps down into view behind him, runs up, and gets
                ready to let him have it. As he finally turns to look, too late to save himself, two
                computers slide into view from opposite directions under <char ref="Raven">Raven</char>'s  control and crush
                the would-be shooter between them.<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char>  yells in fright and throws up his arms
                to protect himself; the hardware falls away and so does the smashed figure.<char ref="Raven">Raven</char> 
                winds down her powers and gives<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char>  a hard stare, and a big drop of sweat
                appears on his temple.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr><sd>blushes and chuckles nervously</sd>Call it
                even?</sp>

            <sd><char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char>  meanwhile, has reached the center of the room. Breaking out his sonic
                cannon, he starts to blaze away and soon has help in the form of <char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char>'s 
                fusillade. One of the thieves leaps impossibly high to avoid the blasts, then pushes
                off from the wall and sails straight toward the chip. A flying grab snares the
                bounty, and those steel-booted feet are racing for the door.<char ref="Robin">Robin</char> gives chase and
                hurls his birdarang; it hits the thief's hand and knocks the chip away. <directNote kind="cut">Cut to<char ref="Raven">Raven</char> 
                and<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> </directNote>, whose eyes track its trajectory.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>Mine!</sp>

            <sd>He runs o.c. <directNote kind="cut">Cut to the flying bit of hardware</directNote>; a long, thin tongue lashes into view
                and snags it, and <char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char>  <transform class="mammal">now an anteater</transform>, leaps across the screen and skids to a
                stop at the wall. An attacker's boot comes down on that tongue, which lets go of the
                chip so it can be seized. This one vaults across the room to the door, where the
                other survivors, four in all, have gathered, and throws down a smoke bomb. The
                resulting gray clouds cover the screen and clear to reveal that the five have
                escaped under cover of that diversion. <directNote kind="pull">Pull back to put<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char>  in frame</directNote>; he is
                <transform class="human">back in human form</transform> and thoroughly dazed by what has just happened. <directNote kind="gag">Sight gag: a tear
                of pain, in the shape of a clock pendulum, hangs from his eye and swings back and
                forth</directNote>.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr><sd>as if he had bitten his tongue</sd>That
                tasted so nasty.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr><sd>runs into view toward the door</sd>Titans!
                Go!</sp>

            <sd><char ref="Raven">Raven</char>  starts after him. <directNote kind="snap">Snap to black</directNote>.</sd>

            <cue>OPENING THEME</cue>

        </act>
        <act n="1">
            <title>Act One</title>
            <sd><stageDesc category="open-shot">Opening shot: a chamber similar to the one in which the theft occurred, seen from
                overhead</stageDesc>. The lights are dim but not out, and a large circular hatch, covered with a
                steel grid, is in the center of the floor. The Titans run in.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>Split up!</sp>

            <sd><char ref="Robin">Robin</char>  heads for the hatch as the others fan out toward four other doors. <directNote kind="cut">Cut to just
                below the grid</directNote>; water is heard running, and he stares down through the bars. Inside
                a sewer tunnel,<char ref="Robin">Robin</char> climbs down from an overhead ladder, within the pipe that
                leads here from the hatch, and drops into the water. One of the thieves is making a
                break for it;<char ref="Robin">Robin</char> gives a chase, runs briefly up the pipe wall to avoid a laser
                shot, and throws his birdarang. A huge jump carries the escapee out of its path, and
                a second shot reduces it to junk. Skid around a corner and o.c. down a side channel;
                a grenade is tossed back into view and promptly detonates.</sd>

            <sd>When the smoke clears, we see that the path has been almost entirely blocked by
                collapsed rock and debris. As<char ref="Robin">Robin</char> stops and stares through a small opening in the
                cave-in, the thief moves farther ahead toward a dead end, stops, and raises that
                blaster. <directNote kind="cut">Cut to outside</directNote>, near a mountainside at sunset. The beam emerges from within
                and traces out a door-shaped outline, and the piece falls away; the sewers run
                through the mountain. At the edge of the opening stands the thief, alone for only a
                brief moment until<char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char>  rises to that level.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr>I am asking you nicely to stop running
                and--</sp>

            <sd>Back to the fugitive on the end of this; up comes the weapon, and down goes<char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char> 
                in free fall, having taken the full hit. Her assailant jumps out after her and
                activates jet thrusters hidden in the boot soles to start flying away. Now <char ref="Robin">Robin</char> 
                having dug through the broken rock, reaches the opening just as the armored figure
                zooms up past him. He leaps out into space, a grappling hook in each hand, and fires
                one down and the second up.</sd>

            <sd>The first line wraps around<char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char>  as she drops toward the rocky waterway below,
                while the second loops onto the armored chest. The commando stops ascending and goes
                into a sharp dive;<char ref="Robin">Robin</char> is suddenly yanked along toward the water with a gasp and a
                long scream. Off they go, skimming the surface; the flyer towing<char ref="Robin">Robin</char> towing
                <char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char>  and head toward land. The wake of their passage throws up a wall of water,
                which hides everyone from view briefly.</sd>

            <sd><stageDesc category="close-up">Close-up of<char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char> </stageDesc>, half-dazed on the shore. She comes to and finds a wriggling
                fish stuck in her mouth, then spits it out and burps weakly.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr><sd>from o.c.</sd>Now talk!</sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="cut">Cut to behind her</directNote> and <directNote kind="zoom">zoom in on him</directNote>; he has the masked character by the
                collar.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>Who's <char ref="Slade">Slade</char>  Why does he want this chip?</sp>

            <sd><stageDesc category="close-up">Close-up of his hand</stageDesc> on the black/red-orange face.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr><sd>from o.c.</sd>And why are you
                working...for...him?</sp>

            <sd>On the end of this, he pulls the mask away. The reason for his trailing off is that
                the entire front half of the head comes off in his hand. Behind it is a small
                monitor; this commando is actually a robot, as were all the others involved in the
                heist. The blank display comes to life, resolving into a not-fully-tuned image of
               <char ref="Slade">Slade</char> in his lair. He appears only as a silhouette.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Slade">Slade</spkr>Excellent work, <char ref="Robin">Robin</char> </sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr><char ref="Slade">Slade</char> </sp>

            <sd>The image flickers and refines itself.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Slade">Slade</spkr>Really, I think your skills are improving.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>No more games! What do you want?</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="Slade">Slade</spkr>But you do lack patience. If you're really so curious
                about my intentions, perhaps we should meet face to face.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>Tell me where you're hiding and I'll be there in a
                heartbeat!</sp>

            <sd>The image detunes again.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Slade">Slade</spkr>Patience, <char ref="Robin">Robin</char> <sd>Flicker.</sd>Patience.</sp>

            <sd>A crackle of sparks, and the monitor goes dead. Smoke rises from within the skull as
                the system falls apart.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr><char ref="Robin">Robin</char> </sp>

            <sd>He releases his grip and the robotic body drops to the ground. <directNote kind="zoom">Zoom in on the fierce
                scowl that has settled on his face</directNote>, then <directNote kind="dissolve">dissolve to the exterior of Titans Tower.</directNote>
                It is now nighttime.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr><sd>from inside</sd>Okay. All work and no
                flicks makes me a dull <char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> </sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="cut">Cut to the operations center during this line</directNote>; he is standing before <char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char>  <char ref="Raven">Raven</char> 
                and <char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char>  who have settled on the couch.<char ref="Raven">Raven</char>  is reading a book.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>So, my fellow couch potatoes...<sd><stageDesc category="close-up">Close-up of
                    him.</stageDesc></sd>...what'll it be?<sd>holds up a tape</sd>Super Ninja Showdown
                Eight...</sp>

            <sd>He pushes it toward the camera, giving a clear view of the title and cover art. Two
                ninjas bow and start fighting; one is hit with a low kick and drops out of the
                picture.<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char>  pulls this tape back and holds up a second one.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>...or Maniac Fury: Attack of the
                Protozoids?</sp>

            <sd>He pushes it forward; this cover shows a Godzilla-like creature breathing fire as
                screaming people run for their lives, not to mention out of the picture and off the
                box altogether. The monster leans forward off the box to blow another scorching
                breath before pulling back.<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char>  withdraws the tape and grins broadly.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Raven">Raven</spkr><sd>from o.c.</sd>Gee.<sd><directNote kind="cut">Cut to her and
                   <char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char> </directNote>.</sd>They both sound so good.</sp>

            <sd>She returns to her book; <directNote kind="pull">pull back to frame<char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char> </directNote>.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>Yeah. It's really hard to pick.<sd>grins</sd>Want
                to watch 'em both?</sp>

            <sd>The overly critical Titan gives him a dirty look as a vein flares up on her
                forehead; this was not even close to what she had in mind.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr>Perhaps<char ref="Robin">Robin</char> would enjoy potato-ing the couch
                with us. Tell me, is he--?</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>--In the exact same place he's been since his
                little chat session with <char ref="Slade">Slade</char>  Uh, yeah.</sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="cut">Cut to a <stageDesc category="close-up">close-up</stageDesc> of <char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char>'s  very worried face</directNote> and <directNote kind="zoom">zoom in slightly</directNote>, then
                <directNote kind="dissolve">dissolve to a wall covered with newspaper clippings</directNote> about different villains'
                exploits in Jump City. <directNote kind="pan">Pan slowly across the display</directNote>.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Slade">Slade</spkr><sd>in <char ref="Robin">Robin</char>'s  memory</sd><char ref="Robin">Robin</char>  Is that the best you
                can do?</sp>

            <sd>Recall that he spoke those words during "Forces of Nature." The camera passes a
                support column and now gives a view of<char ref="Robin">Robin</char> standing at a desk under a solitary
                overhead light. This is his room, which was only glimpsed in "Switched." More
                clippings litter the floor.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Slade">Slade</spkr><sd>in <char ref="Robin">Robin</char>'s  memory</sd>Excellent work, <char ref="Robin">Robin</char>  I
                think your skills are improving.</sp>

            <sd>A couple of exposed pipes pass the camera; now we see a <stageDesc category="close-up">close-up of<char ref="Robin">Robin</char> from
                behind</stageDesc>. During the following line, it circles around slowly to point directly at
                him, deep in thought.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Slade">Slade</spkr><sd>in <char ref="Robin">Robin</char>'s  memory</sd>If you're really so curious
                about my intentions, perhaps we should meet face to face.</sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="cut">Cut to his perspective</directNote>, <directNote kind="pan">panning across the desk</directNote>. It is covered with a jumble of
                items: notes, maps, blueprints, wires, electrical instruments, parts of the commando
                robot's equipment, the front half of its head. Included among the lot is a
                communicator marked with a stylized S, very similar to the character on <char ref="Slade">Slade</char>'s 
                staff in "Forces of Nature", his particular insignia.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr><sd>in one of his memories</sd>Who are you?</sp>

            <sd>The door is heard opening; <directNote kind="cut">cut to in front of him again</directNote>. Light streams into the dim
                room from behind him.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr><sd>from "o.c."</sd><char ref="Robin">Robin</char> </sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="pan">Pan slightly</directNote> to show her at the open door.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr>I am wondering if you might wish to--</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>No.<sd><stageDesc category="close-up">Close-up of her</stageDesc>; he continues
                    o.c.</sd>Thanks.<sd><directNote kind="cut">Cut to behind her</directNote>, looking in at him.</sd>But I need to
                figure out why<char ref="Slade">Slade</char> wanted that chip.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr><sd>smiles</sd>Agreed.<sd>flushes a bit</sd>And
                perhaps if you were to take a break, the answer would be easier to--</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr><sd>from o.c.</sd>I can't.</sp>

            <sd>Outside the room again; he approaches her.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>You almost got hurt. Next time, it could be worse.
                He's planning something. I have to find out what.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr>But, <char ref="Robin">Robin</char>  I am sure that--</sp>

            <sd>He ends the conversation by closing the door in her face. <directNote kind="pull">Pull back down the hall</directNote>;
                she hangs her head and sighs quietly. <directNote kind="dissolve">Dissolve to the trashed chamber</directNote> in which the
                opening battle took place and pan across. In the dim light, two prison guards are
                now stationed by the recovered microchip, which has been placed back in the
                suspension field. All is quiet for some seconds, but the calm breaks when an alarm
                goes off and red warning lights flash. Both guards run toward the door; <directNote kind="cut">cut to its
                other side</directNote>, in the chamber where the Titans began their search for the thieves. The
                door is closed, but slides open to admit them. They point their weapons back and
                forth.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Guard1">Guard 1</spkr>I don't like this.</sp>

            <sd><stageDesc category="overhead-shot">Overhead view of the empty chamber,</stageDesc> then <directNote kind="cut">cut to behind the guards</directNote>. The door slides
                shut without warning.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Guard2">Guard 2</spkr><sd>as it closes</sd>Hey!</sp>

            <sd>The alarm falls silent, but the lights continue to flash-the alarm was in that other
                room, and the door has muffled it. <directNote kind="dissolve">Dissolve to a <stageDesc category="long-shot">longer shot</stageDesc> of the portal</directNote> and <directNote kind="pull">pull
                back slowly</directNote> to the chip in its protective field. A figure materializes to face it.
                <charDesc ref="RedX">Skintight black outfit with a large red X emblazoned over the heart; the low end of
                the upward stroke is extended to cross the chest. Long black cape. Gray belt and
                gloves, the latter with X's on the backs of the hands. A black mask whose face
                resembles a white skull, with another red X on the forehead; its upstroke is
                extended, like the one on the chest, to cross the right eye</charDesc>. This is<char ref="RedX">Red X</char>  .</sd>

            <sd>The newcomer plucks the chip from the field. There is an explosion from o.c.; cut to
                the door, which the guards have just blasted off its hinges. They run in.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Guard2">Guard 2</spkr>He's got the chip!</sp>

            <sd>They open fire;<char ref="RedX">Red X</char>  leaps straight up and disappears.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Guard1">Guard 1</spkr>Where'd he go?</sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="dissolve">Dissolve to the full moon in the night sky</directNote> and <directNote kind="tilt">tilt down to a rooftop in Jump City.</directNote>
                A small ringing is heard, similar to a cell phone, and<char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char>  extends his forearm
                into view. On it, a panel appears showing <char ref="Robin">Robin</char>'s  face; what we heard was the
                built-in communicator.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>I'm working a<char ref="Slade">Slade</char> lead on the far side of town.
                Sure you guys can handle this without me?</sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="pull">Pull back</directNote>; the other four Titans are there.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>No problem.</sp>

            <sd><char ref="Robin">Robin</char>  nods and the connection is broken. At the far edge of the roof, a skylight
                opens and<char ref="RedX">Red X</char>  climbs out. <stageDesc category="close-up">Close-up</stageDesc>, then <directNote kind="cut">cut back to the foursome on the next
                line</directNote>;<char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char>  breaks out his cannon.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>You working for <char ref="Slade">Slade</char>  tough guy?</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="RedX">Red X</spkr><char ref="RedX">Red X</char> works alone.</sp>

            <sd>The voice is male, but heavily distorted. He holds out one palm, revealing that same
                mark on it, and fires this toward the Titans.<char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char>  brings the cannon into play as
                the other three scatter; the two shots annihilate each other in midair. More cannon
                blasts send<char ref="RedX">Red X</char>  jumping all over the roof. Launching himself high into the air,
               <char ref="RedX">Red X</char>  fires X's from both palms and forces the big guy to run for cover.<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> 
                takes his place in the battle and <transform class="mammal">becomes a charging lion</transform>. The villain fires off
                another scarlet cross that becomes liquid as it flies; connecting with the green
                feline's face like a glob of mud, it carries him back down to the roof. When he
                lands, he is unable to pull free of the gluey mess. Lion, human, gorilla, falcon,
                elephant, none of those forms is strong enough to allow him to break loose.</sd>

            <sd><char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char>  and<char ref="Raven">Raven</char>  fly in; the former reels off starbolts while the latter prepares
                a spell.<char ref="RedX">Red X</char>  nimbly avoids both the shots and the large black hand that emerges at
                his feet and tries to grab him. Two big X's are hurled at the girls; <directNote kind="cut">cut to
               <char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char> </directNote>. One of them connects and ties her up like a giant rubber band, and she
                drops out of frame. <directNote kind="pan">Pan to<char ref="Raven">Raven</char> </directNote>.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Raven">Raven</spkr>Azarath Met--</sp>

            <sd>Much to <char ref="Raven">Raven</char>'s  shock, a red X plasters itself across her mouth, gagging her. Try as
                she might,<char ref="Raven">Raven</char>  cannot tear the X away and topples over.<char ref="RedX">Red X</char>  is in the clear, but
                a yell from the o.c.<char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char>  marks his approach. He drops into view and tries to
                seize the black-clad enemy, who sidesteps easily.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>Huh?</sp>

            <sd>He tries another punch, with no luck, and<char ref="RedX">Red X</char>  thumps him in the back.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>What?</sp>

            <sd><stageDesc category="close-up">Close-up</stageDesc>; another of the namesake weapons has been slapped on there. The panels open
                up and those gray-gloved hands reach in to tinker with the circuits. <char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char>'s  arms
                flail wildly.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>Hey! Yo, who told you how to shut me down?</sp>

            <sd>On the end of this line, his voice slows down and he slumps over on his feet. A
                little push sends him crashing down. With all four Titans out of action,<char ref="RedX">Red X</char>  bugs
                out.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>Yeah, you better run!</sp>

            <sd>He does exactly that, passing the gagged<char ref="Raven">Raven</char>  and the bound<char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char>  before jumping
                off the roof and disappearing. <directNote kind="cut">Cut to<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> </directNote>, <transform class="human">back in human form</transform> and still caught
                in the red mire.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>So, do you guys see what I don't see?</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>Who was that guy?</sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="dissolve">Dissolve to a <stageDesc category="close-up">close-up</stageDesc> of several pipes</directNote> and <directNote kind="pan">pan from them to <char ref="Slade">Slade</char>'s  lair</directNote>. <char ref="RedX">Red X</char>'s 
                image is on one of the giant monitors; he holds up the microchip in full view of the
                mastermind, who stands on the platform.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="RedX">Red X</spkr>Rumor has it, you're interested in this.</sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="cut">Cut to<char ref="Slade">Slade</char> </directNote>, silhouetted, and <directNote kind="zoom">zoom in slowly</directNote>.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Slade">Slade</spkr>I'm interested in many things, Mr. ...</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="RedX">Red X</spkr>X. <char ref="RedX">Red X</char> </sp>

            <sd><stageDesc category="close-up">Extreme close-up of <char ref="Slade">Slade</char>'s  eye</stageDesc>.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Slade">Slade</spkr>Hmmm. Catchy. So, are you proposing a sale or a
                gift?</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="RedX">Red X</spkr>A partnership. I give you the chip, you cut me in on
                your plans.</sp>

            <sd>The right side of <char ref="Slade">Slade</char>'s  head, panning across.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Slade">Slade</spkr>Partnership. My, my, we are ambitious. But an
                alliance cannot be forged from one small chip.</sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="pull">Pull back across the platform a bit</directNote> and <directNote kind="pan">pan across</directNote> to put him and <char ref="RedX">Red X</char>'s  image in
                frame.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Slade">Slade</spkr>If you're going to win my trust, I'll require
                more.</sp>

            <sd><stageDesc category="close-up">Close-up of the white skull face</stageDesc>.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="RedX">Red X</spkr>Just tell me what you want.</sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="fade">Fade to black</directNote>.</sd>

        </act>
        <act n="2">
            <title>Act Two</title>
            <sd><stageDesc category="open-shot">Opening shot: the exterior of Titans Tower</stageDesc>. It is now the following morning.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr><sd>from inside</sd>I had no idea<char ref="RedX">Red X</char>  would pose
                such a threat.</sp>

            <sd>In the kitchen, he is addressing the other Titans. <char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char>  seated on the counter,
                is clipping the red gunk out of a very annoyed <char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char>'s  hair. <char ref="Raven">Raven</char>'s  back is to
                the camera.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>I should've been there.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>You bet you should've been there. Look what he
                did to my 'do! I'm looking at two months of bad hair days!</sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="gag">Sight gag: a thundercloud floats briefly into view above his head and then vanishes.</directNote>
               <directNote kind="pan"> Quick pan to<char ref="Raven">Raven</char> </directNote>, who is seen to still have that big red X plastered across her
                mouth. She glares and cusses him out as best she can behind the gag. He and<char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char> 
                smile cautiously.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>I don't know, <char ref="Raven">Raven</char>  That's kind of a good
                look for you.</sp>

            <sd><stageDesc category="close-up">Close-up of <char ref="Raven">Raven</char>'s  gagged face</stageDesc> against a red field; the vein throbbing on her
                forehead speaks more clearly about her supreme vexation than her tongue can. The
                background returns to normal, and<char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char>  reaches into view to pry up a corner of the
                X.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr><sd>from o.c.</sd>Hold still...</sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="pull">Pull back</directNote>. As<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char>  and<char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char>  brace for the inevitable, he rips the thing
                away with one swift jerk. The two onlookers scream in sympathetic pain; <directNote kind="cut">cut to
               <char ref="Raven">Raven</char> </directNote>. A vivid red imprint has been left on her face, and she holds her lips pressed
                together as two ghostly images of her pop out to either side and scream through
                gritted teeth. They recede after a moment.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Raven">Raven</spkr><sd>calmly</sd>Ow.<sd>The imprint fades.</sd>Even if
                you had been there, it wouldn't have made any difference.</sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="pan">Pan to<char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char> </directNote>, holding up the X.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>Dude knew exactly how to bring each of us down. I
                guarantee he had a gadget with your name on it.</sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="cut">Cut to<char ref="Robin">Robin</char> on the end of this line</directNote>, then to<char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char>  and <char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> </sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr>Agreed. You need not feel guilt. We are
                undamaged.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr><sd>indicating his mangled
                hair</sd>Hel-lo?</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr><sd>blushing a bit</sd>Mostly undamaged. And we
                are all eager to learn what you have discovered about <char ref="Slade">Slade</char> </sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>Nothing. Lead was a dead end. I should get back to
                work.</sp>

            <sd>He turns away. <directNote kind="cut">Cut to the other four Titans</directNote>, who watch in concern as the side door
                is heard closing to mark his exit. <directNote kind="dissolve">Dissolve to the exterior of Tower</directNote>, at night, and
                <directNote kind="cut">cut to inside the operations center</directNote>. The door opens to admit the foursome in a rush;
                <char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char>'s  hair is back to normal.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>Okay, <char ref="Robin">Robin</char>  what's the...?</sp>

            <sd>All stop and look around.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr><char ref="Robin">Robin</char> </sp>

            <sd>Their perspective of the place, panning slowly across. No <char ref="Robin">Robin</char>  no villains, no
                nothing. <directNote kind="cut">Cut to near the couch</directNote>; they proceed slowly into view.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr><char ref="Robin">Robin</char> </sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>You mean Captain Research? Ah, he's probably
                filling out note cards at the public library.</sp>

            <sd>He yawns expansively.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr><sd>on speaker</sd>I was.</sp>

            <sd>These two words startle the daylights and a short scream out of him. <directNote kind="cut">Cut to behind
                the four</directNote>; <char ref="Robin">Robin</char>'s  face is on the window/screen.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>But then I spotted<char ref="RedX">Red X</char>  pulling a robbery in the
                tech sector.</sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="cut">Cut to them</directNote>, <directNote kind="pan">panning from<char ref="Raven">Raven</char>  to<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> </directNote> on the next line. He has fallen asleep
                on his feet and is snoring loudly.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr><sd>on speaker</sd>I'm on it. Get here as soon as you
                can!</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr><sd>sleepily, drooling a bit</sd>You got it,
                dude. We'll be there any...</sp>

            <sd>He nods off again before he can finish the sentence. A snore or two later,<char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char> 
                reaches down and grabs a fistful of clothing;<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char>  is jerked awake and yanked
                away with a scream. <directNote kind="dissolve">Dissolve to a group of buildings in Jump City</directNote>, viewed from near
                the rooftops, and <directNote kind="tilt">tilt down to the street</directNote>. The leaderless team is gathered there and
                ready for action. Nothing happens until<char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char>  points o.c.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>There!</sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="cut">Cut to behind him</directNote> and <directNote kind="zoom">zoom in</directNote>; he is looking at a nearby building, from whose roof,
               <char ref="RedX">Red X</char>  jumps down with<char ref="Robin">Robin</char> in hot pursuit. After a few dozen yards, the black-clad
                thief stops and throws a net back at the chaser. It ensnares him and sends him
                rolling across the pavement to stop near where he came down from the roof.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr><char ref="Robin">Robin</char> </sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>I'm fine! Get <char ref="RedX">X</char>! Go!</sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="cut">Cut to the other four on the end of this</directNote>. They set off; <directNote kind="cut">cut to a subway station
                entrance</directNote>, where<char ref="RedX">Red X</char>  takes the entire down escalator in one huge leap. Underground,
                <directNote kind="pan">pan from the quiet tunnel to the platform</directNote>. The crew is on the lookout.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>I've adjusted my ocular implant to scan at multiple
                sub-harmonics in the EM spectrum.</sp>

            <sd><stageDesc category="close-up">Extreme close-up, left side of his face</stageDesc>;<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char>  peeks out.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr><sd>confused</sd>'Kay...do you come with
                subtitles?</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>My eye should spot him even if he's invisible.</sp>

            <sd>His red-tinted perspective, pans across the station from track to platform. No
                activity, and then out of nowhere,<char ref="RedX">Red X</char>  drops into view and decks him. Normal view;
               <char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char>  is driven back several yards, then falls onto his back and skids the rest of
                the way to the far end.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Raven">Raven</spkr>It's him.</sp>

            <sd><char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char>  gets up, still a bit woozy and in no condition to immediately retaliate
                against the X that appears in midair and flies toward his back. <stageDesc category="close-up">Close-up of it</stageDesc>,
                being slapped in place by <char ref="RedX">Red X</char>  then pull back. A few sparks fly from the bionic
                Titan, but he remains in full control of his body this time. <directNote kind="pan">Pan from him to the
                would-be hacker</directNote> on the next line.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>You gonna have to learn some new tricks, dog.</sp>

            <sd>He gets five fingers in the material covering the chest and throws<char ref="RedX">Red X</char>  along the
                platform toward the others; the villain lands in a crouch.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr>Surrender! We do not wish to fight you!</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="RedX">Red X</spkr>Sorry. I'm not through with you yet.</sp>

            <sd>He bounds high and throws an X at her, but a last-second energy barrier created by
               <char ref="Raven">Raven</char>  stops it. Now<char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char>  tries to land a few punches, but hits only air, and
               <char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char>  goes for a low-altitude bulldoze that misses its mark but connects with the
                big man. Both crash to the ground. Silhouette view of the platform, <char ref="RedX">Red X</char>  <char ref="Raven">Raven</char> 
                and <char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char>  he nimbly gets the better of both, even after the shape-shifter turns
                into a bear. Normal view:<char ref="Raven">Raven</char>  tumbles down against some crates, and<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> 
                avenges her by ramming<char ref="RedX">Red X</char>  from behind <transform class="mammal">as a bighorn sheep</transform>.</sd>

            <sd>He quickly <transform class="human">resumes human form</transform> and charges again. The foe catches hold of a pole,
                swings his weight around it, and launches himself feet first back the way he came.
                His trajectory forces<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char>  to duck; a punch is thrown at the Titan, who stands
                up just in time to catch it on the jaw. <directNote kind="cut">Cut to the tracks</directNote>, where he is knocked
                across to hit the opposite edge and bounce down to the rails. Sitting up dazedly, he
                snaps back fully when the glare of headlights falls across him and a train whistle
                makes itself heard. The early express is right on time. As<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char>  stares like a
                deer about to snuff it on the grille of a pickup,<char ref="RedX">Red X</char>  hurtles across the tracks
                and pulls him screaming to safety. Both hit the platform an instant before the train
                hurtles through.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>Dude! Did you just save me?</sp>

            <sd>He is answered with a swift kick in the gut. When the train is gone, we see that the
                other three Titans are on the opposite side of the platform.<char ref="RedX">Red X</char>  runs for the exit
                stairs, and the group collects on <char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char>'s  side;<char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char>  helps him up.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr><char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char>  You are undamaged?</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>Who is that guy?</sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="fade">Fade to black</directNote>.</sd>

            <sd><directNote kind="pan">Pan to bring a pool of light into view</directNote>, cast by an overhead source.<char ref="RedX">Red X</char>  sits at a
                desk under it and is busy at a computer. <char ref="Slade">Slade</char>'s  silhouette is on the monitor.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Slade">Slade</spkr>Impressive, <char ref="RedX">Red X</char> <sd><stageDesc category="close-up">Extreme close-up of his eye as
                    he continues</stageDesc>.</sd>I tapped into the security cameras to catch your performance.
                You treated the Titans to quite a show.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="RedX">Red X</spkr>Glad you enjoyed it.</sp>

            <sd>He holds up two microchips; the red one he stole from the computer facility, as well
                as a blue one taken in the recent robbery.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="RedX">Red X</spkr>Is the audition over?</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="Slade">Slade</spkr>Patience. Trust is easy to destroy, but it takes time
                to build.</sp>

            <sd>His image gradually shrinks toward the top right corner of the screen, giving way to
                a pure white field. A third microchip, this one green, is revealed.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Slade">Slade</spkr>One last test. Prove yourself and we'll meet to
                discuss your future.</sp>

            <sd>He fades away, leaving only the bit of hardware on the display. The picture
                disintegrates into static; <directNote kind="pan">pan from it to<char ref="RedX">Red X</char> </directNote>, seen from behind. He turns to the
                camera.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="RedX">Red X</spkr>Good.</sp>

            <sd>The mask is pulled off; revealing none other than<char ref="Robin">Robin</char> behind it.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>It's about time we met face to face.</sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="fade">Fade to black</directNote>.</sd>

        </act>
        <act n="3">
            <title>Act Three</title>
            <sd><stageDesc category="open-shot">Opening shot: the exterior of the Tower</stageDesc>. It is later that same night.<directNote kind="cut"> Cut to a
                computer map of Jump City</directNote>, with two spots marked, and <directNote kind="pull">pull back</directNote>; it is on the
                operations center window/screen, and all the Titans but<char ref="Robin">Robin</char> are looking at it.
               <char ref="Raven">Raven</char>  stands at one of the consoles.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>Okay. That's where<char ref="RedX">Red X</char>  has been. Now we just have
                to figure out where he's gonna strike next.</sp>

            <sd><char ref="Raven">Raven</char>  does a little typing; in response, many more spots on the map light up.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr><sd>wearily</sd>Great.</sp>

            <sd>Footsteps from o.c.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr><char ref="Robin">Robin</char> <sd>He moves into view, carrying a
                    box.</sd>Wonderful! Our efforts to locate the<char ref="RedX">Red X</char>  will benefit greatly from
                you help.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr><sd>heading toward the side door</sd>It'll have to
                wait. I'm close to a breakthrough with <char ref="Slade">Slade</char> </sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr><sd>gasps</sd>More wonderful!<sd><directNote kind="cut">Cut to him at
                    the door</directNote>; she continues o.c.</sd>Perhaps we could be of assistance to...</sp>

            <sd><char ref="Robin">Robin</char>  trails off briefly as his back retreats into the dark hall.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr><sd>from o.c.</sd>...you.</sp>

            <sd><stageDesc category="close-up">Close-up</stageDesc>; she hangs her head dejectedly.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr><sd>from o.c.</sd>Let him go.<sd><directNote kind="cut">Cut to him
                    and the others</directNote>.</sd>Not like he's been much help lately anyway. If<char ref="Robin">Robin</char> wasn't
                always A.W.O.L., <char ref="RedX">X</char> would be K.O.'d by now.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="Raven">Raven</spkr>I can't believe I'm saying this, but <char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char>'s 
                right.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>Y'all think maybe <char ref="Robin">Robin</char>'s  losing his grip?</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr>No! <char ref="Robin">Robin</char>'s  grip is not lost!<sd><directNote kind="cut">Cut to the
                    others</directNote>, nonplussed; she continues o.c.</sd>He works harder than any of you! He
                works to catch<char ref="Slade">Slade</char> before something terrible happens!<sd>Back to her.</sd>He works
                to save us all!</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>Yeah. That's why every time we need him, he
                disappears.</sp>

            <sd><char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char>  has no ready answer for this charge. <directNote kind="dissolve">Dissolve to an overhead view of
                <char ref="Robin">Robin</char>'s  room</directNote>, with that single overhead light still shining down on the loaded desk.
                The door is closed, but opens to admit her; as she proceeds in and looks at the
                newspaper-covered walls,<char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char>  recalls some of his words.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr><sd><char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char>'s  memory; sentences overlap</sd>Who's
                <char ref="Slade">Slade</char> ...You almost got hurt. Next time, it could be worse...Nothing. Lead was a
                dead end...I'm close to a breakthrough...Sure you guys can handle this without
                me?</sp>

            <sd><char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char>  stops at the desk to look at the items and picks up, from one end, the
                blasted birdarang from the sewer chase in.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr><char ref="Robin">Robin</char>  where have you gone?</sp>

            <sd>There is a flash from o.c., the level of the desk, and she drops the weapon with a
                gasp. It glances off a small metal globe on the corner of the desk and knocks it
                over the edge. This thing bounces a couple of times and rolls slowly to a stop near
                the wall. A beam of light shoots straight up from it and splits into two that fold
                down toward the floor on either side. Between them, a holographic image of<char ref="Robin">Robin</char> 
                appears; caught up in the net as during the Titans' first pursuit of <char ref="RedX">Red X</char>  He
                flickers a bit.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Hologram Robin</spkr>I'm fine! Get <char ref="RedX">X</char>! Go!</sp>

            <sd><char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char>'s  foot steps into view near it.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr><sd>from o.c.</sd>Huh?<sd><directNote kind="cut">Cut to
                her</directNote>.</sd><char ref="Robin">Robin</char> </sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Hologram Robin</spkr>I'm fine! Get <char ref="RedX">X</char>! Go!<sd>as<char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char> 
                    reaches through him</sd>I'm fine! Get <char ref="RedX">X</char>! Go!</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr>If you were not really there, then where
                were...</sp>

            <sd>She gasps sharply as the truth dawns on her; <char ref="Robin">Robin</char>'s  masquerade as <char ref="RedX">Red X</char>  coupled
                with the fact that the<char ref="Robin">Robin</char> who accompanied the other Titans on their chase was
                this double. <directNote kind="cut">Cut to a <stageDesc category="close-up">close-up</stageDesc> of the green microchip</directNote> seen during his last talk with
                <char ref="Slade">Slade</char>  in a protective field of its own. <directNote kind="pull">Pull back as<char ref="RedX">Red X</char>  approaches</directNote> to show the
                surrounding area dimly lit. He plucks the item away; <directNote kind="pan">pan across the area</directNote> to show a
                pool of light cast from one overhead lamp.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Slade">Slade</spkr><sd>from o.c.</sd>Excellent work.</sp>

            <sd>The thief turns toward the light. A figure approaches it from the far side, so that
                the details are momentarily washed out, but as it steps to the center of the circle,
                it is revealed as <char ref="Slade">Slade</char>  <charDesc ref="Slade">He is garbed in the same manner as his commando robots;
                black armor, steel reinforcements and hand/footgear, but with two differences. One,
                a dark gray sash crosses his chest from right shoulder to left side; two, his mask
                is red-orange on the left side, as seen in "Forces of Nature," and black on the
                right. The black half has no eyehole</charDesc>.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Slade">Slade</spkr>Honestly, I couldn't have done better myself.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="RedX">Red X</spkr>So, do we have a deal?</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="Slade">Slade</spkr>Indeed. You and I are so very much alike. It seems
                only natural that we should be partners.</sp>

            <sd><stageDesc category="close-up">Close-up of his open hand</stageDesc> on the end of this, then <directNote kind="cut">cut to<char ref="RedX">Red X</char> </directNote>, who holds up all
                three microchips.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="RedX">Red X</spkr>What are they for? I need to know what we're
                planning...partner.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="Slade">Slade</spkr>Patience. You can't expect me to trust you with such
                sensitive information right away...<sd><stageDesc category="close-up">Extreme close-up of his eye</stageDesc>.</sd>...can
                you..., <char ref="Robin">Robin</char> </sp>

            <sd><char ref="RedX">Red X</char>'s  eyes pop at the realization that his cover has been blown. There is a flash
                from behind him, and a small net flies from this into view, sweeps the three
                components from his hand, and carries them to <char ref="Slade">Slade</char>'s . Now the lights come up to
                reveal the room as a large, oblong chamber with several robots standing around the
                perimeter. They are identical to the ones that attacked the H.I.V.E. graduates
                during the highlight reel at the start of "Final Exam." In addition, there is a
                balcony that is now packed with ranks of commando robots. From one direction after
                another, the mechanical enforcers advance slightly to close in.<char ref="RedX">Red X</char>  gets ready to
                throw down, and the <directNote kind="cut">camera cuts to<char ref="Slade">Slade</char> </directNote>. As the robots on either side of him start
                to advance, the entire room shakes with the force of an o.c. explosion. <directNote kind="cut">Cut to its
                source</directNote>; the ceiling has been blown out, and shadows start to appear in the
                smoke.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr><sd>within the smoke</sd>Titans! Go!</sp>

            <sd><char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char>  drops into view, then <char ref="Raven">Raven</char>  and finally <char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char>  As<char ref="RedX">Red X</char>  sprints across
                the room, <char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char>  <transform class="fish">now an octopus</transform>, yanks one robot away, and<char ref="Raven">Raven</char>  levitates a
                second and forces it off.<char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char>  hits the ground running and gets a hand on that
                black cape; <directNote kind="pan">pan from him to<char ref="RedX">Red X</char> </directNote>.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>Gotcha!</sp>

            <sd><char ref="Slade">Slade</char>  turns and runs out of the place.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="RedX">Red X</spkr><sd>struggles while pointing</sd>Let go! Stop
                him!</sp>

            <sd><char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char>  flies in through the ceiling hole.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr>No! Release him! He is--</sp>

            <sd>He unmasks himself.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>--Me!</sp>

            <sd>The other three Titans are caught flat-footed by this and make noises of surprise
                for a moment.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Raven">Raven</spkr><char ref="Robin">Robin</char>  We...</sp>

            <sd>He pulls loose and runs to the door.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr><char ref="Slade">Slade</char>'s  getting away! Come on!</sp>

            <sd>A huge leap carries him over the two robots flanking the door, but they just stare
                after him. Now several commandos jump down from the balcony; <directNote kind="pull">pull back slowly</directNote>, then
                <directNote kind="dissolve">dissolve to a <stageDesc category="long-shot">longer shot</stageDesc></directNote> and <directNote kind="pull">keep pulling back to the wall</directNote>. More of them land with
                their backs to the camera.</sd>

            <sd><directNote kind="cut">Cut to</directNote> a <directNote kind="pan">pan across the rooftop</directNote> of this building. A vent cap pops off, and out comes
               <char ref="Slade">Slade</char> as if launched from a cannon;<char ref="Robin">Robin</char> comes out after him, having ditched the
               <char ref="RedX">Red X</char>  outfit in favor of his own. He chases<char ref="Slade">Slade</char> from one rooftop to the next, the
                <directNote kind="pan">camera panning to follow</directNote>, and matches the criminal on every leap across a space
                between buildings. A birdarang is thrown ahead, but a quick backhand from<char ref="Slade">Slade</char> 
                shatters it.<char ref="Robin">Robin</char> stares down at the pieces as his nemesis runs to the edge and
                takes an impossible flying leap toward a distant rooftop that has a framework of
                support beams erected on it. A huge electric billboard throws a red glow over this
                area.</sd>

            <sd><char ref="Slade">Slade</char>  stops for a look back and sees<char ref="Robin">Robin</char> standing on the high, far plateau. <char ref="Robin">The
                Boy Wonder</char> takes a few steps back and goes into a headlong rush; <stageDesc category="overhead-shot">overhead view of
                the street</stageDesc>, <directNote kind="pan">panning across</directNote>, as he vaults into the elevated emptiness and begins to
                drop toward the pool of red light. He lands safely and tumbles a bit before coming
                up in a crouch to face <char ref="Slade">Slade</char> </sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Slade">Slade</spkr>Careful. I wouldn't want you getting hurt.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>I'm not the one who's going to get hurt. Now hand
                them over!</sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="cut">Cut to a spot between them</directNote>.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Slade">Slade</spkr><sd>walking into view</sd><char ref="Robin">Robin</char>  I thought we had a
                deal.</sp>

            <sd><char ref="Robin">Robin</char>'s  feet come into view; they circle.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr><sd>from o.c.</sd>Sorry. I have a strict rule against
                giving stolen technology to psychos.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="Slade">Slade</spkr>How very noble of you. But stealing in order to trap
                me? That wasn't so noble. Two wrongs don't make a--</sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="cut">Cut to<char ref="Robin">Robin</char> </directNote>.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>Don't ever lecture me! Whatever you're planning,
                <char ref="Slade">Slade</char>  it's over!</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="Slade">Slade</spkr>On the contrary, <char ref="Robin">Robin</char>  it's just begun.</sp>

            <sd>They charge at one another. Silhouetted in the harsh glow from that billboard, they
                try a few times to hit each other. Backing up a bit,<char ref="Slade">Slade</char> dodges a couple of
                <char ref="Robin">Robin</char>'s  strikes; another silhouette view shows him avoiding more blows and then
                landing a kick that tumbles<char ref="Robin">Robin</char> several yards, almost to the edge. The teen gets
                to his feet and goes on the offensive, forcing<char ref="Slade">Slade</char> to back around a corner while
                dodging a kick.</sd>

            <sd>Now the battle has shifted to within the framework.<char ref="Slade">Slade</char> avoids <char ref="Robin">Robin</char>'s  punches and
                nails him with another kick, then rushes in to attempt a follow-up hit. Back and
                forth they go, neither connecting with the other until a green fist is caught in a
                steel one. That big armored elbow is driven into <char ref="Robin">Robin</char>'s  solar plexus, knocking the
                wind out of him, and he is flung toward the edge of the rooftop. He stumbles against
                a couple of crates and falls out of sight with a short scream.</sd>

            <sd><stageDesc category="close-up">Close-up of his fingers</stageDesc>, which are clinging to the ledge for dear life, and <directNote kind="pull">pull
                back to frame<char ref="Robin">Robin</char> </directNote> hanging hundreds of feet above the traffic. The masonry starts
                to crumble, then gives way to drop him screaming toward the street. Another <stageDesc category="close-up">close-up
                of his hand</stageDesc>;<char ref="Slade">Slade</char> reaches into view and seizes the wrist. The masked face stares
                intently down at him.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>You...saved me?</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="Slade">Slade</spkr>I'm not through with you.</sp>

            <sd>He hauls<char ref="Robin">Robin</char> back up and tosses him easily toward the framework. The youth lands
                on one of the upper beams and hurls himself back downward to start the brawl all
                over again. Back and forth they go once more; this time, it ends when<char ref="Robin">Robin</char> lands a
                flying straight punch that sends<char ref="Slade">Slade</char> and the three microchips careening away. The
                latter land in a pile, while the former slides to the edge. <directNote kind="cut">Cut to just behind him</directNote>;
               <char ref="Robin">Robin</char> strides up.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>This ends now!</sp>

            <sd>He pulls the man's mask off. <directNote kind="cut">Cut to a <stageDesc category="close-up">close-up</stageDesc> of the head</directNote>-whose entire front half
                has come away, just like that of the commando robot he tried to interrogate after
                the first heist. This is not the real <char ref="Slade">Slade</char>  then, but merely a mechanical double.
                Its head contains a monitor that shows the genuine evil mastermind, seen in full
                detail, exactly matching this robot, and in his lair. The image is not properly
                tuned.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Slade">Slade</spkr>Patience, <char ref="Robin">Robin</char> <sd>Image fine-tunes.</sd>We'll meet
                face to face some other time. Oh, and speaking of time...</sp>

            <sd>A large number 5 superimposes itself on the view and changes to 4, then 3. Realizing
                what is about to happen,<char ref="Robin">Robin</char> puts his feet in overdrive. The counter is now at 2;
                it drops to 1, and the <directNote kind="pull">camera pulls back to a <stageDesc category="long-shot">long shot</stageDesc> of the building</directNote> as a long
                beep marks zero. A massive explosion roars from the rooftop; the detonation of the
               <char ref="Slade">Slade</char> robot. <directNote kind="cut">Cut to the blast site</directNote> and <directNote kind="pan">pan to<char ref="Robin">Robin</char> </directNote>, who is staring morosely at it,
                and the other Titans gathered at a distance.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>Heh. At least he didn't get the chips.</sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="fade">Fade to black</directNote>.</sd>

            <sd><directNote kind="fade">Fade in to the exterior of the Tower</directNote>. It is later that same night. Inside, <directNote kind="cut">cut to
                the floor of <char ref="Robin">Robin</char>'s  room</directNote> and <directNote kind="tilt">tilt up slowly to frame him at the wall</directNote>. The door is
                heard opening; side view of him, staring at the<char ref="Slade">Slade</char> robot's mask that he has hung
                on the wall. <directNote kind="pan">Pan slightly to put<char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char>  in view</directNote> as she enters. He does not
                turn.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>You want to yell at me, too?<sd><stageDesc category="close-up">Close-up of the mask</stageDesc>;
                    he pulls it down and continues o.c.</sd>Everyone else has.</sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="pull">Pull back to frame him</directNote> on the end of this line. He stares at the mask.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr><sd>turning around</sd>And I don't blame them.</sp>

            <sd><char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char>  approaches.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr>I do not wish to yell, merely to understand.
                <char ref="Robin">Robin</char>  why did you not tell us the truth?</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>I needed to fool <char ref="Slade">Slade</char>  If you guys knew it was me
                under that mask, you would've held back.<sd><directNote kind="zoom">Zoom in slowly</directNote>.</sd>Doesn't matter
                anyway.<char ref="Slade">Slade</char> figured it out, and I still haven't figured out anything about
                him.</sp>

            <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr>That is not true. Whoever<char ref="Slade">Slade</char> is, you and he
                are similar.<char ref="Slade">Slade</char> did not trust you,<sd><stageDesc category="close-up">Close-up of him</stageDesc>; <directNote kind="zoom">zoom in as she continues</directNote>
                    o.c.</sd>and you did not trust us.</sp>

            <sd><directNote kind="pull">Pull back to frame both</directNote>; she gives him one last reproachful look and heads for the
                door, her footsteps echoing hollowly in the space. He gazes at the mask in his hand
                for a long moment, lost in thoughts of how this undercover job could have unfolded
                had<char ref="Slade">Slade</char> not bowled him out. <directNote kind="pull">Pull back to just inside the open door</directNote>, the camera
                pointing at the cluttered walls and floor and the now-cleared desk under that single
                light. <char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char>'s  shadow retreats in the shaft of light from the hall. <directNote kind="fade">Fade to black</directNote>
                as the door closes.</sd>
        </act>
    </body>
</root>