<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../schema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?><root>
    <head>
        <episode>FINAL EXAM</episode>
        <writer>David Slack</writer>
        <director>Ciro Nieli</director>
        <storyboard>Kalvin Lee, Rafael Rosado, Alan Wan</storyboard>
        <animation>Dong Woo Animation Company, Ltd.</animation>
        <source>https://teentitans.fandom.com/wiki/Divide_and_Conquer_(Transcript)</source>
        <issueList>
            <issueInfo none="y"/>
        </issueList>
    </head>
    <characterList>
        <charList type="nonrecurring" id="Guard1">Guard 1</charList>
        <charList type="nonrecurring" id="Guard3">Guard 3</charList>
        <charList type="nonrecurring" id="Guard8">Guard 8</charList>
        <charList type="recurring" subtype="villain" id="Cinderblock">Cinderblock</charList>
        <charList type="recurring" subtype="titan" id="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</charList>
        <charList type="recurring" subtype="titan" id="Robin">Robin</charList>
        <charList type="recurring" subtype="titan" id="Starfire">Starfire</charList>
        <charList type="recurring" subtype="titan" id="Raven">Raven</charList>
        <charList type="recurring" subtype="titan" id="Cyborg">Cyborg</charList>
        <charList type="nonrecurring" id="Prisoners">Prisoners</charList>
        <charList type="recurring" subtype="villain" id="P385901">Prisoner 385901</charList>
        <charList type="nonrecurring" id="Guards">Guards</charList>
        <charList type="nonrecurring" id="Prisoner1">Prisoner 1</charList>
        <charList type="nonrecurring" id="Prisoner2">Prisoner 2</charList>
        <charList type="recurring" subtype="villain" id="Slade">Slade</charList>
        <charList type="recurring" subtype="villain" id="Plasmus">Plasmus</charList>
    </characterList>
    <body>
        <act n="0">
            <title>Prologue</title>
            <sd><stageDesc category="open-shot">Opening shot: an overhead view of a prison at
                    night</stageDesc>. Smoke pours from behind the outer wall and the shattered
                front entrance, as well as from a spot on the bridge that leads to the complex.
                    <annot>If these clues are not enough to indicate that something very bad is
                    going on, the blaring klaxons and sirens settle the point decisively</annot>.
                    <directNote kind="zoom">Zoom in very slowly</directNote> and <directNote kind="cut">cut to inside the
                    entrance</directNote>; three guards run in through it.<charDesc ref="Guards">Each has a number emblazoned on his shoulder-1, 3, 8.</charDesc></sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Guard1">Guard 1</spkr>Code red! Cellblock Nine! Move out!</sp>
            <sd>The other two follow orders, and he brings up the rear. They run in a short distance
                and then slow to a walk, weapons at the ready.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Guard1">Guard 1</spkr>Main yard secure.</sp>
            <sd>Something very large is thrown down in front of them to roll a little bit.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Guard3">Guard 3</spkr>There he is!</sp>
            <sd>They advance.</sd>
            <sp><spkr ref="Guard8">Guard 8</spkr>He’ll free the criminals!</sp>
            <sd>They level their weapons.</sd>
            <sp><spkr ref="Guard1">Guard 1</spkr>Fire!</sp>
            <sd>Their target has already bashed a large hole through the wall of the cellblock and
                is on the way in-he threw part of the torn-out section at them. Seen from the back,
                    <charDesc ref="Cinderblock">this creature is at least ten feet tall, very
                    blocky, and appears to be built entirely of concrete</charDesc>.<annot>We have
                    just met the villain<char ref="Cinderblock">Cinderblock</char> </annot>. Laser blasts from the
                guards strike the edges of the hole he has made, while a few connect with his back
                and others fly past. He turns to them, <charDesc ref="Cinderblock">revealing an equally blocky face with small
                red eyes</charDesc>. The shots are having no discernible effect on him. Voicing a grating roar,
                he raises one massive foot and stomps the ground; this produces a long fissure that
                throws debris and dust into the three guards’ faces to spoil their aim.<directNote kind="cut">Cut to inside the cellblock</directNote>. He moves in and stops upon
                hearing the next words.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr><sd>from o.c.</sd>You know,
                    <char ref="Cinderblock">Cinderblock</char> , normally the bad guys break out of jail.</sp>
            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr><sd>from o.c.</sd>And I can think of five good
                reasons why you don’t want to break in.</sp>
            <sd><directNote kind="cut">Cut to<char ref="Robin">Robin</char> </directNote>; he leaps across the
                floor and lands in a crouch.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr><sd>voice over</sd>One!</sp>
            <sd>Now<char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char> swoops and lands, looking sidelong at the camera from over
                her shoulder.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr><sd>voice over</sd>Two!</sp>
            <sd><char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> , as a<transform class="mammal">tiger</transform>, lunges in.
                When he comes down, he has taken human form except for his head and one arm; he
                quickly restores these as well.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr><sd>voice over</sd>Three!</sp>
            <sd>Next,<char ref="Raven">Raven</char> drops in and gets ready to cast a spell.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Raven">Raven</spkr><sd>voice over</sd>Four!</sp>
            <sd>Finally<char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char> jumps in.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr><sd>voice over</sd>Five!</sp>
            <sd>The Titans stand ready for battle now.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr><oneLine>No matter how you do the math, it all adds up to you
                going down.</oneLine> So, are you going to go quietly...</sp>
            <sd>
                <directNote kind="pan">Pan to<char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char> </directNote>
            </sd>
            <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>…or is this gonna get loud?</sp>
            <sd><char ref="Cinderblock">Cinderblock</char> roars and barrels straight toward them.</sd>
            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>Titans! Go!</sp>
            <sd>They charge;<annot><char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> becomes a<transform class="bird">hawk</transform>to fly behind<char ref="Raven">Raven</char> and
                    <char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char> </annot>.Yelling, the five heroes and the one oversized
                villain hurtle toward one another.<directNote kind="freeze-frame">Freeze frame and
                    snap to black</directNote>.</sd>

            <cue>OPENING THEME</cue>

        </act>
        <act n="1">
            <title>Act 1</title>
            <sd><stageDesc category="open-shot">Opening shot:<char ref="Cinderblock">Cinderblock</char> continuing his
                    rush</stageDesc>. The Titans do likewise. After a few seconds,
                    <directNote kind="shift">the view shifts to
                    <stageDesc>letterbox</stageDesc></directNote>, with the image in the top half of
                the screen. Silhouettes of the two sides charge ahead, after which<directNote kind="shift">the view returns to fullscreen</directNote>and<char ref="Robin">Robin</char> 
                lands a solid kick that staggers the foe. He turns around just in time to catch a
                double dose of starbolts in the back, courtesy of<char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char> . Now
                    <char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char> aims a right hook; even though<char ref="Cinderblock">Cinderblock</char>  stops
                it, he is still driven back by the impact.</sd>

            <sd><char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> dives in and rakes his<transform class="bird">talons</transform>across the concrete body time after time, forcing
                    <char ref="Cinderblock">Cinderblock</char> to run to another corner.<char ref="Raven">Raven</char> puts herself
                in his path and levitates a section of the floor, tilting it up until it stands
                vertical. She rises out of the way an instant before he crashes through this
                improvised barrier, then flies away as<char ref="Robin">Robin</char> ,<char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char> , and
                    <char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char> rush him</sd>

            <sd><annot>One giant backhand leaves only<char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char> still in motion; the other
                    two have been knocked away</annot>. She throws a couple of starbolts, but is
                then grabbed in those two enormous hands and pulled in with a little gasp for a
                face-to-face look at<char ref="Cinderblock">Cinderblock</char> . A smile comes over her face.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr>I am sorry to disappoint you, but I am stronger
                than I look.</sp>
            <sd><annot>She proves it by breaking his hold and delivering a high kick that drives him
                    back against the wall.</annot>A cry from the o.c.<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char>-<transform class="bird">hawk</transform>is heard, and he swoops in
                again; in an instant, he has hit the ground and transformed into a<transform class="reptile">tyrannosaurus rex</transform>.<char ref="Cinderblock">Cinderblock</char> stands pat
                before his thundering charge and knocks him back with a single left hook.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Raven">Raven</spkr>Azarath Metrion-</sp>
            <sd>She cuts off the incantation with a sharp, shocked gasp as she discovers<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char>’s shadow falling over her and sees him dropping from above.
                    <stageDesc category="overhead-shot">Overhead view; his panicked yell from o.c.
                    is accompanied by the shadow’s change to human form</stageDesc>. He falls on her
                like a ton of bricks and is the first to get up, shaking his head to clear it.
                    <char ref="Raven">Raven</char> stands a moment later and grits her teeth in anger before
                getting herself under control. A lock of hair falls over her face.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr><sd>sheepishly</sd>Heh… watch out for falling
                dinosaurs?</sp>
            <sd>She gives him a hard glance and blows the hair aside.</sd>
            <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>I’m gonna leave you alone now.</sp>
            <sd>He bugs out.<char ref="Cinderblock">Cinderblock</char> chuckles to himself and starts to cross the
                area, but<char ref="Robin">Robin</char> jumps onto his neck and tries to put him in a headlock.
                Stumbling about at random, the stone behemoth tears a girder loose from the wall.
                    <stageDesc>A chunk of concrete from the floor goes with it.</stageDesc></sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>Thrashing only makes me hold tighter!</sp>
            <sd><char ref="Cinderblock">Cinderblock</char> raises the girder for a swing back over his shoulder to hit
                    <char ref="Robin">Robin</char> , but misses when the Boy Wonder jumps away just in time; he
                only clocks himself in the head.<char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char> looks at another girder.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>Now there’s an idea.</sp>
            <sd>He rips it free and charges.<stageDesc category="letterbox">Letterbox: he and
                        <char ref="Cinderblock">Cinderblock</char> , in silhouette, swing at each other, the entire
                    screen flashing blue every time their makeshift clubs collide</stageDesc>.
                    <char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char> steadily gains ground on the enemy.<stageDesc category="fullscreen">Fullscreen: they struggle at close quarters, and
                        <char ref="Cinderblock">Cinderblock</char> pushes<char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char> back in preparation for a
                    mighty swing</stageDesc>.It connects, sending the Titan and his
                girder skidding across the floor.<char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char> floats down from above;
                    <char ref="Cinderblock">Cinderblock</char> gets ready to let her have it, but the quick flash of a
                starbolt causes the steel to heat and soften in his hands. He grunts in surprise,
                and she laughs as<char ref="Raven">Raven</char> looks on.</sd>

            <sd><char ref="Cinderblock">Cinderblock</char> grunts and runs off down<stageDesc category="setting">the
                    corridor, heading deeper into the prison</stageDesc>.<char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char> is still
                flat on his back, but gets up with a helping hand from<char ref="Robin">Robin</char> and dusts
                himself off.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>Want to give this guy the Sonic Boom?</sp>
            <sd><char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char> smiles and converts his arm to sonic cannon mode.</sd>
            <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr><oneLine>I got the Sonic if you got the Boom.</oneLine></sp>
            <sd>Their three teammates regroup and look off down the corridor.<directNote kind="cut">Cut to<char ref="Cinderblock">Cinderblock</char> , still heading farther in.</directNote></sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr><sd>from o.c.</sd>Yo, Rockhead!</sp>
            <sd>He stops and turns around to find<char ref="Robin">Robin</char> and<char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char> running
                straight at him. They peel off to opposite sides and go up the walls, then jump
                toward each other as the cannon warms up. Whatever they were planning goes badly
                wrong, however, as their feet get tangled up and they are left spinning out of
                control in midair. Finally they fly apart and<char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char> crashes into the
                wall. His cannon goes off, producing a blast of sound that engulfs<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char>and<char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char> .<char ref="Robin">Robin</char> slams against the other
                wall; a disc in his hand slides away and detonates at<char ref="Raven">Raven</char> ’s feet.</sd>

            <sd>
                <stageDesc category="setting"><char ref="Cinderblock">Cinderblock</char> is completely unscathed by the
                    fireworks and clumps away, smashing straight through one wall after another in
                    his path.<char ref="Prisoners">Prisoners</char> step out to look after the lumbering colossus,
                    then start to sprint out the same way he came in.</stageDesc>
            </sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Prisoners">Various prisoners</spkr>Hey, hey, look at this. It’s
                freedom!...Let’s do it!...Let’s get outta here!...Yeah!</sp>
            <sd>Other voices are heard among these words.<directNote kind="cut">Cut to
                        <char ref="Robin">Robin</char> , on his feet and rubbing his head</directNote>; the
                commotion reaches him from around the corner, and soon a throng of escaping
                     prisoners is coming straight at him. He whips out his fighting staff
                and extends it to full length, and he,<char ref="Raven">Raven</char> ,<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> ,
                    and<char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char> get ready to throw down.<stageDesc category="letterbox">Letterbox: silhouettes of the four Titans and
                        the prisoners against a red background</stageDesc>. As the latter
                are caught by surprise, the former let them have it.<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> resumes
                    his<transform class="reptile">T-rex</transform>form to scare the living bejesus
                out of them.</sd>

            <sd><stageDesc category="fullscreen">Fullscreen: close-up of a sign on a cell door.
                "Prisoner<char ref="P385901">385901</char> -Absolute Silence!"</stageDesc>
                <char ref="Cinderblock">Cinderblock</char> ’s footsteps rumble from o.c. and his shadow appears over
                the sign.<stageDesc category="setting">Inside the cell, which is extremely large, a
                    cylindrical glass tank of liquid is suspended from the ceiling</stageDesc>.
                Within it is the figure of a man, floating erect and<charDesc ref="P385901">clad only
                    in a pair of underwear</charDesc>.<stageDesc category="setting">The door is
                    smashed off its hinges</stageDesc>, and<char ref="Cinderblock">Cinderblock</char> enters and
                approaches the tank. In close-up,<charDesc ref="P385901">the man is seen to be
                    perhaps in his thirties, very thin, with a shaved head</charDesc>. He is asleep
                and snoring loudly.</sd>

            <sd><char ref="Cinderblock">Cinderblock</char> rips the entire tank away from the ceiling-mounted apparatus
                that holds it; broken hoses spew liquid and gases about the cell. He then punches a
                hole in the floor and jumps through it to make his escape, pulling the tank after
                himself. Even though the container gets briefly stuck and has to be yanked forcibly
                through the hole,<char ref="P385901">385901</char> does not so much as stir in his sleep.</sd>

            <sd>
                <directNote kind="wipe">Wipe to just outside the entrance of the cellblock as two
                         prisoners run out in a bid for freedom.</directNote>
            </sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Prisoner1">Prisoner 1</spkr>Let’s go, let’s go!</sp>
            <sp><spkr ref="Prisoner2">Prisoner 2</spkr>I think we’re gonna make it!</sp>
            <sp><spkr ref="Prisoner1">Prisoner 1</spkr>Yeah!</sp>
            <sd><stageDesc>Their perspective: they approach the smashed gate in the outer wall-which
                    is promptly closed when the pieces fly back into the frame</stageDesc>. Back to
                the prisoners, who stop in their tracks.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Prisoner1 Prisoner2">Prisoners 1, 2</spkr>Huh?</sp>
            <sd>
                <directNote>Snap to black, which resolves into a swirling vortex in front of the
                    gate. It recedes to nothing as<char ref="Raven">Raven</char> floats in through the
                    barrier-repaired by her telekinesis.</directNote>
            </sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Raven">Raven</spkr>Think again.</sp>
            <sd><directNote kind="wipe">Wipe to the corridor</directNote>, near the holes
                    <char ref="Cinderblock">Cinderblock</char> smashed through the walls.<char ref="Guards">Guards</char> keep watch
                as the prisoners return to their cells, their arms shackled behind their
                    backs.<directNote kind="pan">Pan from here to the Titans ;
                        <char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> is now a<transform class="mammal">gorilla</transform>,
                    but he quickly assumes human form.</directNote></sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>Jailbreak? I don’t see any jailbreak.</sp>
            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>None of us would have seen one if<char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char> 
                hadn’t messed up!</sp>
            <sd>He looks away.</sd>
            <sd>
                <stageDesc category="gag">Sight gag: each speaker’s head grows a size when he
                    speaks, then shrinks back to normal.</stageDesc>
            </sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>Me? I messed up nothing!</sp>
            <sd>with great force;<char ref="Robin">Robin</char> ’s cape blows back</sd>
            <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>You got in my way!</sp>
            <sd>He looks away as well.</sd>
            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr><sd>turning back</sd>You were too far forward, and
                    <char ref="Cinderblock">Cinderblock</char> got away because of it!</sp>
            <sd><charDesc ref="Robin">An angry little spark pops up on his temple during the end of
                    this and then winks out when his head deflates</charDesc>.<stageDesc>Now the
                    background goes red and the sight gag becomes more exaggerated, with the
                    non-speaker shrinking a bit as he gets yelled at as well.</stageDesc></sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr><sd>turning back</sd>You saying this is my
                fault?</sp>
            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>Want me to say it again?</sp>
            <sd>
                <stageDesc>The sight gag ends. Sparks fly between both pairs of eyes before
                        <char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char> pops up between them.</stageDesc>
            </sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr>Stop! No more mean talking!</sp>
            <sd>They turn their backs on her and each other, and<stageDesc>the normal background
                    restores itself as<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> speaks up.</stageDesc></sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>Yeah. If you two are gonna fight, we need time
                to sell tickets.</sp>
            <sd>He backs off;<char ref="Raven">Raven</char> steps up.</sd>
            <sp><spkr ref="Raven">Raven</spkr><char ref="Cinderblock">Cinderblock</char> escaped. No amount of yelling
                will change that. So stop acting like idiots, and let’s go home.</sp>
            <sd><char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char> and<char ref="Robin">Robin</char> throw each other a disdainful glance from
                over their shoulders.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Robin Cyborg">Robin, Cyborg</spkr>Hmph!</sp>
            <sd>Their respective exhalations are visible in the air. Now they stride away, leaving
                the other Titans nonplussed.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr><sd>softly</sd>Loser.</sp>
            <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr><sd>softly</sd>Jerk.</sp>
            <sd>
                <stageDesc category="letterbox">Letterbox view: they whirl to face one
                    another.</stageDesc>
            </sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Robin Cyborg">Robin, Cyborg</spkr>What did you say?!?</sp>
            <sd>
                <stageDesc category="fullscreen">Fullscreen: they go face to face. The background
                    turns red again</stageDesc>
            </sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>Do you have a problem, Tin Man?</sp>
            <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>Yeah! It’s four feet tall and smells like cheap
                hair gel!</sp>
            <sd>This hits him the wrong way.<directNote kind="cut">Cut to the others against the
                    wall</directNote>.<stageDesc category="gag">Sight gag: they have become scared
                    infants, with the pair’s shadows thrown across them as rough
                    caricatures.</stageDesc></sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr><sd>from o.c.</sd>Well, you’re an oversized klutz and
                your feet smell like motor oil!</sp>
            <sd><char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> starts to cry.</sd>
            <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr><sd>from o.c.</sd>You’re bossy, you’re rude, you
                got no taste in music!</sp>
            <sd>
                <directNote kind="shift">The sight gag ends as the camera shifts to frame all five
                    again.</directNote>
            </sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>I don’t even know why you’re on this team!</sp>
            <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>That makes two of us! I QUIT!!</sp>
            <sd>These two words leave the rest of the group staring wide-eyed in total shock.
                    <stageDesc category="letterbox">Letterbox, in the top third of the screen: his
                    silhouette stalks away from theirs against a blue field, and<char ref="Robin">Robin</char> 
                    hangs his head</stageDesc>.<directNote kind="fade">Fade to black as the sound of
                    machinery makes itself heard.</directNote></sd>

            <sd><directNote kind="fade">Fade in to a close-up of turning gears</directNote>and
                    <directNote kind="dissolve">dissolve to a series of other shots of heavy
                    equipment hard at work-cams and pistons and crankshafts</directNote>.
                    <directNote kind="pan">Pan from the last view across a large enclosure
                    illuminated chiefly by dim red light, then stop on a shadowy figure seated on a
                    large chair atop a raised platform</directNote>.<charDesc ref="Slade">No
                    features can be seen except the glint of full-body armor and one eye, the left.
                    An overhead fixture pours light down on the seat.</charDesc>This is
                    <char ref="Slade">Slade</char> , though he will not be named for some time to come. In the
                harsh glare,<charDesc ref="Slade">the right side of the head and shoulder show a
                    gray tint, while red-orange appears on the other side.</charDesc></sd>

            <sd><char ref="Cinderblock">Cinderblock</char> stumps into the light and places the tank containing
                <char ref="P385901">385901</char> on the floor. When<char ref="Slade">Slade</char> speaks, his tone is even
                and measured.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Slade">Slade</spkr><char ref="Cinderblock">Cinderblock</char> . I see your mission was a
                success. Good. We will proceed with Phase Two. Wake him.</sp>
            <sd>The behemoth strains at the metal cap on the top end of the tank and manages to
                unscrew it, releasing thick clouds of vapor. When they clear, the occupant begins to
                stir from his slumber.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="P385901">385901</spkr><sd>through glass, startled</sd>I’m...awake? I
                should never be awake! I’m only human when I’m sleeping!</sp>
            <sp><spkr ref="Slade">Slade</spkr>But for what I have in mind, your human form is
                    useless.<sd>leaning forward</sd>I need<char ref="Plasmus">Plasmus</char> .</sp>
            <sd><transform class="Plasmus">The man’s form begins to swell and distort within the
                    tank</transform>, causing the glass to bulge and finally shatter. What comes out
                    is<charDesc ref="Plasmus">a mass of purplish slime</charDesc>that overwhelms the
                    nearby<char ref="Cinderblock">Cinderblock</char> , accompanied by more fumes from the liquid
                inside. When the view clears, the overhead light has gone out and<charDesc ref="Plasmus">the ooze has formed itself into a very large, roughly shaped
                    humanoid with an extremely wide mouth and two tiny yellowish
                    eyes</charDesc>-<char ref="Plasmus">Plasmus</char> , the form taken
                by<char ref="P385901">385901</char> whenever he is not asleep.<annot>The reason for the silence
                    warning on his cell’s door is now abundantly clear.</annot>
                <char ref="Plasmus">Plasmus</char> comes forward and lets off a screeching roar.<directNote kind="fade">Fade to black.</directNote></sd>
        </act>
        <act n="2">
            <title>Act 2</title>
            <sd><stageDesc category="open-shot">Opening shot: the exterior of Titans 
                    Tower.</stageDesc>It is now the next day. Ringing is heard over a telephone
                line, followed by the click of the call being answered.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr><sd>on answering machine</sd>This is
                    <char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char> . I’m either in the gym, playing GameStation-<sd>Zoom in
                    slowly.</sd>-or kicking bad-guy butt. Leave a message.</sp>
            <sd>Beep.</sd>
            <sd><directNote kind="cut">Cut to the operations center.</directNote>
                <char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char> is at the kitchen counter,<char ref="Raven">Raven</char> is looking at a
                bank of monitors, and<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> paces with a cell phone in hand-he made
                the call.<char ref="Robin">Robin</char> stands at the windows.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>Hello? Cy? Pick up!<sd>Pause.</sd>Come on, Cy,
                pick up!<sd><stageDesc category="close-up">Close-up of<char ref="Raven">Raven</char> ; he paces
                        behind her.</stageDesc></sd>I know you’re there. The phone’s built in your
                arm!</sp>
            <sd>
                <stageDesc>In this shot, we can now see that<char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char> is mixing something
                    in a bowl.<char ref="Raven">Raven</char> reaches up to press a key. Now <char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char>hangs up disgustedly.<directNote kind="cut">Cut to an extreme
                        close-up of<char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char> , who holds up a spoonful of glop from her
                        bowl.</directNote></stageDesc>
            </sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr>Taste.</sp>
            <sd><directNote kind="pull">Pull back; she is holding it out to<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> ,
                    and she shoves it into his mouth without warning.</directNote>It sends him into
                convulsions, which end with him on all fours and trying to keep from vomiting.
                Finally he spits out the mess and scrubs frantically at his tongue to remove the
                last fragments.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>What is that? Cream of toenails?</sp>
            <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr>Pudding of Sadness.<sd>taking a spoonful</sd>
                It is what the people of my planet eat when bad things happen.</sp>
            <sd>She eats it and is suddenly on the verge of blowing her own chow; after a monster
                effort, she gets it down and ends up having a fit as well.<char ref="Raven">Raven</char> 
                continues checking the monitors as<char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char> brings her the bowl.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr>Try. The displeasing taste will ease your
                troubled mind.</sp>
            <sd><char ref="Raven">Raven</char> turns to her.</sd>
            <sp><spkr ref="Raven">Raven</spkr>My mind is never troubled. People come, people go.
                It’s pointless to be upset about<char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char> .</sp>
            <sd>Her hair flies wildly about her face and all the monitors crack-a sudden flare-up of
                her powers, caused by the fact that she actually is upset about his absence. She
                does not notice the damage, as she is looking directly at<char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char> ’s
                wide-eyed expression.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Raven">Raven</spkr>What?</sp>
            <sd>
                <stageDesc category="letterbox">Letterbox, top half of the screen.
                        <char ref="Robin">Robin</char> ’s silhouette, against the sunlight through the top-floor
                    windows, looks morosely out over Jump City as<char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char> ’s flies to
                    him with her horrid concoction.</stageDesc>
                <stageDesc category="fullscreen">Fullscreen: she holds the bowl out to
                    him.</stageDesc>
            </sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr>Here,<char ref="Robin">Robin</char> . You must need this
                most of all since...well...</sp>
            <sd>She lets it hang.</sd>
            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>I’m fine.</sp>
            <sd>He turns away.<stageDesc category="letterbox">Letterbox, top two-thirds of screen;
                    his silhouette retreats from hers.</stageDesc></sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>Who knows? Maybe we’re better off without him.</sp>
            <sd><stageDesc category="fullscreen">Fullscreen: she lowers her bowl and gazes after him
                    with obvious concern.</stageDesc>
                <directNote kind="wipe">Wipe to a close-up of him in the gym; he is punching
                    something just o.c. with great vigor.</directNote>
                <directNote kind="pull">Pull back to reveal the target as a heavy bag.</directNote>
                He delivers a final roundhouse kick and slumps over, winded. Looking up, he sees his
                    and<char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char> ’s weight benches-the latter equipped with the sort of
                giant barbells only that Titan could lift.</sd>

            <sd><stageDesc category="setting">In the kitchen</stageDesc>,<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> 
                hoists a stack of dirty plates onto the counter by the sink. Many others are already
                piled up there.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>Yo! Whose turn to do dishes?</sp>
            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr><sd>from o.c.</sd>
                <char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char> .</sp>
            <sd>The green Titan cries out briefly in surprise like a monkey at this.
                    <char ref="Robin">Robin</char> goes to the sink and starts to wash a plate.<directNote kind="dissolve">Dissolve to him on the couch in the operations center; he is now
                    playing on the GameStation system and blasting enemy aircraft out of the sky.
                    The screen is projected onto the windows.</directNote></sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>Come on, come on...I’m not scared to take...no! Yeah!
                Got it! Just one more and...yes!</sp>
            <sd>
                <stageDesc category="close-up">Close-up of the screen, which flashes red and blue
                    and shows the message "Cyborg-1,000,000."</stageDesc>
            </sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr><sd>from o.c.</sd>New high score!</sp>
            <sd><char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char> ’s name is smashed away by<char ref="Robin">Robin</char> ’s, and the score
                changes to 5,000,000. However, the Titan who set it is no longer elated
                by his achievement.<directNote kind="cut">Cut to the hall; he approaches the door
                        of<char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char> ’s room.</directNote>It opens to show the interior, and
                    <directNote kind="pan">the camera starts to swivel slowly around</directNote>.
                    <stageDesc category="setting">Bookcase with pictures and a baseball on top,
                    computer desk with a football by the monitor, trophy case in one rear corner,
                    and areas for self-repair and diagnostics. A large inclined table with a
                    footstop at its lower end is in the other rear corner-what the missing
                         Titan uses for a bed.</stageDesc></sd>

            <sd>
                <directNote kind="pan">The camera comes full circle to<char ref="Robin">Robin</char> , who has
                    taken a picture from the dresser and is looking at it.</directNote>
                <stageDesc category="close-up">Close-up: it is of the pair, laughing and having a
                    grand time.</stageDesc>
                <directNote kind="pull">Pull back into the room.</directNote>
            </sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr><sd>softly</sd>I’m sorry.</sp>
            <sd>An alarm shatters the silence.<directNote kind="cut">Cut to<char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char> ,
                        <char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> , and<char ref="Raven">Raven</char> in the operations center,
                    looking ahead at something o.c. with surprise.</directNote>
                <directNote kind="cut">Cut to it: a map of Jump City projected on the window/screen,
                    with a large flashing dot that slowly moves along.</directNote>
                <char ref="Robin">Robin</char> runs in.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr><char ref="Cinderblock">Cinderblock</char> strikes again?</sp>
            <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>You wish.</sp>
            <sd><directNote kind="dissolve">Dissolve to a long shot of a chemical factory; it is now
                    nighttime.</directNote>
                <stageDesc category="setting">Inside, jets of colored solutions shoot down from
                    overhead nozzles and flow together in a pipeline that snakes across the factory
                    floor. The mixture emerges from its other end and falls into a waiting
                    barrel</stageDesc>;<directNote kind="pan">pan from here to<char ref="Plasmus">Plasmus</char> 
                    at the free end of the conveyor on which it and others are resting.</directNote>
                As the belt starts to move, he picks up each arriving barrel and guzzles it, growing
                a few feet taller after each of the first two. The third is hit with a starbolt
                before he can finish it; the remaining chemicals spill out the broken end, and he
                lifts the barrel to his eye to peer through it.</sd>

            <sd>His perspective, swiveling across the area. The four Titans are waiting
                for him.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>That stuff can’t be good for you.</sp>
            <sd>Back to<char ref="Plasmus">Plasmus</char> , who throws the barrel aside and belches.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>Nice one!</sp>
            <sd>He roars and shoots gobbets of sludge from his body toward the heroes, who scatter
                to avoid being hit.<char ref="Robin">Robin</char> jumps and flips like mad, just barely staying
                ahead of the barrage, and lands on a crate near a mixing tank.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>Star! Let him have it!</sp>
            <sd>She obliges with a starbolt that blows a hole clear through the creature’s
                chest.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr><sd>gasping</sd>Did I let him have too
                much?</sp>
            <sd>He sucks in a huge breath; the hole fills in.</sd>
            <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>I’m thinking not enough.</sp>
            <sd>Its hand balled into a fist, one gooey arm extends itself toward
                    <char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char> , who shrieks as<char ref="Raven">Raven</char> plows her out of the
                way.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr><sd>pulling a disc from his belt</sd><oneLine>Maybe he just
                needs to chill.</oneLine></sp>
            <sd>He scales the projectile at<char ref="Plasmus">Plasmus</char> ; it freezes the long arm solid upon
                impact. The owner of said arm looks at it in surprise, then shatters it against an
                overhead pipe.<char ref="Robin">Robin</char> jumps for cover, while<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> turns into a
                    <transform class="bird">pterodactyl</transform>and lifts off.
                    <char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char> blazes away from above, driving<char ref="Plasmus">Plasmus</char> back a
                bit, and<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> executes several punching strikes with his talons. The
                foe blocks these and retaliates by lashing out with many thick tentacles from the
                stump of his missing arm.</sd>

            <annot>Animation goof: He is seen to have two arms while backing up from her
                barrage.</annot>

            <sd>Both Titans cut and run to stay out of the mess.<char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char> 
                throws shots every which way to fend off the attack as<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> does a
                few evasive maneuvers. Now<char ref="Raven">Raven</char> rises into the air.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Raven">Raven</spkr>Azarath Metrion Zinthos!</sp>
            <sd>She levitates several barrels and launches them at<char ref="Plasmus">Plasmus</char> ; they strike
                him in the chest, end first, and stick there. His arm now regrown,he gathers his
                strength and sends them right back, forcing her to dive for cover.
                    <char ref="Robin">Robin</char> leaps in for a flying kick only to get that leg stuck in the
                mire, followed by his other leg and one hand when he tries more blows. He struggles
                to get loose.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>Come on! Let me go, you giant zit!</sp>
            <sd>It only snarls and roars down at him before sending forth a huge jet of slime that
                carries him screaming along with it. The purple tide washes over<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char>-<transform class="human">back to human form</transform>-as well.
                Dripping with it,<char ref="Robin">Robin</char> groans and gets up as<char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char>  rushes
                over.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr><char ref="Robin">Robin</char> !</sp>
            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>I’m okay… sort of.</sp>
            <sd>He spits out a wad or two.<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> , meanwhile, has made it partway to
                his feet; his eyes are watering profusely.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>And I thought Star’s pudding tasted bad!</sp>
            <sd>A fresh howl from<char ref="Plasmus">Plasmus</char> ’ direction refocuses the attention of all
                    four Titans in a hurry.<directNote kind="cut">Cut to a fuzzy image of
                    him that flickers as the camera pulls back a bit to show this as a giant
                    monitor, with two silhouettes standing before it.</directNote>
                <charDesc ref="Slade">One of them-large, muscular, armored</charDesc>-is
                    <char ref="Slade">Slade</char> ; the other is a shorter
                    individual</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Slade">Slade</spkr>Disappointing.</sp>
            <sd>
                <stageDesc category="close-up">Close-up of<char ref="Slade">Slade</char> and the shorter person-an elderly fellow, bald on top, in a white
                        suit and tie and a black shirt.</stageDesc>
            </sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Slade">Slade</spkr>With one Titan missing, this is almost too
                        easy.<sd><stageDesc category="close-up">Extreme close-up of his
                        eye.</stageDesc>I was expecting more of a challenge.
                        <char ref="Cinderblock">Cinderblock</char> .</sd></sp>
            <sd><directNote kind="pull">Pull back. An overhead light shines down on him, enveloping
                    the old man and part of<char ref="Cinderblock">Cinderblock</char> .</directNote>The latter can be
                seen holding some large piece of equipment.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Slade">Slade</spkr>Begin Phase Three.</sp>
            <sd>An answering grunt, and<char ref="Cinderblock">Cinderblock</char> stumps away.<directNote kind="fade">Fade to black.</directNote></sd>
        </act>
        <act n="3">
            <title>Act 3</title>
            <sd><stageDesc category="open-shot">Opening shot: an open area of the factory
                    floor.</stageDesc>A gush of<char ref="Plasmus">Plasmus</char> ’ muck splatters down from above,
                    and<char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char> stands up within it and groans disgustedly.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr>I feel like the underside of a Zornian muck
                beetle.</sp>
            <sd><char ref="Raven">Raven</char> gets up next to her.</sd>
            <sp><spkr ref="Raven">Raven</spkr>Tell me about it.</sp>
            <sd><char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> runs for his life as<char ref="Plasmus">Plasmus</char> pursues.</sd>
            <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>Dude, I am not on the menu!</sp>
            <sd><char ref="Robin">Robin</char> ’s birdarang sails into view trailing a long line behind it. This
                grappling hook flies around<char ref="Plasmus">Plasmus</char> ’ legs to wrap them up;
                    <char ref="Robin">Robin</char> is quick to arrive as well. He grabs the free end of the line
                and takes a few more turns around the giant.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>Maybe the best way to take you down…<sd>pulling
                    mightily</sd>…is to tie you up!</sp>
            <sd><char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> , now a<transform class="mammal">rhinoceros</transform>,
                charges and scores a direct hit that sends<char ref="Plasmus">Plasmus</char> toppling backward to
                fall among a group of support columns.<char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char> bends one over to pin him, and
                    <char ref="Raven">Raven</char> does likewise with others. He struggles against these bonds as
                the four inspect the handiwork;<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> is back in<transform class="human">human form.</transform></sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr>We did it!</sp>
            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>Nice work, team.</sp>
            <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>Yeah. Didn’t think we’d pull it off
                without-</sp>
            <sd><char ref="Raven">Raven</char> angrily socks him in the shoulder to cut him off. He lets off a
                surprised little sheep-like bleat, then laughs and sweats nervously.
                    <char ref="Robin">Robin</char> checks a locator device briefly before tucking it away in his
                belt.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>We finished just in time.<char ref="Cinderblock">Cinderblock</char> ’s
                been spotted downtown. Come on!</sp>
            <sd>The four Titans turn to leave, but a loud gurgling noise from
                    <char ref="Plasmus">Plasmus</char> ’ direction stops<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> . He turns back.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>Huh?</sp>
            <sd><directNote kind="cut">Cut to an overhead view of the trapped creature, panning
                    slowly along his length, as he starts to ooze a bit under those
                    girders.</directNote>Back to a head-on view;<charDesc ref="Plasmus">his entire
                    body flows together and free of the restraints, then shapes itself into a
                    gigantic crab-like thing with one claw, an octopus-like appendage, and a snaky
                    rear limb.</charDesc></sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>Uh… heads up.</sp>
            <sd>Now having formed a second crab claw,<char ref="Plasmus">Plasmus</char> rushes at the foursome;
                they burst out through a set of double doors.<directNote kind="cut">Cut to just
                    outside as they make it through and slam the doors shut just in time, leaning
                    against them with all their weight.</directNote>
                <char ref="Plasmus">Plasmus</char> ’ snarling and pounding can be heard through the metal.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>Four against five. Not good odds.</sp>
            <annot>He is referring to the claws/beetles, octopus, snake, and body together-five
                battering rams to employ against the doors.</annot>

            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>Forget the odds. We need a plan.</sp>
            <sd>The doors tremble even more violently under<char ref="Plasmus">Plasmus</char> ’ assault, and he
                finally forces them partway open and pushes a tendril out, then another.
                    <char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char> screams as the opening grows wider and the head
                appears.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr> Titans ! Separate!</sp>
            <sd>The doors are finally smashed open.<char ref="Robin">Robin</char> ,<char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char> , and
                    <char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> go in three different directions among the machinery; the
                latter turns into a<transform class="mammal">cheetah</transform>as he runs.
                    <char ref="Plasmus">Plasmus</char> ’ snake, separated from the rest of the body, chases
                    <char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char> ; she turns in midair and bombards it with starbolts, but
                it lunges and catches her to drag her from the air.<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> sprints
                along the floor, with one of the crab claws in hot pursuit. It opens wide and lashes
                out a long tongue that snares him. He breaks loose by turning into a<transform class="mammal">gorilla</transform>, but is knocked off his feet by a flying
                tackle.</sd>

            <sd><char ref="Raven">Raven</char> , meanwhile, flies along as the octopus chases on the ground. She
                exerts her powers over all the machinery here, causing the bolts and screws to fall
                out, and the loosened vessels topple into the aisle one after another. The octopus
                swerves and slides to miss several of them, but is finally hit broadside. She looks
                back smugly only to find that it has recovered and placed itself directly in front
                of her; there is only time for one shocked gasp before it rears up to strike.</sd>

            <sd>The only one left is<char ref="Robin">Robin</char> , who keeps going full steam among the other
                process equipment; the other crab claw is after him and not letting up. He reaches a
                set of double doors, and<directNote kind="snap">the screen snaps to black-the
                    darkened area on the other side, which is illuminated as he hurls himself
                    through and into space</directNote>. Lurid green light rises from the direction
                of the floor. Something breaks his fall, and he finds himself carried along in
                midair as he rubs his head;<directNote kind="pull">pull back to show him standing on
                    a moving conveyor belt above several large vats of glowing
                    chemicals.</directNote></sd>

            <sd>The crab claw lands behind him and pulls back to strike.<char ref="Robin">Robin</char> has his
                staff out in a snap and delivers several blows that merely splatter through the
                purple goo. The end is caught and broken off, but he simply extends the other end to
                make up for the lost length and swings again. This time, his weapon is not only
                blocked but dashed from his hands to go spiraling over the vats. Going into classic
                kung fu mode, he backs up a few steps and lunges for a high kick.</sd>

            <sd><directNote kind="cut">Cut to<char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char> , still held fast by
                        <char ref="Plasmus">Plasmus</char> ’ snake portion.</directNote>As she struggles, it wraps
                a coil around her head and squeezes itself together into a large ball. She bursts
                out of it after a moment and sees the main body perched on top of an equipment
                cabinet, lying in wait.<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> -<transform class="human">back in human
                    form</transform>-and<char ref="Raven">Raven</char> are carried into view, still held by their
                respective captor body parts, and the snake reforms at the feet of one very
                frightened Tamaranean teenager. She recoils at its strike.</sd>

            <sd>Back to the conveyor.<char ref="Robin">Robin</char> steadily backs up before the opponent’s
                advance, and it soon throws itself on top of him to pin him to the belt’s surface.
                    The Boy Wonder struggles mightily as both are swept toward the free
                end, which hangs over a bubbling vat. He goes partway over, then smiles wickedly and
                flips the claw backward off the precipice; however; he miscalculates and has to grab
                the corner of the belt to keep from going down with it.<stageDesc category="close-up">Close-up of this: the housing starts to pull loose, and a
                    camera shift reveals why-the claw has seized one boot and is pulling with all
                    its strength.</stageDesc>
                <char ref="Robin">Robin</char> strains with all the power he can put into his one-handed grip,
                but the conveyor has had all it can take.<annot>His fingers slide away from the
                    ripping material to leave him plummeting toward the last bath he will ever
                    take.</annot></sd>

            <sd>Out of nowhere,<charDesc ref="Cyborg">a familiar bionic arm</charDesc>shoots into
                view and grabs his wrist.<directNote>The camera turns down from him to the surface
                    of the vat, where the sludgy apparition is dissolving harmlessly after having
                    fallen in.</directNote>On the conveyor,<char ref="Robin">Robin</char> has been hoisted up
                    by<char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char> , who stands behind him, and tries desperately to catch his
                breath.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr><sd>smiling</sd>I still got the Sonic if you still
                got the Boom.</sp>
            <sd><char ref="Robin">Robin</char> returns the smile-the feud between the two has ended in a
                twinkling. On the factory floor,<char ref="Plasmus">Plasmus</char> ’ other four body parts have
                reassembled themselves and the other three are nowhere to be seen. He laughs
                nastily, but stops short when<char ref="Robin">Robin</char> and<char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char> square off
                against him.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Robin Cyborg">Robin, Cyborg</spkr>Teen Titans ! Go!</sp>
            <sd>They go into the same sequence of moves they used while trying to pull off the Sonic
                Boom attack against<char ref="Cinderblock">Cinderblock</char> inside the prison. This time, however,
                they do not get tangled up in midair, and<char ref="Robin">Robin</char> hurls an explosive disc
                    while<char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char> fires his cannon. The combined effect of the two weapons
                is enough to blow<char ref="Plasmus">Plasmus</char> apart into small puddles of gunk;
                <stageDesc>when the screen clears, we see<char ref="P385901">385901</char> dozing among the
                    slop and snoring fitfully.</stageDesc></sd>

            <sd><directNote kind="cut">Cut to<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> and<char ref="Raven">Raven</char> , who sit up
                    out of the remains of their captors</directNote>, and<directNote kind="pan">pan
                        to<char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char> , who has already done likewise-they had been
                    engulfed by the slime</directNote>.<char ref="Robin">Robin</char> and<char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char>  look
                down at<charDesc ref="P385901">the frail man</charDesc>who has just inflicted so much
                damage on the factory.<directNote kind="dissolve">Dissolve to them outside, watching
                    as he is loaded onto a truck for the return trip to prison; he is contained in a
                    new tank.</directNote></sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>Look, uh… sorry about…</sp>
            <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>Yeah.</sp>
            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>So… are we cool?</sp>
            <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr><sd>smiling, holding out a fist</sd>Frosty.</sp>
            <sd><char ref="Robin">Robin</char> smiles back as they tap fists.<directNote kind="pan">Pan to the
                    other three Titans in the background.</directNote></sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr>You made up! Glorious! I wish to initiate a
                group hug.</sp>
            <sp><spkr ref="Raven">Raven</spkr>Pass.</sp>
            <sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr>Yeah, yeah, yeah, warm fuzzies all around. But
                we still gotta stop<char ref="Cinderblock">Cinderblock</char> .</sp>
            <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr><sd>from o.c.</sd>No, we don’t.<sd>Back to him
                        and<char ref="Robin">Robin</char> .</sd>Thought I’d bring a present, ‘case you were still
                mad.</sp>
            <sd>He gestures behind himself, and in response<char ref="Cinderblock">Cinderblock</char> is hoisted up on
                a winch-with the equipment he had been carrying in<char ref="Slade">Slade</char> ’s lair wrapped
                around his body to bind him.<charDesc ref="Cinderblock">The stone
                villain</charDesc>grumbles angrily.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>Thanks. But there is one thing that’s still bothering
                me.</sp>
            <sd><char ref="Raven">Raven</char> ,<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> , and<char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char> first react with
                surprise, then go wide-eyed in disbelief that anything could be bothering their
                leader at this point, given the events of the past few hours.<directNote kind="zoom">Zoom in slowly on him.</directNote></sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>Breaking into jail? Using<char ref="Plasmus">Plasmus</char> to
                distract us? The whole plan seems to be a little too smart for
                    <char ref="Cinderblock">Cinderblock</char> .</sp>
            <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>I’ve been thinking the same thing.</sp>
            <sd>The other three are relieved;<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> and<char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char> sigh
                visibly.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>Someone must have been pulling the strings. But
                who?</sp>
            <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>Well, whoever they are-</sp>
            <sd>
                <stageDesc category="letterbox">Letterbox, top half of screen: the
                         Titans are silhouetted against the evening sky, with a full moon
                    behind them.</stageDesc>
            </sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr>-they’re no match for the Teen
                 Titans .</sp>
            <sd>He and<char ref="Robin">Robin</char> trade a high five.</sd>
            <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr>I heard that!</sp>
            <sd><stageDesc category="fullscreen">Fullscreen:<directNote kind="dissolve">dissolve to
                        a close-up of a teacup and saucer on a table or ledge</directNote>. A fist
                    is slammed down, breaking them, after which a pair of
                        white-gloved hands reaches down with a small broom and dustpan to sweep up
                        the pieces.</stageDesc>
                <directNote kind="pull">Pull back; it is the elderly man previously seen with
                        <char ref="Slade">Slade</char> -a butler.</directNote>He has a fresh cup, which he sets
                on the arm of his employer’s chair.<char ref="Slade">Slade</char> is once again seated and lit as
                before. Despite having just lashed out, his voice retains its control.</sd>

            <sp><spkr ref="Slade">Slade</spkr>Next time my plans will succeed.<sd><stageDesc category="close-up">Extreme close-up of his eye; zoom in as it
                        narrows.</stageDesc></sd>And the Titans will pay.</sp>
            <sd>
                <directNote kind="fade">Fade to black.</directNote>
            </sd>

            <cue>End</cue>
        </act>
    </body>
</root>