<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="comments_schema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?><media source="nbc" category="science"><title>Genome Reveals How Cats Evolved to Tolerate Humans</title><mainContent><link>http://www.nbcnews.com/science/weird-science/genome-reveals-how-cats-evolved-tolerate-humans-n245671</link><author>Tia Ghose</author><description>Thousands of years ago, a wildcat first started lingering on the outskirts of a human camp, perhaps to eat the mice living in people's granaries. Now, billions of house pets and countless cat videos later, researchers have revealed the genetic roots of the special relationship between humans and cats.
            
            A new study traces the genetic changes that make kitties snuggle up with humans and purr for treats. Many of the changes have altered the cat's motivation to seek rewards and have lessened their fear of new situations, said study co-author Wesley Warren, a geneticist at the Genome Institute at the Washington University School of Medicine in St. Louis.
            
            Cats and humans go way back: Some studies suggest cats were first domesticated about 9,000 years ago in the Near East, while others trace cat domestication back to China around 5,000 years ago. To unravel the mysteries of cat domestication, scientists sequenced the genome of an Abyssinian cat named Cinnamon in 2007. But that analysis wasn't complete. Warren and his colleagues did a second sequence of Cinnamon's genome, along with the genomes of several other domestic cats and two species of wildcat, and compared them with the genomes for the tiger, the dog and many other animals. [ Animal Code: Our Favorite Genomes ]
            
            In domestic cats, genes linked to motivation and fear faced strong evolutionary pressure over history, leading the cats to be less shy and more driven by rewards, Warren said.
            
            Dogs have many more copies of genes for smell receptors than cats do, which probably accounts for the canines' superior sense of smell. On the other hand, the genes for feline night vision and keen hearing were under strong selection — which may explain why felines are such expert hunters, Warren said.
            
            The findings help underpin some of the biological changes associated with domestication in cats.
            
            "The study is great, especially in defining changes in the genome that have led to domestication or, more correctly, to the adaptation of the ancestors of domestic cats that allowed them to associate with humans and thus gain both protection from their predators and an ample food supply (rodents)," Niels Pedersen, a veterinary researcher at the University of California at Davisy, said in an email.
            
            The findings were published Monday in the Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences. </description><statistics><subscribers>0</subscribers><views>0</views><likes>0</likes><dislikes>0</dislikes><totalComments>17</totalComments><publishDate>11/10/2014</publishDate></statistics></mainContent><commentSection><comment type="joke" tone="neutral" relevance="subject" thumbsUp="9"><commenter>Jonathan Reid-1158169</commenter><sentence structure="good">Meanwhile at the Cat Institute, leading feline scientists have announced that Phase Three of world domination is proceeding as planned with Phase Four (elimination of all vacuum cleaners) running into early issues.</sentence></comment><comment type="jok response" tone="neutral" relevance="commenter" thumbsUp="1"><commenter>Brisaber</commenter><sentence structure="good">I, for one, welcome our new cat overlords.</sentence></comment><comment type="joke response" tone="neutral" relevance="commenter"><commenter>Barry-NJ</commenter><sentence structure="good">Cats (and dogs) have always been our overlords.</sentence></comment><comment type="joke" tone="neutral" relevance="subject" thumbsUp="0"><commenter>helicohunter</commenter><sentence structure="good">"Tolerate".</sentence><sentence structure="good">A very appropriate word.</sentence><sentence structure="good">Cats still have some evolving left to do.</sentence></comment><comment type="serious" tone="argumentative" relevance="commenter subject" thumbsUp="2"><commenter>Mike in B-more</commenter><sentence structure="good">"Cats still have some evolving left to do."</sentence><sentence structure="good">As do dogs, humans, monkeys, 'pet' birds, cattle, sheep, pigs, etc.</sentence><sentence structure="good">I grew up on a farm - the farm was not complete <caps>UNLESS</caps> there were at least one dog and multiple cats - the dog to make sure the other (domesticated) animals 'behaved' themselves, the cats to hunt and kill rats and mice for supplemental food for themselves.</sentence><sentence structure="good">And I'll not even comment on how humans need to evolve, especially <caps>CON</caps>servatives.</sentence></comment><comment type="serious" tone="argumentative" relevance="commenter subject" thumbsUp="2"><commenter>helicohunter</commenter><sentence structure="good">As if evolution is a deterministic process with goals.</sentence><sentence structure="good">Evolution is something that will happen when pressure is applied to populations of a species otherwise that population will inevitably die off.</sentence><sentence structure="good">Cats are less social toward their human hosts than dogs because dogs are simply more domesticated than cats.</sentence><sentence structure="good">Which brings me to the point that the evolution of cats, and to a greater degree, dogs has been guided by humans through selective breeding rather than natural selection.</sentence></comment><comment type="joke" tone="neutral" relevance="commenter subject" thumbsUp="4"><commenter>inmissouri</commenter><sentence structure="good">Why?</sentence><sentence structure="good">They've evolved to the point where they can train their humans very well.</sentence></comment><comment type="joke" tone="argumentative" relevance="commenter" thumbsUp="2"><commenter>Rex-1306908</commenter><sentence structure="good">We're doing quite well Mike, beating the hell out of you Democ<caps>RATS</caps> last week.</sentence><sentence structure="good">Or is that Demo<caps>CRAPS</caps>?</sentence></comment><comment type="joke" tone="neutral" relevance="subject" thumbsUp="4"><commenter>Jim-1301592</commenter><sentence structure="poor">meow meow meow meow, meow you!</sentence></comment><comment type="normal" tone="neutral" relevance="subject article"><commenter/><sentence structure="good">The article made note of genes for fear.</sentence><sentence structure="good">Never really perceived cats that way, even though when I grew up  the phrase "scaredy cat" was frequently heard - sometimes as an epithet and sometimes as a dare.</sentence></comment></commentSection></media>