<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<script>
<title>Close Rick-counters of the Rick Kind</title>
    <airdate date="4/7/2014"/>
    <cultureRef year="1977" genre="movie">Close Encounters of the Third Kind</cultureRef>
<scene no="1">
[The Smith family is seen sitting around the table eating breakfast. The viewer at this point doesn't know that this scene is set in a dimension that is not Dimension C-137 with a different Smith family, but this will be apparent at the end of the scene.]

<convo>
            <speech designation="dim" character="notBeth">
                <persName level="dimension">Dead Beth</persName>
                <persName level="main">Beth</persName>Beth: So dad, guess what tomorrow is...</speech>

<speech designation="dim" character="notRick">
                <persName level="dimension">Dead Rick</persName>Rick: Martin Luther King Jr.'s birthday.</speech>

    <speech designation="dim" character="notBeth">
                <persName level="dimension">Dead Beth</persName>
                <persName level="main">Beth</persName>Beth: No... well, it might be...</speech>

    <speech designation="dim" character="notRick">
                <persName level="dimension">Dead Rick</persName>Rick: It is.</speech>

    <speech designation="dim" character="notBeth">
                <persName level="dimension">Dead Beth</persName>
                <persName level="main">Beth</persName>Beth: Fine, but also, tomorrow is your one year anniversary back in our lives. I'm gonna make you flying saucer-shaped pancakes.</speech>

    <speech designation="dim" character="notRick">
                <persName level="dimension">Dead Rick</persName>Rick: Oh, there's no need to do that, Beth. Regular pancakes are fine.</speech>
        </convo>

(A portal appears on their wall and <persName level="dimension">Evil Rick</persName> and <persName level="dimension">Evil Morty</persName> emerge from it carrying a gun and a tranquilizer respectively. Evil Rick shoots Rick in the head and kills him. Evil Morty shoots Morty in the shoulder with his tranquilizer and he passes out. Evil Morty then drags Morty across the breakfast table and he and Evil Rick drag Morty through the portal, and the portal disappears. The family screams in horror the entire time.)
</scene>
[Opening sequence plays]

<scene no="2">(The Smith family is seen sitting around the table eating breakfast. This scene takes place in Dimension C-137)

<convo>
            <speech designation="main" character="beth">
                <persName level="main">Beth</persName>Beth: Happy anniversary, dad!</speech>

<speech designation="main" character="rick">
                <persName level="main">Rick</persName>Rick: Oh, I get it. Regular pancakes are already shaped like flying saucers. [takes bite] Mmm, I should be making you breakfast for putting up with me.</speech>

<speech designation="main" character="jerry">
                <persName level="main">Jerry</persName>Jerry: Should be making us a whole restaurant.</speech>

<speech designation="main" character="beth">
                <persName level="main">Beth</persName>Beth: Nonsense, we couldn’t be happier to have you around. I just wish I got to see more of you.</speech>
</convo>
(Three armed Ricks come into the room through a portal)

<convo>
            <speech designation="dim" character="rick1">
                <persName level="dimension">Rick 1</persName>Rick 1: Rick Sanchez of Earth dimension C-137. You are under arrest for crimes against alternate Ricks by the authority of the transdimensional council of Ricks.</speech>

<speech designation="main" character="jerry">
                <persName level="main">Jerry</persName>Jerry: Hey! What the heck?</speech>

<speech designation="dim" character="rick1">
                <persName level="dimension">Rick 1</persName>Rick 1: Neutralise the Jerry.</speech>

<speech designation="main" character="jerry">
                <persName level="main">Jerry</persName>Jerry: Wait, no!</speech>

<speech designation="dim" character="rick2">
                <persName level="dimension">Rick 2</persName>(Rick 2 shoots at Jerry, freezing him)</speech>
</convo>
<convo>
            <speech designation="main" character="summer">
                <persName level="main">Summer</persName>Summer: Dad!</speech>

<speech designation="main" character="beth">
                <persName level="main">Beth</persName>Beth: Dad!</speech>
        </convo>

<convo>
            <speech designation="main" character="morty">
                <persName level="main">Morty</persName>Morty: Rick!</speech>

<speech designation="main" character="rick">
                <persName level="main">Rick</persName>Rick (C-137): Everybody relax. If I know these a-holes, and I am these a-holes, they just wanna haul me to their stupid clubhouse and waste my time with a bunch of questions. Let’s get it over with.</speech>

<speech designation="dim" character="rick1">
                <persName level="dimension">Rick 1</persName>Rick 1: Bring his mo-[belches]-orty.</speech>

<speech designation="main" character="morty">
                <persName level="main">Morty</persName>Morty: Oh, man.</speech>

    <speech designation="main" character="rick">
                <persName level="main">Rick</persName>Rick (C-137): Leave my [belches] Morty out of this!</speech>

<speech designation="dim" character="rick1">
                <persName level="dimension">Rick 1</persName>Rick 1: You lost the right to have a say in these things when you refused to join [belches] the council.</speech>

<speech designation="main" character="beth">
                <persName level="main">Beth</persName>Beth: Wait, wh-wh-wh-what about Jerry?</speech>

    <speech designation="main" character="rick">
                <persName level="main">Rick</persName>Rick (C-137): Will you at least unfreeze my daughter’s idiot?</speech>

<speech designation="dim" character="rick1">(<persName level="dimension">Rick 1</persName> unfreezes Jerry.</speech>
            <speech designation="dim" character="rick2"> <persName level="dimension">Rick 2</persName>
            </speech> and <speech designation="dim" character="rick3">
                <persName level="dimension">Rick 3</persName>Rick 3 take</speech> <speech designation="main" character="rick">Rick through</speech> the portal and all exit)
</convo>
<convo>
            <speech designation="main" character="jerry">
                <persName level="main">Jerry</persName>Jerry: -give you anything! I have a rare antique coin collection, just don’t hurt me! [pauses] Okay, maybe not antique, but it was a limited minting. They have little R2D2s instead of George Washingtons.</speech>

<speech designation="main" character="beth">
                <persName level="main">Beth</persName>Beth: Our son’s been abducted!</speech>

<speech designation="main" character="jerry">
                <persName level="main">Jerry</persName>Jerry: You hate me for buying those coins!</speech>
</convo>
[Trans. Ext Citadel of Ricks]
</scene>
<scene no="3">
[Trans. Int Citadel of Ricks. The three armed Ricks and C-137 Rick and Morty enter through a portal]

<convo>
            <speech designation="main" character="morty">
                <persName level="main">Morty</persName>Morty (C-137): Geez, Rick! Wh-what is this place?</speech>
    
    <speech designation="main" character="rick">
                <persName level="main">Rick</persName>Rick (C-137): The citadel of Ricks. It’s the secret headquarters for the council of Ricks.</speech>

<speech designation="main" character="morty">
                <persName level="main">Morty</persName>Morty (C-137): Council of Ricks?</speech>

    <speech designation="main" character="rick">
                <persName level="main">Rick</persName>Rick (C-137): As you know, Morty, I’ve got a lotta enemies in the universe that consider my genius a threat. Galactic terrorists, a few sub-galactic dictators, most of the entire intergalactic government: wh-wherever you find people with heads up their asses someone wants a piece of your grandpa. And a lot of versions of me on different timelines had the same problem. So a few thousand versions of me had the INGENIOUS IDEA OF BANDING TOGETHER like a herd of cattle or a school of fish or those people who answer questions on yahoo answers.</speech>

<speech designation="main" character="morty">
                <persName level="main">Morty</persName>Morty (C-137): Hey, what do you know? It’s a cowboy version of me!</speech>

    <speech designation="main" character="rick">
                <persName level="main">Rick</persName>Rick (C-137): Geez, you’re easy to impress. Yeah, most timelines have a Rick and most Ricks have a Morty. This place is a real who’s-who of who’s you and me.</speech>
</convo>
<convo>
            <speech designation="dim" character="rickSalesman1">
                <persName level="dimension">Rick Salesman 1</persName>: Turn your boring old Morty into a hot fashion statement, with some Morty dazzlers!</speech>

<speech designation="dim" character="rickSalesman2">
                <persName level="dimension">Rick Salesman 2</persName>: Hey, check this out!

(Rick Salesman 2 holds up a Morty doll and presses a button in the middle)</speech>

Morty Doll: Show me the Morty!

    <speech designation="main" character="rick">
                <persName level="main">Rick</persName>Rick (C-137): Dumb.</speech>

<speech designation="main" character="rickSalesman3">
                <persName level="dimension">Rick Salseman 3</persName>: ‘Scuse me, sir, is your Morty insured? You know, every year hundreds of Mortys are injured in-</speech>

    <speech designation="main" character="rick">
                <persName level="main">Rick</persName>Rick (C-137): Back off! Not my cup of tea, this place.</speech>
        </convo>
</scene>
<scene no="4">
[Trans. Hallway leading to the Council]

    <convo>
            <speech designation="main" character="rick">
                <persName level="main">Rick</persName>Rick (C-137): I say the point of being a Rick is being a Rick.</speech>

<speech designation="dim" character="rick1">
                <persName level="dimension">Rick 1</persName>Rick 1: Save your anti-Rick speech for the council of Ricks, terror-Rick!</speech>

        <speech designation="main" character="rick">
                <persName level="main">Rick</persName>Rick (C-137): Hey, save your Rick rules for the [belches] sheep-Ricks, Rick-pig!</speech>

<speech designation="dim" character="rick1">
                <persName level="dimension">Rick 1</persName>Rick 1: Fuck me, pal.</speech>

        <speech designation="main" character="rick">
                <persName level="main">Rick</persName>Rick (C-137): Fuck you? No no no no no, fuck me!</speech>
        </convo>

(They reach the end of the hallway and the door opens automatically, revealing the council of Ricks)
</scene>
<scene no="5">
<convo>
            <speech designation="dim" character="rickCouncil1">
                <persName level="dimension">Rick Council 1</persName>: Bring up the holograms!

(A screen depicting several dead Ricks appears)

Rick Council 1: Twenty-seven Ricks brutally murdered in their own timelines. An unprecedented Rick-icidal epidemic. What say you, Earth Rick C-137?</speech>

    <speech designation="main" character="rick">
                <persName level="main">Rick</persName>Rick (C-137): You think I did this? Why am I the first Rick you pull in every time a Rick stubs his toe?</speech>

<speech designation="dim" character="rickCouncil1">
                <persName level="dimension">Rick Council 1</persName>: You [belches] have a history of non-cooperation with the council.</speech>

    <speech designation="main" character="rick">
                <persName level="main">Rick</persName>Rick (C-137): Yeah, so does the scientist formerly known as Rick! Wh-wh-wh-why isn’t he here in handcuffs?</speech>

<speech designation="dim" character="rickCouncil1">
                <persName level="dimension">Rick Council 1</persName>: Because he’s dead too!

Rick crowd: No!

Rick Council 1: Who else would you have us question? You fit the profile. Of all the Ricks in the central finite curve, you’re the malcontent. The rogue.</speech>

    <speech designation="main" character="rick">
                <persName level="main">Rick</persName>Rick (C-137): I’m the Rick. And so were the rest of you before you formed this stupid alliance. You wanted to be safe from the government so you became a stupid government. That makes every Rick here less Rick than me.

Rick crowd: (Can you believe this guy? This guy needs to get out of here, etc. Ad lib)

Rick (C-137): Yeah, murmur it up, d-bags. Now if you’ll excuse me, I’ve got pancakes back home with syrup on top of them. They’re about to hit that critical point of syrup absorption that turns the cakes into a gross paste. And I hate to get all Andy Rooney about it, but I think we all like fluffy discs of cake with syrup on top! And I think we also like to be accused of crimes when there’s evidence! So as they say in Canada, peace oot!</speech>

<speech designation="dim" character="rickCouncil1">
                <persName level="dimension">Rick Council 1</persName>: Evidence? Good idea. Scan his portal gun!</speech>

(Rick 1 reaches into C-137’s lab coat and retrieves his portal gun)

    <speech designation="main" character="rick">
                <persName level="main">Rick</persName>Rick (C-137): Oh, come on. Don’t look at another man’s portal gun history. We-we all go to weird places.</speech>

<speech designation="dim" character="rickCouncil1">
                <persName level="dimension">Rick Council 1</persName>: Yes, but it appears you alone have been going to the exact timelines and locations in which the murders occured!</speech>

(A diagram appears on the screen, displaying C-137’s portal gun history. Entries for certain dimensions flash green before it finally settles on a select few which flash red)

    <speech designation="main" character="rick">
                <persName level="main">Rick</persName>Rick (C-137): What? That’s Rick-diculous. I’m obviously being set up!</speech>

<speech designation="dim" character="rickCouncil1">
                <persName level="dimension">Rick Council 1</persName>: Earth Rick C-137! The council of Ricks sentences you to the machine of unspeakable doom, which swaps your conscious and unconscious minds, rendering your fantasies pointless while everything you know becomes impossible to grasp. Also every ten seconds it stabs your balls.</speech>

    <speech designation="main" character="rick">
                <persName level="main">Rick</persName>Rick (C-137): I’ve heard enough.</speech>

(C-137 elbows <speech designation="dim" character="rick1">
                <persName level="dimension">Rick 1</persName>Rick 1</speech> and tackles him into <speech designation="dim" character="rick2">
                <persName level="dimension">Rick 2</persName>Rick 2</speech>, taking his gun and shooting through his own and then Morty’s handcuffs. The two run away)
</convo>
    <convo>
            <speech designation="main" character="rick">
                <persName level="main">Rick</persName>Rick (C-137): Run, Morty!</speech>

<speech designation="dim" character="mortyAnother">
                <persName level="dimension">Another Morty</persName>(A Morty from the crowd starts to run too)</speech>

Crowd rick: Uh uh, not you!</convo>
</scene>
<scene no="6">
[Trans. back to corridor. Rick and Morty (C-137) are running, and are being chased by Ricks]

<speech designation="main" character="morty">
            <persName level="main">Morty</persName>Morty (C-137): Aaaaah!</speech>

    <convo>
            <speech designation="main" character="rick">
                <persName level="main">Rick</persName>(Rick shoots into the side walls with his portal gun. As the chasing Ricks pass, several of them get set on fire, attacked by insects, dragged into the portals by tentacles or hit by falling pumpkins)</speech>

<speech designation="dim" character="rickArmed1">
                <persName level="dimension">Armed Rick 1</persName>: Nooo!</speech>

<speech designation="dim" character="rickArmed2">
                <persName level="dimension">Armed Rick 2</persName>: Arrrrgh! Ahhhh!</speech>

<speech designation="dim" character="rickArmed3">
                <persName level="dimension">Armed Rick 3</persName>: Aaaah!</speech>

<speech designation="dim" character="rickArmed4">
                <persName level="dimension">Armed Ricks 4</persName>
            </speech> <speech designation="dim" character="rickArmed5">
                <persName leve="dimension">Armed Rick 5</persName>and 5: Oof!</speech>
</convo>
(The two reach the end of the corridor, which cuts off to a moveable ramp which is currently down and is blocked by a railing. They leap over. As they fall, Rick C-137 shoots a portal beneath them which they then fall through)
</scene>
<scene no="7">
[Trans. Buttworld. Rick and Morty C-137 fall through a portal onto a large butt mountain. They bounce off and continue running]

<convo>
            <speech designation="main" character="morty">
                <persName level="main">Morty</persName>Morty (C-137): Oh! Oooh!</speech>

    <speech designation="main" character="rick">
                <persName level="main">Rick</persName>(Rick C-137 shoots a portal in between two buttcheeks, which they run through, with the other Ricks in hot pursuit)</speech>
</convo>
    </scene>
<scene no="8">
[Trans. Pizza dimension. A pizza sits on a couch dialing on a phone, while another is lying down on another couch)

<convo>
            <speech designation="dim" character="pizza1">
                <persName level="dimension">Pizza 1</persName>: Yeah, I’d like to order one large person with extra people please.</speech>

<speech designation="dim" character="pizza2">
                <persName level="dimension">Pizza 2</persName>: White people. No no no no no, black people. And hispanic on hal</speech>f.
</convo>
(C-137 Rick and Morty run out of a portal and shoot another portal onto the opposite wall, then run through. The Ricks and Mortys chasing them follow)
</scene>
<scene no="9">
[Trans. Greasy grandma world. The dimension is full of greasy grandmas. A banner says “Welcome to greasy grandma world. Population: A whole lot, sonny!”]

(C-137 Rick and Morty run through, avoiding the grandmas as much as possible. They shoot another portal in the wall and run through. The Ricks and Mortys chasing them follow)
</scene>
<scene no="10">
[Trans. Phone dimension. A phone sits on a pizza dialing on a person, while another is lying down on another pizza]

<convo>
            <speech designation="dim" character="phone1">
                <persName level="dimension">Phone 1</persName>: Yes, I’d like to order one large sofa chair with extra chair please.</speech>

<speech designation="dim" character="phone2">
                <persName level="dimension">Phone 2</persName>: High chair. No no no no no, recliner! And wheelchair on half.</speech>
</convo>
(C-137 Rick and Morty run out of a portal and shoot another portal onto the opposite wall, then run through. The Ricks and Mortys chasing them follow)
</scene>
    <scene no="11">
[Trans. Doopidoo dimension. Several doopidoo creatures stand around repeating the phrase “Doopidoo” over and over]

(Rick C-137 shoots several portals into the wall, and enters the last one. The Ricks and Mortys chasing them enter the dimension but don’t know which portal to go into)

<speech designation="dim" character="rickArmed6">
            <persName level="dimension">Armed Rick 6</persName>: They could have gone into any one of these.</speech>

Armed Ricks: (Ugh, son of a-, aw geez, aw man, we lost him, etc. Ad lib)
</scene>
<scene no="12">
   
[Trans. Chair dimension. A sofa sits on a person dialing on a pizza, while another is lying down on another person)

<convo>
            <speech designation="dim" character="sofa1">
                <persName level="dimension">Sofa 1</persName>: Yeah, I’d like to order one large phone with extra phones please.</speech>

<speech designation="dim" character="sofa2">
                <persName level="dimension">Sofa 2</persName>: Cellphone. No no no no no, rotary! And payphone on half.</speech>
        </convo>

(C-137 Rick and Morty run out of a portal)

<convo>
            <speech designation="main" character="rick">
                <persName level="main">Rick</persName>Rick: That’ll keep ‘em [belches] busy for a while.</speech>

<speech designation="main" character="morty">
                <persName level="main">Morty</persName>Morty: Those guys were wrong, right? You don’t- you wouldn’t kill yourself… y-yourselves?</speech>

<speech designation="main" character="rick">
                <persName level="main">Rick</persName>Rick: ‘Course not, Morty! How could that profit me? Someone out there is killing Ricks, and the council ain’t gonna stop thinking it’s me until we clear our names.</speech>

(The two pass a <persName level="dimension">Homeless Sofa</persName>homeless sofa, who’s initially drinking but stares at them as they pass and dumps out his bottle)

<speech designation="main" character="rick">
                <persName level="main">Rick</persName>Rick: By finding the real Rick killer.</speech>

<speech designation="main" character="morty">
                <persName level="main">Morty</persName>Morty: I’m scared, Rick! Maybe we should go home and stockpile weapons like that show Doomsday Preppers.</speech>

<speech designation="main" character="rick">
                <persName level="main">Rick</persName>Rick: Not really my style, Morty. Besides, your home is most likely swarming with Ricks right now.</speech>
</convo>
</scene>
<scene no="13">
[Trans. Smith living room. Jerry’s reading a newspaper, Summer’s on her phone, and a bunch of Ricks and Mortys are searching the place]

<convo>
            <speech designation="dim" character="rick1">
                <persName level="dimension">Rick 1</persName>Rick 1: Alright, listen, Jerry. If Rick calls, this device is going to trace his location. You just gotta keep ‘em on the phone for thirty seconds or longer.</speech>

<speech designation="main" character="beth">
                <persName level="main">Beth</persName>Beth: Who wants lemonade?</speech>

<speech designation="dim" character="rick1">
                <persName level="dimension">Rick 1</persName>Rick 1: Oh yeah! Mmm! Oh, delicious!</speech>

<speech designation="dim" character="rick2">
                <persName level="dimension">Rick 2</persName>Rick 2: Beth, [belches] you’re a treasure.</speech>

<speech designation="dim" character="rick3">
                <persName level="dimension">Rick 3</persName>Rick 3: I have a Beth just like you in my [belches] reality, except you know what? She’s not as brilliant or [belches] attractive!</speech>

<speech designation="main" character="beth">
                <persName level="main">Beth</persName>Beth: Aww, thank [belches] you!</speech>
        </convo>
    
All Ricks: Ohohoho! She did it! She did it!

<convo>
            <speech designation="dim" character="rick4">
                <persName level="dimension">Rick 4</persName>(Phone rings. Rick 4 makes a signal to say they’re tracing the signal. Jerry picks it up)</speech>

<speech designation="main" character="jerry">
                <persName level="main">Jerry</persName>Jerry: Uh, hello?</speech>

<speech designation="dim" character="phoneRick">
                <persName level="dimension">Phone Rick</persName>Rick (phone): Hey Jerry, it’s Rick.</speech>

<speech designation="main" character="jerry">
                <persName level="main">Jerry</persName>Jerry: Rick! Heyy. Haha, what’s- what’s up?</speech>

    <speech designation="dim" character="phoneRick">
                <persName level="dimension">Phone Rick</persName>Rick (phone): So listen, the heat’s on and [belches] there’s nowhere left to turn so Morty and I are just going to fly my spaceship into a black hole.</speech>

<speech designation="main" character="jerry">
                <persName level="main">Jerry</persName>Jerry: What?</speech>

    <speech designation="dim" character="phoneRick">
                <persName level="dimension">Phone Rick</persName>Rick (phone): Is that cool with you, dog?</speech>

<speech designation="main" character="jerry">
                <persName level="main">Jerry</persName>Jerry: Rick, no! Mortyyyy!</speech>

<speech designation="dim" character="rick4">
                <persName level="dimension">Rick 4</persName>Rick 4: I got it! The call’s coming from… inside the house!</speech>

All Ricks: [laughing] (Look at his face! I can’t believe our daughter married you, too easy, etc. Ad lib)</convo>

</scene>
<scene no="14">
[Trans. Chair dimension. Rick and Morty are in a restaurant run by chairs]

<convo>
            <speech designation="main" character="rick">
                <persName level="main">Rick</persName>Rick: The Ricks are probably gonna waste some time messing with Jerry. They won’t be able to help themselves. But as soon as they get bored they’ll be on to us.</speech>

<speech designation="dim" character="chairWaiter">
                <persName level="dimension">Chair Waiter</persName>: Phones á la clams, and phonesgetti with phoneballs. Anything else?
</speech>
<speech designation="main" character="rick">
                <persName level="main">Rick</persName>Rick: Yeah, more phonesticks please.</speech>

<speech designation="dim" character="chairWaiter">
                <persName level="dimension">Chair Waiter</persName>Phone waiter: Right away, sir.</speech>

<speech designation="main" character="morty">
                <persName level="main">Morty</persName>Morty: You know Rick, when I first saw all those Ricks and Mortys, I thought ‘gee, that kinda devalues our bond.’ But then I realised that just means that our relationship must be pretty special to span over all those different timelines.</speech>

<speech designation="main" character="rick">
                <persName level="main">Rick</persName>Rick: Yeah, it’s gotta be that way. You’re a camouflage.</speech>

<speech designation="main" character="morty">
                <persName level="main">Morty</persName>Morty: Camouflage? Wh-wh-what are you talking about, Rick?</speech>

<speech designation="main" character="rick">
                <persName level="main">Rick</persName>Rick: Ricks have a very distinct and traceable brainwave due to our genius. The best way to hide from an enemy’s radar is to stand near someone with complementary brainwaves that make ours invisible. See, wh-wh-when a Rick is with a Morty, the genius waves get cancelled out by the uh, [clears throat] Morty waves.</speech>

<speech designation="main" character="morty">
                <persName level="main">Morty</persName>Morty: Um… because… our personalities are so different?</speech>

<speech designation="main" character="rick">
                <persName level="main">Rick</persName>Rick: Oh, shit dog! My portal gun was hacked remotely Morty, obviously by the real killer to frame me. But I was able to trace the signal. Come on, let’s go!

(The two stand up. As they’re about to leave, two Ricks and a Morty enter the restaurant and address the waiter)

Rick (C-137): Uh-oh!</speech>
        </convo>

<convo>
            <speech designation="dim" character="rick1">
                <persName level="dimension">Rick 1</persName>Rick 1: ‘Scuse me, we’ve tracked a pair of dangerous criminals to this exact location. They look exactly like us, so in order to avoid confusion I’m going to mark us each with a red X right now. That way if someone has a gun and we both tell you to shoot the other one because they’re the evil one, you’ll know who’s lying.</speech>

<speech designation="dim" character="rick2">
                <persName level="dimension">Rick 2</persName>Rick 2: Hey, check it out!</speech>

(Two person-chairs that look like Rick and Morty from behind are beside a table. When the two Ricks rush over to turn them around, it’s revealed that they’re not)

<speech designation="dim" character="rick1">
                <persName level="dimension">Rick 1</persName>Rick 1: Dammit!</speech>

<speech designation="main" character="rick">
                <persName level="main">Rick</persName>(They look out the window, to see C-137 flipping them off from in a police hovercraft. They rush outside, and the waiter follows)</speech>

<speech designation="dim" character="chairWaiter">
                <persName level="dimension">Chair Waiter</persName>Chair waiter: Hey, you didn’t pay your bill!</speech>

<speech designation="dim" character="rick1">
                <persName level="dimension">Rick 1</persName>Rick 1: The red X! Red X!</speech>
        </convo>

</scene>
<scene no="15">
[Trans. Green planet. Rick and Morty are flying in the police hovercraft, searching]

<convo>
            <speech designation="main" character="rick">
                <persName level="main">Rick</persName>Rick: Hey, it’s a good thing that space outlet had labcoats and your favourite kind of shirt in stock, huh Morty?</speech>

<speech designation="main" character="morty">
                <persName level="main">Morty</persName>Morty: Yeah, Rick. I-I heard you the first time. You don’t have to keep saying it over and over and over.</speech>

<speech designation="main" character="rick">
                <persName level="main">Rick</persName>Rick: Man, this place is wayyy off the grid. This guy does not wanna be found.</speech>

<speech designation="main" character="morty">
                <persName level="main">Morty</persName>Morty: Well, if he’s a Rick, doesn’t he just have to stand by a Morty to hide? I mean, isn’t that what Mortys are? Human cloaking devices?</speech>

<speech designation="main" character="rick">
                <persName level="main">Rick</persName>Rick: Morty, you’re making a bigger deal out of this than it is.</speech>

(In the distance a dome comes into view. Faint yelling can be heard)

<speech designation="main" character="morty">
                <persName level="main">Morty</persName>Morty: Oh my god, Rick, look! There’s a bunch of people strapped all over that building!</speech>

<speech designation="main" character="rick">
                <persName level="main">Rick</persName>Rick: Not people, Morty. Mortys.</speech>

(As they get closer, it’s revealed that the dome is covered top to bottom in naked Mortys, who are strapped to the surface and are being tortured with contraptions that stab their sides constantly. Constant Morty yelling can be heard)

<speech designation="main" character="morty">
                <persName level="main">Morty</persName>Morty (C-137): Oh my god… wh-why would somebody do this? It’s horrible!</speech>

<speech designation="main" character="rick">
                <persName level="main">Rick</persName>Rick: Well, one Morty’s enough to hide from the bureaucrats. But you g- you get a whole matrix of Mortys and put ‘em in agonising pain. That creates a pattern that can hide even from other Ricks, motherfucker. I fiddled with a [belches] concept like this once.

(They land. Morty stares at Rick)

Rick: On paper, Morty, on paper! I wouldn’t do this, it’s barbaric overkill. I mean, you could accomplish the same result with like five Mortys and a jumper cable. [pauses as Morty glares at him] Which I also wouldn’t do! I’m just saying, it’s bad craftsmanship.</speech>
</convo>
</scene>
<scene no="16">
[Trans. Smith living room. Ricks are playing cards while Mortys watch. Jerry’s on his laptop]

<speech designation="main" character="beth">
            <persName level="main">Beth</persName>Beth: Coffee time!</speech>

All ricks: (Yeah! That’s what I like to hear! etc. Ad lib)

(The Ricks run into the kitchen, and the Mortys take the place of the Ricks on the cards table. Doofus Rick enters the house)

<convo>
            <speech designation="main" character="jerry">
                <persName level="main">Jerry</persName>Jerry: Ugh.</speech>

<speech designation="dim" character="doofusRick">
                <persName level="dimension">Doofus Rick</persName>Doofus Rick:: Hi Jerry!</speech>

<speech designation="main" character="jerry">
                <persName level="main">Jerry</persName>Jerry: Leave me alone, I’m working!</speech>

<speech designation="dim" character="doofusRick">
                <persName level="dimension">Doofus Rick</persName>Doofus Rick:: Oh, you are? Wh-wh-what do you do?</speech>

<speech designation="main" character="jerry">
                <persName level="main">Jerry</persName>Jerry: Ugh. I’m- I’m in between advertising jobs.</speech>

<speech designation="dim" character="doofusRick">
                <persName level="dimension">Doofus Rick</persName>Doofus Rick:: Advertising? Wow! So, people need help figuring out what to buy and then y-you help them?</speech>

<speech designation="main" character="jerry">
                <persName level="main">Jerry</persName>Jerry: W-well, it’s a little more complicated than that…</speech>

<speech designation="dim" character="doofusRick">
                <persName level="dimension">Doofus Rick</persName>Doofus Rick:: Well, I mean, you do it, and you seem like a guy that really has it all together!</speech>

<speech designation="main" character="jerry">
                <persName level="main">Jerry</persName>Jerry: [Looks around for hiding Ricks] Dude, are you… wh- you’re being a dick, right?</speech>

<speech designation="dim" character="doofusRick">
                <persName level="dimension">Doofus Rick</persName>Doofus Rick:: Oh gosh, wh- I hope not! I-I-I-I wouldn’t want to offend you in any way!</speech>

<speech designation="main" character="jerry">
                <persName level="main">Jerry</persName>Jerry: You’re really a Rick?</speech>

<speech designation="dim" character="doofusRick">
                <persName level="dimension">Doofus Rick</persName>Doofus Rick:: Ohoho! Y-of course I am! Just as much as my Morty’s a Morty!</speech>

(Doofus Rick’s morty waves to Doofus Rick from the poker table)

<speech designation="main" character="jerry">
                <persName level="main">Jerry</persName>Jerry: Hey, he looks a lot like Eric Stoltz from the movie ‘Mask.’ You know, the one with Cher in it?</speech>

<speech designation="dim" character="doofusRick">
                <persName level="dimension">Doofus Rick</persName>Doofus Rick:: That’s right, Jerry! He-he’s from a reality where everyone is Eric Stoltz mask people! He’s Eric Stoltz mask Morty! They assigned him to me because… I never had any kids of my own. But if I did, boy, I’d love ‘em  if they were as smart and as successful as you are, Jerry.</speech>

(Ricks return with coffee)</convo>

<convo>
            <speech designation="dim" character="rick1">
                <persName level="dimension">Rick 1</persName>Rick 1: Hey, get a load of this! Jerry’s hanging out with doofus Rick.</speech>

<speech designation="dim" character="rick2">
                <persName level="dimension">Rick 2</persName>Rick 2: Haha, this is perfect.</speech>

<speech designation="dim" character="doofusRick">
                <persName level="dimension">Doofus Rick</persName>Doofus Rick:: I’m not doofus Rick! I’m Rick J-19-Zeta-7!</speech>

<speech designation="dim" character="rick1">
                <persName level="dimension">Rick 1</persName>Rick 1: Oh, is that the timeline where everybody eats poop? Jerry, you know this guy eats poop, right?</speech>

<speech designation="dim" character="doofusRick">
                <persName level="dimension">Doofus Rick</persName>Doofus Rick:: Hey! I don’t eat poop! Y-you guys are always so mean to me!</speech>

<speech designation="dim" character="rick1">
                <persName level="dimension">Rick 1</persName>Rick 1 </speech>
            <speech designation="dim" character="rick2">and 2: [laughing]</speech>
        </convo>

<convo>
            <speech designation="dim" character="doofusRick">
                <persName level="dimension">Doofus Rick</persName>Doofus Rick:: I guess it’s only fair to tell you now, Jerry… I’m the worst Rick of them all.</speech>

<speech designation="main" character="jerry">
                <persName level="main">Jerry</persName>Jerry: According to who? Other versions of you? If I’ve learned one thing, it’s that before you get anywhere in life, you gotta stop listening to yourself.</speech>

<speech designation="dim" character="doofusRick">
                <persName level="dimension">Doofus Rick</persName>Doofus Rick:: Wow, you really are wise, Jerry. I-I guess that’s why you work in advertising!</speech>

<speech designation="main" character="jerry">
                <persName level="main">Jerry</persName>Jerry: The fact that you feel that way makes you the best Rick of them all.</speech>
        </convo>

</scene>
<scene no="17">
[Trans. Int dome. Rick and Morty are exploring corridors]

<convo>
            <speech designation="main" character="morty">
                <persName level="main">Morty</persName>Morty: You don’t care about me at all! I’m no different than that jacket you’ve got on! Y-y-or-or your stupid portal gun! I’m just a tool! I-I’m just an object!</speech>

<speech designation="main" character="rick">
                <persName level="main">Rick</persName>Rick: Hey, it’s your choice to take it personally, Morty. Now for the love of god, be quiet! The point of this is to get the drop on the guy!</speech>

<speech designation="main" character="morty">
                <persName level="main">Morty</persName>Morty: You know what Rick, I’ll tell you something! I’m more than a human shield!</speech>

<speech designation="main" character="rick">
                <persName level="main">Rick</persName>Rick: Yeah, that’s right! You are! You’re a perfect impenetrable sheet of human armour, Morty! Because you’re as dumb as I am smart! Which is why when I say ‘shut up’ it’s really good advice.

(Morty tears up. A bunch of lobster-like aliens come out of the nearby corridors and surround them)

Rick: Great, nice work, Morty.

(Rick starts attacking and kicking the aliens. He kills the first wave, but more surround them quickly)

Rick: Urrgh.</speech>
        </convo>

(Evil Rick and Evil Morty emerge. Evil Rick is slow clapping)

<convo>
            <speech designation="dim" character="evilRick">
                <persName level="dimension">Evil Rick</persName>Evil Rick: Ooh, look at you, C-137! You’re- aren’t you a tough customer?</speech>
    
<speech designation="main" character="rick">
                <persName level="main">Rick</persName>Rick: The slow clap? Really? Kinda played out, dude.</speech>

<speech designation="dim" character="evilRick">
                <persName level="dimension">Evil Rick</persName>Evil Rick: Not in this dimension it isn’t. In fact, hah, I invented it and nobody else has ever even done it here before.</speech>

<speech designation="main" character="rick">
                <persName level="main">Rick</persName>Rick: Well lah-dee-dah. [slow claps]</speech>

<speech designation="dim" character="evilRick">
                <persName level="dimension">Evil Rick</persName>Evil Rick: Hey, that’s mine!</speech>
        </convo>
</scene>
<scene no="18">
[Trans. Rick and Morty have been apprehended and are being carried down the corridor by lobster aliens]

<convo>
            <speech designation="main" character="rick">
                <persName level="main">Rick</persName>Rick: I don’t like the look of that Rick, Morty. We gotta escape.</speech>

<speech designation="main" character="morty">
                <persName level="main">Morty</persName>Morty: I’m not gonna help you, Rick. Y-you’re a monster.</speech>

<speech designation="main" character="rick">
                <persName level="main">Rick</persName>Rick: Don’t be Rickdiculous, Morty</speech>.

<speech designation="main" character="morty">
                <persName level="main">Morty</persName>Morty: W-will you stop saying that? It’s stupid.</speech>
        </convo>

<speech designation="dim" character="evilRick">
            <persName level="dimension">Evil Rick</persName>Evil Rick: Take his Morty away.</speech>

<convo>
            <speech designation="dim" character="evilMorty">
                <persName level="dimension">Evil Morty</persName>: Come with me.</speech>

<speech designation="main" character="morty">
                <persName level="main">Morty</persName>Morty: Yeah, gladly. Geez man, Ricks huh?</speech>

(The two leave to the left. The view changes to another, smaller corridor, which the two walk down)

<speech designation="main" character="morty">
                <persName level="main">Morty</persName>Morty: Hey man, you seem to know how this place works. Is there any way we can… shut down that grid and rescue all those Mortys out there?</speech>

<speech designation="dim" character="evilMorty">
                <persName level="dimension">Evil Morty</persName>: It would be pointless. Mortys have no chance of defeating a Rick.

(He opens a door)

Evil Morty: In here.</speech>
        </convo>

(As Morty walks in, he sees it’s filled with a crowd of scared, shivering Mortys. As he tries to leave, Evil Morty closes the door behind him, locking him in)
</scene>
<scene no="19">
[Trans. Evil Rick’s lab. Rick is tied to an examination table. An array of computers and other devices are visible. Many of the Mortys from the outside of the dome are visible] Evil Rick: Ahh, isn’t it beautiful?

<convo>
            <speech designation="main" character="rick">
                <persName level="main">Rick</persName>Rick: Yeah, yeah, looks like payday at Neverland ranch in here. Zing!</speech>

<speech designation="dim" character="lobsterAlien">
                <persName level="dimension">Lobster Alien</persName>Lobster Alien: Hehehehehehehehehe.</speech>
    
<speech designation="main" character="rick">
                <persName level="main">Rick</persName>Rick: That guy got it.</speech>

<speech designation="dim" character="evilRick">
                <persName level="dimension">Evil Rick</persName>Evil Rick: Ah-ah Rick, quiet. You’re missing my symphony.</speech>

(Evil Rick presses a button, allowing the sounds of the Mortys in pain to come through. He conducts it for a bit)

<speech designation="main" character="rick">
                <persName level="main">Rick</persName>Rick: Hey, I’ll take it over Mumford and Sons. Zip!</speech>

<speech designation="dim" character="lobsterAlien">
                <persName level="dimension">Lobster Alien</persName>Lobster Alien: Hehehehehehehehehe.</speech>

<speech designation="main" character="rick">
                <persName level="main">Rick</persName>Rick: This guy is on it!</speech>

<speech designation="dim" character="evilRick">
                <persName level="dimension">Evil Rick</persName>Evil Rick: He’s not laughing at your dumb jokes, Rick. That’s just a random noise it makes every ten seconds.</speech>

<speech designation="dim" character="lobsterAlien">
                <persName level="dimension">Lobster Alien</persName>Lobster Alien: Hehehehehehehehehe.</speech>

<speech designation="main" character="rick">
                <persName level="main">Rick</persName>Rick: Awww.</speech>

<speech designation="dim" character="evilRick">
                <persName level="dimension">Evil Rick</persName>Evil Rick: See, Rick, you’re not as clever as you think you are. I wanted you to find me. We’re not so [belch] different, you and I.</speech>

(Evil Rick activates a display showing all the Ricks from different timelines)

<speech designation="main" character="rick">
                <persName level="main">Rick</persName>Rick: Yeah, duh!</speech>

<speech designation="dim" character="evilRick">
                <persName level="dimension">Evil Rick</persName>Evil Rick: See this right here, Rick? I crunched the numbers, I created a spectrum of all the Ricks. I listed ‘em out from most evil to least evil. Here’s where I am. And look at right here’s where you are, Rick. This guy right here? Super weird.</speech>

<speech designation="main" character="rick">
                <persName level="main">Rick</persName>Rick: I get it. So you want me to team up with you to take down the council of Ricks, right? Is that where you’re going with this? ‘Cause that’s where I’d be going.</speech>

<speech designation="dim" character="evilRick">
                <persName level="dimension">Evil Rick</persName>Evil Rick: Please. I think I’m doing pretty good on my own. I’m simply going to download the contents of your brain, and then kill you.</speech>
</convo>
</scene>
<scene no="20">
[Trans. Rick’s garage. Doofus Rick is mixing chemicals and Jerry is watching]

<convo>
            <speech designation="dim" character="doofusRick">
                <persName level="dimension">Doofus Rick</persName>Doofus Rick:: Okay, if we add a little more titanium nitrate, and just a tad of chlorified tartrate: ovenless brownies!</speech>

(Jerry takes a brownie, eats it and smiles)

<speech designation="main" character="jerry">
                <persName level="main">Jerry</persName>Jerry: It’s incredible what a gifted mind can accomplish when priorities are in order!</speech>

<speech designation="dim" character="doofusRick">
                <persName level="dimension">Doofus Rick</persName>Doofus Rick:: Well, come on, I can’t take all the credit, Jerry. It was your idea. C’mere Jerry!</speech>

(Both hug and laugh)

<speech designation="main" character="jerry">
                <persName level="main">Jerry</persName>Jerry: Hey, uh. C’mere, uh. I-I wanna show you something.

(They exit the garage and Jerry pulls out a box, then opens it to reveal coins with R2D2s on them)

Jerry: Okay, look. Everybody makes fun of me for getting these, but… you’re a genius scientist, what do you think? There’s little R2D2s where the George Washingtons should be!</speech>

<speech designation="dim" character="doofusRick">
                <persName level="dimension">Doofus Rick</persName>Doofus Rick:: You know Jerry, I’m not gonna tell you that these will increase in value, or even hold their current value. The truth is… you bought ‘em ‘cause you like ‘em. They have value to you. That’s what matters.</speech>

<speech designation="main" character="jerry">
                <persName level="main">Jerry</persName>Jerry: (tearing up) How long are you staying?</speech>

<speech designation="dim" character="doofusRick">
                <persName level="dimension">Doofus Rick</persName>Doofus Rick:: Until we find your Rick.</speech>

<speech designation="main" character="jerry">
                <persName level="main">Jerry</persName>Jerry: (hugging doofus Rick) I found mine. I found mine.</speech>
        </convo>

</scene>
<scene no="21">
[Trans. Morty prison. C-137 Morty is bashing at the door. He is approached by a group of Mortys wearing robes and facepaint]

<convo>
            <speech designation="main" character="morty">
                <persName level="main">Morty</persName>Morty (C-137): Help!</speech>

<speech designation="dim" character="religiousMorty">
                <persName level="dimension">Religious Morty</persName>: There is no escape, my son. We will find our peace in the next world.</speech>

(Religious Morty offers C-137 a pamphlet titled “The Good Morty”)

<speech designation="main" character="morty">
                <persName level="main">Morty</persName>Morty (C-137): So what? Y-y-y-y-you’re just going to give up?</speech>
<speech designation="main" character="morty">(<persName level="main">Morty</persName> opens “The Good Morty” to the first page, then scoffs and throws it away)

Morty (C-137): Alright Mortys, listen up! My name is Morty Smith, from Earth dimension C-137! I know you’re scared, because I’m scared, but that’s no reason to accept our fate. We’re Mortys! We’re not defined by our relationships to Rick! Our destiny is our own!</speech>

<speech designation="dim" character="religiousMorty">
                <persName level="dimension">Religious Morty</persName>: We’re giving in to the power of the One True Morty. One day he will return!</speech>

All religious Mortys: Praise the One True Morty!


<speech designation="dim" character="morty1">
                <persName level="dimension">Morty 1</persName>Morty 1: This sounds like something the One True Morty might say. I’m sick of being a human shield! I-I-I-I wanna be a gardener!</speech>

<speech designation="dim" character="morty2">
                <persName level="dimension">Morty 2</persName>Morty 2: I wanna write really crazy, intense action novels!</speech>

<speech designation="dim" character="hammerMorty">
                <persName level="dimension">Hammer Morty</persName>Hammer Morty: I’m more than just a hammer!</speech>

<speech designation="dim" character="religiousMorty">
                <persName level="dimension">Religious Morty</persName>Religious Morty: He is the one true Morty! The one true Morty!</speech>

All Mortys: Hooray!

(The door opens, and a lobster alien walks in)

<speech designation="dim" character="lobsterAlien">
                <persName level="dimension">Lobster Alien</persName>Lobster Alien: Hey, keep it down!</speech>

All Mortys: Raaaaugh!

(The Mortys rush the door, breaking free and charging down the corridor)</convo>
</scene>
<scene no="22">
[Trans. Evil Rick’s lab. Evil Rick is going through Rick’s memories on a screen]

<convo>
            <speech designation="dim" character="evilRick">
                <persName level="dimension">Evil Rick</persName>Evil Rick: You’ve lived quite a life, Rick. It’s a real shame you’re not gonna be around to see it through.

(The memories change theme to feature Morty in each one. Rick tears up)

Evil Rick: You’re crying? Over a Morty?</speech>

<speech designation="main" character="rick">
                <persName level="main">Rick</persName>Rick: No, I’m just allergic to dipshits</speech>.

<speech designation="dim" character="evilRick">
                <persName level="dimension">Evil Rick</persName>Evil Rick: Ugh, pathetic. We both know that if there’s any truth in the universe, it’s that Ricks don’t care about Mortys.

(The Mortys break through the door and rush at Evil Rick, killing the lobster aliens, surrounding him and tearing into him)

Evil Rick: Do your worst, you little bastards! Kill me! Do it! Do it!</speech>

(Evil Rick dies. Morty C-137 appears and approaches Rick)</convo>

<convo>
            <speech designation="main" character="rick">
                <persName level="main">Rick</persName>Rick: Morty! Get me out of this! Come on!</speech>

<speech designation="main" character="morty">
                <persName level="main">Morty</persName>Morty (C-137): You’re lucky I’m not a Rick.

(Morty C-137 unbuckles Rick from the examination table</speech>)

<speech designation="main" character="rick">
                <persName level="main">Rick</persName>Rick: Point taken, but this is [belches] no time for arcs.</speech>
</convo>
(He presses a button, disengaging the Morty shield. Mortys are released and pour down off the dome. Rick grabs a phone and rings home)

<convo>
            <speech designation="dim" character="rick1">
                <persName level="dimension">Rick 1</persName>Rick 1: Yeah, hello?</speech>

<speech designation="main" character="rick">
                <persName level="main">Rick</persName>Rick (C-137): Hey, what do me and O.J. not have in common?</speech>

<speech designation="dim" character="rick1">
                <persName level="dimension">Rick 1</persName>Rick 1: Huh? Wh-who is this?</speech>

    <speech designation="main" character="rick">
                <persName level="main">Rick</persName>Rick (C-137): I found the real killer, biitch! Get over here!</speech>
        </convo>
</scene>
<scene no="23">
[Trans. Jerry and doofus Rick are playing with legos. Rick 1 opens the door]

<speech designation="dim" character="rick1">
            <persName level="dimension">Rick 1</persName>Rick 1: Yo ding-dong! We’re done here. Time to go.</speech>
    
<convo>
            <speech designation="dim" character="doofusRick">
                <persName level="dimension">Doofus Rick</persName>Doofus Rick:: Well Jerry, I [belches] guess this means goodbye</speech>.

<speech designation="main" character="jerry">
                <persName level="main">Jerry</persName>Jerry: W-w-well, does it have to? Heh, you, you look just like Rick. We could maybe… you know… get rid of him? I’m not saying kill him, necessarily, I-I’m also not saying necessarily not kill him, but-</speech>

<speech designation="dim" character="doofusRick">
                <persName level="dimension">Doofus Rick</persName>Doofus Rick:: Jerry. W-we both know it wouldn’t work. It’s time to go back to our lives. I love you, Jerry. I love ya.</speech>
</convo>
(Doofus Rick hugs Jerry and leaves. Jerry makes as if to follow him, then stops and punches a wall. The lego castle they built falls apart)
</scene>
<scene no="24">
[Trans. Evil Rick’s lab. The Mortys are still fighting. Ricks from the citadel move in and stop each Morty, pulling them off Evil Rick’s corpse and bringing them back to the citadel]

<convo>
            <speech designation="main" character="morty">
                <persName level="main">Morty</persName>Morty (C-137): Wh-wh-what’s gonna happen to all these Mortys?</speech>

<speech designation="dim" character="rickCouncil1">
                <persName level="dimension">Council Rick 1</persName>: They’ll go back to their families, attend school regularly, play video games, date girls… poor little Rickless bastards.</speech>
</convo>
</scene>
<scene no="25">
[Trans. Citadel of Ricks. The council has gathered around C-137 Rick and Morty]

<convo>
            <speech designation="dim" character="rickCouncil1">
                <persName level="dimension">Council Rick 1</persName>: Earth Rick C-137, the council apologises for its false accusation. And in the way of reparations for our terrible mistake, we would like to compensate you with this voucher for a free replacement Morty, in the event that [belches] your current [belches] Morty should-</speech>

<speech designation="main" character="rick">
                <persName level="main">Rick</persName>Rick: Uh, guys? Not a good time. Come on, Morty, let’s hit it.</speech>
</convo>
(Before they leave, Rick takes the voucher anyway)
</scene>
<scene no="26">
[Trans. Citadel outside. Rick and Morty are walking away from the council]

<convo>
            <speech designation="main" character="morty">
                <persName level="main">Morty</persName>Morty: Is it time for arcs yet, Rick? I did a pretty great job back there for a human cloaking device. Saved your ass.</speech>

<speech designation="main" character="rick">
                <persName level="main">Rick</persName>Rick: Alright, Morty, don’t break an arm jerking yourself off.</speech>

<speech designation="main" character="morty">
                <persName level="main">Morty</persName>Morty: Man, I can’t believe you, Rick! That right there! Tha-that was a great opportunity to show a little humanity. You know? To connect with me a little?</speech>

<speech designation="main" character="rick">
                <persName level="main">Rick</persName>Rick: Hey Morty, you want connection? Go be part of some stupid club like all those dumb Ricks. You know, maybe I don’t connect because I’m the Rickest Rick there is. And you know, it would [belch] go without saying that the Rickest Rick… would have the Mortyest Morty.</speech>

<speech designation="main" character="morty">
                <persName level="main">Morty</persName>Morty: It would go without saying, huh?</speech>

<speech designation="main" character="rick">
                <persName level="main">Rick</persName>Rick: Yeah, it would. Did you hear me say it?</speech>

<speech designation="main" character="morty">
                <persName level="main">Morty</persName>Morty: Nah… (to himself) The Mortyest Morty…</speech>

<speech designation="main" character="rick">
                <persName level="main">Rick</persName>Rick: Just don’t get too big for your loafers, Buster Brown. A cocky Morty could lead to some big problems. Could be a real bad thing for everybody.</speech>

<speech designation="main" character="morty">
                <persName level="main">Morty</persName>Morty: Oh yeah, how’s that?</speech>

<speech designation="main" character="rick">
                <persName level="main">Rick</persName>Rick: I-I-I’ll explain when you’re older.</speech>
        </convo>

</scene>
<scene no="27">
[Trans. Evil Rick’s lab. Evil Rick is lying in a pool of blood being inspected by Ricks. For the Damaged Coda by Blonde Redhead starts playing in the background]

<convo>
            <speech designation="dim" character="rick1">
                <persName level="dimension">Rick 1</persName>Rick 1: What a mess…</speech>

<speech designation="dim" character="rick2">
                <persName level="dimension">Rick 2</persName>Rick 2: Pride cometh before the fall. I guess he got what he deserved.</speech>

<speech designation="dim" character="rick1">
                <persName level="dimension">Rick 1</persName>Rick 1: What is that?</speech>

(Rick 1 turns Evil Rick’s head over to reveal wires)

<speech designation="dim" character="rick2">
                <persName level="dimension">Rick 2</persName>Rick 2: Hand me the laser defibrillator.</speech>

<speech designation="dim" character="doofusRick">
                <persName level="dimension">Doofus Rick</persName>Doofus Rick:: Hey guys! Uh, c-can I help?</speech>

<speech designation="dim" character="rick2">
                <persName level="dimension">Rick 2</persName>Rick 2: No! Go clean the toilets! Maybe you’ll make friends with some turds!</speech>

<speech designation="dim" character="rick1">
                <persName level="dimension">Rick 1</persName>Rick 1: You make us ashamed to be ourselves!

(Rick 2 removes the top of Evil Rick’s head to reveal electronics woven into his brain. They pull out a chip)

Rick 1: My god! I’ve seen this technology before! This Rick was being controlled remotely, puppeteered by somebody else. This is the receiver!</speech>

<speech designation="dim" character="rick2">
                <persName level="dimension">Rick 2</persName>Rick 2: Yeah, but where’s the transmitter?</speech>
        </convo>

</scene>
<scene no="28">
[Trans. Citadel of Ricks. Mortys are being loaded into spaceships to be delivered to their respective dimensions]

(Evil Morty follows them, and removes his eyepatch, revealing the transmitter. He crushes it underfoot and hides the wires, then follows the rest of the Mortys)

[Credits play]
</scene>
<scene no="29">
[After credits scene: Jerry is sitting in Rick’s bedroom, trying not to cry. Rick enters]

<convo>
            <speech designation="main" character="rick">
                <persName level="main">Rick</persName>Rick: Wubbalubbadubdub! Oh. Hey Jerry. Wh-wh-what are you doing in my room, buddy?</speech>

<speech designation="main" character="jerry">
                <persName level="main">Jerry</persName>Jerry: Nothing! I was just, um, checking the smoke detectors.</speech>

<speech designation="main" character="rick">
                <persName level="main">Rick</persName>Rick: Alright. Okay, get out.</speech>
        </convo>

<convo>
            <speech designation="main" character="jerry">
                <persName level="main">Jerry</persName>(Jerry leaves and goes down to the dining room.</speech> He looks outside the window and sees <speech designation="dim" character="doofusRick">doofus Rick standing in the rain</speech> and smiles. Rick appears beside Jerry)
</convo>
<speech designation="main" character="rick">
            <persName level="main">Rick</persName>Rick: What’s that dipshit doing out there? Are you friends with him? You know he eats his own shit, right? Oh my god, this is rich! I’ve got like [belches] ten Ricks to call right now!</speech>
</scene>
[Episode ends]
</script>