<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="aticleSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?><article><heading><title>Episcopal Diocese prepares for secession vote</title><pubDate>September 9, 2008 12:00 AM </pubDate><author>By Ann Rodgers </author><pubSource>Pittsburgh Post-Gazette</pubSource></heading><body>In response to a lawsuit led by one of its parishes, <sec>the <sect type="Episcopal">Episcopal</sect> Diocese of Pittsburgh</sec> has agreed to have a court-appointed neutral party inventory all of its property and assets as it prepares for a<sec><schism>final vote on seceding</schism> from the <sect type="Episcopal">Episcopal</sect> Church.</sec>
        
        The agreement between representatives of the diocese and <sec><parish>Calvary Episcopal Church</parish>,<location> Shadyside</location></sec>, came after a hearing yesterday before <sec><who ref="James">Joseph M. James</who>, president judge of Common Pleas Court</sec>. In <sec><date>2005</date>, <who ref="James">he</who> oversaw a settlement after <parish>Calvary</parish></sec> sued the diocese to prevent the transfer of property from the denomination to individual parishes.
        
        <parish>Calvary</parish> has led a <schism>minority of parishes that oppose <who ref="Duncan">Bishop Robert Duncan's</who> plan to leave the <sec><location>U.S.</location> branch of the <sect type="Anglican">Anglican</sect> Communion</sec></schism> and <schism>realign with the more <sec>conservative<sect type="Anglican"> Anglican</sect> Province of the <location>Southern Cone in South America</location></sec> over concerns about doctrine and sexual ethics.</schism><schism>A final vote is set for <date>Oct. 4.</date></schism><sec>The <date>2005</date> agreement said that property held by the central diocese </sec>-- such as endowment funds, but not necessarily parish property -- would continue to be held by the <quote ref="agreement">"<sec><sect type="Episcopal">Episcopal</sect> Diocese of <location>Pittsburgh</location></sec> of the<sec><sect type="Episcopal"> Episcopal</sect> Church of the <location>United States of America</location></sec>"</quote> whether or not any parishes or diocesan leaders secede. <parish>Calvary</parish> claims that the diocese has violated its end of the <date>2005</date> agreement.
        
        The diocese will pursue <quote ref="Frank">"a fair and equitable distribution of property"</quote> if the realignment resolutions pass, said <sec>its spokesman, the <who ref="Frank">Rev. Peter Frank</who>.</sec>
        
        The diocese also agreed yesterday to permit parishes that oppose <schism>secession</schism> to divert diocesan support payments to escrow accounts that would remain in the <sect type="Episcopal">Episcopal </sect>Church.
        
        The agreement assumes that new leaders affiliated with the church will be <sec>elected for <location>Pittsburgh</location> if <who ref="Duncan">Bishop Duncan</who><schism>secedes.</schism></sec><quote ref="Deforest"> "It is highly likely that <who ref="Duncan">Bishop Duncan</who> and the other leadership of the diocese will purport to <schism>separate from the <sect type="Episcopal">Episcopal</sect> Church</schism>, and it is our position that the<sec> court order of <date>Oct. 14, 2005</date>,</sec> addresses what will happen in that regard,"</quote> said <sec><who ref="Deforest">Walter DeForest</who>, attorney for <parish>Calvary</parish>.</sec><quote ref="Deforest"> "It is certainly the position of <parish>Calvary</parish> that the <schism>new leadership of the diocese</schism> will be in charge of those assets."</quote></body></article>