<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="aticleSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?><article><heading><title>Judge clarifies ownership of disputed Episcopal diocesean assets</title><pubDate>October 7, 2009 12:00 AM </pubDate><author>By Amy McConnell Schaarsmith</author><pubSource>Pittsburgh Post-Gazette</pubSource></heading><body><sec>An <location>Allegheny County</location> court</sec> awarded the <sec><sect type="Episcopal">Episcopal</sect> Diocese of <location>Pittsburgh</location></sec> more than <fact>$15 million in endowments, bank accounts and other assets that a <schism>secessionist diocese</schism> had sought to retain.</fact><sec><who ref="James"> Judge Joseph James</who> of the Court of Common Pleas in<location> Allegheny County</location></sec>ruled yesterday that the assets -- although not necessarily buildings and land titled in the name of the <schism>parishes that seceded</schism> -- belong to the <sec><sect type="Episcopal">Episcopal</sect> Diocese of <location>Pittsburgh</location> of the <sect type="Episcopal">Episcopal</sect> Church of the<location> United States of America.</location></sec>
        
        The <schism>secessionist church</schism>, the<sec><sect type="Episcopal">Episcopal </sect>Diocese of <location>Pittsburgh</location><sect type="Anglican">(Anglican)</sect></sec>, is in violation of its <sec><date>October 2005</date> agreement with the <sect type="Episcopal">Episcopal</sect> Church of <location>America</location></sec>, <who ref="James">Judge James </who>ruled.
        
        Many pages of the parties' briefs, he noted, were spent explaining the meaning of Paragraph One of the agreement, which describes what must be done with the <schism>diocese's centrally owned assets.</schism><quote ref="James">"However, I find that the language is clear and unambiguous and, therefore, requires no further explanation,"</quote> the order states. <quote ref="James">"The property is to be held or administered by the <sec><sect type="Episcopal">Episcopal</sect> Diocese of the <sect type="Episcopal">Episcopal</sect> Church of the <location>United States of America</location>.</sec> Regardless of what name <schism>defendants now call themselves, they are not the <sec><sect type="Episcopal">Episcopal</sect> Diocese of the <sect type="Episcopal">Episcopal</sect> Church of the <location>United States of America.</location></sec>"</schism></quote><fact>Assets must be detailed within 30 days and transferred within 20 days after that</fact>, the order states.
        
        <sec>The <sect type="Episcopal">Episcopal</sect> Diocese of <location>Pittsburgh </location><sect type="Anglican">(Anglican)</sect> withdrew in <date>October 2008</date> with <stat>58 parishes, or about 60 percent</stat> of the parishes in the diocese before the split.</sec> Members of the <schism>seceding group voted to leave the <sect type="Episcopal">Episcopal</sect> Church for what they considered failure to uphold biblical doctrine.</schism>
        
        The <sect type="Anglican">Anglican</sect> diocese now is <sec>affiliated with the <sect type="Anglican">Anglican</sect> Province of the <location>Southern Cone in South America</location></sec><sec> and the new <sect type="Anglican">Anglican</sect> Church in <location>North America</location></sec>.
        
        <sec><who ref="Duncan">Archbishop Robert Duncan</who>, of the <sect type="Episcopal">Episcopal</sect> Diocese of <location>Pittsburgh</location><sect type="Anglican">(Anglican)</sect></sec>, said he had not seen the ruling and that members of<schism> the diocese would be disappointed if the court had awarded the assets to the <sect type="Episcopal">Episcopal</sect> Diocese</schism>. But regardless, <schism>members of the seceding diocese are confident about their new life together</schism>, he said.
        
        <quote ref="Duncan">"We have managed the last year without any income from our assets," he said. "We are doing well."</quote><sec><who ref="Creehan">Rich Creehan</who>, communications director for the <sect type="Episcopal">Episcopal</sect> Diocese,</sec> said after the assets are transferred, the diocese will begin working on how to <schism>transfer buildings and land to the seceding parishes that want them.</schism><quote ref="Creehan">"<schism>Anyone who wants to come back to the <sect type="Episcopal">Episcopal</sect> Church is welcome, and we hope to find a way to proceed with those who don't [want to return] in a spirit of reconciliation,</schism>"</quote> he said.
    </body></article>