<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../../ODD/out/RickandMortyODD.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?><?xml-model href="../../ODD/out/RickandMortyODD.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title>The Wedding Squanchers</title>
                <author>Justin Roiland</author>
                <editor>D. Lint</editor>
            </titleStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <p>Digital edition hosted on <ref target="http://rickandmorty.newtfire.org">http://rickandmorty.newtfire.org</ref> and GitHub: <ref target="https://github.com/dorothealint/Rick-and-Morty">https://github.com/dorothealint/Rick-and-Morty</ref></p>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>The Wedding Squanchers</title>
                    <date when="2015-"/>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        <encodingDesc>
            <p>Some small changes to the original transcriptions were made including fixed spelling errors and adding names and scene cuts.</p>
        </encodingDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
jerry    The trick to cereal is keeping 70% above the milk.
beth    Jerry, get a job.
    [ Knock on door ]
rick    Uh, w-why don’t you get it, Jerry? You’re the man of the house, and you don’t have a job.
    [Jerry Sighs ]
courier flap    Delivery for Rick.    Morning, Summer, Beth, and Jerry.
summer    Gross. What is that thing?
    It’s a courier flap.
    It’s like the intergalactic version of u.P.S., but less off-putting.
    Oh, shiiit!
    It looks like an egg-vite from birdperson.
    Must be time for his annual Oscar party.
    And, by the way, our TV signals take light years to reach his planet.
    Nobody tell him that "braveheart" wins.
    [ Music plays ]
birdperson    Greetings. This is birdperson.
tammy    And Tammy!
birdperson    Inviting you to planet squanch for our mate-melding ceremony... blugh! [ Muffled ] 
tammy    If you’re from earth, that means we’re getting married!
summer    Oh, my God! My friend Tammy’s marrying birdperson!
jerry    What the hell is a birdperson?
morty    He’s Rick’s best friend.
rick    Uh, l-let’s not get carried away, Morty.
courier flap    Would you like to rsvp or send a gift?
rick    No. Weddings are basically funerals with cake.
    If I wanted to watch someone throw their life away, [burps] I’d hang out with Jerry all day.
courier flap    Affirmative! Returning to sender.
beth    No, hold on, stay, courier flaps.
courier flap    Staying!
    Dad, you have a friend that’s getting married.
    That’s a big deal.
jerry    It’s a big deal he has a friend.
rick    What do you know about friendship, Jerry?
courier flap    Confirmed, shipping Jerry.
jerry    [ Muffled ] Whoa, whoa, wait! Aah!
beth    Oh, God! Jerry!
morty    Dad! Dad!
summer    Where is it taking him?
rick    I assume planet squanch...
    6,000 light years across the galaxy.
morty    Whoa, t-that’s... that’s insane!
rick    Yeah, I know. Now we have to go to the wedding.
[opening credits]
    ♪[ Upbeat music playing]
    [ Bottles rattling ]
squanchy    Rick Sanchez!
    You psycho bag of squanch!
rick    Hey, what’s up, squanchy?
Summer and Morty: Hey, squanchy.
squanchy    Morty, Summer! And you must be Beth.
    Mwah! Ensquanche!
beth    You’re language has the word "squanch" in it a lot.
    Doesn’t that become tedious and worn out, like the smurf thing?
rick    Beth, squanchy culture is more contextual than literal.
    You just say what’s in your squanch and people understand.
beth    Oh. Okay.
reth    I squanch my family.
    Uh... What, I do.
    I squanch my family.
rick    Stop saying it. Gross.
squanchy    Come on in, guys.
    The guest are having cocksquanches.
    [ Groaning ]
    [ Gasps ]
jerry    Where am I?!
beth    You’re at a wedding. Go change.
    ♪ And I’m an alien with jazz rap style ♪
    ♪ Jazz rapping for an alien mile ♪ ♪ Fat beats and an alien smile ♪ ♪ jazz space phone, alien dial is my friend ♪ ♪ I got a mouthful of jazz for your ass ♪
    [ Crying ]
    ♪ And I’m gonna keep jazzing ♪
    [ both squealing ]
tammy    Oh, you made it!
summer    I wouldn’t it for the world!
    Oh, my God. I love your ring.
tammy    Thanks. It was birdperson’s grandmother’s.
    She fought a squirrel for it.
rick    Birdperson.
birdperson    Rick, I am pleased you and your family could witness my melding with Tammy.
beth    Our pleasure.
rick    Yeah, I just hope you got a pre-meld.
morty    Rick! 
rick    What?! It’s just a practical way of making sure that when she’s done with you, you can get one of your balls back.
beth    Jesus, dad.
morty    He’s just grumpy from the flight.
rick    Ohh, I-I was happy on the flight.I’m grumpy from the landing.
jerry    [ Sighs ]
    Well, I looked at the guest book. We don’t know a damn person here. Hi! Jerry Smith... father of the bride’s friend. Advertising is my usual game, but I’m between...
beth    Jerry, stop networking. We’re in space.
jerry    "Jerry, get a job! Jerry, don’t look for a job at an alien wedding!" I don’t get you.
beth    This is the closest I’ve ever gotten to this part of my father’s life.I don’t want to blow it.
jerry    Okay, I get it. I’m cramping your style.
beth    You say you get it, but I’m scared you’ll keep doing it. Look, here’s some humans you can practice on.
Pat    You must be Summer’s mom and dad.  We’re Tammy’s parents... pat and Donna guterman.
    Hi. Beth.
beth    This is Jerry.
jerry    So you’re teenage daughter’s marrying a birdman. Are you guys down with that? [ Chuckles ] No pun intended.
pat    We’re quite proud. He’s a wonderful person and an incredible bird.
jerry    Still, what is he, 40? [ Chuckles ]
    It’s just, you know, when he was 30, she was an actual child.
    When he was her age, she wasn’t born.
    When he was, let’s see, like, 18, she was literally in there in your womb.
    Imagine being pregnant with your daughter and a bird teenager comes into your home and says, "I’ll take that. I’ll have s*x with that."
    [ Both chuckle ]
beth    Give us one second.
jerry    Oof! 
beth  Were you born with your feet in your mouth?
jerry    I was transported here against my will in a meatball, all right?
    So take your attitude to the men’s section of kmart ‘cause you need to cut me some slack... S.
beth    I want you to stand in the corner and face the corner and talk to nobody.
jerry    Maybe... I... Will.
morty    You know, you’re not being very supportive of birdperson on his big day.
rick    Birdperson’s big day, Morty, was at blood Ridge on glapflap’s third moon against the gromflamites!
    This? This is a losing battle.
morty    Geez, Rick, it’s not like he’s dying.
    He’s getting married!
    I mean, what do you think’s gonna happen if you open yourself up a little bit?
    I mean, look around.
    This is your family and friends all around you, you know?
    Take the day off.
    There’s nothing to run from, nothing to fight.
tammy    [ Whistles ] That’s his last name.
summer    Are you hyphenating it?
jerry    Squanch this, mo-fo.
    [ Both laugh ]
rick    Good one, Morty. Excuse me, bartender. Can you make me a dumb grandson pep talk? It’s one part lame advice about stuff you know nothing about and a lot of vodka.
bartender    Mm-hmm. I have a lot of vodka.
rick    Then I’ll take one of those. I don’t need the rest.
morty    God, whatever, Rick.
beth    Oh, it sounds like you and my dad have a long history together.
    Wish I could say the same.
birdperson    The road your father and I walked together is soaked deeply with the blood of both friends and enemies.
beth    Must be nice.
    Um, I used to have to draw him into family photos with a crayon.
birdperson    The war in which we fought is far from over.
    We live our lives in hiding.
beth    I guess I should be happy for you.
    I mean, great, you guys got to hang out.
    I hope you had a blast.
birdperson    The galactic government considers us terrorists.
    It’s unwise of me to share these details, but I’ve become inebriated.
beth    I don’t know if you can appreciate what it means to grow up without a father, but... the guest list at this wedding includes 17 of the federation’s most wanted.
birdperson    We have committed numerous atrocities in the name of freedom.
beth    Annnd during that time, I don’t suppose he ever mentioned his daughter.
    Are those baby quiches?
birdperson    Night crawler pate.
    I should prepare for the ceremony.
beth    Like talking to a brick wall.
    [ Squawking ]
squanchy    In the name of the squanch, the six rivers, the four squanches, and the nine balls, I unite these two organisms in eternal squanch!
    Tammy, you may squanch your vows now.
tammy    Birdperson... [ Inhales sharply ] You are my seed, my worm, my earliness, and my lack of cats. I promise to be yours until your death.
squanchy    Nice!
All    Aww!
squanchy    Birdperson.
birdperson    Tammy, I was approaching infertility when I met you, but there is still time.
    I am yours until my death.
All   Aww!
rick    [ Burping ] Aww.
squanchy    I now pronounce you squanch and birdperson!
    [ Cheers and applause and profane kissing ]
    ♪ Girl, you got it going on ♪
    [ children laughing ]
cyborg    [ Monotone ] I am not staring at you. I am a cyborg photographer. Just act natural.
    This is a candid shot.
    I don’t require a camera so... sorry.
    Hi. I am not staring at you.
    [ Screams ]
    [ Clinking ]
rick    Uh, hi, everybody.
    I’m ri[Burps]ck.
    You know, when I first met birdperson, he was, uhh...
    Listen, I’m not the nicest guy in the Universe because I’m the smartest.
    And being nice is something stupid people do to hedge their bets.
    Now, I haven’t been exactly subtle about how little I trust marriage.
    I couldn’t make it work, and I could turn a black hole into a sun, so at a certain point, you got to ask yourself what are the odds this is legit and not just some big lie we’re all telling ourselves because we’re afraid to die alone?
    Because, you know, that’s exactly how we all die... alone.
summer    Oh, boy. 
beth     Oh, dad.
jerry    Jesus.
rick    But... but... Here’s the thing.
    Birdperson is my best friend, and if he loves Tammy, well, then I love Tammy, too.
    [ Cheers and applause ]
    To friendship, to love, and to my greatest adventure yet... opening myself up to others.
    Summer: Hear, hear! Cheers!
squanchy    Cheers to that, mother[Bleep]
birdperson    Thank you, Rick.
tammy    That was beautiful.
    Gosh, I look around this room, and I think, "uh, Tammy, you’re a high-school senior from the planet earth, and you’re marrying a 40-year-old birdperson? Like, what?!"
    [ Laughter ]
summer    Yeah, Tammy!
tammy    But then I think, you know, in a lot of ways, I’m not a high-school senior from the planet earth.
    In a lot of ways, what I really am is a deep-cover agent for the galactic federation, and you guys are a group of wanted criminals, and this entire building is, in a certain sense, surrounded.
    [ All murmur ]
rick    Oh, sh1t.
summer    I...Don’t get the metaphor.
rick    I’ll explain it to you later.
tammy    Everyone here is under arrest for crimes against the federation.
drunk    L’Chaim!
birdperson    Tammy, what are you doing?
tammy    Sit your bird ass down.
birdperson    Tammy?
    [ Cawing weakly ]
rick    Birdperson!!
    No!!
    [ Screaming ]
    Holy...
tammy    [ beep ] Drop the portal gun.
    Slide it to the center of the room.
    [ Beeping ]
    Somebody confiscate that and don’t damage it.
    They’ll want it at...
    [ whooshing ]
    [ High-pitched ringing and muffled background ]
    [ Sighs, roars ]
squanchy    There’s no time to squanch!
    Get your family out of here!
    I got this.
    [ Gulps ]
    [ Roaring ]
    [ Deep voice ] How about a taste of my squanch?!
    [ Growling ]
rick    Come on, this way!
squanchy    Squanch this!
    [ Engine turns over ]
jerry    Good thing I grabbed a space weapon.
rick    That’s a confetti gun, you [Bleep] idiot!
beth     Dad! 
rick    Hold on tight!
pat    Aaah!!
diane    Aaaah!!
    [ Sirens wailing ]
rick    God damn it! God damn it!!
beth    What the hell happened back there?!
rick    This is on you guys. I told you weddings are stupid.
jerry    Uh, Rick, is there anything you’d like to tell us about your relationship with this previously unknown galactic government?
rick    All the important points seem pretty clear, no?
    They think they control the galaxy, I disagree.
    Don’t hate the player, hate the game, son.
jerry    How could you be so dishonest with this family?
rick    Oh! Oh, should I have been more open and trusting and loving like, oh, I don’t know, my now dead best friend? Or your daughter, who is bffs with an intergalactic narc?
summer    Hey, Tammy was cool!
rick    And now we know why. Because of you!
    [Bleep] You, Summer, and [Bleep] the government, and [Bleep] me for letting my guard down, which I will never do again.
morty    Geez, Rick!
    You can’t say f... "‘f’ you" to your granddaughter.
rick    I just did, Morty. Here’s dessert. [Bleep] You.
beth    Look, I think we’ve all had a tough wedding.
    Actually, the wedding was beautiful.
    The reception got out of hand.
    Anyway, I say we go home, sleep it off, and have a family meeting in the morning.
rick    Yeah, about going home, we can’t... ever.
    All: What?!
rick    Oh, these guys are looking for us now.
    Earth will be swarming with them.
beth    Us?! Jerry... I want to go home!
rick    Look, anyone that wants to go back to earth is free to go back to earth.
    But here’s what’s gonna happen.
    Aliens bureaucrats are gonna arrest you.
    They’re gonna put the intergalactic equivalent of [Burps] jumper cables under your nuts and or labia and hook them up to an alien car battery until you tell them where I am... which I guarantee you, you’re not gonna know, which I guarantee they won’t believe.
    So who’s homesick? By applause.
    [ Sobbing ] Ladies? Anybody?
summer    What are we going to do?
    Where are we going to live?
jerry    Take it easy. This is a blessing in disguise.
rick    [Bleep] Earth.
    You realize our planet’s name means dirt, right?
    We’ll find a new world.
    Computer, how many planets in the milky way are at least 90% similar to earth?
    [ Beeping ]
computer 765 known planets.
rick    How many of those are outside federal jurisdiction?
computer    [ Beeping ] Three.
rick    See? Our cup runneth over.
    Now, who wants to go shopping for a brand-new mother[Bleep] world?!
    All right!
    Look at this baby!
    Would you even know that wasn’t earth?
Morty   Yes, because there’s no Africa.
rick    Pssh. White-people problems, Morty.
    Let’s go down and check her out.
    [ Thud, water splashing ]
    Oh. I thought it was further away.
    I uh... I guess this one’s a little small.
    All right, uh, maybe... maybe we should go check out the other two, huh?
    Okay, this one’s bigger.
    This looks nice.
morty    Mom, dad, look!
    Strawberries on a cob!
    [ Munching ]
jerry    Whoa! Hey, check this out!
    Flowers on a cob! [ Laughs ]
rick    Huh. Strawberries and flowers on a cob, huh?
jerry    That’s pretty cool.
beth    Are those... Mountains on a cob?
    [ Birds cawing ]
Rick  Oh, my God.
    Get in the ship, sweetie. 
beth    What?
rock    Get in the god[Bleep] ship!!
    Everything’s on a cob!!
    The whole planet’s on a cob!! Go, go, go!!
    [ Engine turns over ]
    [ Burps ] All right, third time’s the charm.
    See what we got here.
jerry    Seems good.
    And nothing on the cob.
    Didn’t know that was a necessity, but...
rick    No, it’s nice. I think this might be it.
morty    Wow! Hey, look, you guys.
    The sun’s rising.
sun    Aaaaaaaaaaaaah!!
beth    Uh, dad, how long are the days on this planet?
rick    Uh, computer, how long are the days on this planet?
    [ Screaming continues ]
    42 hours.
    All right, well, those are the two choices ‘cause cob planet is off the table.
    Now let’s take a vote.
alien newscaster Well, it’s official.
    The obscure planet known as earth, formerly the hiding place of interstellar terrorist and fugitive Rick Sanchez, has just become the 6,048th planet to join the galactic federation.
    The plucky little ball of water and dirt, which is where it gets its name, is dominated by seven billion primate-descended natives who love to eat spaghetti and pray to kangaroos.
female newscaster    Spaghetti, kangaroos? I’ve got to check this place out.
    [ Both laugh ]
alien newscaster    Well, you can.
    Contact the ministry of tourism for details.
    Up next, teenagers are calling it
    [ growls and squeals]
    And it’s not what you think.
morty    What are you... what did you do that for?
summer    Dramatic effect.
rick    Good morning, family.
    Oh, do I smell bacon?
beth    Yes, we discovered a species of tiny pig off the coast of new Australia about 30 yards east. Or 300 yards west.
    We’d offer you some, but we hunted it to extinction for breakfast.
rick    Well, I thought I’d walk to the South pole and do a little bit of exploring.
    If you guys need me, just yell or throw something so hard that it goes around the world and hits me.
jerry    [ Door shuts ] Okay, now that he’s gone, can we please talk about our situation?
morty    Dad, you can’t talk about people behind their back.
    You know, it’s a small world.
jerry    Please, he’s in the South pole!
    And we need to have a serious conversation.
    [ Insects chirping ]
    [ Thunder rumbles ]
    [ Wind howling ]
rick    South pole discovered, baby!
    Ohhhh!
    Oh [Bleep] an ice cave?
    [Bleep]
    Things just keep on getting better.
    Wow, it’s the planet’s core.
jerry    I’m just saying, we keep acting like there’s only two options, but there’s not.
    So, yes, if we went back to earth, as long as Rick was out there, they’d want to interrogate us.
    But, and this is purely hypothetical, what if we turned your father in to the government?
beth    Jerry, so help me God, if you ever bring this up again, no more bacon.
jerry    There already is no more bacon!
    This world sucks!
    Our life sucks!
    Why are we doing this for someone that would never do anything for anyone but himself?
Morty That’s not the point, dad!
    We love Rick... F-for the most part.
Summer Yeah, you don’t love people in hopes of a reward, dad, you love them unconditionally.
beth    That’s very good, kids. I’m proud of you.
jerry    Okay, so let me get this straight.
    For the rest of your lives, no matter how much it hurts you, no matter how much it destroys our children’s futures, we’re gonna do whatever Rick wants, whenever he wants?
All Yes. 
jerry    Why?!
beth    Because I don’t want him to leave again, you dumb asshole!!
rick    Hey. Uh...
    I was gonna hope over to the gloppydrop system, get some ice cream.
morty    You... you want me to come with?
    I mean, don’t you need my brain waves for camouflage or something?
rick    I’ll be okay.
    Bye, Morty.
morty    Rick?
    You’re not leaving, right?
rick    Yeah, I am. To get ice cream.
morty    So, you’re coming back?
rick    Morty, if you go to where there’s a bunch of ice cream and then you don’t come back, you haven’t actually gotten ice cream, you’ve just gone where ice cream is.
morty    Rick, I can handle it if you go, but you’ll break mom’s heart.
    And I won’t forgive you for that.
rick    Where’s the van, Morty?
morty    It’s over the horizon in the driveway.
    [ Engine turns over ]
    ♪ I hurt myself today ♪
    [ dialing ]
    [ Woman speaking gibberish ]
phone    For English, press 2.
    [ Beep] Connecting to agent.
agent     Ongoing investigations.
rick    Uh, hi, my name is Jerry Smith, I’m from planet earth.
    I know the whereabouts of Rick Sanchez, the wanted criminal.
agent    Hold on! [ Ringing ]
gribbles    This is special agent gribbles.
    You have a tip about Rick Sanchez?
rick    Yeah, he kidnapped me and my family, and he left us on dwarf terrace-9.
    He said he was gonna go to the plimplom tavern.
    And listen. 
gribbles    Yes?
    I’m doing what’s right for the galaxy by calling you, so if we come back to earth, can my family have a normal life?
gribbles    We only want Sanchez, sir. Your family will be fine.
rick    Nice. Thank you.
    I’m Jerry Smith, and I love sucking big, sweaty [bleep] And licking disgusting furry testicle sacks.
gribbles    Uh... Okay.
    ♪ What have I become ♪
    ♪ my sweetest friend ♪ ♪ everyone I know ♪ ♪ goes away in the end ♪ ♪ you could have it all ♪
beth    He’s not coming back, is he?
morty    No.
    ♪ My empire of dirt ♪
jerry    Hey, look, cops.
    ♪ I will you down ♪
officer    Good morning.
    ♪ I will make you hurt ♪
customs    How long will you be visiting earth?
jerry    Oh, we live here.
    We were just off-planet for a wedding.
customs    Go that way.
    [ Tires screech, beeping ]
    I have processed that you are in in distress and have proscribed antidepressants.
    Compliments of the galactic federation.
jerry    I feel better.
customs    Your debt is 7,000 fed credits.
    Report to the ministry of employment and you will be assigned a function.
jerry    Honey! I got a job!
    ♪ You could have it all ♪
cyborg    [ monotone ] Sorry, I am not staring at you, I am taking your mug shot.
    ♪ My empire of dirt ♪
    ♪ I will let you down ♪ 

♪ I will make you hurt ♪

prisoner    Hey, what are you in for?
rick    Everything.
    [‘‘Post-Credit Scene’’]
mr. poopybutthole    Hoo-whee, what a cliffhanger.
    Oh, boy, oh, my!
    That’s a real crazy ending, huh?
    Hi, I’m Mr. poopybutthole from episode 204.
    [ Groans ] As you can see, I’m still recovering from the bullet shot that I got from Beth.
    Remember that one? Ooh-whee!
    [ Meowing ]
    Come and get it, kitty.
    You know, these little fellows help me get through the day.
    [ Gulping ]
    Ooh-whee.
    Oh, whoo-whee! Feels better.
    [ Doorbell rings ]
    I got a large pepperoni and some crazy sticks.
    Hey, what did you think of that finale, huh?
    Mm! You think the Smith family is gonna be okay?
    Yeah, I don’t know what you’re talking about, bro.
    Your total is $12.37.
    Whoo-whee! You think Rick’s gonna get out off jail?
    Whoo-whee, you think the family’s gonna rescue him?
    Hey, what the [Bleep]?! Get the [Bleep] off me!
    [ Laughing and saying "ooh-whee!" ]
    Ow!
    Turn in to "Rick and Morty" season three in, like, a year and a half...
    Or longer to see how we unravel this mess.
    Ooh-whee! 
    
    <trailer><name>The Wedding Crashers</name><date>2005</date></trailer>
    </body>
    </text>
</TEI>