<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../../ODD/out/RickandMortyODD.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?><?xml-model href="../../ODD/out/RickandMortyODD.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title>The ABCs of Beth</title>
                <author>Justin Roiland</author>
                <editor>D. Lint</editor>
            </titleStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <p>Digital edition hosted on <ref target="http://rickandmorty.newtfire.org">http://rickandmorty.newtfire.org</ref> and GitHub: <ref target="https://github.com/dorothealint/Rick-and-Morty">https://github.com/dorothealint/Rick-and-Morty</ref></p>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>The ABCs of Beth</title>
                    <date when="2015-"/>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        <encodingDesc>
            <p>Some small changes to the original transcriptions were made including fixed spelling errors and adding names and scene cuts.</p>
        </encodingDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
<sp><speaker>News Anchor</speaker><p>: In local news, child murderer Joseph Eli Lipnip is scheduled to die tomorrow by lethal injection, his execution already drawing dozens more spectators than the death of TV news. Carla?</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Carla Johnson</speaker><p>: The man that once ate his own son </p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Beth</speaker><p>: Wow. He’s really getting executed after all this time. You know the son that he ate was -- </p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Summer</speaker><p>: Your best friend -- Tommy. We know. Stop true-crime bragging.</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Beth</speaker><p>:I was traumatized, Summer. Okay, your generation wouldn’t get that.</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Summer</speaker><p>:  Bitch, my generation gets traumatized for breakfast.</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Beth</speaker><p>:  It took years of therapy to even process the reality. I mean, when I was a kid, I just told myself that Tommy had gotten lost in the magical realm of Froopyland.</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Summer</speaker><p>:"Froopyland?" </p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Beth</speaker><p>: My make-believe world.  I know the name’s stupid, but it was so real to me.</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Rick</speaker><p>:  Aren’t you guys supposed to be at your father’s for custody weekend?</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Morty</speaker><p>:We’re not in a hurry. Dad sleeps until sundown. Can we talk a little bit more about this Froopy--</p></sp>

<stage>[ Zap, bloop ]</stage>
<sp><speaker>Summer</speaker><p>:Not the bubble gun! There’s no air -- </p></sp>

<stage>[ Zap, bloop ]</stage>
<sp><speaker>Beth</speaker><p>:I gotta say, I am warming up to the bubble gun.</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Rick</speaker><p>: You know, if you’re so great at naming things, why don’t you do it from now on? </p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Beth</speaker><p>:-What? </p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Rick</speaker><p>:-Froopyland. Was it my best work? I don’t know. Does it deserve to be shit on creatively? Yeah, that’s right. I agree with your look of horrified realization. You can be very inconsiderate sometimes.</p></sp>

<stage>(cut to garage)</stage>

<sp><speaker>Rick</speaker><p>:[ Rattling ] [ Grunting ] Here it is. You know, I collapsed a quantum tesseract to </p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Beth</speaker><p>: -- Dad, I don’t care how you made it. I want to know if Tommy’s still in there!</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Rick</speaker><p>:  Relax, Beth. (draws door on wall) [ Jingling, crackling)  If he is, we’ll find him. He’ll be the only sun-bleached skeleton with non-imaginary DNA.</p></sp>

<stage>(opening credits)</stage>

<stage>(Froopyland)</stage>

<sp><speaker>Beth</speaker><p>:  Tommy! Tommy! This is a nightmare. I can’t believe you used to lock me up in this glorified chicken coop.</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Rick</speaker><p>:  Chicken coop? Those are procedurally generated clouds, Beth. That river is a rainbow. Literally. Come on, I-I-I put real elbow grease into this place.</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Beth</speaker><p>:  Well, you’re supposed to put elbow grease into your daughter!</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Rick</speaker><p>:Gross.</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Beth</speaker><p>:  Do you think something ate him?</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Rick</speaker><p>: Nope. Froopyland creatures were designed to be harmless. He definitely just starved to death.</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Beth</speaker><p>:  I could have been the one who starved to death in here. What if I’d gotten hurt?</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Rick</speaker><p>:God, you’re right. I’m a terrible dad. Well, nothing to live for. Goodbye, cruel world! (jumps off cliff)</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Beth</speaker><p>: Dad! </p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Rick</speaker><p>:[ Thump ] Oh, how do you like that? What kind of merciless creator makes the ground bouncy? I’m gonna have to drown myself.</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Beth</speaker><p>: [Jumps, Thump ] Unh!</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Rick</speaker><p>:(sticks head in water)  Oh, no. Oh, the water’s breathable? Who went and did that?</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Beth</speaker><p>:Oh, whatever.</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Rick</speaker><p>:Yeah, whatever. A dad makes a toilet look like R2-D2, and it breaks the front page of Reddit, but I’m Charles Manson because I gave you your own world instead of an iPad. I think the words you’re looking for are -- Aah! [Gets grabbed by a raptor. Screeches ] Holy [bleep] [Bleep] This thing has claws!</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Beth</speaker><p>:Yeah, I get it. It’s a childproof world.</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Rick</speaker><p>:   No, no, seriously, this hurts really bad! This thing is sinking razor-sharp claws in -- Aah! [Bleep]</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Beth</speaker><p>: You’ve made your point, Dad. Dad? </p></sp>

    
    <stage>(cut to summer and morty in bubble)</stage>    
    <stage>[ Pop, pop ]</stage>
<sp><speaker>Morty</speaker><p>:Ugh!</p></sp>
<stage>[ Both panting ]</stage>
<sp><speaker>Summer</speaker><p>:   Whose idea was this stupid custody weekend thing?</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Morty</speaker><p>: I think it’s supposed to help prevent abandonment issues.</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Summer</speaker><p>:   I want to be abandoned.</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Morty</speaker><p>:   Yeah, I’m talking about Dad.</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Jerry</speaker><p>:   <stage>[ Door opens ]</stage> Bienvenue a la Chez Divorced Dad.</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Summer</speaker><p>:   Wow, Dad. Your place looks way less like a crackhouse.</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Morty</speaker><p>:  It’s actually clean, like a cocaine house. Dad, what’s going on?</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Jerry</speaker><p>:  I’m simply centered, activated -- <stage>[ Glass clinks, Warble ]</stage></p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Morty</speaker><p>:And telekinetic?</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Jerry</speaker><p>:  Pretty cool, huh? Check it out. Who wants a smoothie? <stage>[ Rattle, Blender whirring ]</stage> Oh -- Oh, no. Uh, oh, God. Summer -- Summer, can you --</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Summer</speaker><p>:-Aah!</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Jerry</speaker><p>:  -Sorry.</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Kiara</speaker><p>:   <stage>[ Warble ]</stage> You have much to learn, my Uloo.</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Jerry</speaker><p>:   Morty, Summer, this is Kiara. She’s a Krootabulan warrior priestess from Krootabulon.</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Morty</speaker><p>:   I-I know where Krootabulans are from, Dad. Uh, Chaimuntolo.</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Kiara</speaker><p>:    Chaimuntolo, younglings.</p></sp>
            
<sp><speaker>Summer</speaker><p>:  Hymencholo.</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Kiara</speaker><p>: Your father’s mind holds love for you. I am humbled to meet in physicality.</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Summer</speaker><p>:   Dad, are you </p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Jerry</speaker><p>:-- In love with a badass, sexy alien lady? Ha, ha, I don’t know, Summer. You tell me.</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Summer</speaker><p>:  I wasn’t going to ask if you were in love since you barely know her.</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Jerry</speaker><p>:   Summer. Kiara and I met on that interstellar dating service Rick was always suggesting when your mom and I were together. And things just kind of clicked.</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Kiara</speaker><p>:   We must move! Our reservation is at 7:00.</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Jerry</speaker><p>:  <stage>[ Whoosh ]</stage> I hate to see her leave, but I love to watch her phase shift away. I’m sure you noticed what she has three of, but guess what she has two of?</p></sp>

    
    
    <stage>(Froopyland)</stage>
<sp><speaker>Rick</speaker><p>:   <stage>[ Screeches ]</stage> Oof! All right, knock it off! Listen, I’ve been giving you a pass because I’m charmed that life finds a way, but -- Aah! All right, you know what? <stage>[ Ray gun fires ]</stage> Ouch! Oh! Unh! Ouch! God! <stage>[ Sizzling ]</stage> Aah! Agh! <stage>[ Arm clicks ]</stage></p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Beth</speaker><p>:  Oh, yeah, this place is the safest.    Best dad ever. Can’t you just say, "I admit it, I screwed up"?</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Rick</speaker><p>:   Uh, what would be the point of that?</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Beth</speaker><p>: <stage>[ Chuckling ]</stage> You can’t do it, can you? You can’t just [bleep] apologize.</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Rick</speaker><p>:   Okay, okay, Beth, I’m sorry you think you deserve an apology. <stage>[raptor Screeches ]</stage> Hey, don’t look at me. You let your kid roll around on the floor of a target, it’s gonna get stepped on. <stage>[raptor Screeches, Whir, zap ]</stage> Huh. Well, here’s the problem right here. We’ve got a bunch of Froopyland procedural carbons all gummed up and mixed in with real human DNA.</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Beth</speaker><p>:  Are you saying Tommy survived here by having sex with Froopy creatures, creating Froopy-human hybrid offspring, and then consuming their proteins, sustaining himself with an endless cycle of cannibalistic incest?</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Rick</speaker><p>:  It’s just a working theory. Of course, if that’s the case, I expect he’d be worshiped as a kind of god by a medieval-level society of his least-delicious children.</p></sp>

<stage>(enter group of Tommy's offspring)</stage>

<sp><speaker>Lead Froopy Creature</speaker><p>:  Halt! You are now prisoners of our exalted ruler, giver and taker of life, helper and consumer of mortality, dispenser of life</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Rick</speaker><p>:-- Yeah, if I could interrupt? We’re way ahead of the reveal here.</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Beth</speaker><p>:  Yeah, just take us to King Tommy.</p></sp>

 
<stage>(cut to restaurant)</stage>

<sp><speaker>Morty</speaker><p>:   I thought warrior priestesses could only leave Krootabulon on a hunt.</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Jerry</speaker><p>:   Mmm. Thank you, sweetie.</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Morty</speaker><p>:   I hope it’s not human season.</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Kiara</speaker><p>:   I’m on Earth hunting the Varrix. I would never hunt a human. Your father and I are soul-bonded.</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Morty</speaker><p>:   Soul-bonded?</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Summer</speaker><p>: Um, does your planet have shorter days, because you guys are moving kind of fast, no?</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Kiara</speaker><p>: Sniff <stage>[ Dramatic music plays, Whoosh, Varrix alien waiter reveal]</stage></p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Jerry</speaker><p>:  Go get him, honey! She’s always hunting. <stage>[ Chuckles ]</stage> She probably knew a Varrix worked here, and that’s why she said the Yelp reviews didn’t matter.</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Morty</speaker><p>:   Dad, do you understand how serious Krootabulon soul-bonding is?</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Jerry</speaker><p>:  Uh, gee, Morty, I don’t know. It’s got such a casual name. If you want to lecture anyone about commitment, start with your mom.</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Summer</speaker><p>:  Oh, my God. Dad, is that what this is about? Are you rushing into a new thing to get back at Mom?</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Jerry</speaker><p>:   Every weekend, you two have told me to move on.</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Summer</speaker><p>:   Move on, like, out of bed. Like, stop using paper towels for toilet paper, not move on into a sloppy rebound.</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Morty</speaker><p>:   Dad, you need to slow down, rethink this soul bond.</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Jerry</speaker><p>:   Why don’t you just say what you really mean? You think it’s cool that having sex with her gives me telekinesis and you recognize she’s got a hot bod like Cheetara in "Thundercats," but you’re grossed out by her avocado-shaped head and blue skin, and you think I want to put a bag and a wig on her head. After all the time and energy I spent teaching you two about race <stage>[ Varrix screams ]</stage> you ended up racist.</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Kiara</speaker><p>:   <stage>[ Whoosh ]</stage> Soon your world will be rid of Varrix. Tomorrow, we celebrate.</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Jerry</speaker><p>:  We could take the kids to the water park.</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Kiara</speaker><p>:   We celebrate with a hunt!</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Jerry</speaker><p>:  Ooh. You kids want to hunt?</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Morty</speaker><p>: -Yes.</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Summer</speaker><p>:  -Yes.</p></sp>



<stage>(Froopyland)</stage>


<stage>[ Trumpet fanfare ]</stage>
<sp><speaker>Offspring creature</speaker><p>:    All kneel for King Tommy!</p></sp>
<sp><speaker>Rick</speaker><p>:  I’m not kneeling. Suck my [bleep]</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Tommy</speaker><p>:   Well, hello, all! I am the King of Froopyland, but I go by another name, too.</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Beth</speaker><p>:   We know.</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Tommy</speaker><p>:   It’s Tommy!</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Beth</speaker><p>: -We know.</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Rick</speaker><p>:   -We know.</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Tommy</speaker><p>:   I have lived here since I was a mere child.</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Beth</speaker><p>:   -We know.</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Rick</speaker><p>:   -Got it.</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Tommy</speaker><p>:   I suppose you’re wondering, how do I sustain myself?</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Rick</speaker><p>:     -Oh, boy.</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Beth</speaker><p>:   -No, we aren’t.</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Tommy</speaker><p>:   I always find the theater is the best way to clarify things.</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Beth</speaker><p>:   -Ugh.</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Rick</speaker><p>:   -Seriously?</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Beth</speaker><p>:  Oh, my God.</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Tommy</speaker><p>:   Players, go!</p></sp>

<stage>(Froopy creatures begin drama)</stage>

<sp><speaker>Little Tommy</speaker><p>:  I am little Tommy.</p></sp>

<stage>[ Crowd cheers ]</stage>

<sp><speaker>Tiny Beth</speaker><p>:   I am tiny Beth.</p></sp>

<stage>[ Crowd boos ]</stage>

<sp><speaker>Beth</speaker><p>:  Oh, come on.</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Tiny Beth</speaker><p>:  Come with me to a magic land.</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Froopy Voice</speaker><p>:Don’t do it!</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Tiny Beth</speaker><p>:  This is my secret Froopyland where I have no rules!</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Little Tommy</speaker><p>:  I am excited.</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Tiny Beth</speaker><p>:  I am jealous of Tommy’s friends and his Nintendo and his dad who likes him.</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Rick</speaker><p>:   I take it Tommy wasn’t class playwright.</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Tiny Beth</speaker><p>:  You want to see the Honey Swamp?</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Little Tommy</speaker><p>:  Yes! Let’s do it!</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Tiny Beth</speaker><p>:  Well, I want to see you dead.</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Little Tommy</speaker><p>:  Ow, help! I’m stuck! I’m covered in honey.</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Rick</speaker><p>:   Huh. Well, that’s interesting.</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Beth</speaker><p>:   Fake news.</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Little Tommy</speaker><p>:  Many nights have passed, trapped in this strange land. I am hungry, and all I can do to pass the time is hump. I will hump this rock. <stage>[ Tapping ]</stage> I will hump this tree. <stage>[ Tapping ]</stage> I will hump this beast of the land and put my seed in it.<stage>[ Tapping ]</stage></p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Little Offspring</speaker><p>: I am the first of Tommy’s children. Eat of my flesh so you may survive.</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Little Tommy</speaker><p>:  And so I did.</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Rick</speaker><p>:   Oh, wow. Okay. Yeah. Certified fresh. Good -- Good job.</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Tommy</speaker><p>:   Perhaps a demonstration is in order.<stage>[ Unzips shorts ]</stage></p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Beth</speaker><p>:   No, that is the last thing that is in order! Ugh. Oh, my God.</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Rick</speaker><p>:   Poor Froopy character. Leave him alone.</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Tommy</speaker><p>:   <stage>[ Shorts zip ]</stage> Ahh. Gather round, gang! <stage>[ Moos ]</stage> Dinner time. <stage>[ Splorch ]</stage></p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Rick</speaker><p>:   All right, that’s it. I’m outta here.</p></sp>

<stage>(draws circle on floor and leaves Froopyland)</stage>
    
<stage>(smith family living room)</stage>

<sp><speaker>Beth</speaker><p>:   What are you doing? We’re in the middle of an adventure.</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Rick</speaker><p>:   Here’s some things an adventure needs, Beth. Conflict, stakes, a way for me to benefit, and, clearly, Morty.</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Beth</speaker><p>:   But Tommy’s still in there, raping Muppets and eating babies.</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Rick</speaker><p>:   Yep. Luckily, that’s not our problem. Time to pull the plug.</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Beth</speaker><p>:   Pull the plug? We have to get Tommy out of there, okay? We -- We need to do the right thing. Do what you never did as a dad -- Put in a little effort.</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Rick</speaker><p>:   All right, cut the high-road routine. We both saw Tommy’s shitty play. You pushed him in the Honey Swamp, Beth. His very happy life is in your hands. You go save him from it.</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Beth</speaker><p>:   <stage>[ Scoffs ]</stage> You’re gonna believe a play over your own daughter?</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Rick</speaker><p>: Yes, I am, Beth, because you’re not my own daughter.</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Beth</speaker><p>:   Oh, God, yes. I’m one of infinite Beths with infinite fathers in infinite universes. It’s called a hug, Dad. It won’t kill you.</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Rick</speaker><p>:   Yeah, don’t be so sure. You know why all Ricks made a Froopyland for all their little girls? Same reason I wasn’t surprised by Tommy’s overwritten, badly structured, cheaply produced flashback. You were a scary [bleep] kid, man.</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Beth</speaker><p>:   <stage>[ Scoffing ]</stage> Oh, my God.</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Rick</speaker><p>:   I didn’t make Froopyland to get rid of you, Beth. I did it to protect the neighborhood. Not in a [burps] noble sense. It was just more practical to sequester you before I had to start, you know, cloning a replacement for every less-than-polite little boy or gullible animal that might cross your socio-path.</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Beth</speaker><p>:   You would rather believe I’m evil than admit that you were a bad father?</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Rick</speaker><p>:  Oh, dude, no. No, bad father all the way to the max over here. I’m a [bleep] nutcase. And the acorn plopped straight down, baby. Look at some of this shit you were asking me to make you as a kid. Ray guns. A whip that forces people to like you. Invisibility cuffs, a parent trap, a lightning gun, a teddy bear with anatomically correct innards, night-vision googly-eye glasses, sound-erasing sneakers, false fingerprints, fall-asleep darts, a lie-detecting doll, an indestructible baseball bat, a Taser shaped like a ladybug, a fake police badge, location-tracking stickers (time = 10:55 <location><geo>-5.243, 47.394</geo></location>, rainbow-colored duct tape, mind-control hair clips, poison gum, a pink, sentient switchblade.</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Pink Sentient Switchblade</speaker><p>:   Hi, Beth, you’ve gotten taller. Shall we resume stabbing?</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Beth</speaker><p>:   Has it occurred to you that I asked you to make those things because I wanted you to spend time with me? Has it occurred to you that if I did try killing Tommy, it might be because I was jealous of his family?</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Rick</speaker><p>:   Wait, what? Why? Wasn’t his dad, like, some kind of cannibal? Seems like it must be hereditary.</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Beth</speaker><p>:   Oh, my God. This is your fault. I am not a bad person. I’m gonna go back in there, I’m getting Tommy, and I’m fixing this!</p></sp>

<stage>(draws door enters Froopyland)</stage>

<sp><speaker>Rick</speaker><p>:   Whatever you say, Stone Cold Steve Austin. <stage>[ Jingling ]</stage> I don’t know why I just said that. Doesn’t make a lot of sense, but gotta stand by it. Whatever you say, Stone Cold Steve Austin. I’m owning it.</p></sp>


<stage>(cuts to hunt)</stage>

<stage>[ Ax swings ]</stage>

<sp><speaker>Morty</speaker><p>:No, Dad! You’re not doing it right! <stage>[ Ax swings ]</stage></p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Jerry</speaker><p>: Cutting off their heads isn’t doing it right?</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Morty</speaker><p>: They’re [grunts] clearly regenerative! I-I think you have to stab them through the heart or something.</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Summer</speaker><p>:  You think or you know? I thought you were the alien expert, Isaac Asi-hole.</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Morty</speaker><p>:  Don’t snap at me! I’m tired!</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Summer</speaker><p>: -Me, too!</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Jerry</speaker><p>: -We’re all tired! <stage>[ Ax swings, Whoosh, Grunts ]</stage></p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Kiara</speaker><p>:  That’s the last of them. Tonight, we celebrate.</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Jerry</speaker><p>:   With a hunt?</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Kiara</speaker><p>: Yes, for tomorrow, we hunt.</p></sp>


<stage>(jerry brings kids back to smith house)</stage>

<sp><speaker>Jerry</speaker><p>:   <stage>[ Rain trickling, Clears throat ]</stage> I, uh, really have to get out of this soul bond.</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Summer</speaker><p>:   -What the [bleep] Dad?</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Morty</speaker><p>:   -Oh, my God! Duh!</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Summer</speaker><p>:   -Obviously!</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Morty</speaker><p>:   -Yeah, no kidding!</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Jerry</speaker><p>: Can you guys help me?</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Morty</speaker><p>:   What? How?</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Jerry</speaker><p>:   Can I just, uh, tell her it’s because of my kids? You know, like, you don’t like the shape of her head, or</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Summer</speaker><p>:   -- That’s you, Dad! That’s you! You’re a baby and an idiot!</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Jerry</speaker><p>:   I think that’s been established, Summer. Now help me!</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Summer</speaker><p>:   First, I want you to admit that you’re a closet racist, a beta-male sexist, and you dragged everyone into a horrible situation by only thinking of yourself.</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Jerry</speaker><p>:  Okay.</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Summer</speaker><p>:  I want to hear you say it.</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Jerry</speaker><p>:  <stage>[ Sighs deeply ]</stage> Look, I’m a closeted racist, and I’m sexist and selfish, and I dragged us all into my sexist, racist bad things because I’m stupid.</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Summer</speaker><p>:   Thank you.</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Jerry</speaker><p>:   Now you’re gonna help me, right?</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Morty</speaker><p>:  She just did.</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Summer</speaker><p>:   Yeah, clean up your own mess.</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Jerry</speaker><p>:   Wait, wait, what? Oh, man.</p></sp>


<stage>(Froopyland)</stage>

<stage>[ Trumpet fanfare ]</stage>

<sp><speaker>Tommy</speaker><p>:All right, everybody. Next item on the docket -- I would like to have sex with some of you, and then eat the babies. <stage>[ Froopys murmuring ]</stage> I thought you’d like that. I do keep rolling out the hits, don’t I? <stage>[ Bang beth slams door open ]</stage> Oh! It’s the Magic Crayon Lady! Are you hungry? I was just about to make dinner. And by "make dinner," I mean</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Beth</speaker><p>:  -- Tommy, I’m going to take you to the real world.</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Tommy</speaker><p>:   Well, this is the real world.</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Beth</speaker><p>:   No, you don’t understand! Your dad -- Uh, people think your dad ate you!</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Tommy</speaker><p>:  So? You doy-oy! People should eat people. Just leave me alone!</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Beth</speaker><p>:   Tommy, you don’t understand. I have to make this right because it’s my fault that you’re in here. I’m Beth.</p></sp>

<stage>[ All gasp ]</stage>

<sp><speaker>Tommy</speaker><p>:    -Beth? -The destroyer! </p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Beth</speaker><p>:   Oh, suck it up, Princess Incest. You fell into some honey.</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Tommy</speaker><p>:   Well, it tends to happen when one is pushed into honey.</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Beth</speaker><p>:   I respect your right to believe I pushed you.</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Tommy</speaker><p>:   Oh, do I get to have that? Is my reality like a little side of fries -- a little Kwanzaa you’re willing to slide my way?</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Beth</speaker><p>:  Yes, because I’m focused on saving your father’s life because I’m not a petty piece of [bleep]</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Tommy</speaker><p>:  So, then, it should be pretty easy to say, "Sorry I pushed you."</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Beth</speaker><p>:   Real easy and not necessary, since you coming home will save your dad’s life whereas nothing is changed by anyone stroking your batshit-crazy ego.</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Tommy</speaker><p>:   Sorry, forgive me. Uh, I’ve been in Froopyland for quite a while. Have apologies changed?</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Beth</speaker><p>:   Tommy, I’m sorry you think you deserve an apology. Oh, my God. I’m my father.</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Tommy</speaker><p>:   Uh, will someone just kill this B-word? </p></sp>

<stage>[ Froopys muttering threateningly ]</stage>

<sp><speaker>Beth</speaker><p>:  [ Grunts ] Hi-ya! Oh, my God. I’m my father! Ya! Ooh! </p></sp>

<stage>[Froopy Screams ]</stage>

<sp><speaker>Pink Sentient Switchblade</speaker><p>:It’s stab time!</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Froopies</speaker><p>: Ooh!</p></sp>

<stage>[Cut to school, School bell rings ]</stage>

<sp><speaker>Math Teacher</speaker><p>: And that’s why one pussy plus two pussies makes a bunch of pussies. Come on, y’all, I’m trying to make this appealing to your sex-addicted lifestyles.</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Jerry</speaker><p>:   Hi, I need to pull Morty out of school. Come on, Morty.</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Bully</speaker><p>:   Ha! You heard your daddy, Morty. you have to leave school. Wait, what are my values?</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Summer</speaker><p>: Dad, what’s going on?</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Jerry</speaker><p>:  We’re going to <location><placeName>Alaska</placeName></location>.</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Morty</speaker><p>:  What? Why?</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Jerry</speaker><p>: It’s nice there. Also, I broke up with Kiara, and she didn’t take it well, and she wants to murder you two.</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Morty</speaker><p>:  What? Th-Then why are we walking?</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Jerry</speaker><p>:I’m walking because I’m tired. You guys should definitely run.</p></sp>

<stage>[Enter Kiara Whoosh ]</stage>

<sp><speaker>Kiara</speaker><p>:   <stage>[ Screams, Thud ]</stage> Excuse me, I just -- You know what? I’m -- I’m just gonna go left. No, okay, your left, that’s fine. Do you know what left is, ‘cause -- Ugh!</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Morty</speaker><p>:  What does your breakup have to do with us? <stage>[ Engine starts ]</stage></p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Summer</speaker><p>:  Yeah, we chose Mom hands down. I thought we made that clear at the lawyer’s office and in the comments under your weird rant on Facebook.</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Jerry</speaker><p>:  <stage>[ Crash, Tires squeal ]</stage> She kind of blames you guys for the breakup.</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Summer</speaker><p>:  -Why?</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Morty</speaker><p>:-Why?</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Jerry</speaker><p>:  Because I told her it was your fault.</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Summer</speaker><p>:  -What?!</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Morty</speaker><p>:-What?!</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Jerry</speaker><p>:  Look, I’m not an evil person. I’m just not very imaginative! <stage>[ Warbling, Grunts, Metal twisting ]</stage> Oh! <stage>[ All scream ]</stage></p></sp>


<sp><speaker>Rick</speaker><p>:Doo-doo butt Doo-doo-doo -- doo-doo butt No. <stage>[ Jingling ]</stage> Doo-doo butt, doo-doo butt</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Beth</speaker><p>:  Hey.</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Rick</speaker><p>:  Hey.</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Beth</speaker><p>:   Um, hmm, so just, like, out of curiosity, if you were gonna make a clone of Tommy, what would you need to get started?</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Rick</speaker><p>:   I don’t kn-- Tommy’s DNA?</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Beth</speaker><p>:  Okay, ‘cause he, um Yeah, he didn’t want to come back, so, um, he gave me this.</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Rick</speaker><p>:   He gave you his finger?</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Beth</speaker><p>:   Uh, well, what happened is</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Rick</speaker><p>: -- It’s okay. It doesn’t matter.</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Beth</speaker><p>:   Okay.</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Rick</speaker><p>:  This’ll take about three hours.</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Beth</speaker><p>:   Okay.</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Rick</speaker><p>:   Hey. You want to help?</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Beth</speaker><p>:  Okay.</p></sp>

<stage>(music while beth and rick make clone of tommy{   Doo I got a doo-doo in my butt Doo-doo-doo-doo And I don’t know what to do With the doo-doo in my butt But I know that a father should say to you That he’s proud of you Doo Every daughter is a doo-doo from a father’s butt Biologically speaking, the butt is a nut And every father fathers wrong Ooh And there isn’t a song That can change that })</stage>
<sp><speaker>Beth</speaker><p>:   I am wiped out.  I guess I’ll turn in.</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Rick</speaker><p>:   Cool.</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Beth</speaker><p>:   Dad? I feel like I’ve spent my life pretending you’re a great guy and trying to be like you. And the ugly truth has always been</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Rick</speaker><p>: -- That I’m not that great a guy and you’re exactly like me.</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Beth</speaker><p>:   Am I evil?</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Rick</speaker><p>: Worse. You’re smart.  When you know nothing matters, the universe is yours. And I’ve never met a universe that was into it. The universe is basically an animal. It grazes on the ordinary. It creates infinite idiots just to eat them, not unlike your friend Timmy.</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Beth</speaker><p>:   Tommy.</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Rick</speaker><p>:   Yeah, it hardly matters now, sweetie. You know, smart people get a chance to climb on top, take reality for a ride, but it’ll never stop trying to throw you. And, eventually, it will. There’s no other way off.</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Beth</speaker><p>:   Dad, I’m out of excuses to not be who I am. So who am I? What do I do?</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Rick</speaker><p>:  My advice -- Take off. Put a saddle on your universe. Let it kick itself out.</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Beth</speaker><p>:   I can’t do that. The kids, Jerry, my job, and, as much as I hate to admit it, ABC’s "The Bachelor." </p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Rick</speaker><p>: I can make a clone of you, a perfect instance of you, with all your memories. An exact copy in every way. It’ll love and provide for the kids, do your job, and consume broadcast-network reality TV on the same allegedly ironic level as you. You could be gone a day, a week, or the rest of your life with zero consequences. The moment you decide to come back, I flip a switch, and the clone’s job is done. It feels no pain, it regrets nothing, and has zero chance of going "Blade Runner."</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Beth</speaker><p>:  If nothing matters, why would you do that for me?</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Rick</speaker><p>:  I don’t know, maybe you matter so little that I like you. Or maybe it makes you matter. Maybe I love you. Maybe something about your mother. Don’t jump a gift shark in the mouth.</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Beth</speaker><p>:  I don’t know if I can do it.</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Rick</speaker><p>:  Then stay, and luxuriate in a life you can finally know you’ve chosen. My secret bonus is that no matter what you choose, you’re finally gonna chill the [bleep] out.</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Beth</speaker><p>:  Okay. I know what I want to do.</p></sp>

    
<stage>(cut to cave)</stage>

<sp><speaker>Kiara</speaker><p>:  <stage>[ Whoosh ]</stage> Aah! <stage>[ Thud ]</stage> Ow! You can’t run forever!</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Summer</speaker><p>:  She’s really pissed off.</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Jerry</speaker><p>:   I know. It’s kinda hot.</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Summer</speaker><p>:  Shut up!</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Varrix</speaker><p>:  The hunters! They’re back! Run!</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Morty</speaker><p>:  -We’re not hunters.</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Summer</speaker><p>:   -We want to hide with you.</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Varrix</speaker><p>:  We’re not hiding. We’re nesting.</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Morty</speaker><p>:  Ooh la la.</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Kiara</speaker><p>:   <stage>[ All scream ]</stage> The children must be destroyed so that we can be together.</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Summer</speaker><p>:   You need to break up with her, Dad -- properly! <stage>[ Whoosh ]</stage> God damn it, Dad! <stage>[ Grunts ]</stage> Dump her!</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Jerry</speaker><p>:   Okay, okay. Kiara, let’s just run away.</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Summer</speaker><p>:  -Dad!</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Morty</speaker><p>:-Come on!</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Summer</speaker><p>:  Just rip the Band-Aid off!</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Jerry</speaker><p>:   Okay! Kiara, when I told you my kids were bigoted racists who were demanding I break up with you, I lied. If anybody deserves to be telekinetically strangled, it’s me. I’m the one who wants to break up. I -- I’m not an evil person. I’m lazy, I’m cowardly, and -- and I do not know what I’m doing. Look, I got someone pregnant at 17. We’re getting a divorce. None of this is on purpose. I was excited to date someone cool because it would make my ex notice me.</p></sp>

 <sp><speaker>Kiara</speaker><p>:  I would expect nothing less from humanity -- a selfish, manipulative, dishonest species that</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Trandor</speaker><p>:-- -Kiara?</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Kiara</speaker><p>:  -Trandor!</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Trandor</speaker><p>:  What are you doing here?</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Kiara</speaker><p>:  Just hunting.</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Trandor</speaker><p>:   Do you really expect me to believe it has nothing to do with us? You knew Earth was my domain.</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Kiara</speaker><p>:   I don’t like what you’re insinuating.</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Summer</speaker><p>:  Dad, can we go now?</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Jerry</speaker><p>:  Hold on a second. I’m starting to get the feeling that I was the rebound.</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Morty</speaker><p>:   Dad, you just got handed an Ex Machina. You’re taking it.</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Trandor</speaker><p>:   Varrix nests spread across 300 galaxies, and you just happened to pick this planet to hunt? That’s Gorgon shit -- total Gorgon shit!</p></sp>


<stage>(Smith house)</stage>

<stage>[ Birds chirping ]</stage> 

<sp><speaker>Summer</speaker><p>: We’re home!</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Beth</speaker><p>: Hey, guys!</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Summer</speaker><p>: What’s for dinner?</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Beth</speaker><p>: How was Jerry’s?</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Summer</speaker><p>:     The usual. Can we have pizza?</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Beth</speaker><p>:  Pizza sounds great.</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Morty</speaker><p>:  Hey, Rick, did you know my dad was dating an alien? No.</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Rick</speaker><p>:  Gross.: For the alien.</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Beth</speaker><p>:  Aw, crap, I think Arnaldo’s is closed. Are you guys sure you want pizza?</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Rick</speaker><p>:   <stage>[ Whoosh ]</stage> Arnaldo’s isn’t closed in the dimension where they didn’t invent Daylight Savings!</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Beth</speaker><p>:  What would we do without you? I love you, Dad.</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Rick</speaker><p>:   Love you, too, sweetie. By the way, that wasn’t time travel. There were just a couple pizzas on the counter. I grabbed them.</p></sp>

<stage>(end credits Post-credit scene)</stage>

<sp><speaker>Kiara</speaker><p>:   [ Beep ] Hey, Jerry, it’s Kiara. Listen, my boyfriend saw those texts you’ve been sending me, and he got pretty pissed off. If he calls you, just ignore him! [ Beep ]</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Carmox</speaker><p>: [ Beep ] This is Carmox. I have intercepted sexual communications between you and my new girlfriend, Kiara. I am coming to kill you now! [ Beep ]</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Rick</speaker><p>:  [ Beep]Yo, Jerry, it’s the Big R. Uh, I killed that alien that was coming after ya. Looking out for ya, buddy. [ Beep ] [ Beep ] Hey, Jerry, it’s Rick. Don’t be mad. I [bleep] your ex-girlfriend Kiara.</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Kiara</speaker><p>:Who are you talking to, Rick? Doesn’t matter.</p></sp>

<sp><speaker>Michael</speaker><p>:Hey, Jerry, this is Michael down at The Antique Phone rentals. Um, I’m gonna go ahead and let you off the hook for the $70 late fee. You can go ahead and keep that answering machine. Nobody really uses those anymore except for exposition on TV shows, anyways.</p></sp>


            <stage>[END]</stage>
            <trailer><name>The ABC's of Death</name><date>2013</date></trailer>
            
            
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>