<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<listBibl><bibl><author><!-- MISSING --></author><title>Omiah's farewell; inscribed to the ladies of London.</title><editor><!-- MISSING --></editor><publisher>printed for G. Kearsly, in Fleet-Street, MDCCLXXVI.</publisher><pubPlace>London</pubPlace><date>1776</date><note>Discussses a native of Otaheitee and is found in the literature section of ECCO.  Talks about tattooing bums (as in butts) in relation to Omai</note></bibl><bibl><author>Alexander, William (d. 1783)</author><title>The history of women, from the earliest antiquity, to the present time; giving some
            account of almost every interesting particular concerning that sex, among all nations,
            ancient and modern. By William Alexander, M.D. In two volumes.</title><editor>London : printed for W. Strahan, and T. Cadell, in the Strand, MDCCLXXIX.
            [1779].</editor><publisher>W. Strahan and T. Cadell</publisher><pubPlace>London</pubPlace><date>1779</date><note>The term Otaheite found references to Otaheite. This helped find a voyage logs of when
            Otaheite was mentioned. Also the date range from 1750-1790 narrowed the search to the
            date range that Captain Wallis's voyages were documented.</note></bibl><bibl><author>Perry, James</author><title>Mimosa: or, The sensitive plant; A poem. Dedicated to Mr. Banks, and addressed to
            Kitt Frederick, Dutchess of Queensberry, Elect.</title><editor/><publisher/><pubPlace>The second edition, with additions. London, 1779. Eighteenth Century Collections
            Online. Gale. University of Pittsburgh Libraries</pubPlace><date> Sep.18, 2013</date><note>It is a poem dedicated to Mr. Banks, and is under the Ecco literature section.</note></bibl><bibl><author>Fitzgerald, Gerald.</author><title>The injured islanders, or the influence of art upon the happiness of nature: a
            poetical epistle from Oberea of Otaheite to Captain Wallis. By the ...</title><editor/><publisher/><pubPlace>Dublin, 1779. Eighteenth Century Collections Online. Gale. University of
            Pittsburgh Libraries. 18 Sept. 2013 </pubPlace><date> Sep. 8, 2013</date><note>It is a poem based off of the journey to Otaheite written for Captain Wallis.  It is under the literature section in Ecco. </note></bibl><bibl><author>Various</author><title>The fugitive miscellany. Being a collection of such fugitive pieces, in prose and
            verse, as are not in any other collection. With many pieces never before published. </title><editor/><publisher/><pubPlace>London</pubPlace><date>1774</date><note>The hit was an epistle written as through it were from Oberea to Joseph Banks. The hit
            for poe was actually poem in the epistle but Otaheite was refered to multiple
            times.  There is also an Epitaph by Dr. Hawkesworth and many other Epitaphs and proses.  It is in the literature section of ECCO.</note></bibl></listBibl>