<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<listBibl><bibl><author/><title>Beauties of nature and art displayed, in a tour through the world; ... Illustrated and embellished with copper plates.</title><editor/><vol>11, 12, 15</vol><publisher>G.Robinson</publisher><pubPlace>London</pubPlace><date>1775</date><note>The text refers to Otaheite multiple times as well as talking about how the Otaheitians made their weapons from the wood of the Etoa tree. It gives descriptions of the types of weapons they made from the wood.</note></bibl><bibl><author>Alexander, William (d. 1783)</author><title>The history of women, from the earliest antiquity, to the present time; giving some account of almost every interesting particular concerning that sex, among all nations, ancient and modern. By William Alexander, M.D. In two volumes.</title><editor>London : printed for W. Strahan, and T. Cadell, in the Strand, MDCCLXXIX. [1779].</editor><vol>1, 2</vol><publisher>W. Strahan and T. Cadell</publisher><pubPlace>London</pubPlace><date>1779</date><note>The term Otaheite found references to Otaheite. This helped find a voyage logs of when Otaheite was mentioned.
            Also the date range from 1750-1790 narrowed the search to the date range that Captain Wallis's voyages were documented.</note></bibl><bibl><author>Adams, John (1750?-1814)</author><title>Modern voyages: containing a variety of useful and entertaining facts, respecting the expeditions and the principal discoveries of Cavendish, Dampier, Monk, Spilbergen, Anson, Byron, Wallis, Carteret, Bougainville Dixon, Portlock, Paterson, and others. Comprehending The most interesting Particulars of Brisson's Narrative of his Shipwreck and Captivity;-The Shipwreck of the Antelope, East India Packet, and a Description of the amiable Inhabitants of the Pelew Islands, never before known to any European;-Also the latest authentic Accounts from Botany Bay;-as well as curious Information from several ingenious Writers and Travellers. For the Amusement and Instruction of Youth of Both Sexes. In two volumes. ... . By the Reverend John Adams, A.M.</title><editor>printed for G. Kearsley, at Johnson's Head, in Fleet Street, MDCCXC. [1790].</editor><vol>1</vol><publisher>G. Kearsley</publisher><pubPlace>London</pubPlace><date>1790</date><note>The term Captain n 10 Wallis found reference to the words Captain and Wallis within 10 characters of each other. This helped find a voyage log of Captain Wallis
            Also the date range from 1750-1790 narrowed the search to the date range that Captain Wallis's voyages were documented.</note></bibl><bibl><author>"missing"</author><title>An Account of the mutinous seizure of the bounty; with the succeeding hardships of the crew. To which are added, secret anecdotes of the Otaheitean females.</title><editor>"missing"</editor><publisher>"missing"</publisher><pubPlace>London</pubPlace><date>1790</date><note>Tootahah, also written Too?ahah, is referenced as one of the natives who served as a guide to Mr. Banks. </note></bibl><bibl><author>NA</author><title>A new, authentic, and complete collection of voyages round the world,
            undertaken and performed by royal authority.</title><editor>NA</editor><publisher>Alex Hogg</publisher><pubPlace>London</pubPlace><date>1784-1786</date><note>The name Kihiargo was used in close relation to the name King George
            as it is also in Book I chapter XIV. This is a good indicator that they
            are actually talking about the same person and would maybe help support
            what we are looking for. Also the use of islanders and Tubourai Tamaide
            were meantioned in the short passage in this search for Kihiargo.
            Tubourai Tamaide was a common name meantioned throughout chapter XIV in
            relation to the funeral and general observations.</note></bibl></listBibl>