<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../schema_v2.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?><?xml-model href="../tv-schematron.sch" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?><root>
    <head>
        <episode>BETRAYAL</episode>
        <writer>Amy Wolfran</writer> 
        <director>Alex Soto</director> 
        <storyboard>Irineo Maramba, Samuel Montes, Scooter Tidwell, Chap Yaep</storyboard>
        <animation>Dongwoo Animation Co. Ltd.</animation>
        <source>https://teentitans.fandom.com/wiki/Betrayal_(Transcript)</source>
    </head>
    <characterList>
        <charList type="recurring" subtype="titan" id="Starfire">Starfire</charList>
        <charList type="recurring" subtype="titan" id="Cyborg">Cyborg</charList>
        <charList type="recurring" subtype="titan" id="Robin">Robin</charList>
        <charList type="recurring" subtype="titan" id="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</charList>
        <charList type="recurring" subtype="titan" id="Raven">Raven</charList>
        <charList type="nonrecurring" subtype="villain" id="Slade">Slade</charList>
        <charList type="recurring" subtype="both" id="Terra">Terra</charList>
    </characterList>
    <locationList>
        <locList id="tower" lat="37.8002" lon="-122.5004">Titan's Tower</locList>
        <locList id="amusement_park" lat="38.1315" lon="-122.2293">Amusement Park in Jump City</locList>
        <locList id="bens_diner" lat="37.7624" lon="-122.4349">Ben's Diner</locList>
        <locList id="city" lat="37.776961" lon="-122.437408">Streets of Jump City</locList>
    </locationList>
    <body>
        <act n="0">
         <title>PROLOGUE</title>

            <sd><setNote shot="yes">Opening shot: a complex of buildings overlooking a rocky ridge.</setNote> It is early evening. Zoom in slowly, then cut to a room inside; a guard falls unconscious to the floor, and several of<char ref="Slade">Slade</char>'s commando robots, one carrying a large canister, walk past him. <setNote shot="yes">Overhead view: many other guards lie knocked out as well. Outside, a section of the wall is blown out and the screen fills with dust, which clears to show the robots making their exit</setNote>.<action mrkr="Robin" with="all" move="1" place="city" timestamp="2004-01-10T00:09:10"/><char ref="Robin">Robin</char>'s birdarang flashes across the screen and smashes away part of the leader's head; cut to a close-up of it in flight and follow it back to the thrower's hand. Pull back to show the original five Titans on the scene.</sd>

<sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr> Tell<char ref="Slade">Slade</char> the Titans have a message for him. <sd>Tilt up;<char ref="Terra">Terra</char> stands on one of several floating boulders.</sd></sp>

<sp><spkr ref="Terra">Terra</spkr> Eat dirt!</sp>

<sd>We see that she has forgone the goggles she used in "Terra" and "Titan Rising." She sends all the spare rocks across the open area and neatly crushes several robots.</sd>

<sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr> Titans! Go!</sp>

            <sd>All six move in,<char ref="Terra">Terra</char> bringing a few more rocks along. She changes positions and lowers the one she was standing on so that<char ref="Robin">Robin</char> can hop aboard. Laser blasts from the surviving robots slash the air, but he swerves expertly around them. Finally, he leaps off; the stone crashes into one shooter, and he delivers a flying kick to another. More shots emerge from farther back, zeroing in on the approaching<action mrkr="Starfire" with="all" move="1" place="city" timestamp="2004-01-10T00:09:10"/><char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char>. She returns fire with her eye beams, tracing a blazing path through three other robots; it explodes after a moment and throws them in all directions.</sd>

            <sd><action mrkr="Raven" with="all" move="1" place="city" timestamp="2004-01-10T00:09:10"/><char ref="Raven">Raven</char>'s turn. She levitates an enormous slab of rock.</sd>

<sp><spkr ref="Raven">Raven</spkr><char ref="Terra">Terra</char>! Catch!</sp>

<sd>She propels the mass at the blonde, who puts her hands up and gets it under control as<char ref="Raven">Raven</char> lets go. Down it comes like a few dozen loads of bricks to crush a knot of robots to pancakes.</sd>

<sp><spkr ref="Terra">Terra</spkr> Thanks a ton.</sp>

<sp><spkr ref="Raven">Raven</spkr> Closer to two tons, actually.</sp>

            <sd>She creates a shield in front of herself; a laser shot immediately blasts it apart and throws her backward. The robot that fired it flies up behind her, using its boot-mounted rockets to stay aloft, and cuts loose with another blast that shatters<char ref="Terra">Terra</char>'s stone platform. She tumbles to the ground and very soon finds herself staring up at a couple of the burglars, but <action mrkr="BeastBoy" with="all" move="1" place="city" timestamp="2004-01-10T00:09:10"/><char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char>, as a large gorilla, jumps down behind her and roars, pounding his chest in fury. Cut to one robot, which gets a huge green smack across the face, then pan to the other just in time for it to receive the same. A third runs toward<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> and is swatted away; a fourth jumps on his back, but he picks it off, slams it to the ground, and throws it against a charging fifth. Finally, he roars, scoops<char ref="Terra">Terra</char> up, and returns to human form.</sd>

<sp><spkr ref="Terra">Terra</spkr> You saved me.</sp>

<sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr> <sd>blushing, hearts in eyes</sd> Yeah. That was cool.</sp>

<sp><spkr ref="Terra">Terra</spkr> Uh,<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char>? You can put me down now. <sd>He comes to his senses with a little yelp and does so, then backs up.</sd></sp>

<sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr> Right. I was just, uh...</sp>

<sd>A robot being thrown past them cuts him off; he gives her a big sheepish grin and runs in the direction it came from. Brief close-up of<char ref="Terra">Terra</char>'s suddenly worried face, then cut to another part of the plain, where<char ref="Robin">Robin</char> and a commando charge at each other. His fighting staff out and at full length, he nails the enemy with a backward flip kick to the chin and swings the weapon to knock away another one when it rushes in. A roar and jump carry him in range to bash a third upside the head, the camera panning to follow. As he lands the blow, there is a brief flicker and click as of a camera shutter snapping. After this, we see him in freeze frame; his name appears on the screen along with a few computer graph readouts.</sd>

            <sd>Cut to<char ref="Raven">Raven</char>, rising higher in the air with a black aura surrounding her body. She forms this into a group of energy streams and hurls them downward; freeze frame just like<char ref="Robin">Robin</char>'s. From here, cut to <action mrkr="Cyborg" with="all" move="1" place="city" timestamp="2004-01-10T00:09:10"/><char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char> running at a commando. He drills it with a killer uppercut, then brings out his sonic cannon and fires in a different direction, and he too is seen in freeze frame. Cut to a group of robots, fleeing from a hail of starbolts, and as smoke pours up from the points of impact,<char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char> flies out of it and hurls another one. Freeze frame. Cut to<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> and pan to follow him as he becomes a bighorn sheep and rams another of the thieves. Freeze frame.</sd>

<sd><setNote shot="yes">Smoke billows up to cover the entire screen. It clears to show a silhouetted figure watching a wall of small monitors; each of the preceding five shots appears several times on them.</setNote> This person's back is to us, but the voice is a dead giveaway.</sd>

<sp><spkr ref="Slade">Slade</spkr> Excellent.</sp>

<sd>Close-up of a desk, panning across the surface. It is littered with notes, books, maps, and Titan equipment; some of<char ref="Robin">Robin</char>'s discs, dismantled communicator, grappling hook, fighting staff.</sd>

<sp><spkr ref="Slade">Slade</spkr> <sd>from o.c.</sd> You've done well. Very well. All your hard work is about to pay off. <sd>Cut to behind him.</sd> Tonight we strike.</sp>

<sd>Pull back a bit to partially frame a second shadowy figure at a distance.</sd>

<sp><spkr ref="Slade">Slade</spkr> And by sunrise tomorrow... <sd>Extreme close-up of a large blue eye; he continues o.c.</sd> ...the Titans will be annihilated.</sp>

<sd>Smoke washes over the screen. Fade to black.</sd>


OPENING THEME
</act>

<act n="1">
<title>ACT ONE</title>

    <sd>Opening shot: the exterior of <location>Titans Tower</location>. It is now later that night. Zoom in slowly, then cut to a litter of dirty dishes and open pizza boxes and zoom in again. A single piece lies in one of the boxes, among a litter of half-eaten fragments. Cut to a blue background, against which panels showing all six Titans' heads are arranged in a circle;<char ref="Terra">Terra</char> is drinking a soda, and <action mrkr="BeastBoy" with="all" move="2" place="tower" timestamp="2004-01-10T00:09:15"/><char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> is back in human form. The slice drops into view, away from the camera, and lands at the center of the screen.</sd>

<sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr> <sd>reaching to it</sd> And the last slice of pizza goes to...</sp>

<sd>He spins it like the pointer on a game wheel as he says this. When it stops, it is pointing at...</sd>

<sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr> ...Terra!</sp>

<sd>It slides behind her panel. She is caught by surprise; assorted reactions from the others.</sd>

<sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr> All right!</sp>

<sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr> Whoooo!</sp>

<sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr> You are the winner!</sp>

<sp><spkr ref="Raven">Raven</spkr> Congratulations.</sp>

<sd>Sight gag: the view changes to the sidelines of a stadium packed with cheering fans.<char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char>, dressed as a sportscaster with microphone in hand, is interviewing the football-uniformed pizza champ, whose jersey sports a large blue T. She holds a trophy topped by a gold slice. Beneath both, an assortment of sports equipment rolls by on a ticker; the occasional T is interspersed with them.</sd>

<sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr> Just a rookie, and already you're an MVP holding the coveted Four-Cheese Trophy.<char ref="Terra">Terra</char>...</sp>

<sd>He points to his right, and the upper-screen view pans away to show an outer-space view of Earth, with a nervously eager face and a complete body attached. A rather disgruntled moon floats in orbit.</sd>

<sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr> <sd>from o.c.</sd> ...the world wants to know. <sd>Pan back to the two.</sd> How does it feel?</sp>

<sp><spkr ref="Terra">Terra</spkr> Um...good...and kinda greasy.</sp>

<sd>The world applauds, as does the crowd. Pull back a bit as<char ref="Robin">Robin</char> and<char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char>, both suited up as<char ref="Terra">Terra</char>'s teammates, hoist her onto their shoulders. Farther back,<char ref="Raven">Raven</char> appears as a reluctant cheerleader and someone in the stands holds up a sign with<char ref="Terra">Terra</char>'s name on it. From the side of<char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char>'s head, a tiny microphone extends on a jointed boom and shifts to each speaker in turn.</sd>

<sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr> Seriously,<char ref="Terra">Terra</char>, great job tonight. We're glad to have you on the team.</sp>

<sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr> And we are most mirthful to claim you as our friend.</sp>

<sp><spkr ref="Raven">Raven</spkr> Yeah. What they say.</sp>

<sd>She gives her pompoms a lackluster shake.<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char>, as a puppy, bounds happily into view and jumps onto<char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char>'s head to lick<char ref="Terra">Terra</char>'s face.</sd>

<sp><spkr ref="Terra">Terra</spkr> <sd>laughing</sd><char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char>...</sp>

<sd>The sight gag ends when the entire view slides up and off the screen to reveal the two of them in the kitchen. He is in human form, seeming a bit embarrassed, and she pushes the scene as if raising a windowpane.</sd>

<sp><spkr ref="Terra">Terra</spkr> Thanks, guys, really, for everything. But you shouldn't, I'm just doing my job, you know? No big deal.</sp>

<sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr> Well, it's a big deal to us. Good friends don't come along every day, you know?</sp>

    <sd>She smiles at this. Cut to <action mrkr="Cyborg" with="all" move="2" place="tower" timestamp="2004-01-10T00:09:30"/><char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char>, approaching the door. A small panel opens up on the wall to reveal a handprint reader pad; he puts a palm to it and brings up a screen that shows schematics of <location>the Tower</location> and assorted systems. Pull back to an overhead shot of the operations center, showing the pizza boxes on the coffee table, as the lights go out. Back to him; he yawns widely.</sd>

<sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr> All right, y'all. <location>Titans Tower</location>'s locked up and <char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char>'s shutting down.</sp>

<sd>He walks out. Cut to<char ref="Terra">Terra</char> and <char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char>; the palm reader and panel close behind them.</sd>

    <sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr> <sd>from o.c.</sd> We should all get some sleep. <sd>Pull back to frame him, <action mrkr="Starfire" with="all" move="2" place="tower" timestamp="2004-01-10T00:09:30"/><char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char> and <action mrkr="Raven" with="all" move="2" place="tower" timestamp="2004-01-10T00:09:30"/><char ref="Raven">Raven</char> by the couch.</sd> We may have stopped<char ref="Slade">Slade</char> tonight, but we need to figure out what he's planning tomorrow.</sp>

<sd>He and the other two girls head for their rooms. Close-up of<char ref="Terra">Terra</char>, suddenly worried.</sd>

<sp><spkr ref="Raven">Raven</spkr> <sd>from o.c.</sd> 'Night.</sp>

<sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr> <sd>from o.c.</sd> Pleasant shlorvaks!</sp>

<sd>The newest Titan wheels away from the camera. Pull back to show her looking at<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char>, who waves to her.</sd>

<sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr> Nighty-night,<char ref="Terra">Terra</char>. <sd>He, too, heads for the hall.</sd></sp>

<sp><spkr ref="Terra">Terra</spkr> <sd>preoccupied</sd> Yeah. See you tomorrow.</sp>

<sd>Dissolve to the exterior of the <location>Tower</location>, zooming in slowly, then cut to<char ref="Terra">Terra</char>'s room. The camera is positioned by the coffee table in front of her couch. A laptop computer sits open on this, next to a lava lamp, and after a moment, she steps into view and sits down at the keyboard. Zoom in slightly as she looks warily over each shoulder to make sure she is alone. She then lets out a huge breath and starts typing; close-up of her gloved fingers on the keys, then of an e-mail SEND button on the screen. The mouse pointer moves to this and clicks it; immediately, there is a loud thumping at the door.<char ref="Terra">Terra</char> gasps and closes the lid of her laptop. When she gets to the door, it opens to reveal<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> in the hall. He smiles broadly.</sd>

<sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr> Hi.</sp>

<sp><spkr ref="Terra">Terra</spkr> Hi.</sp>

<sd>Hearts pop up behind him; for the moment, he can only grin stupidly as a big drop of sweat appears on his temple. Cut to her, then to him, then pull back to frame both: he has still not said a word. After a rather tense silence, she finds a few words and plasters a smile on her face.</sd>

<sp><spkr ref="Terra">Terra</spkr> Okay, well... <sd>waves goodbye</sd> ...nice talking to you.</sp>

<sd>She turns back toward her room. Cut to<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char>, still mute against those hearts, but after a second he yells in surprise and his eyes pop so wide that they could be used for bowling balls. With one hand, he whips out a large, lumpy, badly wrapped package that shimmers in the light.</sd>

<sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr> I kinda...made you something. <sd>She leans out.</sd></sp>

<sp><spkr ref="Terra">Terra</spkr> You did? <sd>She takes the parcel.</sd></sp>

<sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr> Yeah.</sp>

<sd>He laughs a bit and brings out a glue dispenser in his other hand. The leaking adhesive has stuck it fast.</sd>

<sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr> Went a little crazy with the glue gun.</sp>

<sd>He tries to shake it loose, but with no luck, and a vein pops out on his forehead as he thrashes angrily about. Close-up of the package, which she unwraps to reveal a heart-shaped box. She flips the lid open, finding it to be hinged along the heart's upper lobes, and the camera tilts up a bit to show her reflection in a mirror set on its inner surface. A small gasp is followed by a warm smile across her face.</sd>

<sp><spkr ref="Terra">Terra</spkr><char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char>...it's...I don't know what to say. <sd>He leans into view.</sd></sp>

<sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr> You could say yes, 'cause I'm about to ask you out on a date.</sp>

<sp><spkr ref="Terra">Terra</spkr> Oh...wow.</sp>

<sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr> So... <sd>She closes the box.</sd> ...want to do something tomorrow night?</sp>

<sp><spkr ref="Terra">Terra</spkr> Tomorrow...I...I'm sorry,<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char>, I can't.</sp>

<sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr> But--</sp>

<sp><spkr ref="Terra">Terra</spkr> <sd>turning back toward her room</sd> I just can't.</sp>

<sd>The door closes just in time for him to run into it face first; close-up of his stunned, contorted expression, then pull back to show him still standing at the entrance. Pause.</sd>

<sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr> Um...okay...maybe some other time?</sp>

<sd>He hangs his head for a moment, then yells in frustration and pulls on his ears. A vein throbs above one eye.</sd>

<sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr> You idiot!</sp>

<sd>Cut to his hopelessly cluttered room; he yells at his image in the mirror.</sd>

<sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr> How could you mess that up? All you had to do was knock on the door and say...</sp>

<sd>The view changes to the five-second countdown before the start of a movie. It blinks out at 2, and at the proper time the view snaps to a shot of a clapper board: the device used to indicate when actors are to begin a scene. It shows production number 257-330, the actual number for this episode, scene A67, take 1, and the director is listed as Soto. The board snaps and falls away to reveal<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char>, who does a quick twirl and transforms into a bodybuilder like Arnold Schwarzenegger.</sd>

<sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr> Yo,<char ref="Terra">Terra</char>. You, me, movies, Friday?</sp>

<sd>Flash to the clapper: scene A69, take 2. Snap, fall away, and the view has shifted to a moonlit stretch of ocean. The lovestruck Titan, now a debonair Frenchman complete with beret and rose, zips in; he sniffs the flower a moment and then leans to the camera.</sd>

<sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr> <sd>French accent</sd> You are the most beautiful woman I have ever seen.</sp>

<sd>He clamps the stem in his teeth and pops his eyebrows up and down. Flash to the clapper: scene A70, scene 3: snap, fall away to a black screen.<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> walks into view away from the camera. Now he is dressed as a 1950s teenage gang member, with a winged skull on the back of his leather jacket and a ducktail haircut, and he twirls a set of keys as he looks over his shoulder.</sd>

<sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr> You want to go for a ride on my moped?</sp>

<sd>On the end of this, pan slightly to one side and bring up a spotlight to show this vehicle nearby. He presses a button on the keychain, activating the alarm, and we flash to the clapper once more: scene A71, take 4. Snap, fall away, and<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> sits in puppy form against a backdrop of flowers. He wags, barks, and pants happily. Flash to the clapper: scene A72, take 5: snap, fall away, and the rain is now pouring down. He slides into view on his knees, hands clasped pleadingly, eyes wide and full of tears.</sd>

<sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr> Pleeeeeeeeeease?</sp>

<sd>A vein pops out on his temple as he says this. Flash back to him at the mirror.</sd>

<sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr> Anything would've been better than giving her a stupid glue-covered box and acting like a total goober! <sd>He drops to all fours and sobs a bit.</sd> Now she'll never go out with me.</sp>

<sd>The sound of her throat being cleared o.c. shakes him out of his funk. He looks up and voices a shocked yell; cut to his window, outside of which she is standing on a floating rock. Pull back to frame him in the foreground, with a big sweat drop on his temple.</sd>

<sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr> Um...how long have you been standing there?</sp>

<sp><spkr ref="Terra">Terra</spkr> Want to go out?</sp>

<sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr> Huh? <sd>He stands up.</sd> Yeah! I mean...uh...that's cool. <sd>He approaches her.</sd> But why didn't you just knock on my door? <sd>She leans down and holds out one hand.</sd></sp>

<sp><spkr ref="Terra">Terra</spkr> Do you trust me?</sp>

<sd>He gives this a long thought and comes up with a big smile.</sd>

<sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr> More than anyone I've ever met.</sp>

<sd>He takes the proffered hand and is lifted onto the rock. Cut to the exterior of the Tower; the stone, visible only as a black spot from this distance, sails toward <location>Jump City</location>.</sd>

<sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr> <sd>from the stone, fading out</sd> So, you want to catch a late movie?</sp>

<sd>A light comes on in an upper-story window. Cut to the hall, outside a closed door; it opens to reveal<char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char>, the light is in his room, and the camera cuts to a close-up of his midsection. Loud rumbling from his gut, which he covers with one hand, then tilt up to his unsettled face.</sd>

<sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr> Oh, man.</sp>

<sd>He steps out into the hall, letting the door close behind him, and the screen blacks out due to the lost light. Now only the eye implant's red glow marks his progress.</sd>

<sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr> I knew I shouldn't have given up that last slice of pizza.</sp>

<sd>The next illumination is from the kitchen's refrigerator, which he has opened in search of a midnight snack. Close-up; he yawns loudly while rooting around.</sd>

<sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr> Oh, well. <sd>stands and brings out a large hoagie</sd> Nothing a foot-long ham and beef jerky sandwich won't--</sp>

<sd>His face goes slack as he trails off. The reason for this surprise is revealed when the camera cuts to behind him: many of<char ref="Slade">Slade</char>'s commando robots stand on the kitchen counter and glare down at him, having somehow penetrated the Tower's security measures. He turns around; pull back across the floor as still more of the mechanical intruders move to hem him in. Close-up.</sd>

<sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr> <sd>horrified</sd> No.</sp>

<sd>Fade to black.</sd></act>

<act n="2">
<title>ACT TWO</title>
<sd>Opening shot: a pan across the city skyline, quiet under a full moon. Cut to<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> and<char ref="Terra">Terra</char> on an outcropping of stone, well outside the urban center.</sd>

<sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr> When you asked me out, I didn't realize you meant "out of town."</sp>

<sp><spkr ref="Terra">Terra</spkr> Looks cool, doesn't it? <sd>He nods.</sd> Guess sometimes, you have to leave a place to really appreciate it.</sp>

<sd>A few silent seconds pass, during which the wind toys with her hair a bit.</sd>

<sp><spkr ref="Terra">Terra</spkr> You hungry?</sp>

<sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr> Always.</sp>

    <sd>Dissolve to the exterior of <action mrkr="BeastBoy" with="none" move="3" place="bens_diner" timestamp="2004-01-10T00:09:20"/>Ben's, a diner in the city. A big rig rolls past in front; behind its rear end, the view changes to inside the front door. The camera is trained on its upper edge, where a bell is attached to mark entrances and exits. As the door swings open, tilt down to show<char ref="Terra">Terra</char> leading<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> in. He stops at the threshold, eyes widening in mild shock; cut to his perspective; men around a pool table, staring right back at him before resuming their game, and pan to the counter, where his date has already parked herself on a stool.</sd>

<sd>Back to him. After a nervous look around, he walks in and sits by<char ref="Terra">Terra</char>, who is reading the menu. He picks up a copy for himself; cut to his perspective of it, there are pictures of the various platters, all of which contain liberal portions of meat. In between them is the face of a thick-browed man, presumably Ben himself, licking his chops, with a word balloon showing a heart. Needless to say, this is not the sort of cuisine he would prefer. Lowering the menu, he finds both<char ref="Terra">Terra</char> and a waitress looking at him.</sd>

<sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr> Um... <sd>Pull back to frame him.</sd> ...don't suppose you guys have a veggie burger?</sp>

<sd>The waitress gives him a long, funny look as if he had just addressed her in Tagalog.<char ref="Terra">Terra</char> takes the menu from him.</sd>

<sp><spkr ref="Terra">Terra</spkr> We'll just get the usual, Pam.</sp>

<sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr> So, um, I'm guessing you've been here before.</sp>

<sp><spkr ref="Terra">Terra</spkr> I've been everywhere before. <sd>fiddles with her spoon</sd> I was quite the traveler before I became a Titan, remember?</sp>

<sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr> Okay. What's the coolest place you've ever been? <sd>She thinks hard and gazes at the spoon.</sd></sp>

<sp><spkr ref="Terra">Terra</spkr> Don't know. <sd>Close-up of her reflection.</sd> Probably <location>Titans Tower</location>. <sd>Pull back; she brightens and lowers the utensil.</sd> But there's plenty of cool stuff out here. Who knows? If you're really nice to me, maybe I'll give you the tour.</sp>

<sd>Pam, the waitress, brings two plates of food. Close-up as she sets them down: pie a la mode.<char ref="Terra">Terra</char> hands<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> a spoon.</sd>

<sp><spkr ref="Terra">Terra</spkr> Dig in.</sp>

<sd>Taking a bite, he lets off a muffled yelp as his eyes bug out and his hair stands on end. Ever so slowly, he pulls the spoon from his mouth.</sd>

<sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr> <sd>solemnly</sd> This is the greatest pie in the history of pie. <sd>He smiles; cut to her.</sd></sp>

<sp><spkr ref="Terra">Terra</spkr> There's a place about two hundred miles outside of <location>Gotham</location> that bakes a mean cherry.</sp>

<sd>She swivels on her stool to face the mirror behind the counter, and the camera pans slightly to show<char ref="Slade">Slade</char>'s image in the glass. However, she does not notice him straight away.</sd>

<sp><spkr ref="Terra">Terra</spkr> But for apple, this is the best there--</sp>

<sd>Now she sees the masked figure, and her eyes pop as she gasps. Extreme close-up of that left eye, then pull back; she whirls to face the camera. Cut to the men at their pool game and pan to a small counter in the back corner. A couple of other customers sit here, drinking coffee and reading the paper, and there is no sign of<char ref="Slade">Slade</char> anywhere around here. Back to the two teens;<char ref="Terra">Terra</char> is still turned around and staring wide-eyed at nothing,<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char>'s full attention remains on the pie he is wolfing down, and<char ref="Slade">Slade</char>'s image is gone. She darts a few quick glances here and there, puts some coins on the counter to cover the tab, and climbs off her stool to pass<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char>.</sd>

<sp><spkr ref="Terra">Terra</spkr> Let's get outta here. Night's still young.</sp>

<sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr> But, pie!</sp>

<sd>She reaches back into view and seizes his arm; he is whisked out with a surprised yell, dropping his communicator. The camera shifts to point out the door after the pair, the bell jingling as they sail away on a rock, and tilts down to the item on the floor. It comes to life after a moment.</sd>

<sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr> <sd>over comm</sd><char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char>! Come in!</sp>

    <sd>Cut to the exterior of the Tower. All is quiet here, but the mood is soon shattered when the operations center window explodes. Inside,<char ref="Slade">Slade</char>'s android troops advance down the hall with lasers blazing. Pan from them to a piece of rubble, behind which<action mrkr="Robin" with="S C R" move="2" place="tower" timestamp="2004-01-10T00:09:30"/><char ref="Robin">Robin</char> hunches down to use his communicator.</sd>

<sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr><char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char>, where are you? Answer me!</sp>

<sd>A shot strikes the edge of his makeshift bunker and cuts him off. He makes a break for it, dodging a fusillade of blasts, and hurls himself with a yell through a hole blown in the floor. On the story below are more shooters, which he easily dispatches, but a squad of reinforcements soon moves in. Off he goes again.</sd>

<sd>Cut to<char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char> and<char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char>, taking cover around the edge of a doorway. When the right moment comes, they lean out of the room and unleash a double-barreled assault with cannon and starbolts. Pull back as<char ref="Robin">Robin</char> dives through the portal and lands at its opposite edge.</sd>

<sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr> He's not responding.</sp>

<sd>He looks out and catches sight of<char ref="Raven">Raven</char> rising up through the floor.</sd>

<sp><spkr ref="Raven">Raven</spkr> And<char ref="Terra">Terra</char>'s not in her room. <sd>Close-up of<char ref="Robin">Robin</char>, one eyebrow cocked; pan to<char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char> and<char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char>.</sd></sp>

<sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr> Somebody want to explain how two hundred armed robots got past my security?</sp>

<sd>On the end of this line, cut to a contingent of said robots; they advance at a leisurely pace and train a steady stream of fire along the hall. Snap to black, which resolves into a patch of light as<char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char> opens a small hatch and peers toward the camera. Cut to his side of it; inside is a circuit board with a large button. He presses this and is rewarded with a jolt of electricity that makes him yell in pain. The firefight continues unabated.</sd>
    <!-- amp: I'm not marking it for now, but do we want to include an action element if no characters move, but they're no longer with the same characters as before? So like, in this case, Beast Boy is no longer at the Tower, which would change everyone else's @with attribute? -->

<sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr> Can't even access the computer! We're locked out!</sp>

<sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr> They are too numerous to fight! <sd>Long shot of the doorway; she continues from out of sight.</sd> What shall we do? <sd>Cut to<char ref="Robin">Robin</char> and zoom in.</sd></sp>

<sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr> Fight anyway. Titans! Go!</sp>

<sd>All four rush into the hall.<char ref="Robin">Robin</char> catches one robot with a flying kick and decapitates another with a birdarang throw. This buys him only a moment, though; a third aims a punch at him, but he ducks and comes back with an uppercut that nearly lifts the metal soldier clear off its feet. A crushing kick puts it down, after which the camera pans to another group.<char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char> charges at them and punches away one after another, followed by<char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char>, who fares well with both shots and strength. Once she has cleared a bit of room, she takes flight down the hall and strafes the next rank of invaders.</sd>

<sd>In her wake, one is flung across under<char ref="Raven">Raven</char>'s control and crashes into the wall. Cut to the telekinetic Titan, floating above one bunch and slinging them every which way while blocking a shot or two.</sd>

<sp><spkr ref="Raven">Raven</spkr> Azarath Metrion Zinthos!</sp>

<sd>As she chants the spell, black claws grow from the fingers of one hand and shoot straight ahead. They slice through one enemy, sending up sparks as it crashes down, and she glares toward it. Another crew runs toward her from a doorway and the darkness of the hall's other end; her eyes go very wide and then narrow in pure rage.</sd>

<sp><spkr ref="Raven">Raven</spkr> That's my room.</sp>

<sd>She sweeps her hands down, and as the robots get close, two thick sections of the wall come loose and bulldoze them away.</sd>

<sp><spkr ref="Raven">Raven</spkr> Nobody goes in my room.</sp>

<sd>A swing of her arms caves in a long stretch of the floor and sends the survivors down to the story below. Zoom in on one robot as it falls, then continue on to<char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char>, who is in the path of the collapse. He goes down yelling, and a few thousand pounds of rubble crash down on the bunch. The dust clears to show all of them lying prone in the gym below.<char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char> is first to start to his feet with a groan, only to meet a commando rushing at him and swinging a piece of the junk. This blow connects against the big man's head and knocks him into a wall.</sd>

<sd>Cyborg ducks a punch, deals back several more that drive his attacker across the room, and hurls it bodily against the spot he hit a moment ago. In a flash, two more have landed on his back to get him in a headlock; he picks them free and slings them away, only to be jumped by several others. He slams into the wall again.</sd>

<sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr> Don't know how you guys got in, <sd>He dodges a punch.</sd> but I know how you're getting out!</sp>

<sd>Close-up of his right fist, cocked back, and pan to follow it across the short distance to the sound of his yell. It crashes through a robot's solar plexus and drops the thing sparking to the floor. When a different one tries to punch, he clamps a hand on the face and puts all his weight into a throw. Cut to the hall; the robot plows out through this wall and tumbles senseless. Pan to<char ref="Starfire">Starfire</char>, farther down the way, as she throws one member of a group and lets others have it in spades. Fists and starbolts fly everywhere before several reinforcements arrive and dogpile on her. She struggles within the mass of metallic encroachers; cut to an extreme close-up of her blazing eyes and pull back. One beam after another slices through the bunch, followed by a small explosion that hurls them all backward. When the glare subsides, we see her in the clear, still jacked up on fury and adrenaline, but it soon wears off and she passes out from this Herculean exertion.</sd>

<sd>The light in the hall begins to flicker. Cut to a group of survivors, gathered around the canister they stole in the prologue. It is clamped to the wall, and one of them is operating a control panel set in the side. One of<char ref="Robin">Robin</char>'s discs whistles into view and glances off the canister, detonating and throwing the robot backward. Cut to the Titan, staff in one hand, as the invader crashes down before him. Another rushes, but he extends the staff and knocks it down with ease. Its buddy moves in as well and gets the same treatment; for the next one,<char ref="Robin">Robin</char> leaps to the ceiling and brings the staff's end down onto the crown of its head, wrecking it in one blow. Still more troops start after him, and he growls and charges straight at the camera.</sd>

    <sd>When he is just about to collide with it, cut to an overhead view of a roller coaster at an amusement park. A sign identifies this as the <location>Megacoaster</location>, and it is in operation. When the focus shifts to one section of track, the string of cars comes around a bend and thunders past the camera. Cut to a close-up, revealing <action mrkr="BeastBoy" with="none" move="4" place="amusement_park" timestamp="2004-01-10T00:09:25"/><char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> and<char ref="Terra">Terra</char> in the front seat and coming down a steep incline. He has his arms up, but she is positively petrified with fright.</sd>

<sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr> Ya-HOOOOO!!</sp>

<sd>He laughs and whoops exuberantly as the coaster tops another hill and plunges out of sight. Dissolve to the pair on a bench elsewhere in <location>the park</location> and zoom in slowly. He perches on its back; she sits normally and appears very preoccupied.</sd>

<sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr> Yeah! This place is awesome! <sd>Brief pause.</sd></sp>

<sp><spkr ref="Terra">Terra</spkr> Spent a lotta time here when I was on the road. It's the closest thing I've ever had to a home.</sp>

<sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr> You mean, besides <location>Titans Tower</location>.</sp>

<sp><spkr ref="Terra">Terra</spkr> Yeah. So you want to ride the bumper cars, or--? <sd>He sits next to her.</sd></sp>

<sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr><char ref="Terra">Terra</char>, is everything okay?</sp>

<sp><spkr ref="Terra">Terra</spkr> <sd>smiling hugely</sd> Totally! What makes you--?</sp>

<sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr> 'Cause I'm having fun. A-And I really want you to have fun. But if you're not, you know, with me--</sp>

<sp><spkr ref="Terra">Terra</spkr> <sd>thumping his arm</sd><char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char>, you're my definition of fun. <sd>He smiles; she takes his hand and leads him away.</sd> Come on, let's ride some rides.</sp>

<sd>Cut to the bumper car arena. The two Titans zip past each other, after which he doubles back and stops, perplexed. A moment later, she speeds in and knocks him hard enough to send him into the distance, and she raises her fists in triumph. Wipe to a close-up of them spinning past the camera and pull back to show them riding the Tilt-a-Whirl, or Centrifuge, at a speed that would probably be unsafe for any normal person. Inside,<char ref="Terra">Terra</char> raises her fists again, while<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char>'s eyes show just how woozy he has gotten. A surprise turnaround comes when<char ref="Terra">Terra</char>, not he, is the first to go green and clap hands to mouth in order to keep from vomiting. They are swept o.c.</sd>

<sd>A flash, and the view has changed to become a photograph of the two; he stands surprised near the camera, she much farther back. The same transition carries us through the following shots, taken at a photo booth. Second: both flex their muscles, he with forehead vein popping. Third: she laughs as he hangs upside down, tongue hanging out and eyes rolling crazily. Fourth: they have traded positions, and he is now picking his nose. Fifth: he has become a puppy for her to hug. Sixth: she screams and cowers before his Frankenstein's-monster advance. Seventh, she lands an uppercut that launches him upward and out of frame. Eighth: he has come down, face badly bashed up from the punch, and she is distressed at the sight. Ninth: she winks at the camera, while he has a thermometer in his mouth, a big lump on his forehead, and a bandage on his cheek. Tenth: both yell dementedly at the camera, mouths open wide.</sd>

<sd>Flash to a slow pan through the Chamber of Horrors; a graveyard scenario at night, with red eyes flashing in the darkness.<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> and<char ref="Terra">Terra</char> ride through it; she is quite at ease, he much less so. They pass a dark patch, after which the camera cuts to a close-up. On his side, a group of ghosts pops up, followed by a few spiders and a skull on hers, then a collection of monsters all around. Each display causes him to freak out, but she just smiles and laughs at his overreaction. After the third, he seems utterly spent; a bit of drool oozes out of his mouth and he leans against her shoulder. Zoom in as she blushes a bit.</sd>

<sd>Dissolve to them running in place on a small, spinning planet, then tilt down slightly as it becomes a thrown baseball. A flash, and it has knocked over a stack of cans in a game booth.<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> has made the throw, eliciting cheers from<char ref="Terra">Terra</char>; next, she grabs a ball and lets fly at a second stack. Her throw is a bit weak, though, it just dribbles out of her hand, and he gives her a condescending smile. Another flash marks his next throw, which plows into those cans and gets her cheering again. She gives him a hug with enough force to squeeze a tear from his eye, complete with a tiny copy of his face. It retracts as she loosens her grip, and both laugh.</sd>

<sd>Tilt up from them to the night sky. A bottle rocket blasts into view and explodes, followed by additional bursts of fireworks. From here, dissolve to<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> and<char ref="Terra">Terra</char> taking a stroll. As they look up, she links her arm through his; the move catches him off guard, but he quickly smiles again. Long shot of the area, pulling back slowly; fireworks, games, tents, the Big Wheel. This is a Ferris wheel, toward which they are heading.</sd>

[Note: Except for the background music, there is no audio for the preceding five paragraphs.]

<sd>Dissolve to them in one of the cars. Her mind again seems to be on other things as he slides a bit closer.</sd>

<sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr> So, what made you change your mind?</sp>

<sp><spkr ref="Terra">Terra</spkr> Excuse me?</sp>

<sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr> About going out with me. It was the ears, wasn't it? Ladies love the pointy ears. <sd>She laughs a bit.</sd></sp>

<sp><spkr ref="Terra">Terra</spkr> Actually, it was because...of all the things I could've done tonight, I realized all I really wanted to do was spend time with you.</sp>

<sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr> Lucky for me, you didn't have other plans.</sp>

<sp><spkr ref="Terra">Terra</spkr><char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char>, if you knew something bad about me, would you still be my friend?</sp>

<sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr> <sd>now a bit wary</sd> Of course.</sp>

<sp><spkr ref="Terra">Terra</spkr> I mean, if you were really my friend, I could tell you anything. And no matter how horrible it was, you'd still like me, right?</sp>

<sd>Close-up of him. In the far corner behind him, a silhouetted figure is partially visible: it was not there when this sequence began.</sd>

<sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr> Yes. I promise,<char ref="Terra">Terra</char>. <sd>Moves toward her.</sd> No matter what.</sp>

<sd>When he shifts position, the third individual is revealed to have only one eye, the left; it can only be<char ref="Slade">Slade</char>, but he does not notice. Cut to the two teens;<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> concentrates on getting close enough to<char ref="Terra">Terra</char> to kiss her, but the next words end the romance in a very big hurry.</sd>

<sp><spkr ref="Slade">Slade</spkr> <sd>from o.c.</sd> Hello,<char ref="Terra">Terra</char>. <sd>She gasps softly; cut to him.</sd> Remember me?</sp>

<sd>He stands up into the light. Fade to black.</sd></act>

<act n="3">
<title>ACT THREE</title>

<sd>Opening shot:<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> and<char ref="Terra">Terra</char>, backed as far across the seat as they can get.<char ref="Slade">Slade</char> steps into view and heaves him aside like a pile of dirty laundry; the young man bangs into the car door, and the camera cuts to outside as it falls away. He is left hanging by his fingertips while the Big Wheel slowly rotates.</sd>

<sp><spkr ref="Slade">Slade</spkr> <sd>looking toward<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char></sd> I have plans for you,<char ref="Terra">Terra</char>. <sd>He turns to her.</sd> Did you think you and your little boyfriend could just run away?</sp>

<sd>Pan to frame said boyfriend, now back inside.</sd>

<sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr> Let her go!</sp>

<sd>He becomes a velociraptor, eyes<char ref="Slade">Slade</char> for a moment, and lunges with a screeching roar. Both tumble o.c.</sd>

<sp><spkr ref="Terra">Terra</spkr><char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char>!</sp>

<sd>He is back in human form and has knocked<char ref="Slade">Slade</char> onto the top of the next car.</sd>

<sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr><char ref="Terra">Terra</char>! Run!</sp>

<sp><spkr ref="Slade">Slade</spkr> Stay where you are, child.</sp>

<sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr> What do you want with her?</sp>

<sp><spkr ref="Slade">Slade</spkr> You mean she didn't tell you? I thought you two were friends</sp>

<sd>He flips the shape-changer over the edge, then gets himself upright and looks down. The cry of a falcon interrupts him, pull back to show a big green one rising. It becomes a tiger and lands next to<char ref="Slade">Slade</char>, who brings out his fighting staff. The adversaries circle carefully in the tight space; finally,<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> leaps, but<char ref="Slade">Slade</char> blocks the attack and, after some seconds of struggle, thrusts him into empty space. Looking down, he finds one Titan in the first car and the other, back in human form, hanging off its roof.</sd>

<sd>Terra gasps sharply as both look up; here comes<char ref="Slade">Slade</char>, leaping down at<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char>. The latter dodges a roundhouse staff swing and jumps backward to end up clinging to the rear exterior. His teeth grind in a silent snarl; cut to<char ref="Slade">Slade</char>, stepping toward that edge, only to find a gorilla climbing up to face him. A bellowing roar escapes<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char>'s lips as he advances on the enemy, who backs up until he drops over the edge.</sd>

<sd>The big green ape follows suit and begins to chase him all over the Big Wheel, roof to roof, up the framework and sign, back onto an upper car. Here,<char ref="Slade">Slade</char> puts<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> in a headlock.</sd>

<sp><spkr ref="Slade">Slade</spkr> You think you know her. You know nothing. She never even liked you.</sp>

<sd>Zoom in on<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char>'s eyes as they go wide with surprise. He then plucks<char ref="Slade">Slade</char> off, slams him onto the metal surface, and throws him overboard. Behind him,<char ref="Terra">Terra</char> rises into view on a rock; her expression reveals just how much of a strain this night has turned into for her.</sd>

<sp><spkr ref="Terra">Terra</spkr><char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char>, come on!</sp>

<sd>He does not move or speak. As the ride turns, another car is carried down on the far side, and<char ref="Slade">Slade</char> is standing atop it. Her eyes widen as<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> turns into a screeching baboon and leaps across the space. The impact throws<char ref="Slade">Slade</char> off to land on a different car, but he quickly recovers and bounds to the framework with the green primate in hot pursuit.<char ref="Terra">Terra</char> watches, horrified, as the two struggle and<char ref="Slade">Slade</char> gets the upper hand. Back in human form,<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> is pinned down.</sd>

<sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr><char ref="Terra">Terra</char>!</sp>

<sd>Yelling, she backs higher into the air and spreads her arms wide. Cut to ground level, where a large fissure opens, and tilt up slightly to show it racing toward the Big Wheel. The supports start to buckle.</sd>

<sp><spkr ref="Terra">Terra</spkr><char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char>! Fly!</sp>

<sd>Close-up of his face, then cut to<char ref="Slade">Slade</char> as a little green bird flutters up and out of his grasp.</sd>

<sp><spkr ref="Slade">Slade</spkr><char ref="Terra">Terra</char>! No!</sp>

<sd>Those two words throw a bit of fear into her, but she does not alter her stance or stop her seismic assault on the Big Wheel. The entire structure collapses in a roiling dust cloud that quickly envelops her. Cut to ground level; she and<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char>, in human form, run from the destruction and stop at the entrance to the House of Mirrors for a second before entering.</sd>

<sd>Inside, they advance into the darkness and o.c.; after they are gone,<char ref="Slade">Slade</char> steps to the entrance. Cut to another area, where many reflections of each Titan cross the screen, followed by the two real McCoys after a moment. The same thing happens around a bend, after which they stop in a large chamber. He reaches into his belt for something but does not find it.</sd>

<sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr> I lost my communicator! Gimme yours!</sp>

<sp><spkr ref="Terra">Terra</spkr> I don't have it.</sp>

<sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr> Then we've gotta get back to <location>the Tower</location> and...</sp>

<sp><spkr ref="Terra">Terra</spkr><char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char>, I'm not going back. I can't.</sp>

<sd>The patch of hair above her right ear, formerly held back by her butterfly clip, slides forward to cover that side of her face on the end of this. She dips her head and closes her eyes.</sd>

<sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr> What? Why can't you?</sp>

<sp><spkr ref="Slade">Slade</spkr> <sd>from o.c., echoing</sd> Because she's not your friend. <sd>His image appears in the mirrors.</sd> She's my apprentice.</sp>

<sd>Those last three words explain the early events of this episode. She collected the data on the other five Titans for<char ref="Slade">Slade</char> to analyze; the equipment on his desk was purloined by her; the dismantled communicator was hers, as was the blue eye seen in shadow; the e-mail she sent was to<char ref="Slade">Slade</char>.<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> instantly gets his dander up at seeing that masked visage all around him. He steps here and there, inspecting the reflections;<char ref="Terra">Terra</char> has gone. All of<char ref="Slade">Slade</char>'s following lines echo as did the previous one.</sd>

<sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr><char ref="Terra">Terra</char>?<char ref="Terra">Terra</char>!</sp>

<sp><spkr ref="Slade">Slade</spkr> The girl you knew was merely an illusion. A fantasy. In reality, she's been working for me.</sp>

<sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr> That's a lie!</sp>

<sd>He rushes over and shatters a mirror with one punch.</sd>

<sp><spkr ref="Slade">Slade</spkr> I found her. <sd>Smash.</sd> I trained her to control her impressive powers. <sd>Smash.</sd> And then I sent her to destroy your little T... <sd>Smash; extreme close-up of his eye.</sd> ...from the inside out.</sp>

<sd>This image, too, is shattered. Now<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> backs away; all the mirrors we can see behind him have been broken and gone blank.</sd>

<sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr> No!<char ref="Terra">Terra</char> would never--</sp>

<sd>Cut to behind him. A single pane is intact and still showing<char ref="Slade">Slade</char>'s figure.</sd>

<sp><spkr ref="Slade">Slade</spkr> Tonight, her orders were to strike. But I guess she took pity on you. <sd>Close-up; zoom in on his eye and pan a bit.</sd> Perhaps she wanted to keep you as a pet. However, despite this minor error in judgment... <sd>Cut to<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char>; he continues o.c.</sd> ...she was kind enough to deactivate the security at <location>Titans Tower</location>. Your friends are being annihilated as we speak.</sp>

<sd>That next-to-last sentence explains how all those robots got in; the last one works the Titan's last good nerve.</sd>

<sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr> Liar!</sp>

<sp><spkr ref="Terra">Terra</spkr> <sd>from o.c.</sd><char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char>...it's the truth.</sp>

<sd>Cut to the master and apprentice. The one unbroken mirror has slid away, and they are standing in its place.<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> takes a fumbling step toward them, his whole face going slack and his eyes staring in disbelief.</sd>

<sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr><char ref="Terra">Terra</char>...why?</sp>

<sp><spkr ref="Slade">Slade</spkr> Because you could never give her what she needs.</sp>

<sd>With a primal scream, the changeling becomes a tiger and charges at the pair.<char ref="Terra">Terra</char> ducks out of the way as<char ref="Slade">Slade</char> grabs him out of the air and throws him past the mirrors. In this dark space, a roar from<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> is answered with the leveled muzzle of<char ref="Slade">Slade</char>'s blaster; he carries one just like those of his robots. The shot drops the Titan to the floor, unconscious and back in human form, and<char ref="Slade">Slade</char> steps close to deliver a point-blank kill shot. Behind him,<char ref="Terra">Terra</char> moves up and gasps in surprise;<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> moans weakly and she gets her hands ready.</sd>

<sp><spkr ref="Terra">Terra</spkr> No! I won't let you hurt my friend! <sd>Close-up of<char ref="Slade">Slade</char>.</sd></sp>

<sp><spkr ref="Slade">Slade</spkr> Dear child, you don't have any friends.</sp>

<sd>A very large shadow falls over him; pull back to frame<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char>, on his feet as a bear with one paw raised to strike. The claws send<char ref="Slade">Slade</char> to the floor and knock his blaster away, and the ursine Titan goes after him as<char ref="Terra">Terra</char> backs off. When the masked villain stands up again, fresh gouges are visible on his armor and mask.<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> pins him, at which point the focus shifts to<char ref="Terra">Terra</char> in the background; she turns and runs through the opening in the mirror wall.</sd>

<sd>Cut to her, sprinting as she did when that giant scorpion tried to capture her in "Terra". She stops at another reflective wall, catches full sight of herself with a gasp, and backs away slowly. More images of the slim blonde appear in the glass sheets: a multiplicity of shocked, speechless, hopelessly confused<char ref="Terra">Terra</char>s staring every which way. Cut to just in front of her and rotate to show all the mirrors; her reflections are now huge and distorted, and they collapse as she does.</sd>

<sp><spkr ref="Terra">Terra</spkr> <sd>sobbing</sd><char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char>, I'm sorry. I'm so sorry. I never meant for any of this to happen. <sd>He moves partially into view near the camera.</sd></sp>

<sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr> <sd>from o.c.</sd> Then why did you let it? <sd>She stands up.</sd></sp>

<sp><spkr ref="Terra">Terra</spkr> I don't know, okay? I don't know.</sp>

<sd>As she continues, the view shifts to frame her in a spotlight against a totally dark room. A second spot it halfway in view to her right.</sd>

<sp><spkr ref="Terra">Terra</spkr><char ref="Slade">Slade</char>...he helped me, saved me from myself. <sd>Pan to frame<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char> in the other spot; she continues o.c.</sd> He said I owed him, but--</sp>

<sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr> So it was all a game? You were just pretending? <sd>Cut to frame both.</sd></sp>

<sp><spkr ref="Terra">Terra</spkr> <sd>steps to him</sd> No. You said you'd be my friend no matter what, remember?</sp>

<sd>She reaches out to touch his shoulder, but he gives her the hardest glare he can and turns away.</sd>

<sp><spkr ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</spkr><char ref="Slade">Slade</char> was right. You don't have any friends.</sp>

<sd>That jab hits her like a two-by-four upside the head.</sd>

<sp><spkr ref="Slade">Slade</spkr> <sd>from o.c.</sd> Apprentice. <sd>She backs up.</sd> Come.</sp>

<sd>Pull back to frame him, standing just behind her. She bows her head and closes her eyes.</sd>

<sp><spkr ref="Slade">Slade</spkr> We've had a change of plans.</sp>

<sd>Her eyes open as her whole face rearranges itself into an expression of sullen hatred. She and her new master slowly retreat into a shadowy niche; cut to<char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char>, his back to us, and pull back slowly.</sd>

<sd>Dissolve to the exterior of <location>the Tower</location>. It is now the next day, and the place looks like a hundred miles of bad road thanks to the onslaught of<char ref="Slade">Slade</char>'s robots. Cut to a slow pan across the ravaged entrance hall; metal body parts lie among the smashed armchairs and smoking debris.</sd>

<sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr> <sd>voice over</sd> Well...looks like we won.</sp>

<sd>In the cluttered stairwell, a robot sprawls on the landing. Pull back slowly.</sd>

<sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr> <sd>voice over</sd> Then why does it not feel like a victory?</sp>

<sd>The ceiling of the gym. An arm hangs down limply; tilt down from here to frame all the wreckage and broken fighters.</sd>

<sp><spkr ref="Raven">Raven</spkr> <sd>voice over</sd> I knew it. I knew it! We never should have trusted her.</sp>

<sd>Pan across the garage, in which a large pile of robots has accumulated.</sd>

<sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr> <sd>voice over</sd> But we did. We all did.</sp>

<sd>Overhead view of the operations center, zooming in on these four Titans. They are gathered where the couch and coffee table used to be;<char ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</char> works a few controls on his forearm.</sd>

<sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr> I've regained access to the computer. Security codes and encryption strings have all been reset.</sp>

<sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr> And all enemy surveillance technology has been located and destroyed.</sp>

<sp><spkr ref="Raven">Raven</spkr> Problem is,<char ref="Terra">Terra</char> gave<char ref="Slade">Slade</char> more than secret codes and hidden cameras. She gave him us. Our flaws, our weaknesses, everything he'd ever need to know.</sp>

<sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr> It doesn't matter. When<char ref="Slade">Slade</char> makes his next move, we'll be ready.</sp>

<sd>Dissolve to a slow pan across<char ref="Terra">Terra</char>'s trashed room. Something is on her bed.</sd>

<sp><spkr ref="Cyborg">Cyborg</spkr> <sd>voice over</sd> And <char ref="BeastBoy">Beast Boy</char>?</sp>

<sp><spkr ref="Starfire">Starfire</spkr> <sd>voice over</sd> He will be all right?</sp>

    <sd>On these last two words, dissolve to a close-up of the bed and pull back slowly. <action mrkr="BeastBoy" with="all" move="5" place="tower" timestamp="2004-01-10T00:09:30"/>The heartbroken Titan is curled up on the blankets as a large, melancholy dog, and the box he gave<char ref="Terra">Terra</char> lies next to him.</sd>

<sp><spkr ref="Robin">Robin</spkr> <sd>voice over</sd> He just needs a little time.</sp>

<sd>Dissolve to just outside the room's closed door and pull back slowly across the hall. Soft whimpering is heard from inside before the view fades to black.</sd>
</act>
    </body>
    
</root>