<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="STS.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?><xml>
    <sts stsNum="009">STS-9</sts>
    <mission type="spacelabConstruct" org="nasa">Mission: Orbital Laboratory and Observations Platform/First Spacelab Mission/First Rollback/First 6 Crew Member Flight</mission>
    <orbiter oName="columbia">Space Shuttle: Columbia</orbiter>
    <launchPad sBase="kennedySpaceCenter" padNum="39A">Launch Pad: 39A</launchPad>
    <launch sDateTime="1983-11-28T11:00:00">Launched: November 28, 1983 at 11:00:00 a.m. EST</launch>
    <landPad eBase="edwardsAirForceBase">Landing Site: Edwards Air Force Base, Calif.</landPad>
    <land eDateTime="1983-12-08T03:47:24">Landing: December 8, 1983 at 3:47:24 a.m. PST</land>
    <duration time="P10DT7H47M24S">Mission Duration: 10 days, 7 hours, 47 minutes and 24 seconds</duration>
    <altitude alt="155">Orbit Altitude: 155 nautical miles</altitude>
    <inclination deg="57">Orbit Inclination: 57 degrees</inclination>
    
    <desc cargo="spacelab-1">This flight carried first Spacelab mission and first astronaut to represent the European Space Agency (ESA), Ulf Merbold of Germany. ESA and NASA jointly sponsored the Spacelab-1 and conducted investigations which demonstrated the capability for advanced research in space. Spacelab is an orbital laboratory and contains an observations platform composed of cylindrical pressurized modules and U-shaped unpressurized pallets which remain in the orbiter's cargo bay during flight. Altogether 73 separate investigations were carried out in astronomy and physics, atmospheric physics, Earth observations, life sciences, materials sciences, space plasma physics and technology. This was the first time six persons were carried into space on a single vehicle.
    
    Crew consisted of Commander John W. Young, Pilot Brewster H. Shaw Jr., Mission Specialists Owen K. Garriott, Robert A. R. Parker and Payload Specialists Byron K. Lichtenberg and Ulf Merbold of the European Space Agency.</desc>
    
    
</xml>