<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="STS.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?><xml>
    <sts stsNum="004">STS-4</sts>
    <mission type="test" org="dod">Mission: Department of Defense/Continuous Flow Electrophoresis System (CFES)</mission>
    <orbiter oName="columbia">Space Shuttle: Columbia</orbiter>
    <launchPad sBase="kennedySpaceCenter" padNum="39A">Launch Pad: 39A</launchPad>
    <launch sDateTime="1982-06-27T11:00:00">Launched: June 27, 1982 at 11:00:00 a.m. EDT</launch>
    <landPad eBase="edwardsAirForceBase">Landing Site: Edwards Air Force Base, Calif.</landPad>
    <land eDateTime="1982-07-04T09:09:31">Landing: July 4, 1982 at 9:09:31 a.m. PDT</land>
    <duration time="P7DT1H9M31S">Mission Duration: 7 days, 1 hour, 9 minutes and 31 seconds</duration>
    <altitude alt="197">Orbit Altitude: 197 nautical miles</altitude>
    <inclination deg="28.5">Orbit Inclination: 28.5 degrees</inclination>
    
    <desc cargo="experiments">The Final Space Transportation System research and development flight. In addition to classified Department of Defense payload, cargo included first Get Away Specials, (G-001) which contained nine experiments from Utah State University; first commercial experiment involving Continuous Flow Electrophoresis System (CFES); Monodisperse Latex Reactor (MLR); Induced Environment Contamination Monitor (IECM), which was deployed, and two Shuttle Student Involvement Program (SSIP) experiments. Crew performed medical experiments on themselves for two student projects, operated remote manipulator arm to swing IECM around orbiter, and took photos of lightning activity in Earth's atmosphere. Two solid rocket booster casings were lost when main parachutes failed and they impacted the water and sank. Some rainwater penetrated protective coating of several tiles while orbiter on pad. On orbit, affected area turned toward sun and water vaporized, preventing further tile damage from freezing water.
    
        Crew consisted of Commander Thomas K. Mattingly II and Pilot Henry W. Hartsfield, Jr.</desc>
</xml>