<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="STS.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?><xml>
    <sts stsNum="064">STS-64</sts>
    <mission type="science" org="nasa">Mission: LITE; SPARTAN-201</mission>
    <orbiter oName="discovery">Space Shuttle: Discovery</orbiter>
    <launchPad sBase="kennedySpaceCenter" padNum="39B">Launch Pad: 39B</launchPad>
    <launch sDateTime="1994-09-09T18:22:55">Launched: September 9, 1994, 6:22:55 p.m. EDT</launch>
    <landPad eBase="edwardsAirForceBase">Landing Site: Edwards Air Force Base, Calif.</landPad>
    <land eDateTime="1994-09-20T17:12:52">Landing: September 20, 1994, 5:12:52 p.m. EDT</land>
    <duration time="P10DT22H49M57S">Mission Duration: 10 days, 22 hours, 49 minutes, 57 seconds</duration>
    <altitude alt="140">Orbit Altitude: 140 nautical miles</altitude>
    <inclination deg="57">Orbit Inclination: 57 degrees</inclination>
    
    <desc cargo="LITE">STS-64 marked first flight of Lidar In-space Technology Experiment (LITE) and first untethered U.S. extravehicular activity (EVA) in 10 years. LITE payload employs lidar, which stands for light detection and ranging, a type of optical radar using laser pulses instead of radio waves to study Earth's atmosphere. First spaceflight of lidar was highly successful technology test. LITE instrument operated for 53 hours, yielding more than 43 hours of high-rate data. Unprecedented views were obtained of cloud structures, storm systems, dust clouds, pollutants, forest burning and surface reflectance. Sites studied included atmosphere above northern Europe, Indonesia and the south Pacific, Russia and Africa. Sixty-five groups from 20 countries are making validation measurements with ground-based and aircraft instruments to verify LITE data. LITE science program is part of NASA's Mission to Planet Earth.
    Mission Specialists Lee and Meade completed the 28th EVA of the Space Shuttle Program on Sept. 16. During six-hour, 15-minute EVA, they tested new backpack called Simplified Aid for EVA Rescue (SAFER), designed for use in event crew member becomes untethered while conducting an EVA.
    
    Crew consisted of Commander Richard N. Richards, Pilot L. Blaine Hammond Jr., Mission Specialists Jerry M. Linenger, Susan J. Helms, Carl J. Meade and Mark C. Lee.</desc>
    
</xml>