<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="STS.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?><xml>
    <sts stsNum="076">STS-76</sts>
    <mission type="science" org="nasa">Mission: Third Shuttle-Mir Docking; SPACEHAB</mission>
    <orbiter oName="atlantis">Space Shuttle: Atlantis</orbiter>
    <launchPad sBase="kennedySpaceCenter" padNum="39B">Launch Pad: 39B</launchPad>
    <launch sDateTime="1996-03-22T03:13:04">Launched: March 22, 1996, 3:13:04 a.m. EST</launch>
    <landPad eBase="edwardsAirForceBase">Landing Site: Edwards Air Force Base, Calif.</landPad>
    <land eDateTime="1996-03-31T05:28:57">Landing: March 31, 1996, 5:28:57 a.m. PST</land>
    <duration time="P9DT5H15M53S">Mission Duration: 9 days, 5 hours, 15 minutes, 53 seconds</duration>
    <altitude alt="160">Orbit Altitude: 160 nautical miles</altitude>
    <inclination deg="56.1">Orbit Inclination: 56.1 degrees</inclination>
    
    <desc cargo="SPACEHAB">Third linkup between U.S. space shuttle and Russian Space Station Mir highlighted by transfer of veteran astronaut Shannon Lucid to Mir to become first American woman to live on station. Her approximately four-and-a-half month stay also will eclipse long-duration U.S. spaceflight record set by first American to live on Mir, Norm Thagard.
    
    Payload bay configuration included Orbiter Docking System in forward area and SPACEHAB single module toward the aft. STS-76 marked first flight of SPACEHAB pressurized module to support shuttle-Mir dockings; single module primarily served as stowage area for large supply of equipment slated for transfer to space station, but also carried European Space Agency’s Biorack experiment rack for on-orbit research.
    
    During five days of docked operations, about 1,500 pounds (680 kilograms) of water and two tons of scientific equipment, logistical material and resupply items transferred to Mir; experiment samples and miscellaneous equipment brought over to orbiter. In Biorack, 11 separate scientific investigations were conducted. Study topics included effect of microgravity and cosmic radiation on plants, tissues, cells, bacteria and insects and effects of microgravity on bone loss.
    
    Crew consisted of Commander Kevin P. Chilton, Pilot Richard A. Searfoss, Mission Specialists Shannon W. Lucid, Linda M. Godwin, Michael R. Clifford, Ronald M. Sega.</desc>
    
</xml>