<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="STS.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?><xml>
    <sts stsNum="079">STS-79</sts>
    <mission type="crewTransfer" org="nasa">Mission: Fourth Shuttle-Mir Docking</mission>
    <orbiter oName="atlantis">Space Shuttle: Atlantis</orbiter>
    <launchPad sBase="kennedySpaceCenter" padNum="39A">Launch Pad: 39A</launchPad>
    <launch sDateTime="1996-09-16T04:54:49">Launched: September 16, 1996, 4:54:49 a.m. EDT</launch>
    <landPad eBase="kennedySpaceCenter">Landing Site: Kennedy Space Center, Florida</landPad>
    <land eDateTime="1996-09-26T08:13:15">Landing: September 26, 1996, 8:13:15 a.m. EDT</land>
    <duration time="P10DT3H18M26S">Mission Duration: 10 days, 3 hours, 18 minutes, 26 seconds</duration>
    <altitude alt="245">Orbit Altitude: 196-245 statute miles</altitude>
    <inclination deg="51.6">Orbit Inclination: 51.6 degrees</inclination>
    
    <desc cargo="SPACEHAB">STS-79 highlighted by return to Earth of U.S. astronaut Lucid after 188 days in space, first U.S. crew exchange aboard Russian Space Station Mir, and fourth Shuttle-Mir docking. Lucid’s long-duration spaceflight set new U.S. record as well as world record for a woman.
    
    STS-79 also marked second flight of SPACEHAB module in support of Shuttle-Mir activities and first flight of SPACEHAB Double Module configuration.
    
    During five days of mated operations, two crews transferred more than 4,000 pounds (1,814 kilograms) of supplies to Mir, including logistics, food and water generated by orbiter fuel cells. Three experiments also were transferred: Biotechnology System (BTS) for study of cartilage development; Material in Devices as Superconductors (MIDAS) to measure electrical properties of high-temperature superconductor materials; and Commercial Generic Bioprocessing Apparatus (CGBA), containing several smaller experiments, including self-contained aquatic systems.
    
    About 2,000 pounds (907 kilograms) of experiment samples and equipment transferred from Mir to Atlantis; total logistical transfer to and from station of more than 6,000 pounds (2,722 kilograms) was most extensive to date.
    
    Crew consisted of Commander William F. Readdy, Pilot Terrence W. Wilcutt, Mission Specialists Thomas D. Akers, John E. Blaha, Jay Apt and Carl E. Walz.</desc>
    
</xml>