<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="STS.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?><xml>
    <sts stsNum="071">STS-71</sts>
    <mission type="crewTransfer" org="nasa">Mission: First Shuttle-Mir Docking</mission>
    <orbiter oName="atlantis">Space Shuttle: Atlantis</orbiter>
    <launchPad sBase="kennedySpaceCenter" padNum="39A">Launch Pad: 39A</launchPad>
    <launch sDateTime="1995-06-27T15:32:19.044">Launched: June 27, 1995, 3:32:19.044 p.m. EDT</launch>
    <landPad eBase="kennedySpaceCenter">Landing Site: Kennedy Space Center, Florida</landPad>
    <land eDateTime="1995-07-07T10:54:34">Landing: July 7, 1995, 10:54:34 a.m. EDT</land>
    <duration time="P9DT19H22M17S">Mission Duration: 9 days, 19 hours, 22 minutes, 17 seconds</duration>
    <altitude alt="170">Orbit Altitude: 170 nautical miles</altitude>
    <inclination deg="51.6">Orbit Inclination: 51.6 degrees</inclination>
    
    <desc cargo="passangers">STS-71 marked a number of historic firsts in human spaceflight: 100th U.S. human space launch conducted from the Cape; first U.S. space shuttle-Russian Space Station Mir docking and joint on-orbit operations; largest spacecraft ever in orbit; and first on-orbit changeout of shuttle crew.
    
    When linked, Atlantis and Mir formed largest spacecraft ever in orbit, with a total mass of almost one-half million pounds (about 225 tons) orbiting some 218 nautical miles above the Earth. After hatches on each side opened, STS-71 crew passed into Mir for welcoming ceremony. On same day, Mir 18 crew officially transferred responsibility for station to Mir 19 crew, and two crews switched spacecraft.
    For next five days, about 100 hours total, joint U.S.-Russian operations conducted, including biomedical investigations, and transfer of equipment to and from Mir. Fifteen separate biomedical and scientific investigations were conducted, using Spacelab module installed in aft portion of Atlantis' payload bay, and covering seven different disciplines: cardiovascular and pulmonary functions; human metabolism; neuroscience; hygiene, sanitation and radiation; behavioral performance and biology; fundamental biology; and microgravity research. Mir 18 crew served as test subjects for investigations. Three Mir 18 crew members also carried out intensive program of exercise and other measures to prepare for re-entry into gravity environment after more than three months in space.
    
    Crew consisted of Commander Robert L. Gibson, Pilot Charles J. Precourt, Mission Specialists Ellen S. Baker, Bonnie J. Dunbar and Gregory J. Harbaugh. Mir 19 Crew (upload) Anatoly Solovyev, Nikolai Budarin and Mir 18 Crew (download) Norman E. Thagard, Vladimir Dezhurov and Gannady Strekalov.</desc>
    
</xml>