<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="STS.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?><xml>
    <sts stsNum="007">STS-7</sts>
    <mission type="satLaunch" org="business">Mission: Communications Satellite Launch/First U.S. Woman in Space</mission>
    <orbiter oName="challenger">Space Shuttle: Challenger</orbiter>
    <launchPad sBase="kennedySpaceCenter" padNum="39A">Launch Pad: 39A</launchPad>
    <launch sDateTime="1983-06-18T07:33:00">Launched: June 18, 1983 at 7:33:00 a.m. EDT</launch>
    <landPad eBase="edwardsAirForceBase">Landing Site: Edwards Air Force Base, Calif.</landPad>
    <land eDateTime="1983-06-24T06:56:59">Landing: June 24, 1983 at 6:56:59 a.m. PDT</land>
    <duration time="P6DT2H23M59S">Mission Duration: 6 days, 2 hours, 23 minutes and 59 seconds</duration>
    <altitude alt="160">Orbit Altitude: 160-170 nautical miles</altitude>
    <inclination deg="28.5">Orbit Inclination: 28.5 degrees</inclination>
    
    <desc cargo="ANIK C-2, PALAPA-B1">Sally Ride became the first American woman to fly in space. Two communications satellites were deployed, ANIK C-2 for TELESAT Canada and PALAPA-B1 for Indonesia, both were attached to the Payload Assist Module-D (PAM-D) motors. Seven Get Away Special canisters in the cargo bay held a variety of experiments, including one studying affects of space on social behavior of an ant colony in zero gravity. Ten experiments were mounted on the Shuttle Pallet Satellite (SPAS-01) and performed research in forming metal alloys in microgravity and the use of a remote sensing scanner. The orbiter's small control rockets were fired while SPAS-01 was held by the remote manipulator system to test the movement on an extended arm. Experiment 1: To investigate space sickness was carried out. Other payloads on this mission were: Office of Space and Terrestrial Applications-2 (OSTA-2); Continuous Flow Electrophoresis System (CFES); Monodisperse Latex Reactor (MLR) and one Shuttle Student Involvement (SSIP) experiment.
    
    Crew consisted of Commander Robert L. Crippen, Pilot Frederick H. Hauck and Mission Specialists John M. Fabian, Sally K. Ride and Norman E. Thagard.</desc>
    
</xml>