<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="STS.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?><xml>
    <sts stsNum="063">STS-63</sts>
    <mission type="science" org="nasa">Mission: SPACEHAB-3</mission>
    <orbiter oName="discovery">Space Shuttle: Discovery</orbiter>
    <launchPad sBase="kennedySpaceCenter" padNum="39B">Launch Pad: 39B</launchPad>
    <launch sDateTime="1995-02-03T00:22:04">Launched: February 3, 1995, 12:22:04 a.m. EST</launch>
    <landPad eBase="kennedySpaceCenter">Landing Site: Kennedy Space Center, Florida</landPad>
    <land eDateTime="1995-02-11T06:50:19">Landing: February 11, 1995, 6:50:19 a.m. EST</land>
    <duration time="P8DT6H28M15S">Mission Duration: 8 days, 6 hours, 28 minutes, 15 seconds</duration>
    <altitude alt="213">Orbit Altitude: 213 nautical miles</altitude>
    <inclination deg="51.6">Orbit Inclination: 51.6 degrees</inclination>
    
    <desc cargo="SPACEHAB-3">First shuttle flight of 1995 included several history-making achievements: First flight of a female shuttle pilot (Collins) and, as part of Phase I of International Space Station Program, second flight of Russian cosmonaut on shuttle and first approach and flyaround by shuttle with Russian space station Mir.
    
    Crew also worked extensively with payloads aboard Discovery. Flying in forward payload bay and activated on flight day one was SPACEHAB-3. The commercially-developed module was making its third flight on the shuttle and carried 20 experiments: 11 biotechnology experiments; three advanced materials development experiments; four technology demonstrations; and two pieces of supporting hardware measuring on-orbit accelerations. Improvements made to SPACEHAB system to reduce demand on crew time. New video switch added to lessen need for astronaut involvement in video operations, and experiment interface added to telemetry system to allow experiment investigator to link directly via computer with onboard experiment to receive data and monitor status. Charlotte, an experimental robotic device being flown for first time, also will reduce crew workload by taking over simple tasks such as changing experiment samples.
    
    Crew consisted of Commander James D. Wetherbee, Pilot Eileen M. Collins, Missions Specialists C. Michael Foale, Janice E. Voss, Bernard A. Harris, Jr. and Vladimar G. Titov.</desc>
</xml>