<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="STS.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?><xml>
    <sts stsNum="042">STS-42</sts>
    <mission type="science" org="nasa">Mission: IML-1</mission>
    <orbiter oName="discovery">Space Shuttle: Discovery</orbiter>
    <launchPad sBase="kennedySpaceCenter" padNum="39A">Launch Pad: 39A</launchPad>
    <launch sDateTime="1992-01-22T09:52:33">Launched: January 22, 1992, 9:52:33 a.m. EST</launch>
    <landPad eBase="edwardsAirForceBase">Landing Site: Edwards Air Force Base, Calif.</landPad>
    <land eDateTime="1992-01-30T08:07:17">Landing: January 30, 1992, 8:07:17 a.m. PST</land>
    <duration time="P8DT1H14M44S">Mission Duration: 8 days, 1 hour, 14 minutes, 44 seconds</duration>
    <altitude alt="163">Orbit Altitude: 163 nautical miles</altitude>
    <inclination deg="57">Orbit Inclination: 57 degrees</inclination>
    
    <desc cargo="IML-1">The primary payload was the International Microgravity Laboratory-1 (IML-1), making its first flight and using the pressurized Spacelab module. The International crew was divided into two teams for around-the-clock research on the human nervous system's adaptation to low gravity and the effects of microgravity on other life forms such as shrimp eggs, lentil seedlings, fruit fly eggs, and bacteria. Materials processing experiments were also conducted, including crystal growth from variety of substances such as enzymes, mercury iodide and a virus. On flight day six, mission managers concluded enough onboard consumables remained to extend the mission one day to continue science experiments.
    
    Secondary payloads were: 12 Get Away Special (GAS) canisters attached to a GAS Bridge Assembly in the cargo bay and containing a variety of U.S. and international experiments.
    
    Crew consisted of Commander Ronald J. Grabe, Pilot Stephen S. Oswald, Mission Specialists Norman E. Thagard, David C. Hilmers, William F. Readdy and Payload Specialists Roberta L. Bondar and Ulf D. Merbold.</desc>
    
</xml>