<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="STS.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?><xml>
    <sts stsNum="078">STS-78</sts>
    <mission type="science" org="international">Mission: LMS</mission>
    <orbiter oName="columbia">Space Shuttle: Columbia</orbiter>
    <launchPad sBase="kennedySpaceCenter" padNum="39B">Launch Pad: 39B</launchPad>
    <launch sDateTime="1996-06-20T10:49:00">Launched: June 20, 1996, 10:49:00 a.m. EDT</launch>
    <landPad eBase="kennedySpaceCenter">Landing Site: Kennedy Space Center, Florida</landPad>
    <land eDateTime="1996-07-07T08:36:45">Landing: July 7, 1996, 8:36:45 a.m. EDT</land>
    <duration time="P16DT21H47M45S">Mission Duration: 16 days, 21 hours, 47 minutes, 45 seconds</duration>
    <altitude alt="173">Orbit Altitude: 173 statute miles</altitude>
    <inclination deg="39">Orbit Inclination: 39 degrees</inclination>
    
    <desc cargo="LMS">Five space agencies (NASA/USA; European Space Agency/Europe; French Space Agency/France; Canadian Space Agency/Canada; and Italian Space Agency/Italy) and research scientists from 10 countries worked together on primary payload of STS-78, Life and Microgravity Spacelab (LMS). More than 40 experiments flown were grouped into two areas: life sciences, which included human physiology and space biology, and microgravity science, which included basic fluid physics investigations, advanced semiconductor and metal alloy materials processing, and medical research in protein crystal growth.
    
    LMS investigations conducted via most extensive telescience to date. Investigators located at four remote European and four remote U.S. locations, similar to what will happen with International Space Station. Mission also made extensive use of video imaging to help crew members perform inflight maintenance procedures on experiment hardware.
    
    Crew consisted of Commander Terence T. Henricks, Pilot Kevin R. Kregel, Flight Engineer Susan J. Helms, Mission Specialists Richard M. Linnehan, Charles E. Brady, Jr., Payload Specialists Jean-Jacques Favier and Robert Brent Thirsk.</desc>
    
</xml>