<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="STS.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?><xml>
    <sts stsNum="090">STS-90</sts>
    <mission type="science" org="nasa">Mission: Final Spacelab Mission</mission>
    <orbiter oName="columbia">Space Shuttle: Columbia</orbiter>
    <launchPad sBase="kennedySpaceCenter" padNum="39B">Launch Pad: 39B</launchPad>
    <launch sDateTime="1998-04-17T14:19:00">Launched: April 17, 1998, 2:19:00 p.m. EDT</launch>
    <landPad eBase="kennedySpaceCenter">Landing Site: Kennedy Space Center, Florida</landPad>
    <land eDateTime="1998-05-03T12:08:59">Landing: May 3, 1998, 12:08:59 p.m. EDT</land>
    <duration time="P15DT21H50M58S">Mission Duration: 15 days, 21 hours, 50 minutes, 58 seconds</duration>
    <altitude alt="150">Orbit Altitude: 150 nautical miles</altitude>
    <inclination deg="39">Orbit Inclination: 39 degrees</inclination>

    <desc cargo="Neurolab">Neurolab's 26 experiments targeted one of the most complex and least understood parts of the human body — the nervous system. The primary goals were to conduct basic research in neurosciences and expand understanding of how the nervous system develops and functions in space. Test subjects were crew members and rats, mice, crickets, snails and two kinds of fish. This was a cooperative effort of NASA, several domestic partners and the space agencies of Canada (CSA), France (CNES) and Germany (DARA), as well as the European Space Agency (ESA) and the National Space Development Agency of Japan (NASDA). Most experiments were conducted in the pressurized Spacelab long module located in Columbia's payload bay. This was the 16th and last scheduled flight of the ESA-developed Spacelab module although the Spacelab pallets will continue to be used on the International Space Station. Read more about the Neurolab Spacelab Mission findings in this book.
    
    Research was conducted as planned, with the exception of the Mammalian Development Team, which had to reprioritize science activities because of the unexpected high mortality rate of neonatal rats on board.
    
    STS-90 Mission Specialist Kay Hire was Kennedy Space Center's first employee to be chosen as an astronaut candidate.
    
    Crew consisted of Commander Richard A. Searfoss, Pilot Scott D. Altman, Mission Specialists Richard M. Linnehan, Dafydd Rhys Williams, Kathryn P. Hire, Payload Specialists Dr. Jay C. Buckey, Jr. and Dr. James A. Pawelczyk.</desc>
    
</xml>