<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="STS.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?><xml>
    <sts stsNum="101">STS-101</sts>
    <mission type="issConstruct" org="international">Mission: International Space Station Flight 2A.2a</mission>
    <orbiter oName="atlantis">Space Shuttle: Atlantis</orbiter>
    <launchPad sBase="kennedySpaceCenter">Launch Pad: 39A</launchPad>
    <launch sDateTime="2000-05-19T06:11:00">Launched: May 19, 2000, 6:11 a.m. EDT</launch>
    <landPad eBase="kennedySpaceCenter">Landing Site: Kennedy Space Center</landPad>
    <land eDateTime="2000-05-29T00:20:00">Landing: May 29,  2000, 12:20 a.m. EDT</land>
    <duration time="P9DT20H9M0S">Mission Duration: 9 days, 20 hours, 9 minutes</duration>
    <altitude alt="173">Orbit Altitude: 173 nautical miles</altitude>
    <inclination deg="51.6">Orbit Inclination: 51.6 degrees</inclination>
    
    <desc cargo="supplies">The seven-member crew included Commander James Halsell, Pilot Scott Horowitz and Mission Specialists Mary Ellen Weber, Susan Helms, Yury Usachev, James Voss and Jeff Williams. For Usachev — representing the Russian Space Agency — Voss and Helms, the short visit to the station was a preview of the much longer time they would spend aboard the outpost as the Expedition Two crew in 2001.
    
    While docked with the space station, the crew refurbished and replaced components in both the Zarya and Unity Modules. Voss and Williams performed a 6.5-hour space walk the day after docking to install a Russian Strela cargo boom on the outside of Zarya. They also replaced a faulty radio antenna and performed several other tasks in advance of space walks on future station assembly missions.
    
    On STS-101, Atlantis flew as the most updated space shuttle ever, outfitted with a new "glass cockpit" and other state-of-the-art upgrades to key systems, including more than 100 new modifications incorporated during a 10-month period at Boeing's Palmdale, Calif., shuttle factory in 1998.</desc>
    
</xml>