<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="STS.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?><xml>
    <sts stsNum="108">STS-108</sts>
    <mission type="issResupply" org="international">Mission: International Space Station Flight UF-1</mission>
    <orbiter oName="endeavour">Space Shuttle: Endeavour</orbiter>
    <launchPad sBase="kennedySpaceCenter" padNum="39B">Launch Pad: 39B</launchPad>
    <launch sDateTime="2001-12-05T17:19:00">Launched: Dec. 5, 2001, 5:19 p.m. EST</launch>
    <landPad eBase="kennedySpaceCenter">Landing Site: Kennedy Space Center</landPad>
    <land eDateTime="100-12-17T12:585:00">Landing: Dec. 17,  2001, 12:55 p.m. EST</land>
    <duration time="P11DT19H36M0S">Mission Duration: 11 days, 19 hours, 36 minutes</duration>
    <altitude alt="122">Orbit Altitude: 122 nautical miles</altitude>
    <inclination deg="51.6">Orbit Inclination: 51.6 degrees</inclination>
    
    <desc cargo="Raffaello Multi-Purpose Module">STS-108 was the 12th shuttle flight to visit the International Space Station andthe first since the installation of the Russian airlock called Pirs on the station. Endeavour delivered the Expedition Four crew — Commander Yury Onufrienko and Flight Engineers Carl Walz and Dan Bursch — to the orbital outpost. The Expedition Three crew — Commander Frank Culbertson, Pilot Vladimir Dezhurov and Flight Engineer Mikhail Tyurin — returned to Earth on Endeavour.
    
    While at the station, the crew conducted one spacewalk and attached the Raffaello Multi-Purpose Logistics Module to the station so that about 2.7 metric tons (3 tons) of equipment and supplies could be unloaded. The crew later returned Raffaello to Endeavour's payload bay for the trip home.
    During STS-108, NASA honored the victims of the Sept. 11 terrorist attacks by sending nearly 6,000 small U.S. flags into orbit on Space Shuttle Endeavour as part of the "Flags for Heroes and Families" campaign.
    
    The Student-Tracked Atmospheric Research Satellite for Heuristic International Networking Experiment, also called STARSHINE 2, was deployed from Endeavour's payload bay one day before landing.
    Crew consisted of Commander Dominic L. Gorie, Pilot Mark E. Kelly, Mission Specialists Linda M. Godwin and Daniel M. Tani.</desc>
    
</xml>