<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="STS.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?><xml>
    <sts stsNum="51D">STS-51D</sts>
    <mission type="satLaunch" org="business">Mission: TELSAT-I, Communications Satellite SYNCOM IV-3</mission>
    <orbiter oName="discovery">Space Shuttle: Discovery</orbiter>
    <launchPad sBase="kennedySpaceCenter" padNum="39A">Launch Pad: 39A</launchPad>
    <launch sDateTime="1985-04-12T08:59:05">Launched: April 12, 1985 at 8:59:05 a.m. EST</launch>
    <landPad eBase="kennedySpaceCenter">Landing Site: Kennedy Space Center, Florida</landPad>
    <land eDateTime="1985-04-19T08:54:28">Landing: April 19, 1985 at 8:54:28 a.m. EST</land>
    <duration time="P6DT23H55M23S">Mission Duration: 6 days, 23 hours, 55 minutes, 23 seconds</duration>
    <altitude alt="285">Orbit Altitude: 285 nautical miles</altitude>
    <inclination deg="28.5">Orbit Inclination: 28.5 degrees</inclination>
    
    <desc cargo="TELESAT-1">The TELESAT-l (ANIK C-1) communications satellite was deployed attached to the payload assist module (PAM-D) motor. SYNCOM IV-3 (also known as LEASAT-3) was also deployed but the spacecraft sequencer failed to initiate the antenna deployment, spin up and ignition of perigee kick motor. The mission was extended two days to make certain the sequencer start lever was in the proper position. Griggs and Hoffman performed a space walk to attach Flyswatter devices to the remote manipulator system. Seddon engaged LEASAT lever using the remote manipulator system but the post deployment sequence did not begin. Other payloads were: Continuous Flow Electrophoresis System (CFES) III, flying for sixth time; two Shuttle Student Involvement Program (SSIP) experiments; American Flight Echocardiograph (AFE); two Get Away Specials; Phase Partitioning Experiments (PPE); astronomy photography verification test; medical experiments and toys in space, an informal study of the behavior of simple toys in weightless environment, with results to be made available to school students.
    
    Crew consisted of Commander Karol J. Bobko, Pilot Donald E. Williams, Mission Specialists M. Rhea Seddon, Jeffrey A. Hoffman, S. David Griggs and Payload Specialists Charles D. Walker and Sen. E. Jake Garn.</desc>
    
</xml>