<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../../Schematron/ulyssesSchematron.sch" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?><?xml-model href="../../RNC/ulyssesSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?><ulysses>
     <section sectionName="The Telemachiad"/>
     <chapter chapterName="Nestor"/>
     <location name="Dalkey, Dublin Bay" lat="53.278333" lon="-6.100278">

          <said who="Stephen">—You, Cochrane, what city sent for him?</said>

          <said who="class">—Tarentum, sir.</said>

          <said who="Stephen">—Very good. Well?</said>

          <said who="class">—There was a battle, sir.</said>

          <said who="Stephen">—Very good. Where?</said>

          <p> boy’s blank face asked the blank window. <allusion who="William Blake">Fabled by
                    the daughters of memory</allusion>. And yet it was in some way if not as memory
               fabled it. A phrase, then, of impatience, thud of <allusion to="William Blake">Blake’s wings of excess.</allusion>
               <allusion who="William Blake">I hear the ruin of all space, shattered glass and
                    toppling masonry, and time one livid final flame.</allusion> What’s left us
               then?</p>

          <said who="class">—I forget the place, sir. 279 B. C.</said>

          <said who="Stephen">—Asculum, Stephen said, glancing at the name and date in the
               gorescarred book.</said>

          <said who="class">—Yes, sir. And he said: <allusion to="Pyrrhus">_Another victory
                    like that and we are done for.</allusion>_</said>

          <p>That phrase the world had remembered. A dull ease of the mind. From a hill above a
               corpsestrewn plain a general speaking to his officers, leaned upon his spear. Any
               general to any officers. They lend ear.</p>

          <said who="Stephen">—You, Armstrong, Stephen said. What was the end of
               Pyrrhus?</said>

          <said who="Armstrong"><allusion to="Pyrrhus">—End of Pyrrhus, sir?</allusion></said>

          <said who="Comyn">—I know, sir. Ask me, sir, <reference to="ScottishFamily">Comyn</reference> said.</said>

          <said who="Stephen">—Wait. You, Armstrong. Do you know anything about Pyrrhus?</said>

          <p>A bag of figrolls lay snugly in Armstrong’s satchel. He curled them between his palms
               at whiles and swallowed them softly. Crumbs adhered to the tissue of his lips. A
               sweetened boy’s breath. Welloff people, proud that their eldest son was in the navy.
                    <reference to="ItalianPhilosopher">Vico Road, Dalkey.</reference></p>

          <said who="Armstrong">—Pyrrhus, sir? Pyrrhus, a pier.</said>

          <p>All laughed. Mirthless high malicious laughter. Armstrong looked round at his
               classmates, silly glee in profile. In a moment they will laugh more loudly, aware of
               my lack of rule and of the fees their papas pay.</p>

          <said who="Stephen">—Tell me now, Stephen said, poking the boy’s shoulder with the
               book,hat is a pier.</said>

          <said who="Armstrong">—A pier, sir, Armstrong said. A thing out in the water. A kind
               of aridge. Kingstown pier, sir.</said>

          <p>Some laughed again: mirthless but with meaning. Two in the back bench whispered. Yes.
               They knew: had never learned nor ever been innocent. All. With envy he watched their
               faces: Edith, Ethel, Gerty, Lily. Their likes: their breaths, too, sweetened with tea
               and jam, their bracelets tittering in the struggle.</p>

          <said who="Stephen">—Kingstown pier, Stephen said. Yes, a disappointed bridge.</said>

          <p>The words troubled their gaze.</p>

          <said who="Comyn">—How, sir? Comyn asked. A bridge is across a river.</said>

          <p>For Haines’s chapbook. No-one here to hear. Tonight deftly amid wild drink and talk, to
               pierce the polished mail of his mind. What then? A jester at the court of his master,
               indulged and disesteemed, winning a clement master’s praise. Why had they chosen all
               that part? Not wholly for the smooth caress. For them too history was a tale like any
               other too often heard, their land a pawnshop.</p>

          <p>Had Pyrrhus not fallen by a beldam’s hand in Argos or <reference to="RomanHistory">Julius Caesar</reference> not been knifed to death. They are not to be thought
               away. Time has branded them and fettered they are lodged in the room of the <allusion who="Aristotle">infinite possibilities they have ousted</allusion>. But can
               those have been possible seeing that they never were? <allusion who="Aristotle">Or was that only possible which came to pass?</allusion>
               <allusion to="Bible">Weave, weaver of the wind.</allusion></p>

          <said who="class">—Tell us a story, sir.</said>

          <said who="class">—O, do, sir. A ghoststory.</said>

          <said who="Stephen">—Where do you begin in this? Stephen asked, opening another
               book.</said>

          <said who="Comyn">—_Weep no more,_ Comyn said.</said>

          <said who="Stephen">—Go on then, Talbot.</said>

          <said who="class">—And the story, sir?</said>

          <said who="Stephen">—After, Stephen said. Go on, Talbot.</said>

          <p>A swarthy boy opened a book and propped it nimbly under the breastwork of his satchel.
               He recited jerks of verse with odd glances at the text:</p>

          <said who="Talbot"><allusion who="John Milton">—Weep no more, woful shepherds,
                    weep no more For Lycidas, your sorrow, is not dead, Sunk though he be beneath
                    the watery floor..._</allusion></said>

          <p>It must be a movement then, an actuality of the possible as possible. <allusion who="Aristotle">Aristotle’s phrase</allusion> formed itself within the
               gabbled verses and floated out into the studious silence of the library of <allusion who="William Blake">Saint Genevieve where he had read, sheltered from the
                    sin of Paris, night by night. By his elbow a delicate Siamese conned a handbook
                    of strategy. Fed and feeding brains about me: under glowlamps, impaled, with
                    faintly beating feelers: and in my mind’s darkness a sloth of the underworld,
                    reluctant, shy of brightness, shifting her dragon scaly folds.</allusion>
               <allusion who="Aristotle">Thought is the thought of thought.</allusion> Tranquil
               brightness. The soul is in a manner all that is: the soul is the form of forms.
               Tranquility sudden, vast, candescent: form of forms.</p>

          <p>Talbot repeated:</p>

          <said who="Talbot"><allusion who="John Milton">—Through the dear might of Him
                    that walked the waves, Through the dear might..._</allusion></said>

          <said who="Stephen">—Turn over, Stephen said quietly. I don’t see anything.</said>

          <said who="Talbot">—What, sir? Talbot asked simply, bending forward.</said>

          <p>His hand turned the page over. He leaned back and went on again, having just
               remembered. <allusion to="Bible">Of him that walked the waves.</allusion> Here also
               over these craven hearts his shadow lies and on the scoffer’s heart and lips and on
               mine. It lies upon their eager faces who offered him a coin of the tribute. <allusion to="Bible">To <reference to="RomanHistory">Caesar</reference> what is Caesar’s,
                    to God what is God’s.</allusion> A long look from dark eyes, a riddling sentence
               to be woven and woven on the church’s looms. Ay. Riddle me, riddle me, randy ro. My
               father gave me seeds to sow.</p>

          <p>Talbot slid his closed book into his satchel.</p>

          <said who="Stephen">—Have I heard all? Stephen asked.</said>

          <said who="Talbot">—Yes, sir. Hockey at ten, sir.</said>

          <said who="class">—Half day, sir. Thursday.</said>

          <said who="Stephen">—Who can answer a riddle? Stephen asked.</said>

          <p>They bundled their books away, pencils clacking, pages rustling. Crowding together they
               strapped and buckled their satchels, all gabbling gaily:</p>

          <said who="class">—A riddle, sir? Ask me, sir.</said>

          <said who="class">—O, ask me, sir.</said>

          <said who="class">—A hard one, sir.</said>

          <said who="Stephen">—This is the riddle, Stephen said: The cock crew, The sky was
               blue: The bells in heaven Were striking eleven. ’Tis time for this poor soul To go to
               heaven. What is that?</said>

          <said who="class">—What, sir?</said>

          <said who="class">—Again, sir. We didn’t hear.</said>

          <p>Their eyes grew bigger as the lines were repeated. After a silence Cochrane said:</p>

          <said who="Cochrane">—What is it, sir? We give it up.</said>

          <p>Stephen, his throat itching, answered:</p>

          <said who="Stephen">—The fox burying his grandmother under a hollybush.</said>

          <p>He stood up and gave a shout of nervous laughter to which their cries echoed
               dismay.</p>

          <p>A stick struck the door and a voice in the corridor called:</p>

          <said who="class">—Hockey!</said>

          <p>They broke asunder, sidling out of their benches, leaping them. Quickly they were gone
               and from the lumberroom came the rattle of sticks and clamour of their boots and
               tongues.</p>

          <p>Sargent who alone had lingered came forward slowly, showing an open copybook. His
               tangled hair and scraggy neck gave witness of unreadiness and through his misty
               glasses weak eyes looked up pleading. On his cheek, dull and bloodless, a soft stain
               of ink lay, dateshaped, recent and damp as a snail’s bed.</p>

          <p>He held out his copybook. The word _Sums_ was written on the headline. Beneath were
               sloping figures and at the foot a crooked signature with blind loops and a blot.
               Cyril Sargent: his name and seal.</p>

          <said who="Sargent">—<reference to="DeasyLandAct1860">Mr Deasy</reference> told me to
               write them out all again, he said, and show themo you, sir.</said>

          <p>Stephen touched the edges of the book. Futility.</p>

          <said who="Stephen">—Do you understand how to do them now? he asked.</said>

          <said who="Sargent">—Numbers eleven to fifteen, Sargent answered. Mr Deasy said I was
               toopy them off the board, sir.</said>

          <said who="Stephen">—Can you do them yourself? Stephen asked.</said>

          <said who="Sargent">—No, sir.</said>

          <p>Ugly and futile: lean neck and tangled hair and a stain of ink, a snail’s bed. Yet
               someone had loved him, borne him in her arms and in her heart. But for her the race
               of the world would have trampled him underfoot, a squashed boneless snail. She had
               loved his weak watery blood drained from her own. Was that then real? <allusion who="James Joyce">The only true thing in life?</allusion> His mother’s
               prostrate body the fiery <reference to="IrishSaint">Columbanus</reference> in holy
               zeal bestrode. She was no more: the trembling skeleton of a twig burnt in the fire,
               an odour of rosewood and wetted ashes. She had saved him from being trampled
               underfoot and had gone, scarcely having been. A poor soul gone to heaven: and on a
               heath beneath winking stars a fox, red reek of rapine in his fur, with merciless
               bright eyes scraped in the earth, listened, scraped up the earth, listened, scraped
               and scraped.</p>

          <p>Sitting at his side Stephen solved out the problem. He proves by algebra that
               Shakespeare’s ghost is Hamlet’s grandfather. Sargent peered askance through his
               slanted glasses. Hockeysticks rattled in the lumberroom: the hollow knock of a ball
               and calls from the field.</p>

          <p>Across the page the symbols moved in grave <reference to="Moors">morrice</reference>,
               in the mummery of their letters, wearing quaint caps of squares and cubes. Give
               hands, traverse, bow to partner: so: imps of fancy of the Moors. Gone too from the
               world, <reference to="ReligiousPhilosophers Aristotle">Averroes and Moses
                    Maimonides</reference>, dark men in mien and movement, flashing in their mocking
               mirrors the obscure soul of the world, <allusion to="Bible">a darkness shining in
                    brightness which brightness could not comprehend.</allusion></p>

          <said who="Stephen">—Do you understand now? Can you work the second for
               yourself?</said>

          <said who="Sargent">—Yes, sir.</said>

          <p>In long shaky strokes Sargent copied the data. Waiting always for a word of help his
               hand moved faithfully the unsteady symbols, a faint hue of shame flickering behind
               his dull skin. _Amor matris:_ subjective and objective genitive. With her weak blood
               and wheysour milk she had fed him and hid from sight of others his swaddling
               bands.</p>

          <p>Like him was I, these sloping shoulders, this gracelessness. My childhood bends beside
               me. Too far for me to lay a hand there once or lightly. Mine is far and his secret as
               our eyes. Secrets, silent, stony sit in the dark palaces of both our hearts: secrets
               weary of their tyranny: tyrants, willing to be dethroned.</p>

          <p>The sum was done.</p>

          <said who="Stephen">—It is very simple, Stephen said as he stood up.</said>

          <said who="Sargent">—Yes, sir. Thanks, Sargent answered.</said>

          <p>He dried the page with a sheet of thin blottingpaper and carried his copybook back to
               his bench.</p>

          <said who="Stephen">—You had better get your stick and go out to the others, Stephen
               saids he followed towards the door the boy’s graceless form.</said>

          <said who="Sargent">—Yes, sir.</said>

          <p>In the corridor his name was heard, called from the playfield.</p>

          <said who="Mr. Deasy">—Sargent!</said>

          <said who="Stephen">—Run on, Stephen said. Mr Deasy is calling you.</said>

          <p>He stood in the porch and watched the laggard hurry towards the scrappy field where
               sharp voices were in strife. They were sorted in teams and Mr Deasy came away
               stepping over wisps of grass with gaitered feet. When he had reached the schoolhouse
               voices again contending called to him. He turned his angry white moustache.</p>

          <said who="Mr. Deasy">—What is it now? he cried continually without listening.</said>

          <said who="Stephen">—Cochrane and Halliday are on the same side, sir, Stephen
               said.</said>

          <said who="Mr. Deasy">—Will you wait in my study for a moment, Mr Deasy said, till I
               restorerder here.</said>

          <p>And as he stepped fussily back across the field his old man’s voice cried sternly:</p>

          <said who="Mr. Deasy">—What is the matter? What is it now?</said>

          <p>Their sharp voices cried about him on all sides: their many forms closed round him, the
               garish sunshine bleaching the honey of his illdyed head.</p>

          <p>Stale smoky air hung in the study with the smell of drab abraded leather of its chairs.
               As on the first day he bargained with me here. <allusion to="Gloria Patri">As it was
                    in the beginning, is now. On the sideboard the tray of <reference to="James II of England">Stuart coins</reference>, base treasure of a bog:
                    and ever shall be. And <allusion to="Bible">snug in their spooncase of purple
                         plush, faded, the twelve apostles having preached to all the gentiles:
                         world without end.</allusion></allusion></p>

          <p>A hasty step over the stone porch and in the corridor. Blowing out his rare moustache
               Mr Deasy halted at the table.</p>

          <said who="Mr. Deasy">—First, our little financial settlement, he said.</said>

          <p>He brought out of his coat a pocketbook bound by a leather thong. It slapped open and
               he took from it two notes, one of joined halves, and laid them carefully on the
               table.</p>

          <said who="Mr. Deasy">—Two, he said, strapping and stowing his pocketbook
               away.</said>

          <p>And now his strongroom for the gold. Stephen’s embarrassed hand moved over the shells
               heaped in the cold stone mortar: whelks and money cowries and leopard shells: and
               this, whorled as an emir’s turban, and this, the <reference to="pilgrimage">scallop
                    of saint James</reference>. An old pilgrim’s hoard, dead treasure, hollow
               shells.</p>

          <p>A sovereign fell, bright and new, on the soft pile of the tablecloth.</p>

          <said who="Mr. Deasy">—Three, Mr Deasy said, turning his little savingsbox about in
               his hand.hese are handy things to have. See. This is for sovereigns. This is for
               shillings. Sixpences, halfcrowns. And here crowns. See.</said>

          <p>He shot from it two crowns and two shillings.</p>

          <said who="Mr. Deasy">—Three twelve, he said. I think you’ll find that’s
               right.</said>

          <said who="Stephen">—Thank you, sir, Stephen said, gathering the money together with
               shyaste and putting it all in a pocket of his trousers.</said>

          <said who="Mr. Deasy">—No thanks at all, Mr Deasy said. You have earned it.</said>

          <p>Stephen’s hand, free again, went back to the hollow shells. Symbols too of beauty and
               of power. A lump in my pocket: symbols soiled by greed and misery.</p>

          <said who="Mr. Deasy">—Don’t carry it like that, Mr Deasy said. You’ll pull it out
               somewherend lose it. You just buy one of these machines. You’ll find them very
               handy.</said>

          <p>Answer something.</p>

          <said who="Stephen">—Mine would be often empty, Stephen said.</said>

          <p>The same room and hour, the same wisdom: and I the same. Three times now. Three nooses
               round me here. Well? I can break them in this instant if I will.</p>

          <said who="Mr. Deasy">—Because you don’t save, Mr Deasy said, pointing his finger.
               You don’tnow yet what money is. Money is power. When you have lived as long as I
               have. I know, I know. <reference to="proverb">If youth but knew</reference>.
                    <allusion who="William Shakespeare">But what does Shakespeare say? _Put but
                    money in thy purse._</allusion></said>

          <said who="Stephen">—Iago, Stephen murmured.</said>

          <p>He lifted his gaze from the idle shells to the old man’s stare.</p>

          <said who="Mr. Deasy">—He knew what money was, Mr Deasy said. He made money. A poet,
               yes, butn Englishman too. Do you know what is the pride of the English? Do you know
               what is the proudest word you will ever hear from an Englishman’s mouth?</said>

          <p>The seas’ ruler. His seacold eyes looked on the empty bay: it seems history is to
               blame: on me and on my words, unhating.</p>

          <said who="Stephen">—That on his empire, Stephen said, the sun never sets.</said>

          <said who="Mr. Deasy">—Ba! Mr Deasy cried. That’s not English. A French Celt said
               that. Heapped his savingsbox against his thumbnail.</said>

          <said who="Stephen">—I will tell you, he said solemnly, what is his proudest boast.
               _I paidy way._</said>

          <p>Good man, good man.</p>

          <said who="Stephen">—I paid my way. I never borrowed a shilling in my life._ Can you
               feel that? _I owe nothing._ Can you?</said>

          <p>Mulligan, nine pounds, three pairs of socks, one pair brogues, ties. Curran, ten
               guineas. <allusion who="James Joyce">McCann</allusion>, one guinea. <reference to="Irish economist and writer">Fred Ryan</reference>, two shillings. <allusion who="James Joyce">Temple</allusion>,
               two lunches. <allusion who="George William Russell">Russell</allusion>, one
               guinea, Cousins, ten shillings, Bob Reynolds, half a guinea, Koehler, three guineas,
               Mrs MacKernan, five weeks’ board. The lump I have is useless.</p>

          <said who="Stephen">—For the moment, no, Stephen answered.</said>

          <p>Mr Deasy laughed with rich delight, putting back his savingsbox.</p>

          <said who="Mr. Deasy">—I knew you couldn’t, he said joyously. But one day you must
               feel it.e are a generous people but we must also be just.</said>

          <said who="Stephen">—I fear those big words, Stephen said, which make us so
               unhappy.</said>

          <p>Mr Deasy stared sternly for some moments over the mantelpiece at the shapely bulk of a
               man in tartan fillibegs: <person who="Edward VII">Albert Edward, prince of
                    Wales.</person></p>

          <said who="Mr. Deasy">—You think me an old fogey and an old tory, his thoughtful
               voice said. saw three generations since <person who="Daniel O'Connell">O’Connell’s
                    time</person>. I remember the <reference to="Irish famine">famine</reference>
               in ’46. Do you know that the <reference to="Protestant">orange lodges</reference>
               agitated for <reference to="Act of the Union 1800">repeal of the union</reference>
               twenty years before O’Connell did or before <reference to="Roman Catholic Bishops">the prelates of your communion denounced him as a demagogue</reference>? You
                    <reference to="Fenians">fenians</reference> forget some things.</said>

          <p><reference to="Protestant">Glorious, pious and immortal memory</reference>. <reference to="Catholic v. Protestant conflict">The lodge of Diamond in Armagh the splendid
                    behung with corpses of papishes. Hoarse, masked and armed, the planters’
                    covenant. The black north and true blue bible.</reference>
               <reference to="Irish rebel">Croppies</reference> lie down.</p>

          <p>Stephen sketched a brief gesture.</p>

          <said who="Mr. Deasy">—I have rebel blood in me too, Mr Deasy said. On the spindle
               side. But I am descended from <person who="Sir John Blackwood">sir John Blackwood
                    who voted for the union.</person>
               <reference to="proverb">We are all Irish, all kings’ sons.</reference></said>

          <said who="Stephen">—Alas, Stephen said.</said>

          <said who="Mr. Deasy"><person who="Sir John Blackwood">—_Per vias
                    rectas_</person>, Mr Deasy said firmly, was his motto. He voted for it and
               put on his topboots to ride to Dublin from <reference to="Protestant">the Ards of
                    Down</reference> to do so. <reference to="Catholic">Lal the ral the ra The rocky
                    road to Dublin.</reference></said>

          <p>A gruff squire on horseback with shiny topboots. Soft day, sir John! Soft day, your
               honour!... Day!... Day!... Two topboots jog dangling on to Dublin. Lal the ral the
               ra. Lal the ral the raddy.</p>

          <said who="Mr. Deasy">—That reminds me, Mr Deasy said. You can do me a favour, Mr
               Dedalus, with some of your literary friends. I have a letter here for the press. Sit
               down a moment. I have just to copy the end.</said>

          <p>He went to the desk near the window, pulled in his chair twice and read off some words
               from the sheet on the drum of his typewriter.</p>

          <said who="Mr. Deasy">—Sit down. Excuse me, he said over his shoulder, _the dictates
               ofommon sense._ Just a moment.</said>

          <p>He peered from under his shaggy brows at the manuscript by his elbow and, muttering,
               began to prod the stiff buttons of the keyboard slowly, sometimes blowing as he
               screwed up the drum to erase an error.</p>

          <p>Stephen seated himself noiselessly before the princely presence. Framed around the
               walls images of vanished horses stood in homage, their meek heads poised in air:
                    <reference to="horse racing">lord Hastings’ _Repulse_, the duke of Westminster’s
                    _Shotover_, the duke of Beaufort’s _Ceylon_, _prix de Paris_, 1866.</reference>
               Elfin riders sat them, watchful of a sign. He saw their speeds, backing king’s
               colours, and shouted with the shouts of vanished crowds.</p>

          <said who="Mr. Deasy">—Full stop, Mr Deasy bade his keys. _But prompt ventilation of
               thisllimportant question..._</said>

          <p>Where Cranly led me to get rich quick, hunting his winners among the mudsplashed
               brakes, amid the bawls of bookies on their pitches and reek of the canteen, over the
               motley slush. <reference to="horse racing">Even money _Fair Rebel</reference>._ Ten
               to one the field. Dicers and thimbleriggers we hurried by after the hoofs, the vying
               caps and jackets and past the meatfaced woman, a butcher’s dame, nuzzling thirstily
               her clove of orange.</p>

          <p>Shouts rang shrill from the boys’ playfield and a whirring whistle.</p>

          <p>Again: a goal. I am among them, among their battling bodies in a medley, the joust of
               life. You mean that knockkneed mother’s darling who seems to be slightly crawsick?
               Jousts. Time shocked rebounds, shock by shock. Jousts, slush and uproar of battles,
               the frozen deathspew of the slain, a shout of spearspikes baited with men’s bloodied
               guts.</p>

          <said who="Mr. Deasy">—Now then, Mr Deasy said, rising.</said>

          <p>He came to the table, pinning together his sheets. Stephen stood up.</p>

          <said who="Mr. Deasy">—I have put the matter into a nutshell, Mr Deasy said. It’s
               about theoot and mouth disease. Just look through it. There can be no two opinions on
               the matter.</said>

          <p>May I trespass on your valuable space. That doctrine of _laissez faire_ which so often
               in our history. Our cattle trade. The way of all our old industries. <reference to="failed Irish harbour">Liverpool ring which jockeyed the Galway harbour
                    scheme.</reference>
               <reference to="European transatlantic shipping going through Galway">European
                    conflagration. Grain supplies through the narrow waters of the
                    channel.</reference> The pluterperfect imperturbability of the department of
               agriculture. Pardoned a classical allusion. <allusion to="Greek mythology">Cassandra.</allusion>
               <allusion to="Greek mythology">By a woman who was no better than she should
                    be.</allusion> To come to the point at issue.</p>

          <said who="Mr. Deasy">—I don’t mince words, do I? Mr Deasy asked as Stephen read
               on.</said>

          <p><reference to="disease">Foot and mouth disease</reference>. Known as <person who="Robert Koch">Koch’s preparation</person>. Serum and virus. <reference to="TB vaccine">Percentage of salted horses.</reference>
               <reference to="disease">Rinderpest.</reference>
               <person who="Dr. Richard Blaas">Emperor’s horses at Mürzsteg, lower
                    Austria.</person> Veterinary surgeons. Mr Henry Blackwood Price. Courteous
               offer a fair trial. Dictates of common sense. Allimportant question. In every sense
               of the word take the bull by the horns. Thanking you for the hospitality of your
               columns.</p>

          <said who="Mr. Deasy">—I want that to be printed and read, Mr Deasy said. You will
               see at the next outbreak they will put an embargo on Irish cattle. And it can be
               cured. It is cured. My cousin, Blackwood Price, writes to me it is regularly treated
               and cured in Austria by cattledoctors there. They offer to come over here. I am
               trying to work up influence with the department. Now I’m going to try publicity. I am
               surrounded by difficulties, by... intrigues by... backstairs influence by...</said>

          <p>He raised his forefinger and beat the air oldly before his voice spoke.</p>

          <said who="Mr. Deasy">—Mark my words, Mr Dedalus, he said. England is in the hands of
               theews. In all the highest places: her finance, her press. And they are the signs of
               a nation’s decay. Wherever they gather they eat up the nation’s vital strength. I
               have seen it coming these years. As sure as we are standing here the jew merchants
               are already at their work of destruction. Old England is dying.</said>

          <p>He stepped swiftly off, his eyes coming to blue life as they passed a broad sunbeam. He
               faced about and back again.</p>

          <said who="Mr. Deasy">—Dying, he said again, if not dead by now. <allusion who="William Blake">The harlot’s cry from street to street Shall weave old
                    England’s windingsheet</allusion>.</said>

          <p>His eyes open wide in vision stared sternly across the sunbeam in which he halted.</p>

          <said who="Stephen">—A merchant, Stephen said, is one who buys cheap and sells dear,
               jew orentile, is he not?</said>

          <said who="Mr. Deasy">—They sinned against the light, Mr Deasy said gravely. And you
               can seehe darkness in their eyes. And that is why they are <reference to="wandering Jews">wanderers on the earth </reference>to this day.</said>

          <p>On the steps of the Paris stock exchange the goldskinned men quoting prices on their
               gemmed fingers. Gabble of geese. <allusion to="Bible">They swarmed loud, uncouth
                    about the temple</allusion>, their heads thickplotting under maladroit silk
               hats. Not theirs: these clothes, this speech, these gestures. Their full slow eyes
               belied the words, the gestures eager and unoffending, but knew the rancours massed
               about them and knew their zeal was vain. Vain patience to heap and hoard. Time surely
               would scatter all. A hoard heaped by the roadside: plundered and passing on. Their
               eyes knew their years of wandering and, patient, knew the dishonours of their
               flesh.</p>

          <said who="Stephen">—Who has not? Stephen said.</said>

          <said who="Mr. Deasy">—What do you mean? Mr Deasy asked.</said>

          <p>He came forward a pace and stood by the table. His underjaw fell sideways open
               uncertainly. Is this old wisdom? He waits to hear from me.</p>

          <said who="Stephen"><allusion who="Jules Laforgue">—History, Stephen said, is a
                    nightmare from which I am trying to awake.</allusion></said>

          <p>From the playfield the boys raised a shout. A whirring whistle: goal. What if that
               nightmare gave you a back kick?</p>

          <said who="Mr. Deasy">—The ways of the Creator are not our ways, Mr Deasy said. All
               human history moves towards one great goal, the manifestation of God.</said>

          <p>Stephen jerked his thumb towards the window, saying:</p>

          <said who="Stephen">—That is God.</said>

          <p>Hooray! Ay! Whrrwhee!</p>

          <said who="Mr. Deasy">—What? Mr Deasy asked.</said>

          <said who="Stephen"><allusion to="Bible">—A shout in the street</allusion>, Stephen
               answered, shrugging his shoulders.</said>

          <p>Mr Deasy looked down and held for awhile the wings of his nose tweaked between his
               fingers. Looking up again he set them free.</p>

          <said who="Mr. Deasy">—I am happier than you are, he said. We have committed many
               errors and many sins. <allusion to="Bible">A woman brought sin into the
                    world.</allusion> For a woman who was no better than she should be, <allusion to="Greek mythology">Helen, the runaway wife of Menelaus, ten years the Greeks
                    made war on Troy.</allusion> A faithless wife first brought the strangers to our
               shore here, <person who="Dermod MacMurrough">MacMurrough’s wife and her leman,
                    O’Rourke, prince of Breffni.</person>
               <person who="Katherine O'Shea">A woman too brought Parnell low.</person> Many
               errors, many failures but not the one sin. I am a struggler now at the end of my
               days. But I will fight for the right till the end. <reference to="Protestant">For Ulster will fight And Ulster
               will be right.</reference></said>

          <p>Stephen raised the sheets in his hand.</p>

          <said who="Stephen">—Well, sir, he began.</said>

          <said who="Mr. Deasy">—I foresee, Mr Deasy said, that you will not remain here very
               long athis work. You were not born to be a teacher, I think. Perhaps I am
               wrong.</said>

          <said who="Stephen">—A learner rather, Stephen said.</said>

          <p>And here what will you learn more?</p>

          <p>Mr Deasy shook his head.</p>

          <said who="Mr. Deasy">—Who knows? he said. To learn one must be humble. But life is
               the greateacher.</said>

          <p>Stephen rustled the sheets again.</p>

          <said who="Stephen">—As regards these, he began.</said>

          <said who="Mr. Deasy">—Yes, Mr Deasy said. You have two copies there. If you can have
               themublished at once.</said>

          <p>_ Telegraph. Irish Homestead._</p>

          <said who="Stephen">—I will try, Stephen said, and let you know tomorrow. I know
               twoditors slightly.</said>

          <said who="Mr. Deasy">—That will do, Mr Deasy said briskly. I wrote last night to <person who="William Field">Mr
               Field, M.P.</person> There is a <reference to="Irish Cattle Traders and Stock Owners Association">meeting of the cattletraders’ association today at the City
               Arms hotel.</reference> I asked him to lay my letter before the meeting. You see if you can get
               it into your two papers. What are they?</said>

          <said who="Stephen">—The Evening Telegraph..._</said>

          <said who="Mr. Deasy">—That will do, Mr Deasy said. There is no time to lose. Now I
               have tonswer that letter from my cousin.</said>

          <said who="Stephen">—Good morning, sir, Stephen said, putting the sheets in his
               pocket.hank you.</said>

          <said who="Mr. Deasy">—Not at all, Mr Deasy said as he searched the papers on his
               desk. Iike to break a lance with you, old as I am.</said>

          <said who="Stephen">—Good morning, sir, Stephen said again, bowing to his bent
               back.</said>

          <p>He went out by the open porch and down the gravel path under the trees, hearing the
               cries of voices and crack of sticks from the playfield. The lions couchant on the
               pillars as he passed out through the gate: toothless terrors. Still I will help him
               in his fight. Mulligan will dub me a new name: the <allusion who="Homer">bullockbefriending bard.</allusion></p>

          <said who="Mr. Deasy">—Mr Dedalus!</said>

          <p>Running after me. No more letters, I hope.</p>

          <said who="Mr. Deasy">—Just one moment.</said>

          <said who="Stephen">—Yes, sir, Stephen said, turning back at the gate.</said>

          <p>Mr Deasy halted, breathing hard and swallowing his breath.</p>

          <said who="Mr. Deasy">—I just wanted to say, he said. Ireland, they say, has the
               honour ofeing the only country which never persecuted the jews. Do you know that? No.
               And do you know why?</said>

          <p>He frowned sternly on the bright air.</p>

          <said who="Stephen">—Why, sir? Stephen asked, beginning to smile.</said>

          <said who="Mr. Deasy">—<reference to="Jews in Ireland">Because she never let them in</reference>, Mr Deasy said solemnly.</said>

          <p>A coughball of laughter leaped from his throat dragging after it a rattling chain of
               phlegm. He turned back quickly, coughing, laughing, his lifted arms waving to the
               air.</p>

          <said who="Mr. Deasy">—She never let them in, he cried again through his laughter as
               he stamped on gaitered feet over the gravel of the path. That’s why.</said>

          <p>On his wise shoulders through the checkerwork of leaves the sun flung spangles, dancing
               coins.</p>
     </location>
</ulysses>