<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?><?xml-model href="teigeo1.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns:svg="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" xmlns:math="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"><teiHeader type="text"><fileDesc><titleStmt><title> An Account of the Voyages undertaken by the order of His present Majesty for
                    making Discoveries in the Southern Hemisphere, And successively performed by
                    Commodore Byron, Captain Wallis, Captain Carteret, and Captain Cook, In the
                    Dolphin, the Swallow, and the Endeavour: drawn up From the Journals which were
                    kept by the several Commanders, And from the Papers of Joseph Banks, Esq. 3
                    vols. London, 1773.</title><author role="primary">Hawkesworth, John</author><respStmt><resp>TEI-P5 XML Encoding by</resp><orgName>University of Pittsburgh Pacific Project Teams: Digital Archives and
                        Pacific Cultures.</orgName><persName>Elisa Beshero-Bondar</persName><persName>Gregory Bondar</persName><persName>Scott Morgan</persName><persName>Megan Hughes</persName></respStmt><respStmt><resp>with assistance in the Computational Methods in Humanities course at the
                        University of Pittsburgh in Spring 2013, from</resp><persName>David Birnbaum</persName><persName>Mary Zuzack</persName><persName>Eric Gratta</persName></respStmt></titleStmt><publicationStmt><p>London: printed for W. Strahan; and T. Cadell, 1773.</p></publicationStmt><sourceDesc><p>Eighteenth Century Collections Online Text Creation Partnership (ECCO TCP). Ann
                    Arbor, Michigan: University of Michigan Library 2009 April.</p></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text><body><div type="chapter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N"><head>CHAP. IV. The Passage from the Streight of Magellan, to King George the
                    Third's Island, called Otaheite, in the South Sea, with an account of the
                    Discovery of several other Islands, and a description of their
                    Inhabitants.</head><pb n="419"/><p n="3"><rs type="object"><date when="1767-04-12">AS we continued our course to the
                            westward</date>, after having cleared the Streight, we saw a great
                        number of gannets, sheerwaters, pintado birds, and many others,</rs> about
                    the ship, and had for the most part strong gales, hazy weather and heavy seas,
                    so that we were frequently brought under our courses, and there was not a dry
                    place in the ship for some weeks together.</p><p n="4">At <time when="08:00:00">eight in the morning</time><date when="1767-04-22">of the 22d</date>, we had an observation, by which we
                    found our longitude to be <geo select="lon" n="1">95° 46′ W</geo>. and at noon,
                    our latitude was <geo select="lat" n="1">42° 24′ S</geo>. and the variation, by
                    azimuth, 11° 6′ E.</p><p n="5"><date when="1767-04-24">By the 24th</date>, the men began to fall down very fast
                    in colds and fevers, in consequence of the upper works being open, and their
                    cloaths and beds continually wet.</p><p n="6"><date when="1767-04-26">On the 26th</date>, at <time when="16:00:00">four in the
                        afternoon</time>, the variation, by azimuth, was 10° 20′ E. and at <time when="06:00:00">six in the morning</time><date when="1767-04-28">of the next day</date>, it was 9° 8′ E. Our latitude, on
                    the <date when="1767-04-27">27th at noon</date>, was <geo select="lat" n="1">36°
                        54′ S</geo>. our longitude, by account, <geo select="lon" n="1">100°
                    W</geo>. <rs type="ship" subtype="health"><date when="1767-04-27">This
                            day</date>, the weather being moderate and fair, we dried all the
                        people's cloaths, and got the sick upon deck, to whom we gave salop,</rs><pb n="420"/>and wheat boiled with portable soup, every morning for breakfast,
                    and all the ship's company had as much vinegar and mustard as they could use;
                    portable soup was also constantly boiled in their pease and oatmeal.</p><p n="7">The hard gales, with frequent and violent squalls, and a heavy sea, soon
                    returned, and continued with very little intermission. The ship pitched so much,
                    that we were afraid she would carry away her masts, and the men were again wet
                    in their beds.</p><p n="8"><date when="1767-04-30">On the 30th</date>, the variation, by azimuth, was 8° 30′
                    E. our latitude was <geo select="lat" n="1">32° 50′</geo>; longitude, by
                    account, <geo select="lon" n="1">100′ W</geo>. I began now to keep the ship to
                    the northward, as we had no chance of getting westing in this latitude; and the
                    surgeon was of opinion, that in a little time the sick would so much increase,
                    that we should want hands to work the ship, if we could not get into better
                    weather.</p><p n="9"><date when="1767-05-03">On the third of May</date>, about <time when="16:00:00">four in the afternoon</time>, we had an observation of the sun and moon, by
                    which we found our longitude to be <geo select="lon">96° 26′ W</geo>. the
                    variation by the azimuth was 5° 44′ E. at <time when="18:00:00">six in the
                        evening</time>, and at <time when="06:00:00">six</time><date when="1767-05-04">the next morning</date>, it was <geo select="lon" n="1">5° 58′ E</geo>. Our latitude, <date when="1767-05-04">this day</date><time when="12:00:00">at noon</time>, was <geo select="lat" n="1">28° 20′
                        S</geo>. At <time when="16:00:00">four in the afternoon</time> we had
                    several observations for the longitude, and found it to be <geo select="lon">96°
                        21′ W</geo>.; at <time when="19:00:00">seven in the evening</time>, the
                    variation was 6° 40′ E. by the azimuth, and <date when="1767-05-05">the next
                        morning</date><time when="10:00:00">at 10</time> it was, by amplitude, 5° 48′ E.; at <time when="15:00:00">three in the afternoon</time>, the variation, by amplitude,
                    was 7° 40′ E. <date when="1767-05-05">This day</date><rs type="object">we saw a tropic bird</rs>.</p><p n="10">At <time when="06:00:00">six o'clock in the morning</time>, of <date when="1767-05-08">Friday the eighth of May</date>, the variation of the
                    needle, by amplitude, was 7° 11′ E. In the afternoon we saw several sheerwaters
                    and sea swallows. At <time when="08:00:00">eight in the morning</time> of the
                    9th, <date when="1767-05-09"/> the variation by <pb n="421"/>azimuth was 6° 34′
                    E. and in the morning of <date when="1767-05-11">the 11th</date>, by azimuth and
                    amplitude, it was 40° 40′ E. Our latitude was <geo select="lat" n="1">27° 28′
                        S</geo>. longitude, by account, <geo select="lon" n="1">106° W</geo>.<date when="1767-05-11"> This day</date>, <date when="1767-05-12">and the
                        next</date>, we saw several sea swallows, sheerwaters, and porpoises, about
                    the ship.</p><p n="11"><date when="1767-05-14">On the 14th of May</date>, the variation, by four
                    azimuths, was 2° E. <time when="16:00:00">About four o'clock in the
                        afternoon</time>, <rs type="object">we saw a large flock of brown birds,
                        slying to the eastward,</rs> and something which had the appearance of high
                    land, in the same quarter. We bore away for it till sun-set, and it still having
                    the same appearance, we continued our course; but at <time when="02:00:00">two
                        in the morning</time>, having run 18 leagues without making it, we hauled
                    the wind, and at <date when="1767-05-15">day-light</date> nothing was to be
                    seen. We had now the satisfaction to find our ailing people mend apace. Our
                    latitude was <geo select="lat" n="1">24° 50′ S</geo>. our longitude, by account,
                        <geo select="lon" n="1">106° W</geo>. During all this time, we were looking
                    out for the Swallow.</p><p n="12">At <time when="16:00:00">four in the afternoon</time> of <date when="1767-05-16">the 16th</date>, the variation, by azimuth and amplitude, was 6° E. and at
                        <time when="06:00:00">six</time> the <date when="1767-05-17">next
                        morning</date>, by four azimuths, it was 3° 20′.</p><p n="13">The carpenters were now employed in caulking the upper works of the ship, and
                    repairing and painting the boats, and <date when="1767-05-18">on the
                    18th</date>, I gave a sheep among the people that were sick and recovering.</p><p n="14"><date when="1767-05-20">On Wednesday the 20th</date>, we found our longitude, by
                    observation, to be <geo select="lon" n="1">106° 47′ W</geo>. and our latitude
                        <geo select="lat" n="1">20° 52′ S</geo>.</p><p n="15"><date when="1767-05-21">The next day</date> we saw several flying fish, which
                    were the first we had seen in these seas.</p><p n="16"><date when="1767-05-22">On the 22d</date>, our longitude, by observation, was
                        <geo select="lon" n="1">111° W</geo>. and our latitude <geo select="lat" n="1">20° 18′ S</geo>. and this day <rs type="object">we saw some bonettoes,
                        dolphins, and tropic birds.</rs></p><pb n="422"/><p n="17">The people who had been recovering from colds and fevers, now began to fall down
                    in the scurvy, upon which, at the surgeon's representation, wine was served to
                    them: wort was also made for them of malt, and each man had half a pint of
                    pickled cabbage every day. The variation from 4 to 5 E.</p><p n="18"><date when="1767-05-26">On the 26th</date> we saw two grampuses; <date when="1767-05-28">on the 28th</date> we saw another, <date when="1767-05-29">and the next day</date><rs type="object">several birds, among which was <rs type="ship" subtype="animalsighting">one about the size of a swallow, which some of
                            us thought was a land bird</rs></rs>.</p><p n="19"> Our men now began to look very pale and sickly, and to fall down very fast in
                    the scurvy, notwithstanding all our care and attention to prevent it. They had
                    vinegar and mustard without limitation, wine instead of spirits, sweet wort and
                    salop. Portable soup was still constantly boiled in their peas and oatmeal;
                    their birth and cloaths were kept perfectly clean; the hammocks were constantly
                    brought upon the deck at eight o'clock in the morning, and carried down at four
                    in the afternoon. Some of the beds and hammocks were washed every day; the water
                    was rendered wholesome by ventilation, and every part between decks frequently
                    washed with vinegar.</p><p n="20"><date when="1767-05-31">On Sunday the 31st of May</date>, our longitude, by
                    observation, was <geo select="lon" n="1">127° 45′ W</geo>. our latitude <geo select="lat" n="1">29° 38′ S</geo>. and the variation, by azimuth and
                    amplitude, 5° 9′ E.</p><p n="21"><date when="1767-06-01">The next day</date>, at <time when="15:00:00">three in
                        the afternoon</time>, our longitude, by observation, was <geo select="lon" n="1">129° 15′ W</geo>. and our latitude <geo select="lat" n="1">19° 34′
                        S</geo>.<time type="ship" subtype="weather"> We had squally weather, with
                        much lightning and rain,</time><rs type="object">and saw several men of war birds.</rs></p><p n="22"><date when="1767-06-03">On the 3d</date>, we saw several gannets, which, with the
                    uncertainty of the weather, inclined us to hope that land was not <pb n="423"/>very far distant. <date when="1767-06-04">The next day</date><rs type="object">a turtle swam close by the ship;</rs><date when="1767-06-05">on the 5th</date><rs type="object">we saw many birds,</rs> which confirmed our hope that some
                    place of refreshment was near, and at <time when="11:00:00">11 o'clock</time> in
                    the forenoon of <date when="1767-06-06">the 6th</date>, <persName>Jonathan
                        Puller</persName>, a seaman, called out from the mast-head, "Land in the W.
                    N. W." <time when="12:00:00">At noon</time> it was seen plainly from the deck,
                    and found to be a low island, at about five or six leagues distance. The joy
                    which every one on board felt at this discovery, can be conceived by those only
                    who have experienced the danger, sickness, and fatigue of such a voyage as we
                    had performed.</p><p n="23">When we were within about five miles of this island, we saw another, bearing N.
                    W. by W. About <time when="15:00:00">three o'clock in the afternoon</time>,
                    being very near the island that was first discovered, we brought to, and I sent
                        <persName>Mr. Faurneaux</persName>, my second lieutenant, my first
                    lieutenant being very ill, with the boats manned and armed, to the shore. As he
                    approached it, we saw two canoes put off, and paddle away with great expedition
                    towards the island that lay to leeward. <rs type="scout" subtype="island"><time when="19:00:00">At seven in the evening</time> the boats returned, and
                        brought with them several cocoa nuts, and a considerable quantity of
                        scurvy-grass;</rs><rs type="object">they brought also some fish hooks, that were made of
                        oyster-shells, and some of the shells of which they were made</rs>. They
                    reported that they had seen none of the inhabitants, but had visited three huts,
                    or rather sheds, consisting only of a roof, neatly thatched with cocoa nut and
                    palm leaves, supported upon posts, and open all round. They saw also several
                    canoes building, but found no fresh water, nor any fruit but cocoa nuts. They
                    sounded, but found no anchorage, and it was with great difficulty that they got
                    on shore, as the surf ran very high. Having received this account, I stood off
                    and on all night, and <date when="1767-06-07">early the next morning</date> I
                    sent the boats out again to sound, with orders, if possible, to find a place
                    where the ship might come to an <pb n="424"/>anchor; but at <time when="11:00:00">11 o'clock</time> they returned, with no better success than
                    before. The people told me that the whole island was surrounded by a reef, and
                    that although on the weather side of the island there was an opening through it,
                    into a large bason, that extended to the middle of the island, yet they found it
                    so full of breakers, that they could not venture in; neither indeed had they
                    been able to land on any part of the island, the surf running still higher than
                    it had done the day before. As it would therefore answer no purpose to continue
                    here, I hoisted the boats in, and stood away for the other island, which bore S.
                    22° E. distant about four leagues. The island which I now quitted, having been
                    discovered on Whitsun-eve, I called it <placeName>WHITSUN ISLAND</placeName>. It
                    is about four miles long, and three wide. Its latitude is <geo select="lat" n="1">19° 26′ S</geo>. and its longitude, by observation, <geo select="lon" n="1">137° 56′ W</geo>.</p><p n="24">When we came under the lee of the other island, I sent <persName>Lieutenant
                        Furneaux</persName>, with the boats manned and armed, to the shore, where I
                    saw about fifty of the natives armed with long pikes, and several of them
                    running about with firebrands in their hands. I ordered <persName>Mr.
                        Furneaux</persName> to go to that part of the beach where we saw the people,
                    and endeavour to traffick with them for fruit and water, or whatever else might
                    be useful; at the same time, being particularly careful to give them no offence.
                    I ordered him also to employ the boats in sounding for anchorage. About <time when="19:00:00">seven o'clock</time> he returned, and told me that he could
                    find no ground with the line, till he came within half a cable's length of the
                    shore, and that there it consisted of sharp rocks, and lay very deep.</p><p n="25"><rs type="interact">As the boat approached the shore, the Indians thronged down
                        towards the beach, and put themselves upon their guard with their long
                        pikes, as if to dispute the landing.</rs><rs type="island" subtype="natives" ana="trade">Our men then lay upon their oars, and made signs of friendship,
                            <pb n="425"/>shewing at the same time several strings of beads, ribands,
                        knives, and other trinkets. The Indians still made signs to our people that
                        they should depart, but at the same time eyed the trinkets with a kind of
                        wishful curiosity. Soon after some of them advanced a few steps into the
                        sea, and our people making signs that they wanted cocoa nuts and water, some
                        of them brought down a small quantity of both, and ventured to hand them
                        into the boat: the water was in cocoa nut-shells, and the fruit was stripped
                        of its outward covering, which is probably used for various purposes. For
                        this supply they were paid with the trinkets that had been shewed them, and
                        some nails, upon which they seemed to set a much greater value.</rs><rs type="interact" subtype="conflict">During this traffick, one of the Indians
                        found means to steal a silk handkerchief, in which some of our small
                        merchandize was wrapped up, and carried it clear off, with its contents, so
                        dexterously, that no body observed him. Our people made signs that a
                        handkerchief had been stolen, but they either could not, or would not
                        understand them.</rs> The boat continued about the beach, sounding for
                    anchorage, till it was dark; and having many times endeavoured to persuade the
                    natives to bring down some scurvy-grass, without success, she returned on
                    board.</p><p n="26">I stood off and on with the ship all night, and as soon as <date when="1767-06-08">the day</date> broke, I sent the boats again, with orders
                    to make a landing, but without giving any offence to the natives, that could
                    possibly be avoided. <rs type="interact">When our boats came near the shore, the
                        officer was greatly surprised to see seven large canoes, with two stout
                        masts in each, lying just in the surf, with all the inhabitants upon the
                        beach, ready to embark. They made signs to our people to go higher up; they
                        readily complied, and as soon as they went ashore, all the Indians embarked,
                        and sailed away to the westward, being joined <pb n="426"/>by two other
                        canoes at the west end of the island.</rs><time when="12:00:00">About noon</time>, the boats returned, laden with cocoa
                    nuts, palm nuts, and scurvy-grass. <persName>Mr. Furneaux</persName>, who
                    commanded the expedition, told me that the Indians had left nothing behind them
                    but four or five canoes. He found a well of very good water, and described the
                    island as being sandy and level, full of trees, but without underwood, and
                    abounding with scurvy-grass. <rs type="concept" subtype="pac">The canoes, which
                        steered about W. S. W. as long as they could be seen from the mast-head,
                        appeared to be about thirty feet long, four feet broad, and three and an
                        half deep. Two of these being brought along side of each other, were
                        fastened together, at the distance of about three feet asunder, by cross
                        beams, passing from the larboard gunwale of one, to the starboard gunwale of
                        the other, in the middle and near to each end.</rs></p><p n="27">The inhabitants of this island were of a middle stature, and dark complexion,
                    with long black hair, which hung loose over their shoulders. The men were well
                    made, and the women handsome. Their cloathing was a kind of coarse cloth or
                    matting, which was fastened about their middle, and seemed capable of being
                    brought up round their shoulders.</p><p n="28">In the afternoon, I sent <persName>Lieutenant Furneaux</persName> with the boats
                    again on shore. He had with him a mate and twenty men, who were to make a
                    rolling way for getting the casks down to the beach from the well. I gave orders
                    that he should take possession of the island, in the name of <persName>King
                        George the Third</persName>, and give it the name of <placeName>QUEEN
                        CHARLOTTE's ISLAND</placeName>, in honour of her Majesty. The boats returned
                    freighted with cocoa nuts and scurvy-grass, and the officer told me that he had
                    found two more wells of good water, not far from the beach. I was at this time
                    very ill, yet I went ashore with the Surgeon, and several of the people, <pb n="427"/>who were enfeebled by the scurvy, to take a walk. I found the wells
                    so convenient, that I left the mate and twenty men on shore to fill water, and
                    ordered a week's provisions to be sent them from the ship, they being already
                    furnished with arms and ammunition. In the evening I returned on board, with the
                    Surgeon and the sick, leaving only the waterers on shore. As we had not been
                    able to find any anchorage, I stood off and on all night.</p><p n="29"><date when="1767-06-09">In the morning</date>, I sent all the empty water casks
                    on shore: the Surgeon and the sick were also sent for the benefit of another
                    airing, but I gave them strict orders that they should keep near the water-side,
                    and in the shade; that they should not pull down or injure any of the houses,
                    nor, for the sake of the fruit, destroy the cocoa trees, which I appointed
                    proper persons to climb. <time when="12:00:00">At noon</time>, the rolling-way
                    being made, the cutter returned laden with water, but it was with great
                    difficulty got off the beach, as it is all rock, and the surf that breaks upon
                    it, is often very great. <time when="16:00:00">At four</time>, I received
                    another boat-load of water, and a fresh supply of cocoa nuts, palm nuts, and
                    scurvy-grass; the Surgeon also returned with the sick men, who received much
                    benefit from their walk. <date when="1767-06-10">The next morning</date>, as
                    soon as it was light, <rs type="island" subtype="provisions">I dispatched orders
                        to the mate, to send all the water that was filled on board, and to be ready
                        to come off with his people when the boats should return again, bringing
                        with them as many cocoa nuts, and as much scurvy-grass as they could
                        procure. About eight o'clock, all the boats and people came on board, with
                        the water and refreshments, but the cutter, in coming off, shipped a sea,
                        which almost filled her with water: the barge was happily near enough to
                        assist her, by taking great part of her crew on board, while the rest freed
                        her, without any other damage than the loss of the cocoa nuts, and greens
                        that were on <pb n="428"/>board.</rs><time when="12:00:00">At noon</time>, I hoisted the boats in, and there being a
                    great sea, with a dreadful surf rolling in upon the shore, and no anchorage, I
                    thought it prudent to leave this place, with such refreshments as we had got.
                        <rs type="object">The people who had resided on shore, saw no appearance of
                        metal of any kind, but several tools, which were made of shells and stones,
                        sharpened and fitted into handles, like adzes, chissels, and awls. They saw
                        several canoes building, which are formed of planks, sewed together, and
                        fastened to several small timbers, that pass transversely along the bottom
                        and up the sides.</rs> They saw several repositories of the dead, in which
                    the body was left to putrefy under a canopy, and not put into the ground.</p><p n="30"><rs type="interact" subtype="imp">When we sailed, we left a union jack flying
                        upon the island, with the ship's name, the time of our being here, and an
                        account of our taking possession of this place, and Whitsun Island, in the
                        name of his Britannic Majesty, cut on a piece of wood, and in the bark of
                        several trees.We also left some hatchets, nails, glass bottles, beads,
                        shillings, sixpences, and halfpence, as presents to the natives, and an
                        atonement for the disturbance we had given them.</rs><placeName>Queen Charlotte's Island</placeName> is about six miles long, and one
                    mile wide, lies in latitude <geo select="lat" n="1">19° 18′ S</geo>. longitude,
                    by observation, <geo select="lon" n="1">138° 4′ W</geo>. and we found the
                    variation here to be 4° 46′ E.</p><p n="31">We made sail with a fine breeze, and <time when="13:00:00">about one
                        o'clock</time>, saw an island W. by S. <placeName>Queen Charlotte's
                        Island</placeName>, at this time bearing E. by N. distant 15 miles. <time when="15:30:00">At half an hour after three</time>, we were within about
                    three quarters of a mile of the east end of the island, and ran close along the
                    shore, but had no soundings. The east and west ends are joined to each other by
                    a reef of rocks, over which the sea breaks into a lagoon, in the middle of the
                    island, which, therefore, had <pb n="429"/>the appearance of two islands, and
                    seemed to be about six miles long, and four broad. The whole of it is low land,
                    full of trees, but we saw not a single cocoa nut, nor any huts: <rs type="interact">we found, however, at the westermost end, all the canoes and
                        people who had fled, at our approach, from <placeName>Queen Charlotte's
                            Island</placeName>, and some more. We counted eight double canoes, and
                        about, fourscore people, men, women, and children. The canoes were drawn
                        upon the beach, the women and children were placed near them, and the men
                        advanced with their pikes and firebrands, making a great noise, and dancing
                        in a strange manner.</rs> We observed that this island was sandy, and that
                    under the trees there was no verdure. As the shore was every where rocky, as
                    there was no anchorage, and as we had no prospect of obtaining any refreshment
                    here, I set sail at <time when="18:00:00">six o'clock</time> in the evening,
                    from this island, to which I gave the name of <placeName>EGMONT
                        ISLAND</placeName>, in honour of the Earl of Egmont, who was then first Lord
                    of the Admiralty. It lies in latitude <geo select="lat" n="1">19° 20′ S</geo>.
                    longitude, by observation, <geo select="lon" n="1">138° 30′ W</geo>.</p><p n="32">At <time when="13:00:00">one o'clock</time>, <date when="1767-06-11">on the
                        11th</date>, we saw an island in the W. S. W. and stood for it. <time when="16:00:00">At four in the afternoon</time>, we were within a quarter of
                    a mile of the shore, and ran along it, sounding continually, but could get no
                    ground. It is surrounded on every side by rocks, on which the sea breaks very
                    high. It is full of trees, but not one cocoa nut, and has much the same
                    appearance with <placeName>Egmont island</placeName>, but is much narrower.
                    Among the rocks, at the west end, we saw about sixteen of the natives, but no
                    canoes: they carried long pikes or poles in their hands, and seemed to be, in
                    every respect, the same kind of people that we had seen before. As nothing was
                    to be had here, and it blew very hard, I made sail <time when="20:00:00">till
                        eight in the evening</time>, and then brought to. To this island, which is
                    about six miles long, and from <pb n="430"/>one mile to one quarter of a mile
                    broad, I gave the name of <placeName>GLOUCESTER ISLAND</placeName>, in honour of
                    his Royal Highness the Duke. It lies in latitude <geo select="lat" n="1">19° 11′
                        S</geo>. and longitude, by observation, <geo select="lon" n="1">140° 4′
                        W</geo>.</p><p n="33">At <time when="05:00:00">five o'clock in the morning</time>, we made sail, <rs type="ship" subtype="landsighting">and soon after saw another island</rs>.
                        <time when="10:00:00">At 10 o'clock</time>, the weather being tempestuous,
                    with much rain, we saw a long reef, with breakers on each side of the island,
                    and therefore brought the ship to, with her head off the shore. To this island,
                    which lies in latitude <geo select="lat" n="1">19° 18′ S</geo>. longitude, by
                    observation, <geo select="lon" n="1">140° 36′ W</geo>. I gave the name of
                        <placeName>CUMBERLAND ISLAND</placeName>, in honour of his Royal Highness
                    the Duke. It lies low, and is about the same size as <placeName>Queen
                        Charlotte's Island</placeName>. We found the variation of the needle here to
                    be 7° 10′ E. As I had no hope of finding any refreshment here, I stood on to the
                    westward.</p><p n="34">At day-break, on <date when="1767-06-13">Saturday the 13th</date>, <rs type="ship" subtype="landsighting">we saw another small low island, in the
                        N. N. W. right to windward. It had the appearance of small flat keys.</rs>
                    This place I called <placeName>PRINCE WILLIAM HENRY's ISLAND</placeName>, in
                    honour of his Majesty's third son. It lies in latitude <geo select="lat" n="1">19° S</geo>. longitude, by observation, <geo select="lon" n="1">141° 6′
                        W</geo>. I made no stay here, hoping, that to the westward I should find
                    higher land, where the ship might come to an anchor, and such refreshments as we
                    wanted be procured.</p><p n="35">Soon after day-light, <date when="1767-06-17">on the 17th</date>, we saw land
                    bearing W. by N. and making in a small round hummock. <time when="12:00:00">At
                        noon</time>, when it bore N. 64. W. distant about five leagues, its
                    appearance greatly resembled the Mewstone in <placeName>Plymouth
                        Sound</placeName>, but it seemed to be much larger. We found the ship this
                    day, 20 miles to the northward of her reckoning, which I imputed to a great S.
                    W. swell.</p><pb n="431"/><p n="36">At <time when="17:00:00">five in the evening</time>, this island bore N. W.
                    distant about eight miles. I then hauled the wind, and stood on and off all
                    night. <time when="22:00:00">At ten</time>, we saw a light upon the shore,
                    which, though the island was small, proved that it was inhabited, and gave us
                    hopes that we should find anchorage near it. We observed with great pleasure,
                    that the land was very high, and covered with cocoa trees; a sure sign that
                    there was water.</p><p n="37"><rs type="interact" subtype="trade"><date when="1767-06-18">The next
                            morning</date>, I sent <persName>Lieutenant Furneaux</persName> to the
                        shore, with the boats manned and armed, and all kinds of trinkets, to
                        establish a traffick with the natives, for such refreshment as the place
                        would afford. I gave him orders also to find, if possible, an anchoring
                        place for the ship. While we were getting out the boats, several canoes put
                        off from the island, but as soon as the people on board saw them make
                        towards the shore, they put back. At noon, the boats returned, and brought
                        with them a pig and a cock, with a few plantains and cocoa nuts.
                            <persName>Mr. Furneaux</persName> reported, that he had seen at least an
                        hundred of the inhabitants, and believed there were many more upon the
                        island; but that having been all round it, he could find no anchorage, nor
                        scarcely a landing-place for the boat. When he reached the shore, he came to
                        a grapling, and threw a warp to the Indians upon the beach, who caught it
                        and held it fast. He then began to converse with them by signs, and observed
                        that they had no weapon among them, but that some of them had white sticks,
                        which seemed to be ensigns of authority, as the people who bore them kept
                        the rest of the natives back. In return for the pig and the cock, he gave
                        them some beads, a looking-glass, a few combs, with several other trinkets,
                        and a hatchet. The women, who had been kept at a distance, as soon as they
                        saw the trinkets, ran down in a croud to the beach, with great eagerness,
                        but were soon driven away by <pb n="432"/>the men, at which they expressed
                        much disappointment and vexation.</rs><rs type="interact" subtype="conflict">While this traffick was carrying on, a
                        man came secretly round a rock, and diving down, took up the boat's
                        grappling, and at the same time, the people on shore who held the warp, made
                        an effort to draw her into the surf.</rs> As soon as this was perceived by
                    the people on board, they fixed a musket over the man's head who had taken up
                    the grappling, upon which he instantly let it go, with marks of great terror and
                    astonishment; the people on shore also let go the rope. The boats after this,
                    lay some time upon their oars, but the officer finding that he could get nothing
                    more, returned on board. <persName>Mr. Furneaux</persName> told me that both the
                    men and women were cloathed, and he brought a piece of their cloth away with
                    him. The inhabitants appeared to him to be more numerous than the island could
                    support, and for this reason, especially as he saw some large double canoes upon
                    the beach, he imagined there were islands of larger extent, not far distant,
                    where refreshments in greater plenty might be procured, and hoped that they
                    might be less difficult of access. As I thought this a reasonable conjecture, I
                    hoisted in the boats, and determined to run farther to the westward. To this
                    place, which is nearly circular, and about two miles over, I gave the name of
                        <placeName>OSNABURGH ISLAND</placeName>, in honour of <persName>Prince
                        Frederick</persName>, who is bishop of that see. It lies in latitude 17°
                        <geo select="lat" n="1">51′ S</geo>. and longitude <geo select="lon" n="1">147° 30′ W</geo>.; the variation here was 7° 10′ E.</p></div><div type="chapter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N"><head>CHAP. V. An Account of the Discovery of King George the Third's Island, or
                    Otaheite, and of several Incidents which happened both on board the Ship, and on
                    Shore.</head><pb n="433"/><p n="38">AT <time when="14:00:00">two o'clock</time>, <date when="1767-06-18">the same
                        day</date>, we bore away, and in about half an hour, discovered very high
                    land in the W. S. W. At <time when="19:00:00">seven in the evening</time>,
                        <placeName>Osnaburgh Island</placeName> bore E. N. E. and the new discovered
                    land, from W. N. W. to W. by S. As the weather was thick and squally, we brought
                    to for the night, or at least till the fog should break away. At <time when="02:00:00">two in the morning</time>, it being very clear, we made sail
                    again; <date when="1767-06-19">at day-break</date> we saw the land, at about
                    five leagues distance, and steered directly for it; but at <time when="08:00:00">eight o'clock</time>, when we were close under it, <rs type="interact">the
                        fog obliged us again to lie to, and when it cleared away, we were much
                        surprised to find ourselves surrounded by some hundreds of canoes. They were
                        of different sizes, and had on board different numbers, from one to ten, so
                        that in all of them together, there could not be less than eight hundred
                        people. When they came within pistol shot of the ship, they lay by, gazing
                        at us with great astonishment, and by turns conferring with each other. In
                        the mean time we shewed them trinkets of various kinds, and invited them on
                        board. Soon after, they drew together, and held a kind of council, to
                        determine what should be done: then they all paddled round the ship, making
                        signs of friendship, and one of them holding up a branch of the plantain
                        tree, made a speech that lasted near a quarter of an <pb n="434"/>hour, and
                        then threw it into the sea. Soon after, as we continued to make signs of
                        invitation, a fine, stout, lively young man ventured on board: he came up by
                        the mizen chains, and jumped out of the shrouds upon the top of the awning.
                        We made signs to him to come down upon the quarter-deck, and handed up some
                        trinkets to him: he looked pleased, but would accept of nothing till some of
                        the Indians came along side, and after much talk, threw a few branches of
                        plantain tree on board the ship. He then accepted our presents, and several
                        others very soon came on board, at different parts of the ship, not knowing
                        the proper entrance. As one of these Indians was standing near the gang-way,
                        on the larboard side of the quarter-deck, one of our goats butted him upon
                        the haunches: being surprised at the blow, he turned hastily about, and saw
                        the goat raised upon his hind-legs, ready to repeat the blow. The appearance
                        of this animal, so different from any he had ever seen, struck him with such
                        terror, that he instantly leaped over board; and all the rest, upon seeing
                        what had happened, followed his example with the utmost precipitation: they
                        recovered however, in a short time, from their fright, and returned on
                        board. After having a little reconciled them to our goats and sheep, I
                        shewed them our hogs and poultry, and they immediately made signs that they
                        had such animals as these. I then distributed trinkets and nails among them,
                        and made signs that they should go on shore and bring us some of their hogs,
                        fowls and fruit, but they did not seem to understand my meaning: they were,
                        in the mean time, watching an opportunity to steal some of the things that
                        happened to lie in their way, but we generally detected them in the
                        attempt.</rs><rs type="interact" subtype="conflict">At last, however, one of the midshipmen
                        happened to come where they were standing, with a new laced hat upon his
                        head, and began to talk to <pb n="435"/>one of them by signs: while he was
                        thus engaged, another of them came behind him, and suddenly snatching off
                        the hat, leaped over the taffarel into the sea, and swam away with it.</rs></p><p n="39">As we had no anchorage here, we stood along the shore, sending the boats at the
                    same time to sound at a less distance. As none of these canoes had sails, they
                    could not keep up with us, and therefore soon paddled back towards the shore.
                    The country has the most delightful and romantic appearance that can be
                    imagined: towards the sea it is level, and is covered with fruit trees of
                    various kinds, particularly the cocoa nut. Among these are the houses of the
                    inhabitants, consisting only of a roof, and at a distance having greatly the
                    appearance of a long barn. The country within, at about the distance of three
                    miles, rises into lofty hills, that are crowned with wood, and terminate in
                    peaks, from which large rivers are precipitated into the sea. We saw no shoals,
                    but found the island skirted by a reef of rocks, through which there are several
                    openings into deep water. About three o'clock in the afternoon, we brought to,
                    a-breast of a large bay, where there was an appearance of anchorage. The boats
                    were immediately sent to sound it, and while they were thus employed, I observed
                    a great number of canoes gather round them. I suspected that the Indians had a
                    design to attack them, and as I was very desirous to prevent mischief, I made
                    the signal for the boats to come aboard, and at the same time, to intimidate the
                    Indians, I fired a nine pounder over their heads. <rs type="interact" subtype="conflict">As soon as the cutter began to stand towards the ship,
                        the Indians in their canoes, though they had been startled by the thunder of
                        our nine pounder, endeavoured to cut her off. The boat, however, sailing
                        faster than the canoes could paddle, soon got clear of those that were about
                        her; but some others, that <pb n="436"/>were full of men, way-laid her in
                        her course, and threw several stones into her, which wounded some of the
                        people. Upon this, the officer on board fired a musquet, loaded with
                        buck-shot, at the man who threw the first stone, and wounded him in the
                        shoulder. The rest of the people in the canoes, as soon as they perceived
                        their companion wounded, leapt into the sea, and the other canoes paddled
                        away, in great terror and confusion.</rs> As soon as the boats reached the
                    ship, they were hoisted on board, and just as she was about to stand on, we
                    observed a large canoe, under sail, making after us. As I thought she might have
                    some Chief on board, or might have been dispatched to bring me a message from
                    some Chief, I determined to wait for her. She sailed very fast, and was soon
                    along side of the ship, but we did not observe among those on board, any one
                    that seemed to have an authority over the rest. One of them, however, stood up,
                    and having made a speech, which continued about five minutes, threw on board a
                    branch of the plantain tree. We understood this to be a token of peace, and we
                    returned it, by handing over one of the branches of plantain that had been left
                    on board by our first visitors: with this and some toys, that were afterwards
                    presented to him, he appeared to be much gratified, and after a short time, went
                    away.</p><p n="40">The officers who had been sent out with the boats, informed me that they had
                    sounded close to the reef, and found as great a depth of water as at the other
                    islands: however, as I was now on the weather side of the island, I had reason
                    to expect anchorage in running to leeward. I therefore took this course, but
                    finding breakers that ran off to a great distance from the south-end of the
                    island, I hauled the wind, and continued turning to windward all night, in order
                    to run down on the east side of the island.</p><pb n="437"/><p n="41">At <time when="05:00:00">five o'clock</time><date when="1767-06-20">in the morning</date>, we made sail, the land bearing N.
                    W. by W. distant 10 leagues; and there seemed to be land five leagues beyond it,
                    to the N. E.; a remarkable peak, like a sugar loaf, bore N. N. E. when we were
                    about two leagues from the shore, which afforded a most delightful prospect, and
                    was full of houses and inhabitants. We saw several large canoes near the shore,
                    under sail, but they did not steer towards the ship. <time when="12:00:00">At
                        noon</time>, we were within two or three miles of the island, and it then
                    bore from S. ¾ W. to N. W. by W. We continued our course along the shore,
                    sometimes at the distance of half a mile, and sometimes at the distance of four
                    or five miles, but hitherto had got no soundings. <time when="18:00:00">At six
                        o'clock in the evening</time>, we were a-breast of a fine river, and the
                    coast having a better appearance here than in any other part that we had seen, I
                    determined to stand off and on all night, and try for anchorage in the morning.
                    As soon as it was dark, we saw a great number of lights all along the shore.
                        <date when="1767-06-21">At day-break</date>, we sent out the boats to sound,
                    and soon after, they made the signal for 20 fathom. This produced an universal
                    joy, which it is not easy to describe, and we immediately ran in, and came to an
                    anchor in 17 fathom, with a clear sandy bottom. We lay about a mile distant from
                    the shore, opposite to a fine run of water; the extreams of the land bearing
                    from E. S. E. to N. W. by W. As soon as we had secured the ship, I sent the
                    boats to sound along the coast, and look at the place where we saw the water.
                        <rs type="interact" subtype="trade">At this time, a considerable number of
                        canoes came off to the ship, and brought with them hogs, fowls, and fruit in
                        great plenty, which we purchased for trinkets and nails.</rs><rs type="interact" subtype="conflict">But when the boats made towards the
                        shore, the canoes, most of which were double, and very large, sailed after
                        them. At first they kept at a distance, but as the boats approached the <pb n="438"/>shore, they grew bolder, and at last three of the largest ran
                        at the cutter, staved in her quarter, and carried away her out-rigger, the
                        Indians preparing at the same time to board her, with their clubs and
                        paddles in their hands. Our people being thus pressed, were obliged to fire,
                        by which one of the assailants was killed, and another much wounded. Upon
                        receiving the shot, they both fell overboard, and all the people who were in
                        the same canoe, instantly leaped into the sea after them: the other two
                        canoes dropped a-stern, and our boats went on without any farther
                        interruption. As soon as the Indians, who were in the water, saw that the
                        boats stood on without attempting to do them any farther hurt, they
                        recovered their canoe, and hauled in their wounded companions. They set them
                        both upon their feet to see if they could stand, and finding they could not,
                        they tried whether they could sit upright: one of them could, and him they
                        supported in that posture, but perceiving that the other was quite dead,
                        they laid the body along at the bottom of the canoe.</rs> After this some of
                    the canoes went ashore, and others returned again to the ship to traffick, which
                    is a proof that our conduct had convinced them that while they behaved peaceably
                    they had nothing to fear, and that they were conscious they had brought the
                    mischief which had just happened upon themselves.</p><p n="42">The boats continued sounding <time when="12:00:00">till noon</time>, when they
                    returned with an account that the ground was very clear; that it was at the
                    depth of five fathom, within a quarter of a mile of the shore, but that there
                    was a very great surf where we had seen the water. The officers told me, that
                    the inhabitants swarmed upon the beach, and that many of them swam off to the
                    boat with fruit, and bamboos filled with water. They said that they were very
                    importunate with them to come on shore, particularly the women, who came down to
                    the <pb n="439"/>beach, and stripping themselves naked, endeavoured to allure
                    them by many wanton gestures, the meaning of which could not possibly be
                    mistaken. At this time, however, our people resisted the temptation.</p><p n="43">In the afternoon, I sent the boats again to the shore, with some barecas, or
                    small casks, which are filled at the head, and have a handle by which they are
                    carried, to endeavour to procure some water, of which we began to be in great
                    want. In the mean time, many of the canoes continued about the ship, but the
                    Indians had been guilty of so many thefts, that I would not suffer any more of
                    them to come on board.</p><p n="44"><rs type="interact" subtype="conflict">At five in the evening, the boats returned
                        with only two barecas of water, which the natives had filled for them; and
                        as a compensation for their trouble, they thought fit to detain all the
                        rest. Our people, who did not leave their boat, tried every expedient they
                        could think of to induce the Indians to return their water vessels, but
                        without success; and the Indians, in their turn, were very pressing for our
                        people to come on shore, which they thought it prudent to decline.</rs>
                    There were many thousands of the inhabitants of both sexes, and a great number
                    of children on the beach, when our boats came away.</p><p n="45"><date when="1767-06-22">The next morning</date>, <rs type="interact" subtype="trade">I sent the boats on shore again for water, with nails,
                        hatchets, and such other things as I thought most likely to gain the
                        friendship of the inhabitants. In the mean time, a great number of canoes
                        came off to the ship, with bread-fruit*, plantains, a fruit resembling an
                        apple only better, fowls, and hogs, which we purchased with beads, nails,
                        knives, and other articles of the like kind, so <pb n="440"/>that we
                        procured pork enough to serve the ship's company two days, at a pound a
                        man.</rs></p><p n="46">When the boats returned, they brought us only a few calibashes of water, for the
                    number of people on the beach was so great, that they would not venture to land,
                    though the young women repeated the allurements which they had practised the day
                    before, with still more wanton, and, if possible, less equivocal gestures. Fruit
                    and provisions of various kinds were brought down and ranged upon the beach, of
                    which our people were also invited to partake, as an additional inducement for
                    them to leave the boat. They continued, however, inexorable, and shewing the
                    Indians the barecas on board, made signs that they should bring down those which
                    had been detained the day before: to this the Indians were inexorable in their
                    turn, and our people therefore weighed their grapplings, and sounded all round
                    the place, to see whether the ship could come in near enough to cover the
                    waterers, in which case they might venture on shore, in defiance of the whole
                    island. When they put off, the women pelted them with apples and bananas,
                    shouting, and shewing every mark of derision and contempt that they could
                    devise. They reported, that the ship might ride in four fathom water, with sandy
                    ground, at two cables' length from the shore, and in five fathom water at three
                    cables' length. The wind here blew right along the shore, raising a great surf
                    on the side of the vessel, and on the beach.</p><p n="47">At day-break, <date when="1767-06-23">the next morning</date>, we weighed, with a
                    design to anchor off the watering-place. As we were standing off, to get farther
                    to windward, we discovered a bay about six or eight miles to leeward, over the
                    land, from the <pb n="441"/>mast-head, and immediately bore away for it, sending
                    the boats a-head to sound. At <time when="09:00:00">nine o'clock</time>, the
                    boats making the signal for 12 fathom, we hauled round a reef, and stood in,
                    with a design to come to an anchor; but when we came near the boats, one of
                    which was on each bow, the ship struck. Her head continued immoveable, but her
                    stern was free; and, upon casting the lead, we found the depth of water, upon
                    the reef or shoal, to be from 17 fathom to two and a half: we clewed all up as
                    fast as possible, and cleared the ship of what lumber there happened to be upon
                    the deck, at the same time getting out the long-boat, with the stream and kedge
                    anchors, the stream cable and hauser, in order to carry them without the reef,
                    that when they had taken ground, the ship might be drawn off towards them, by
                    applying a great force to the capstern, but unhappily without the reef we had no
                    bottom. Our condition was now very alarming, the ship continued beating against
                    the rock with great force, and we were surrounded by many hundred canoes, full
                    of men: they did not, however, attempt to come on board us, but seemed to wait
                    in expectation of our shipwreck. In the anxiety and terror of such a situation
                    we continued near an hour, without being able to do any thing for our
                    deliverance, except staving some water casks in the fore-hold, when a breeze
                    happily springing up from the shore, the ship's head swung off. We immediately
                    pressed her with all the sail we could make; upon which she began to move, and
                    was very soon once more in deep water.</p><p n="48">We now stood off, and the boats being sent to leeward, found that the reef ran
                    down to the westward about a mile and a half, and that beyond it there was a
                    very good harbour. The master, after having placed a boat at the end of the
                    reef, and furnished the long-boat with anchor and hausers, <pb n="442"/>and a
                    guard to defend her from an attack of the Indians, came on board, and piloted
                    the ship round the reef into the harbour, where, about <time when="12:00:00">twelve o'clock</time>, she came to an anchor in 17 fathom water, with a
                    fine bottom of black sand. </p><p n="49">The place where the ship struck appeared, upon farther examination, to be a reef
                    of sharp coral rock, with very unequal soundings, from six fathom to two; and it
                    happened unfortunately to lie between the two boats that were placed as a
                    direction to the ship, the weathermost boat having 12 fathom, and the
                    leewardmost nine. The wind freshened almost as soon as we got off, and though it
                    soon became calm again, the surf ran so high, and broke with such violence upon
                    the rock, that if the ship had continued fast half an hour longer, she must
                    inevitably have been beaten to pieces. Upon examining her bottom, we could not
                    discover that she had received any damage, except that a small piece was beaten
                    off the bottom of the rudder. She did not appear to admit any water, but the
                    trussle-trees, at the head of all the masts, were broken short, which we
                    supposed to have happened while she was beating against the rock. Our boats lost
                    their grapplings upon the reef, but as we had reason to hope that the ship was
                    sound, they gave us very little concern. As soon as the ship was secured, I sent
                    the master, with all the boats manned and armed, to sound the upper part of the
                    bay, that if he found good anchorage we might warp the ship up within the reef,
                    and anchor her in safety. The weather was now very pleasant, a great number of
                    canoes were upon the reef, and the shore was crouded with people.</p><p n="50">About <time when="16:00:00">four in the afternoon</time> the master returned, and
                    reported, that there was every where good anchorage; I therefore determined to
                    warp the ship up the bay early in <pb n="443"/>the morning, and in the mean
                    time, I put the people at four watches, one watch to be always under arms;
                    loaded and primed all the guns, fixed musquetoons in all the boats, and ordered
                    all the people who were not upon the watch, to repair to the quarters assigned
                    them, at a moment's warning there being a great number of canoes, some of them
                    very large, and full of men, hovering upon the shore, <rs type="interact" subtype="trade">and many smaller venturing to the ship, with hogs, fowls,
                        and fruit, which we purchased of them, much to the satisfaction of both
                        parties;</rs> and at sun-set, all the canoes rowed in to the shore. </p><p n="51">At <time when="06:00:00">six o'clock</time><date when="1767-06-24">the next morning</date>, we began to warp the ship up
                    the harbour, and soon after, a great number of canoes came under her stern.<rs type="ship" subtype="trade"> As I perceived that they had hogs, fowls, and
                        fruit on board, I ordered the gunner, and two midshipmen, to purchase them
                        for knives, nails, beads, and other trinkets, at the same time prohibiting
                        the trade to all other persons on board.</rs> By <time when="08:00:00">eight
                        o'clock</time>, the number of canoes was greatly increased, and those that
                    came last up were double, of a very large size, with twelve or fifteen stout men
                    in each. <rs type="interact" subtype="conflict">I observed, with some concern,
                        that they appeared to be furnished rather for war than trade, having very
                        little on board except round pebble stones; I therefore sent for
                            <persName>Mr. Furneaux</persName>, my first lieutenant being still very
                        ill, and ordered him to keep the fourth watch constantly at their arms,
                        while the rest of the people were warping the ship. In the mean time more
                        canoes were continually coming off from the shore, which were freighted very
                        differently from the rest, for they had on board a number of women who were
                        placed in a row, and who, when they came near the ship, made all the wanton
                        gestures that can be conceived. While these ladies were practising their
                        allurements, the large canoes, which were freighted with <pb n="444"/>stones, drew together very close round the ship, some of the men on board
                        singing in a hoarse voice, some blowing conchs, and some playing on a flute.
                        After some time, a man who sat upon a canopy that was fixed on one of the
                        large double canoes, made signs that he wished to come up to the ship's
                        side; I immediately intimated my consent, and when he came along side, he
                        gave one of the men a bunch of red and yellow feathers, making signs that he
                        should carry it to me. I received it with expressions of amity, and
                        immediately got some trinkets to present him in return, but to my great
                        surprise he had put off to a little distance from the ship, and upon his
                        throwing up the branch of a cocoa-nut tree, there was an universal shout
                        from all the canoes, which at once moved towards the ship, and a shower of
                        stones was poured into her on every side. As an attack was now begun, in
                        which our arms only could render us superior to the multitude that assailed
                        us, especially as great part of the ship's company was in a sick and feeble
                        condition, I ordered the guard to fire; two of the quarter-deck guns, which
                        I had loaded with small shot, were also fired nearly at the same time, and
                        the Indians appeared to be thrown into some confusion: in a few minutes,
                        however, they renewed the attack, and all our people that were able to come
                        upon deck, having by this time got to their quarters, I ordered them to fire
                        the great guns, and to play some of them constantly at a place on shore,
                        where a great number of canoes were still taking in men, and pushing off
                        towards the ship with the utmost expedition. When the great guns began to
                        fire, there were not less than three hundred canoes about the ship, having
                        on board at least two thousand men; many thousands were also upon the shore,
                        and more canoes coming from every quarter: the firing, however, soon drove
                        away the canoes that were about the ship, and put a stop to the <pb n="445"/>coming off of others. As soon as I saw some of them retreating, and the
                        rest quiet, I ordered the firing to cease, hoping that they were
                        sufficiently convinced of our superiority, not to renew the contest. In
                        this, however, I was unhappily mistaken: a great number of the canoes that
                        had been dispersed, soon drew together again, and lay some time on their
                        paddles, looking at the ship from the distance of about a quarter of a mile,
                        and then suddenly hoisting white streamers, pulled towards the ship's stern,
                        and began again to throw stones, with great force and dexterity, by the help
                        of slings, from a considerable distance: each of these stones weighed about
                        two pounds, and many of them wounded the people on board, who would have
                        suffered much more, if an awning had not been spread over the whole deck to
                        keep out the sun, and the hammocks placed in the nettings. At the same time
                        several canoes, well manned, were making towards the ship's bow, having
                        probably taken notice that no shot had been fired from this part: I
                        therefore ordered some guns forward, to be well pointed and fired at these
                        canoes; at the same time running out two guns abaft, and pointing them well
                        at the canoes that were making the attack. Among the canoes that were coming
                        toward the bow, there was one which appeared to have some Chief on board, as
                        it was by signals made from her, that the others had been called together:
                        it happened that a shot, fired from the guns forward, hit this canoe so full
                        as to cut it asunder. As soon as this was observed by the rest, they
                        dispersed with such haste that in half an hour there was not a single canoe
                        to be seen; the people also who had crouded the shore, immediately fled over
                        the hills with the utmost precipitation.</rs></p><p n="52">Having now no reason to fear any further interruption, we warped the ship up the
                    harbour, and <time when="12:00:00">by noon</time>, we were <pb n="446"/>not more
                    than half a mile from the upper part of the bay, within less than two cables'
                    length of a fine river, and about two and a half of the reef. We had here nine
                    fathom water, and close to the shore there were five. We moored the ship, and
                    carried out the stream-anchor, with the two shroud hausers, for a spring, to
                    keep the ship's broad-side a-breast of the river; we also got up and mounted the
                    eight guns which had been put into the hold. As soon as this was done, the boats
                    were employed in sounding all round the bay, and in examining the shore where
                    any of the inhabitants appeared, in order to discover, whether it was probable
                    that they would give us any further disturbance. All the afternoon, and <date when="1767-06-25">part of the next morning</date>, was spent in this
                    service; and <time when="12:00:00">about noon</time>, the master returned, with
                    a tolerable survey of the place, and reported, that there were no canoes in
                    sight; that there was good landing on every part of the beach; that there was
                    nothing in the bay from which danger could be apprehended, except the reef, and
                    some rocks at the upper end, which appeared above water; and that the river,
                    though it emptied itself on the other side of the point, was fresh water.</p><p n="53">Soon after the master had brought me this account, I sent <persName>Mr.
                        Furneaux</persName> again, with all the boats manned and armed, the marines
                    being also put on board, with orders to land opposite to our station, and secure
                    himself, under cover of the boats and the ship, in the clearest ground he could
                    find. About <time when="14:00:00">two o'clock</time> the boats landed without
                    any opposition, and <persName>Mr. Furneaux</persName> stuck up a staff, upon
                    which he hoisted a pendant, turned a turf, and took possession of the island in
                    his Majesty's name, in honour of whom he called it <placeName>KING GEORGE THE
                        THIRD's ISLAND</placeName>: he then went to the river, and tasted the water,
                    which he found excellent, and mixing some of it with rum, every man drank his
                    Majesty's health. <pb n="447"/><rs type="interact" subtype="affin">While he was
                        at the river, which was about twelve yards wide, and fordable, he saw two
                        old men on the opposite side of it, who perceiving that they were
                        discovered, put themselves in a supplicatory posture, and seemed to be in
                        great terror and confusion. <persName>Mr. Furneaux</persName> made signs
                        that they should come over the river, and one of them complied. When he
                        landed, he came forward, creeping upon his hands and knees, but
                            <persName>Mr. Furneaux</persName> raised him up, and while he stood
                        trembling, shewed him some of the stones that were thrown at the ship, and
                        endeavoured to make him apprehend that if the natives attempted no mischief
                        against us, we should do no harm to them. He ordered two of the water casks
                        to be filled, to shew the Indian that we wanted water, and produced some
                        hatchets, and other things, to intimate that he wished to trade for
                        provisions. The old man, during this pantomimical conversation, in some
                        degree recovered his spirits; and <persName>Mr. Furneaux</persName>, to
                        confirm his professions of friendship, gave him a hatchet, some nails,
                        beads, and other trifles; after which he reimbarked on board the boats, and
                        left the pendant flying. As soon as the boats were put off, the old man went
                        up to the pendant, and danced round it a considerable time: he then retired,
                        but soon after returned with some green boughs, which he threw down, and
                        retired a second time: it was not long, however, before he appeared again,
                        with about a dozen of the inhabitants, and putting themselves in a
                        supplicating posture, they all approached the pendant in a slow pace, but
                        the wind happening to move it, when they were got close to it, they suddenly
                        retreated with the greatest precipitation. After standing some time at a
                        distance, and gazing at it, they went away, but in a short time came back,
                        with two large hogs alive, which they laid down at the foot of the staff,
                        and at length taking courage, they began to dance. When they had performed
                            <pb n="448"/>this ceremony, they brought the hogs down to the water
                        side, launched a canoe, and put them on board. The old man, who had a large
                        white beard, then embarked with them alone, and brought them to the ship:
                        when he came along side, he made a set speech, and afterwards handed in
                        several green plantain leaves, one by one, uttering a sentence, in a solemn
                        slow tone, with each of them as he delivered it; after this he sent on board
                        the two hogs, and then turning round, pointed to the land. I ordered some
                        presents to be given him, but he would accept of nothing; and soon after put
                        off his canoe, and went on shore.</rs></p><p n="54">At night, soon after it was dark, we heard the noise of many drums, with conchs,
                    and other wind instruments, and saw a multitude of lights all along the coast.
                        <time when="06:00:00">At six</time><date when="1767-06-26">in the morning</date>, seeing none of the natives on
                    shore, and observing that the pendant was taken away, which probably they had
                    learnt to despise, as the frogs in the fable did King Log, I ordered the
                    lieutenant to take a guard on shore, and if all was well, to send off, that we
                    might begin watering: in a short time I had the satisfaction to find that he had
                    sent off for water casks, and <time when="08:00:00">by eight o'clock</time>, we
                    had four tons of water on board. <rs type="interact" subtype="affin">While our
                        people were employed in filling the casks, several of the natives appeared
                        on the opposite side of the river, with the old man whom the officer had
                        seen the day before; and soon after he came over, and brought with him a
                        little fruit, and a few fowls, which were also sent off to the ship.</rs> At
                    this time, having been very ill for near a fortnight, I was so weak that I could
                    scarcely crawl about; however, I employed my glasses to see what was doing on
                    shore. <rs type="interact" subtype="conflict"><time when="08:30:00">At near half
                            an hour after eight o'clock</time>, I perceived a multitude of the
                        natives coming over a hill at about the distance of a mile, and at the same
                        time a great number of canoes making round the western point, and <pb n="449"/>keeping close along the shore. I then looked at the
                        watering-place, and saw at the back of it, where it was clear, a very
                        numerous party of the natives creeping along behind the bushes; I saw also
                        many thousands in the woods, pushing along towards the watering-place, and
                        canoes coming very fast round the other point of the bay to the eastward.
                        Being alarmed at these appearances, I dispatched a boat, to acquaint the
                        officer on shore with what I had seen, and order him immediately to come on
                        board with his men, and leave the casks behind him: he had, however,
                        discovered his danger, and embarked before the boat reached him. Having
                        perceived the Indians that were creeping towards him under shelter of the
                        wood, he immediately dispatched the old man to them, making signs that they
                        should keep at a distance, and that he wanted nothing but water. As soon as
                        they perceived that they were discovered, they began to shout, and advanced
                        with greater speed. The officer immediately repaired to the boats with his
                        people, and the Indians, in the mean time having crossed the river, took
                        possession of the water casks, with great appearance of exultation and joy.
                        The canoes now pulled along the shore, towards the place, with the utmost
                        expedition, all the people on land keeping pace with them, except a
                        multitude of women and children, who seated themselves upon a hill which
                        overlooked the bay and the beach. The canoes from each point of the bay, as
                        they drew nearer to that part of it where the ship was at anchor, put on
                        shore, and took in more men, who had great bags in their hands, which
                        afterwards appeared to be filled with stones. All the canoes that had come
                        round the points, and many others that had put off from the shore within the
                        bay, now made towards the ship, so that I had no doubt but that they
                        intended to try <pb n="450"/>their fortune in a second attack. As to shorten
                        the contest would certainly lessen the mischief, I determined to make this
                        action decisive, and put an end to hostilities at once; I therefore ordered
                        the people, who were all at their quarters, to fire first upon the canoes
                        which were drawn together in groups: this was immediately done so
                        effectually, that those which were to the westward made towards the shore as
                        fast as possible, and those to the eastward, getting round the reef, were
                        soon beyond the reach of our guns. I then directed the fire into the wood in
                        different parts, which soon drove the Indians out of it, who ran up the hill
                        where the women and children had seated themselves to see the battle. Upon
                        this hill there were now several thousands who thought themselves in perfect
                        security; but to convince them of the contrary, and hoping that when they
                        saw the shot fall much farther than they could think possible, they would
                        suppose it could reach them at any distance, I ordered some of the guns to
                        be let down as low as they would admit, and fired four shot towards them.
                        Two of the balls fell close by a tree where a great number of these people
                        were fitting, and struck them with such terror and consternation, that in
                        less than two minutes not one of them was to be seen. Having thus cleared
                        the coast, I manned and armed the boats, and putting a strong guard on
                        board, I sent all the carpenters with their axes, and ordered them to
                        destroy every canoe that had been run ashore. Before noon, this service was
                        effectually performed, and more than fifty canoes, many of which were sixty
                        feet long, and three broad, and lashed together, were cut to pieces. Nothing
                        was found in them but stones and slings, except a little fruit, and a few
                        fowls and hogs, which were on board two or three canoes of a much smaller
                        size.</rs></p><pb n="451"/><p n="55">At <time when="14:00:00">two o'clock in the afternoon</time>, <rs type="interact" subtype="trade">about ten of the natives came out of the wood with green
                        boughs in their hands, which they stuck up near the water side, and retired.
                        After a short time, they appeared again, and brought with them several hogs,
                        with their legs tied, which they placed near the green boughs, and retired a
                        second time. After this they brought down several more hogs, and some dogs,
                        with their fore legs tied over their heads, and going again into the woods,
                        brought back several bundles of the cloth which they use for apparel, and
                        which has some resemblance to Indian paper. These they placed upon the
                        beach, and called to us on board to fetch them away. As we were at the
                        distance of about three cables' length, we could not then perfectly discover
                        of what this peace-offering consisted: we guessed at the hogs and the cloth,
                        but seeing the dogs, with their fore legs appearing over the hinder part of
                        the neck, rise up several times, and run a little way in an erect posture,
                        we took them for some strange unknown animal, and were very impatient to
                        have a nearer view of them. The boat was therefore sent on shore with all
                        expedition, and our wonder was soon at an end. Our people found nine good
                        hogs, besides the dogs and the cloth: the hogs were brought off, but the
                        dogs were turned loose, and with the cloth left behind. In return for the
                        hogs, our people left upon the shore some hatchets, nails, and other things,
                        making signs to some of the Indians who were in sight, to take them away
                        with their cloth. Soon after the boat had come on board, the Indians brought
                        down two more hogs, and called to us to fetch them; the boat therefore
                        returned, and fetched off the two hogs, but still left the cloth, though the
                        Indians made signs that we should take it. Our people reported, that they
                        had not touched any of the things which <pb n="452"/>they had left upon the
                        beach for them, and somebody suggesting that they would not take our
                        offering because we had not accepted their cloth, I gave orders that it
                        should be fetched away. The event proved that the conjecture was true, for
                        the moment the boat had taken the cloth on board, the Indians came down, and
                        with every possible demonstration of joy, carried away all I had sent them
                        into the wood.</rs> Our boats then went to the watering-place, and filled
                    and brought off all the casks, to the amount of about six tons. We found that
                    they had suffered no injury while they had been in the possession of the
                    Indians, but some leathern buckets and funnels which had been taken away with
                    the casks, were not returned.</p><p n="56"><date when="1767-06-27">The next morning</date><rs type="interact" subtype="affin">I sent the boats on shore, with a guard, to
                        fill some more casks with water, and soon after the people were on shore,
                        the same old man who had come over the river to them the first day, came
                        again to the farther side of it, where he made a long speech, and then
                        crossed the water. When he came up to the waterers, the officer shewed him
                        the stones that were piled up like cannon balls upon the shore, and had been
                        brought thither since our first landing, and some of the bags that had been
                        taken out of the canoes which I had ordered to be destroyed, filled with
                        stones, and endeavoured to make him understand that the Indians had been the
                        aggressors, and that the mischief we had done them was in our own defence.
                        The old man seemed to apprehend his meaning, but not to admit it: he
                        immediately made a speech to the people, pointing to the stones, slings, and
                        bags, with great emotion, and sometimes his looks, gestures, and voice were
                        so furious as to be frightful. His passions, however, subsided by degrees,
                        and the officer, who to his great regret could not understand one <pb n="453"/>word of all that he had said, endeavoured to convince him, by
                        all the signs he could devise, that we wished to live in friendship with
                        them, and were disposed to shew them every mark of kindness in our power. He
                        then shook hands with him, and embraced him, giving him at the same time
                        several such trinkets as he thought would be most acceptable. He contrived
                        also to make the old man understand that we wished to traffick for
                        provisions, that the Indians should not come down in great numbers, and that
                        they should keep on one side of the river and we on the other.</rs><rs type="interact" subtype="trade">After this the old man went away with great
                        appearance of satisfaction, and before noon a trade was established, which
                        furnished us with hogs, fowls, and fruit in great abundance, so that all the
                        ship's company, whether sick or well, had as much as they could use.</rs></p></div><div org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N"><head>CHAP. VI. The Sick sent on Shore, and a regular Trade established with the
                    Natives; some Account of their Character and Manners, of their Visits on board
                    the Ship, and a Variety of Incidents that happened during this
                    Intercourse.</head><pb n="454"/><p n="57">MATTERS being thus happily settled, I sent the Surgeon, with the Second
                    Lieutenant, to examine the country, and fix upon some place where the sick might
                    take up their residence on shore. When they returned, they said, that with
                    respect to health and convenience, all the places that they had seen upon the
                    island seemed to be equally proper; but that with respect to safety, they could
                    recommend none but the watering-place, as they would be there under the
                    protection of the ship and the guard, and would easily be prevented from
                    straggling into the country, and brought off to their meals. To the
                    watering-place therefore I sent them, with those that were employed in filling
                    the casks, and appointed the gunner to command the party that was to be their
                    guard. A tent was erected for them as a shelter both from the sun and the rain,
                    and the Surgeon was sent to superintend their conduct, and give his advice if it
                    should be wanted. <rs type="interact" subtype="affin">It happened that walking
                        out with his gun, after he had seen the sick properly disposed of in the
                        tent, a wild duck flew over his head, which he shot, and it fell dead among
                        some of the natives who were on the other side of the river. This threw them
                        into a panic, and <pb n="455"/>they all ran away: when they got to some
                        distance they stopped, and he made signs to them to bring the duck over:
                        this one of them at last ventured to do, and, pale and trembling, laid it
                        down at his feet. Several other ducks happening at the instant to fly over
                        the spot where they were standing, he fired again, and fortunately brought
                        down three more. This incident gave the natives such a dread of a gun, that
                        if a musquet was pointed at a thousand of them, they would all run away like
                        a flock of sheep; and probably the ease with which they were afterwards kept
                        at a distance, and their orderly behaviour in their traffick, was in a great
                        measure owing to their having upon this occasion seen the instrument of
                        which before they had only felt the effects.</rs></p><p n="58"><rs type="interact" subtype="trade">As I foresaw that a private traffick would
                        probably commence between such of our people as were on shore, and the
                        natives, and that if it was left to their own caprice, perpetual quarrels
                        and mischief would ensue, I ordered that all matters of traffick should be
                        transacted by the gunner, on behalf of both parties, and I directed him to
                        see that no injury was done to the natives, either by violence or fraud, and
                        by all possible means to attach the old man to his interest.</rs><rs type="island" subtype="theft"> This service he performed with great
                        diligence and fidelity, nor did he neglect to complain of those who
                        transgressed my orders, which was of infinite advantage to all parties; for
                        as I punished the first offenders with a necessary severity, many
                        irregularities, that would otherwise have produced the most disagreeable
                        consequences, were prevented: we were also indebted for many advantages to
                        the old man, whose caution kept our people perpetually upon their guard, and
                        soon brought back those who straggled from the party. The natives would
                        indeed sometimes pilfer, but by the terror of a gun, without using it, he
                        always found means to make them bring back what was stolen. A fellow had one
                        day the <pb n="456"/>dexterity and address to cross the river unperceived,
                        and steal a hatchet; the gunner, as soon as he missed it, made the old man
                        understand what had happened, and got his party ready, as if he would have
                        gone into the woods after the thief: the old man, however, made signs that
                        he would save him the trouble, and immediately setting off, returned in a
                        very short time with the hatchet. The gunner then insisted that the offender
                        should be delivered up, and with this also the old man, though not without
                        great reluctance, complied. When the fellow was brought down, the gunner
                        knew him to be an old offender, and therefore sent him prisoner on board. I
                        had no intention to punish him otherwise, than by the fear of punishment,
                        and therefore, after great entreaty and intercession, I gave him his
                        liberty, and sent him on shore.</rs><rs type="interact" subtype="affin">When the natives saw him return in safety,
                        it is hard to say whether their astonishment or joy was greatest; they
                        received him with universal acclamations, and immediately carried him off
                        into the woods: the next day, however, he returned, and as a propitiation to
                        the gunner, he brought him a considerable quantity of bread-fruit, and a
                        large hog, ready roasted.</rs></p><p n="59">At this time, the people on board were employed in caulking and painting the
                    weather-work, over-hauling the rigging, stowing the hold, and doing other
                    necessary business, but my disorder, which was a bilious cholic, increased so
                    much, that this day I was obliged to take to my bed; my First Lieutenant also
                    still continued very ill, and the Purser was incapable of his duty. The whole
                    command devolved upon <persName>Mr. Furneaux</persName>, the Second Lieutenant,
                    to whom I gave general directions, and recommended a particular attention to the
                    people on shore. I also ordered that fruit and fresh provisions should be served
                    to the ship's company as long as they could be procured, and that the boats
                    should never be <pb n="457"/>absent from the ship after sun-set. These
                    directions were fulfilled with such prudence and punctuality, that during all my
                    sickness I was not troubled with any business, nor had the mortification to hear
                    a single complaint or appeal. The men were constantly served with fresh pork,
                    fowls, and fruit, in such plenty, that when I left my bed, after having been
                    confined to it near a fortnight, my ship's company looked so fresh and healthy,
                    that I could scarcely believe them to be the same people.</p><p n="60"><date when="1767-06-28">Sunday the 28th</date> was marked by no incident; but on
                        <date when="1767-06-29">Monday the 29th</date>, <rs type="interact">one of
                        the gunner's party found a piece of saltpetre near as big as an egg. As this
                        was an object of equal curiosity and importance, diligent enquiry was
                        immediately made from whence it came. The surgeon asked every one of the
                        people on shore, separately, whether he had brought it from the ship; every
                        one on board also was asked whether he had carried it on shore, but all
                        declared that they had never had such a thing in their possession.
                        Application was then made to the natives, but the meaning of both parties
                        was so imperfectly conveyed by signs, that nothing could be learnt of them
                        about it: during our whole stay here, however, we saw no more than this one
                        piece.</rs></p><p n="61">While the gunner was trafficking for provisions on shore, we sometimes hauled the
                    seine, but we caught no fish; we also frequently crawled, but with no better
                    success: the disappointment, however, was not felt, for the produce of the
                    island enabled our people to "fare sumptuously every day."</p><p n="62">All matters continued in the same situation till the <date when="1767-07-02">2d
                        of July</date>, when our old man being absent, the supply of fresh
                    provisions and fruit fell short; we had, however, enough to <pb n="458"/>serve
                    most of the messes, reserving plenty for the sick and convalescent.</p><p n="63"><date when="1767-07-03">On the 3d</date>, we heeled the ship, and looked at her
                    bottom, which we found as clean as when she came out of dock, and to our great
                    satisfaction, as sound. <rs type="interact" subtype="affin">During all this
                        time, none of the natives came near our boats, or the ship, in their canoes.
                        This day, about noon, we caught a very large shark, and when the boats went
                        to fetch the people on board to dinner, we sent it on shore. When the boats
                        were putting off again, the gunner seeing some of the natives on the other
                        side of the river, beckoned them to come over; they immediately complied,
                        and he gave them the shark, which they soon cut to pieces, and carried away
                        with great appearance of satisfaction.</rs></p><p n="64"><date when="1767-07-05">On Sunday the 5th</date>, the old man returned to the
                    market-tent, and made the gunner understand that he had been up the country, to
                    prevail upon the people to bring down their hogs, poultry, and fruit, of which
                    the parts near the watering-place were now nearly exhausted. <rs type="interact" subtype="trade">The good effects of his expedition soon appeared, for
                        several Indians, whom our people had never seen before, came in with some
                        hogs that were larger than any that had been yet brought to market. In the
                        mean time, the old man ventured off in his canoe, to the ship, and brought
                        with him, as a present to me, a hog ready roasted. I was much pleased with
                        his attention and liberality, and gave him, in return for his hog, an iron
                        pot, a looking-glass, a drinking-glass, and several other things, which no
                        man in the island was in possession of but himself.</rs></p><p n="65"><rs type="interact" subtype="trade">While our people were on shore, several young
                        women were permitted to cross the river, who, though they were not averse to
                        the granting of personal favours, knew the <pb n="459"/>value of them too
                        well not to stipulate for a consideration</rs>: the price, indeed, was not
                    great, yet it was such as our men were not always able to pay, and under this
                    temptation they stole nails and other iron from the ship. The nails that we
                    brought for traffick, were not always in their reach, and therefore they drew
                    several out of different parts of the vessel, particularly those that fastened
                    the cleats to the ship's side. This was productive of a double mischief; damage
                    to the ship, and a considerable rise at market. When the gunner offered, as
                    usual, small nails for hogs of a middling size, the natives refused to take
                    them, and produced large spikes, intimating that they expected such nails as
                    these. A most diligent enquiry was set on foot to discover the offenders, but
                    all to no purpose; and though a large reward was offered to procure
                    intelligence, none was obtained. I was mortified at the disappointment, but I
                    was still more mortified at a fraud which I found some of our people had
                    practised upon the natives. When no nails were to be procured, they had stolen
                    lead, and cut it up in the shape of nails. Many of the natives who had been paid
                    with this base money, brought their leaden nails, with great simplicity, to the
                    gunner, and requested him to give them iron in their stead. With this request,
                    however reasonable, he could not comply; because, by rendering lead current, it
                    would have encouraged the stealing it, and the market would have been as
                    effectually spoiled by those who could not procure nails, as by those who could;
                    it was therefore necessary, upon every account, to render this leaden currency
                    of no value, though for our honour I should have been glad to have called it
                    in.</p><p n="66"><date when="1767-07-07">On Tuesday the 7th</date>, <rs type="interact" subtype="trade">I sent one of the mates, with thirty men, to a village at a
                        little distance from the market, hoping <pb n="460"/>that refreshments might
                        there be bought at the original price; but here they were obliged to give
                        still more than at the water-side.</rs> In the mean time, being this day
                    able to get up for the first time, and the weather being fine, I went into a
                    boat, and rowed about four miles down the coast. I found the country populous,
                    and pleasant in the highest degree, and saw many canoes on the shore; but not
                    one came off to us, nor did the people seem to take the least notice of us as we
                    passed along. About noon I returned to the ship.</p><p n="67"><rs type="ship" subtype="punishment">The commerce which our men had found means
                        to establish with the women of the island, rendered them much less obedient
                        to the orders that had been given for the regulation of their conduct on
                        shore, than they were at first. I found it necessary therefore, to read the
                        articles of war, and I punished <persName>James Proctor</persName>, the
                        corporal of marines, who had not only quitted his station, and insulted the
                        officer, but struck the Master at Arms such a blow as brought him to the
                        ground.</rs></p><p n="68"><date when="1767-07-08">The next day</date>, <rs type="interact">I sent a party
                        up the country to cut wood, and they met with some of the natives, who
                        treated them with great kindness and hospitality. Several of these friendly
                        Indians came on board in our boat, and seemed, both by their dress and
                        behaviour, to be of a superior rank. To these people I paid a particular
                        attention, and to discover what present would most gratify them, I laid down
                        before them a Johannes, a guinea, a crown piece, a Spanish dollar, a few
                        shillings, some new halfpence, and two large nails, making signs that they
                        should take what they liked best. The nails were first seized, with great
                        eagerness, and then a few of the halfpence, but the silver and gold lay
                        neglected. Having presented them, therefore, with some nails and halfpence,
                        I sent them on shore superlatively happy.</rs></p><pb n="461"/><p n="69"><rs type="interact" subtype="trade">From this time, our market was very ill
                        supplied, the Indians refusing to sell provisions at the usual price, and
                        making signs for large nails.</rs> It was now thought necessary to look more
                    diligently about the ship, to discover what nails had been drawn; and it was
                    soon found that all the belaying cleats had been ripped off, and that there was
                    scarcely one of the hammock nails left. All hands were now ordered up, and I
                    practised every artifice I could think of to discover the thieves, but without
                    success. <rs type="ship" subtype="punishment">I then told them that till the
                        thieves were discovered, not a single man should go on shore: this however
                        produced no effect, except that <persName>Proctor</persName>, the corporal,
                        behaved in a mutinous manner, for which he was instantly punished.</rs></p><p n="70"><date when="1767-07-11">On Saturday the 11th</date>, in the afternoon, <rs type="island" subtype="contact" ana="oberea">the gunner came on board with a
                        tall woman, who seemed to be about five and forty years of age, of a
                        pleasing countenance and majestic deportment. He told me that she was but
                        just come into that part of the country, and that seeing great respect paid
                        her by the rest of the natives, he had made her some presents; in return for
                        which she had invited him to her house, which was about two miles up the
                        valley, and given him some large hogs; after which she returned with him to
                        the watering-place, and expressed a desire to go on board the ship, in which
                        he had thought it proper, on all accounts, that she should be gratified. She
                        seemed to be under no restraint, either from diffidence or fear, when she
                        first came into the ship; and she behaved, all the while she was on board,
                        with an easy freedom, that always distinguishes conscious superiority and
                        habitual command. I gave her a large blue mantle, that reached from her
                        shoulders to her feet, which I threw over her, and tied on with ribands; I
                        gave her also a looking-glass, beads of several sorts, and many other
                        things, of which she accepted with a very good <pb n="462"/>grace, and much
                        pleasure. She took notice that I had been ill, and pointed to the shore. I
                        understood that she meant I should go thither to perfect my recovery, and I
                        made signs that I would go thither the next morning. When she intimated an
                        inclination to return, I ordered the gunner to go with her, who, having set
                        her on shore, attended her to her habitation, which he described as being
                        very large and well built. He said, that in this house she had many guards
                        and domesticks, and that she had another at a little distance, which was
                        enclosed in lattice-work.</rs></p><p n="71"><rs type="person" ana="Oberea"><date when="1767-07-12">The next morning</date> I
                        went on shore for the first time, and my princess, or rather queen, for such
                        by her authority she appeared to be, soon after came to me, followed by many
                        of her attendants. As she perceived that my disorder had left me very weak,
                        she ordered her people to take me in their arms, and carry me not only over
                        the river, but all the way to her house; and observing that some of the
                        people who were with me, particularly the First Lieutenant and Purser, had
                        also been sick, she caused them also to be carried in the same manner, and a
                        guard, which I had ordered out upon the occasion, followed. In our way, a
                        vast multitude crouded about us, but upon her waving her hand, without
                        speaking a word, they withdrew, and left us a free passage. When we
                        approached near her house, a great number of both sexes came out to meet
                        her: these she presented to me, after having intimated by signs that they
                        were her relations, and taking hold of my hand, she made them kiss it. We
                        then entered the house, which covered a piece of ground 327 feet long, and
                        42 feet broad. It consisted of a roof, thatched with palm leaves, and raised
                        upon 39 pillars on each side, and 14 in the middle. The ridge of the thatch,
                        on the inside, was 30 feet high, and the sides of the house, to the edge of
                        the roof, were 12 feet high; all below the <pb n="463"/>roof being open. As
                        soon as we entered the house, she made us sit down, and then calling four
                        young girls, she assisted them to take off my shoes, draw down my stockings,
                        and pull off my coat, and then directed them to smooth down the skin, and
                        gently chafe it with their hands: the same operation was also performed upon
                        the First Lieutenant and the Purser, but upon none of those who appeared to
                        be in health. While this was doing, our Surgeon, who had walked till he was
                        very warm, took off his wig to cool and refresh himself: a sudden
                        exclamation of one of the Indians who saw it, drew the attention of the
                        rest, and in a moment every eye was fixed upon the prodigy, and every
                        operation was suspended: the whole assembly stood some time motionless, in
                        silent astonishment, which could not have been more strongly expressed if
                        they had discovered that our friend's limbs had been screwed on to the
                        trunk; in a short time, however, the young women who were chafing us,
                        resumed their employment, and having continued it for about half an hour,
                        they dressed us again, but in this they were, as may easily be imagined,
                        very aukward; I found great benefit, however, from the chafing, and so did
                        the Lieutenant and Purser. After a little time, our generous benefactress
                        ordered some bales of Indian cloth to be brought out, with which she clothed
                        me, and all that were with me, according to the fashion of the country. At
                        first I declined the acceptance of this favour, but being unwilling not to
                        seem pleased with what was intended to please me, I acquiesced. When we went
                        away, she ordered a very large sow, big with young, to be taken down to the
                        boat, and accompanied us thither herself. She had given directions to her
                        people to carry me, as they had done when I came, but as I chose rather to
                        walk, she took me by the arm, and whenever we came to a plash of water or
                        dirt, she lifted me over with as <pb n="464"/>little trouble as it would
                        have cost me to have lifted over a child if I had been well.</rs></p><p n="72"><date when="1767-07-13">The next morning</date><rs type="person" ana="Oberea">I sent her by the gunner, six hatchets, six
                        bill-hooks, and several other things; and when he returned, he told me that
                        he found her giving an entertainment to a great number of people, which, he
                        supposed, could not be less than a thousand. The messes were all brought to
                        her by the servants that prepared them, the meat being put into the shells
                        of cocoa nuts, and the shells into wooden trays, somewhat like those used by
                        our butchers, and she distributed them with her own hands to the guests, who
                        were seated in rows round the great house. When this was done, she sat down
                        herself, upon a place somewhat elevated above the rest, and two women,
                        placing themselves one on each side of her, fed her, she opening her mouth
                        as they brought their hands up with the food. When she saw the gunner, she
                        ordered a mess for him; he could not certainly tell what it was, but he
                        believed it to be fowl picked small, with apples cut among it, and seasoned
                        with salt water; it was, however, very well tasted. She accepted the things
                        that I sent her, and seemed to be much pleased with them. After this
                        correspondence was established with the queen, provisions of every kind
                        became much more plenty at market;</rs><rs type="interact" subtype="trade">but though fowls and hogs were every day
                        brought in, we were still obliged to pay more for them than at the first,
                        the market having been spoiled by the nails which our men had stolen and
                        given to the women; I therefore gave orders that every man should be
                        searched before he went on shore, and that no woman should be suffered to
                        cross the river.</rs></p><p n="73"><rs type="interact" subtype="affin"><date when="1767-07-14">On the 14th</date>,
                        the gunner being on shore to trade, perceived an old woman on the other side
                        of the river, weeping <pb n="465"/>bitterly: when she saw that she had drawn
                        his attention upon her, she sent a young man, who stood by her, over the
                        river to him, with a branch of the plantain tree in his hand. When he came
                        up, he made a long speech, and then laid down his bough at the gunner's
                        feet: after this he went back and brought over the old woman, another man at
                        the same time bringing over two large fat hogs. The woman looked round upon
                        our people with great attention, fixing her eyes sometimes upon one, and
                        sometimes upon another, and at last burst into tears. The young man who
                        brought her over the river, perceiving the gunner's concern and
                        astonishment, made another speech, longer than the first: still, however,
                        the woman's distress was a mystery, but at length she made him understand
                        that her husband, and three of her sons, had been killed in the attack of
                        the ship. During this explanation, she was to affected that at last she sunk
                        down unable to speak, and the two young men, who endeavoured to support her,
                        appeared to be nearly in the same condition: they were probably two more of
                        her sons, or some very near relations. The gunner did all in his power to
                        sooth and comfort her, and when she had in some measure recovered her
                        recollection, she ordered the two hogs to be delivered to him, and gave him
                        her hand in token of friendship, but would accept nothing in return, though
                        he offered her ten times as much as would have purchased the hogs at
                        market.</rs></p><p n="74"><date when="1767-07-15">The next morning</date>, I sent the Second Lieutenant,
                    with all the boats, and sixty men, to the westward, to look at the country, and
                    try what was to be got. <rs type="interact" subtype="affin">About noon he
                        returned, having marched along the shore near six miles. He found the
                        country very pleasant and populous, and abounding as well with hogs and
                        fowls, as fruit, and other vegetables of various kinds. The inhabitants
                        offered him no molestation, <pb n="466"/>but did not seem willing to part
                        with any of the provisions which our people were most desirous to purchase:
                        they gave them, however, a few cocoa-nuts and plantains, and at length sold
                        them nine hogs and a few fowls. <rs type="interact" subtype="trade">The
                            Lieutenant was of opinion, that they might be brought to trade freely by
                            degrees, but the distance from the ship was so great, that too many men
                            would be necessary for a guard.</rs> He saw a great number of very large
                        canoes upon the beach, and some that were building. He observed that all
                        their tools were made of stone, shells, and bone, and very justly inferred,
                        that they had no metal of any kind. He found no quadrupeds among them,
                        besides hogs and dogs, nor any earthen vessel, so that all their food is
                        either baked or roasted. Having no vessel in which water could be subjected
                        to the action of fire, they had no more idea that it could be made hot, than
                        that it could be made solid.</rs><rs type="person" ana="Oberea">As the queen was one morning at breakfast with us
                        on board the ship, one of her attendants, a man of some note, and one of
                        those that we thought were priests, saw the Surgeon fill the teapot by
                        turning the cock of an urn that stood upon the table: having remarked this
                        with great curiosity and attention, he presently turned the cock, and
                        received the water upon his hand: as soon as he felt himself scalded, he
                        roared out, and began to dance about the cabbin with the most extravagant
                        and ridiculous expressions of pain and astonishment: the other Indians, not
                        being able to conceive what was the matter with him, stood staring at him in
                        amaze, and not without some mixture of terror. The Surgeon, however, who had
                        innocently been the cause of the mischief, applied a remedy, though it was
                        some time before the poor fellow was easy.</rs></p><p n="75"><date when="1767-07-06">On Thursday the 16th</date>, <persName>Mr.
                        Furneaux</persName>, my Second Lieutenant, was taken very ill, which
                    distressed me greatly, as <pb n="467"/>the First Lieutenant was not yet
                    recovered, and I was still in a very weak state myself: I was this day also
                    obliged once more to punish <persName>Proctor</persName>, the corporal of
                    marines, for mutinous behaviour. <rs type="person" ana="Oberea">The queen had
                        now been absent several days, but the natives made us understand, by signs,
                        that the next day she would be with us again.</rs></p><p n="76"><rs type="person" ana="Oberea">Accordingly <date when="1767-07-17">the next
                            morning</date> she came down to the beach, and soon after a great number
                        of people, whom we had never seen before, brought to market provisions of
                        every kind; and the gunner sent off fourteen hogs, and fruit in great
                        plenty.</rs></p><p n="77"><rs type="person" ana="Oberea">In the afternoon of <date when="1767-07-18">the
                            next day</date>, the queen came on board, with a present of two large
                        hogs, for she never condescended to barter, and in the evening she returned
                        on shore. I sent a present with her, by the Master, and as soon as they
                        landed, she took him by the hand, and having made a long speech to she
                        people that flocked round them, she led him to her house, where she clothed
                        him, as she had before done me, according to the fashion of the
                        country.</rs></p><p n="78"><rs type="person" ana="Oberea"><date when="1767-07-19">The next morning</date>,
                        he sent off a greater quantity of stock than we had ever procured in one day
                        before; it consisted of forty-eight hogs and pigs, four dozen of fowls, with
                        bread-fruit, bananas, apples, and cocoa-nuts, almost without
                    number.</rs></p><p n="79"><rs type="interact" subtype="trade"><date when="1767-07-20">On the 20th</date>,
                        we continued to trade with good success,</rs> but in the afternoon it was
                    discovered that <persName>Francis Pinckney</persName>, one of the seamen, had
                    drawn the cleats to which the main sheet was belayed, and, after stealing the
                    spikes, thrown them over board. <rs type="ship" subtype="punishment">Having
                        secured the offender, I called all the people together upon the deck, and
                        after taking some pains to explain his crime, with all its aggravations, I
                        ordered that he should be whipped with nettles while he ran <pb n="468"/>the
                        gauntlet thrice round the deck: my rhetoric, however, had very little
                        effect, for most of the crew being equally criminal with himself, he was
                        handled so tenderly, that others were rather encouraged to repeat the
                        offence by the hope of impunity, than deterred by the fear of punishment. To
                        preserve the ship, therefore, from being pulled to pieces, and the price of
                        refreshments from being raised so high as soon to exhaust our articles of
                        trade, I ordered that no man, except the wooders and waterers, with their
                        guard, should be permitted to go on shore.</rs></p><p n="80"><rs type="person" ana="Oberea"><date when="1767-07-21">On the 21st</date>, the
                        queen came again on board, and brought several large hogs as a present, for
                        which, as usual, she would accept of no return. When she was about to leave
                        the ship, she expressed a desire that I should go on shore with her, to
                        which I consented, taking several of the officers with me. When we arrived
                        at her house, she made us all sit down, and taking off my hat, she tied to
                        it a bunch or tuft of feathers of various colours, such as I had seen no
                        person on shore wear but herself, which produced by no means a disagreeable
                        effect. She also tied round my hat, and the hats of those who were with me,
                        wreaths of braided or plaited hair, and gave us to understand that both the
                        hair and workmanship were her own: she also presented us with some matts,
                        that were very curiously wrought. In the evening she accompanied us back to
                        the beach, and when we were getting into the boat, she put on board a fine
                        large sow, big with young, and a great quantity of fruit. As we were
                        parting, I made signs that I should quit the island in seven days: she
                        immediately comprehended my meaning, and made signs that I should stay
                        twenty days; that I should go two days journey into the country, stay there
                        a few days, bring down plenty of hogs and poultry, and after that leave the
                        island. I again made signs that I must go in seven days; <pb n="469"/>upon
                        which she burst into tears, and it was not without great difficulty that she
                        was pacified.</rs></p><p n="81"><date when="1767-07-22">The next morning</date>, the gunner sent off no less than
                    twenty hogs, with great plenty of fruit. Our decks were now quite full of hogs
                    and poultry, of which we killed only the small ones, and kept the others for sea
                    stores; we found, however, to our great mortification, that neither the fowls
                    nor the hogs could, without great difficulty, be brought to eat any thing but
                    fruit, which made it necessary to kill them faster than we should otherwise have
                    done: two, however, a boar and a sow, were brought alive to
                        <placeName>England</placeName>, of which I made a present to <persName>Mr.
                        Stephens</persName>, Secretary to the Admiralty; the sow afterwards died in
                    pigging, but the boar is still alive.</p><p n="82"><date when="1767-07-23">On the 23d</date>, we had very heavy rain, with a storm
                    of wind that blew down several trees on shore, though very little of it was felt
                    where the ship lay.</p><p n="83"><rs type="interact" subtype="affin"><date when="1767-07-24">The next day</date>,
                        I sent the old man, who had been of great service to the gunner at the
                        market-tent, another iron pot, some hatchets and bills, and a piece of
                        cloth.</rs><rs type="person" ana="Oberea">I also sent the queen two turkies, two geese,
                        three Guinea hens, a cat big with kitten, some china, looking-glasses, glass
                        bottles, shirts, needles, thread, cloth, ribands, peas, some small white
                        kidney beans, called callivances, and about sixteen different sorts of
                        garden seeds, and a shovel, besides a considerable quantity of cutlery
                        wares, consisting of knives, scissars, bill-hooks, and other things. We had
                        already planted several sorts of the garden seeds, and some peas in several
                        places, and had the pleasure to see them come up in a very flourishing
                        state, yet there were no remains of them when Captain Cook left the island.
                        I sent her also two iron pots, and a few spoons. In return for these things,
                        the gunner brought off eighteen hogs, and some fruit.</rs></p><pb n="470"/><p n="84"><date when="1767-07-25">In the morning of the 25th</date>, I ordered
                        <persName>Mr. Gore</persName>, one of the mates, with all the marines, forty
                    seamen, and four midshipmen, to go up the valley by the river as high as they
                    could, and examine the soil and produce of the country, noting the trees and
                    plants which they should find, and when they saw any stream from the mountains,
                    to trace it to its source, and observe whether it was tinctured with any mineral
                    or ore. I cautioned them also to keep continually upon their guard against the
                    natives, and directed them to make a fire, as a signal, if they should be
                    attacked. At the same time, I took a guard on shore, and erected a tent on a
                    point of land, to observe an eclipse of the sun, which, the morning being very
                    clear, was done with great accuracy. The immersion began, by true time, at 6
                    hours 51 minutes 50 seconds. The emersion, by true time, was at 8 hours 1 minute
                    0 seconds. The duration of the eclipse was 1 hour 9 minutes 10 seconds. The
                    latitude of the point, on which the observation was made, was <geo select="lat">17° 30′ S</geo>. the sun's declination was 19° 40′ N. and the variation of
                    the needle 5° 36′ E.</p><p n="85"><rs type="person" ana="Oberea">After the observation was taken, I went to the
                        queen's house, and shewed her the telescope, which was a reflector. After
                        she had admired its structure, I endeavoured to make her comprehend its use,
                        and fixing it so as to command several distant objects, with which she was
                        well acquainted, but which could not be distinguished with the naked eye, I
                        made her look through it. As soon as the saw them, she started back with
                        astonishment, and directing her eye as the glass was pointed, stood some
                        time motionless and silent; she then looked through the glass again, and
                        again sought in vain, with the naked eye, for the objects which it
                        discovered. As they by turns vanished and re-appeared, her <pb n="471"/>countenance and gestures expressed a mixture of wonder and delight which
                        no language can describe. When the glass was removed, I invited her, and
                        several of the Chiefs that were with her, to go with me on board the ship,
                        in which I had a view to the security of the party that I had sent out; for
                        I thought that while the queen, and the principal people were known to be in
                        my power, nothing would be attempted against any person belonging to the
                        ship on shore. When we got on board, I ordered a good dinner for their
                        entertainment, but the queen would neither eat nor drink; the people that
                        were with her eat very heartily of whatever was set before them, but would
                        drink only plain water.</rs></p><p n="86"><rs type="person" ana="Oberea">In the evening our people returned from their
                        excursion, and came down to the beach, upon which I put the queen and her
                        attendants into the boats, and sent them on shore. As she was going over the
                        ship's side, she asked, by signs, whether I still persisted in my resolution
                        of leaving the island at the time I had fixed; and when I made her
                        understand that it was impossible I should stay longer, she expressed her
                        regret by a flood of tears, which for a while took away her speech. As soon
                        as her passion subsided, she told me that she would come on board again the
                        next day; and thus we parted.</rs></p></div><div org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N"><head>CHAP. VII. An Account of an Expedition to discover the inland Part of the
                    Country, and our other Transactions, till we quitted the Island to continue our
                    Voyage.</head><pb n="472"/><p n="87">AFTER the mate came on board, he gave me a written account of his expedition, to
                    the following effect:</p><p n="88">"<time when="04:00:00">At four o'clock in the morning</time>, of <date when="1767-07-25">Saturday the 25th of June</date>, I landed, with four
                    midshipmen, a serjeant and twelve marines, and twenty-four seamen, all armed,
                    besides four who carried hatchets and other articles of traffick, and four who
                    were loaded with ammunition and provisions, the rest being left with the boat:
                    every man had his day's allowance of brandy, and the hatchet men two small kegs,
                    to give out when I should think proper.</p><p n="89"><rs type="interact" subtype="affin">"As soon as I got on shore, I called upon our
                        old man, and took him with us: we then followed the course of the river in
                        two parties, one marching on each side. For the first two miles it flowed
                        through a valley of considerable width, in which were many habitations, with
                        gardens walled in, and abundance of hogs, poultry, and fruit; the soil here
                        seemed to be a rich fat earth, and was of a blackish colour. After this the
                        valley became very narrow, and the ground rising abruptly on one side of the
                        river, we were all obliged to march on the other. Where the stream was
                        precipitated from the hills, channels had been cut to lead the water into
                        gardens and plantations of fruit trees: in these gardens we found an herb
                        which had never been brought down to the <pb n="473"/> water-side, and which
                        we perceived the inhabitants eat raw. I tasted it, and found it pleasant,
                        its flavour somewhat resembling that of the West Indian spinnage, called
                        Calleloor, though its leaf was very different. The ground was fenced off so
                        as to make a very pretty appearance; the bread-fruit and apple trees were
                        planted in rows on the declivity of the hills, and the cocoa nut and
                        plantain, which require more moisture, on the level ground: under the trees,
                        both on the sides and at the foot of the hills, there was very good grass,
                        but no underwood. As we advanced, the windings of the stream became
                        innumerable, the hills on each side swelled into mountains, and vast crags
                        every where projected over our heads. Travelling now became difficult, and
                        when we had proceeded about four miles, the road for the last mile having
                        been very bad, we sat down to rest ourselves, and take the refreshment of
                        our breakfast; we ranged ourselves upon the ground under a large apple tree,
                        in a very pleasant spot; but just as we were about to begin our repast, we
                        were suddenly alarmed by a confused sound of many voices, and a great
                        shouting, and presently afterwards saw a multitude of men, women, and
                        children upon the hill above us; our old man seeing us rise hastily, and
                        look to our arms, beckoned to us to sit still, and immediately went up to
                        the people that had surprised us. As soon as he joined them they were
                        silent, and soon after disappeared; in a short time, however, they returned,
                        and brought with them a large hog ready roasted, with plenty of bread-fruit,
                        yams, and other refreshments, which they gave to the old man, who
                        distributed them among our people. In return for this treat, I gave them
                        some nails, buttons, and other things, with which they were greatly
                        delighted. After this we proceeded up the valley as far as we could,
                        searching all the runs of water, and all the places where water had run, for
                            <pb n="474"/> appearances of metal or ore, but could find none, except
                        what I have brought back with me. I shewed all the people that we met with,
                        the piece of saltpetre which had been picked up in the island, and which I
                        had taken with me for that purpose, but none of them took any notice of it,
                        nor could I learn from them any thing about it. The old man began now to be
                        weary, and there being a mountain before us, he made signs that he would go
                        home: before he left us, however, he made the people who had so liberally
                        supplied us with provisions, take the baggage, with the fruit that had not
                        been eaten, and some cocoa nut-shells full of fresh water, and made signs
                        that they should follow us up the side of the mountain. As soon as he was
                        gone, they gathered green branches from the neighbouring trees, and with
                        many ceremonies, of which we did not know the meaning, laid them down before
                        us: after this they took some small berries with which they painted
                        themselves red, and the bark of a tree that contained a yellow juice, with
                        which they stained their garments in different parts. We began to climb the
                        mountain while our old man was still in sight, and he, perceiving that we
                        made our way with difficulty through the weeds and brush-wood, which grew
                        very thick, turned back, and said something to the natives in a firm loud
                        tone; upon which twenty or thirty of the men went before us, and cleared us
                        a very good path; they also refreshed us with water and fruit as we went
                        along, and assisted us to climb the most difficult places, which we should
                        otherwise have found altogether impracticable. We began to ascend this hill
                        at the distance of about six miles from the place where we landed, and I
                        reckoned the top of it to be near a mile above the river that runs through
                        the valley below. When we arrived at the summit, we again sat down to rest
                        and refresh ourselves. While we were <pb n="475"/> climbing we flattered
                        ourselves that from the top we should command the whole island, but we now
                        saw mountains before us so much higher than our situation, that with respect
                        to them we appeared to be in a valley; towards the ship indeed the view was
                        enchanting: the sides of the hills were beautifully clothed with wood,
                        villages were every where interspersed, and the vallies between them
                        afforded a still richer prospect; the houses stood thicker, and the verdure
                        was more luxuriant. We saw very few habitations above us, but discovered
                        smoke in many places ascending from between the highest hills that were in
                        sight, and therefore I conjecture that the most elevated parts of the
                        country are by no means without inhabitants. As we ascended the mountain, we
                        saw many springs gush from fissures on the side of it, and when we had
                        reached the summit, we found many houses that we did not discover as we
                        passed them. No part of these mountains is naked; the summits of the highest
                        that we could see were crowned with wood, but of what kind I know not: those
                        that were of the same height with that which we had climbed, were woody on
                        the sides, but on the summit were rocky and covered with fern. Upon the
                        flats that appeared below these, there grew a sedgy kind of grass and weeds:
                        in general the soil here, as well as in the valley, seemed to be rich. We
                        saw several bushes of sugar-cane, which was very large and very good,
                        growing wild, without the least culture. I likewise found ginger and
                        turmerick, and have brought samples of both, but could not procure seeds of
                        any tree, most of them being in blossom. After traversing the top of this
                        mountain to a good distance, I found a tree exactly like a fern, except that
                        it was 14 or 15 feet high. This tree I cut down, and found the inside of it
                        also like a fern: I would have brought a piece of it with me, but found it
                        too cumbersome, and I knew not <pb n="476"/> what difficulties we might meet
                        with before we got back to the ship, which we judged to be now at a great
                        distance. After having again recruited our strength by refreshment and rest,
                        we began to descend the mountain, being still attended by the people to
                        whose care we had been recommended by our old man. We kept our general
                        direction towards the ship, but sometimes deviated a little to the right and
                        left in the plains and vallies, when we saw any houses that were pleasantly
                        situated, the inhabitants being every where ready to accommodate us with
                        whatever they had. We saw no beast, except a few hogs, nor any birds, except
                        parrots, parroquets, and green doves; by the river, however, there was
                        plenty of ducks, and every place that was planted and cultivated, appeared
                        to flourish with great luxuriance, though in the midst of what had the
                        appearance of barren ground. <rs type="interact" subtype="imp">I planted the
                            stones of peaches, cherries, and plums, with a great variety of garden
                            seeds, where I thought it was most probable that they would thrive, and
                            limes, lemons, and oranges, in situations which resembled those in which
                            they are found in the West Indies.</rs> In the afternoon, we arrived at
                        a very pleasant spot, within about three miles of the ship, where we
                        procured two hogs and some fowls, which the natives dressed for us very
                        well, and with great expedition. Here we continued till the cool of the
                        evening, and then made the best of our way for the ship, having liberally
                        rewarded our guides, and the people who had provided us so good a dinner.
                        Our men behaved through the whole day with the greatest decency and order,
                        and we parted with our Indian friends in perfect good-humour with each
                        other."</rs></p><p n="90"><rs type="person" ana="Oberea"><time when="10:00:00">About 10 o'clock</time>,
                            <date when="1767-07-26">the next morning</date>, the queen came on board
                        according to her promise, with a present of hogs and fowls, but went on
                        shore again soon afterwards. This day, <pb n="477"/> the Gunner sent off
                        near thirty hogs, with great plenty of fowls and fruit. We completed our
                        wood and water, and got all ready for sea. More inhabitants came down to the
                        beach, from the inland country, than we had seen before, and many of them
                        appeared, by the respect that was paid them, to be of a superior rank. About
                        three o'clock in the afternoon, the queen came again down to the beach, very
                        well dressed, and followed by a great number of people. Having crossed the
                        river with her attendants and our old man, she came once more on board the
                        ship. She brought with her some very fine fruit, and renewed her
                        solicitation, that I would stay ten days longer, with great earnestness,
                        intimating that she would go into the country, and bring me plenty of hogs,
                        fowls, and fruit. I endeavoured to express a proper sense of her kindness
                        and bounty, but assured her that I should certainly sail the next morning.
                        This, as usual, threw her into tears, and after she recovered, she enquired
                        by signs when I should return: I endeavoured to express fifty days, and she
                        made signs for thirty: but the sign for fifty being constantly repeated, she
                        seemed satisfied. She stayed on board till night, and it was then with the
                        greatest difficulty that she could be prevailed upon to go on shore. When
                        she was told that the boat was ready, she threw herself down upon the
                        arm-chest, and wept a long time with an excess of passion that could not be
                        pacified; at last, however, though with the greatest reluctance, she went
                        into the boat, and was followed by her attendants and the old man. The old
                        man had often intimated that his son, a lad about fourteen years of age,
                        should go with us, and the boy seemed to be willing: he had, however, now
                        disappeared for two days; I enquired after him when I first missed him, and
                        the old man gave me to understand that he was gone into the country to see
                        his friends, and would return time <pb n="478"/> enough to go with us; but I
                        have reason to think that, when the time drew near, the father's courage
                        failed, and that to keep his child he secreted him till the ship was gone,
                        for we never saw him afterwards.</rs></p><p n="91"><rs type="interact" subtype="affin">At break of day, on <date when="1767-07-27">Monday the 27th</date>, we unmoored, and at the same time I sent the
                        barge and cutter to fill the few water-casks that were now empty. When they
                        came near the shore, they saw, to their great surprise, the whole beach
                        covered with inhabitants, and having some doubt whether it would be prudent
                        to venture themselves among such a multitude, they were about to pull back
                        again for the ship.</rs><rs type="person" ana="Oberea">As soon as this was perceived from the shore, the
                        queen came forward, and beckoned them; at the same time guessing the reason
                        of what had happened, she made the natives retire to the other side of the
                        river: the boats then proceeded to the shore, and filled the casks, in the
                        mean time she put some hogs and fruit on board, and when they were putting
                        off would fain have returned with them to the ship. The officer, however,
                        who had received orders to bring off none of the natives, would not permit
                        her; upon which she presently launched a double canoe, and was rowed off by
                        her own people. Her canoe was immediately followed by fifteen or sixteen
                        more, and all of them came up to the ship. The queen came on board, but not
                        being able to speak, she sat down and gave vent to her passion by weeping.
                        After she had been on board about an hour, a breeze springing up, we weighed
                        anchor and made sail. Finding it now necessary to return into her canoe, she
                        embraced us all in the most affectionate manner, and with many tears; all
                        her attendants also expressed great sorrow at our departure. Soon after it
                        fell calm, and I sent the boats a-head to tow, upon which all the canoes
                        returned to the ship, and that which had the queen on board came up to the
                        gun-room port, where her <pb n="479"/> people made it fast. In a few minutes
                        she came into the bow of her canoe, where she sat weeping with inconsolable
                        sorrow. I gave her many things which I thought would be of great use to her,
                        and some for ornament; she silently accepted of all, but took little notice
                        of any thing. <time when="10:00:00">About 10 o'clock</time> we were got
                        without the reef, and a fresh breeze springing up, our Indian friends, and
                        particularly the queen, once more bade us farewel, with such tenderness of
                        affection and grief, as filled both my heart and my eyes.</rs></p><p n="92">At noon, the harbour from which we sailed bore S. E. ½ E. distant about twelve
                    miles. It lies in latitude <geo select="lat" n="1">17° 30′ S</geo>. longitude
                        <geo select="lon" n="1">150° W</geo>. and I gave it the name of
                        <placeName>Port Royal Harbour</placeName>.</p></div><div org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N"><head>CHAP. VIII. A more particular Account of the Inhabitants of Otaheite, and of
                    their domestic Life, Manners, and Arts.</head><pb n="480"/><p n="93">HAVING lain off this if island from the <date when="1767-06-24">24th of
                        June</date> to the <date when="1767-07-27">27th of July</date>, I shall now
                    give the best account of its inhabitants, with their manners and arts, that I
                    can; but having been in a very bad state of health the whole time, and for great
                    part of it confined to my bed, it will of necessity be much less accurate and
                    particular than I might otherwise have made it.</p><p n="94">The inhabitants of this island are a stout, well-made, active, and comely people.
                    The stature of the men, in general, is from five feet seven to five feet ten
                    inches, though a few individuals are taller, and a few shorter; that of the
                    women from five feet to five feet six. The complexion of the men is tawney, but
                    those that go upon the water are much redder than those who live on shore. Their
                    hair in general is black, but in some it is brown, in some red, and in others
                    flaxen, which is remarkable, because the hair of all other natives of Asia,
                    Africa, and America, is black, without a single exception. It is generally tied
                    up, either in one bunch, in the middle of the head, or in two, one on each side,
                    but some wear it loose, and it then curls very strongly: in the children of both
                    sexes it is generally flaxen. They have no combs, yet their hair is very neatly
                    dressed, and those who had combs from us, made good use of them. It is a
                    universal custom to anoint the head with cocoa-nut oil, in<pb n="481"/> which a
                    root has been scraped that smells something like roses. The women are all
                    handsome, and some of them extremely beautiful. Chastity does not seem to be
                    considered as a virtue among them, for they not only readily and openly
                    trafficked with our people for personal favours, but were brought down by their
                    fathers and brothers for that purpose: they were, however, conscious of the
                    value of beauty, and the size of the nail that was demanded for the enjoyment of
                    the lady, was always in proportion to her charms. The men who came down to the
                    side of the river, at the same time that they presented the girl, shewed a stick
                    of the size of the nail that was to be her price, and if our people agreed, she
                    was sent over to them, for the men were not permitted to cross the river. This
                    commerce was carried on a considerable time before the officers discovered it,
                    for while some straggled a little way to receive the lady, the others kept a
                    look-out. When I was acquainted with it, I no longer wondered that the ship was
                    in danger of being pulled to pieces for the nails and iron that held her
                    together, which I had before puzzled myself to account for in vain, the whole
                    ship's company having daily as much fresh provision and fruit as they could eat.
                    Both men and women are not only decently but gracefully clothed, in a kind of
                    white cloth, that is made of the bark of a shrub, and very much resembles coarse
                    China paper. Their dress consists of two pieces of this cloth: one of them, a
                    hole having been made in the middle to put the head through, hangs down from the
                    shoulders to the mid-leg before and behind; another piece, which is between four
                    and five yards long, and about one yard broad, they wrap round the body in a
                    very easy manner. This cloth is not woven, but is made, like paper, of the
                    macerated fibres of an inner bark, spread out and beaten together. Their
                    ornaments are feathers, flowers, <pb n="482"/> pieces of shells, and pearls the
                    pearls are worn chiefly by the women, from whom I purchased about two dozen of a
                    small size: they were of a good colour, but were all spoiled by boring. Mr.
                    Furneaux saw several in his excursion to the west, but he could purchase none
                    with any thing he had to offer. I observed, that it was here a universal custom
                    both for men and women to have the hinder part of their thighs and loins marked
                    very thick with black lines in various forms. These marks were made by striking
                    the teeth of an instrument, somewhat like a comb, just through the skin, and
                    rubbing into the punctures a kind of paste made of foot and oil, which leaves an
                    indelible stain. The boys and girls under twelve years of age, are not marked;
                    but we observed a few of the men whose legs were marked in chequers by the same
                    method, and they appeared to be persons of superior rank and authority. One of
                    the principal attendants upon the queen, appeared much more disposed to imitate
                    our manners than the rest; and our people, with whom he soon became a favourite,
                    distinguished him by the name of Jonathan. This man, Mr. Furneaux clothed
                    completely in an English dress, and it sat very easy upon him. Our officers were
                    always carried on shore, it being shoal water where we landed, and Jonathan,
                    assuming new state with his new finery, made some of his people carry him on
                    shore in the same manner. He very soon attempted to use a knife and fork at his
                    meals, but at first, when he had stuck a morsel upon his fork, and tried to feed
                    himself with that instrument, he could not guide it, but by the mere force of
                    habit his hand came to his mouth, and the victuals at the end of the fork went
                    away to his car.</p><p n="95"><rs type="concept" subtype="pac">Their food consists of pork, poultry, dog's
                        flesh, and fish, bread-fruit, bananas, plantains, yams, apples, and a four
                        fruit which, though not pleasant by itself, gives an agreeable<pb n="483"/>
                        relish to roasted bread-fruit, with which it is frequently beaten up. They
                        have abundance of rats, but, as far as I could discover, these make no part
                        of their food. The river affords them good mullet, but they are neither
                        large nor in plenty. They find conchs, muscles, and other shell-fish on the
                        reef, which they gather at low water, and eat raw with bread-fruit before
                        they come on shore. They have also very fine cray-fish, and they catch with
                        lines, and hooks of mother of pearl, at a little distance from the shore,
                        parrotfish, groopers, and many other sorts, of which they are so fond that
                        we could seldom prevail upon them to sell us a few at any price. They have
                        also nets of an enormous size, with very small meshes, and with these they
                        catch abundance of small fish about the size of sardines; but while they
                        were using both nets and lines with great success, we could not catch a
                        single fish with either. We procured some of their hooks and lines, but for
                        want of their art we were still disappointed.</rs></p><p n="96"><rs type="concept" subtype="pac">The manner in which they dress their food is
                        this: they kindle a fire by rubbing the end of one piece of dry wood upon
                        the side of another, in the same manner as our carpenters whet a chissel;
                        then they dig a pit about half a foot deep, and two or three yards in
                        circumference: they pave the bottom with large pebble stones, which they lay
                        down very smooth and even, and then kindle a fire in it with dry wood,
                        leaves, and the husks of the cocoa-nut. When the stones are sufficiently
                        heated, they take out the embers, and rake up the ashes on every side; then
                        they cover the stones with a layer of green cocoa-nut-tree leaves, and wrap
                        up the animal that is to be dressed in the leaves of the plantain; if it is
                        a small hog they wrap it up whole, if a large one they split it. When it is
                        placed in the pit, they cover it with the hot embers, and lay upon them
                        bread-fruit and yams, which are<pb n="484"/> also wrapped up in the leaves
                        of the plantain; over these they spread the remainder of the embers, mixing
                        among them some of the hot stones, with more cocoa-nut-tree leaves upon
                        them, and then close all up with earth, so that the heat is kept in. After a
                        time proportioned to the size of what is dressing, the oven is opened, and
                        the meat taken out, which is tender, full of gravy, and, in my opinion,
                        better in every respect than when it is dressed any other way. Excepting the
                        fruit, they have no sauce but salt water, nor any knives but shells, with
                        which they carve very dexterously, always cutting from them. It is
                        impossible to describe the astonishment they expressed when they saw the
                        Gunner, who, while he kept the market, used to dine on shore, dress his pork
                        and poultry by boiling them in a pot, having, as I have before observed, no
                        vessel that would bear the fire, they had no idea of hot water or its
                        effects: but from the time that the old man was in possession of an iron
                        pot, he and his friends eat boiled meat every day. The iron pots which I
                        afterwards gave to the queen, and several of the Chiefs, were also in
                        constant use, and brought as many people together, as a monster or a
                        puppet-show in a country fair. They appeared to have no liquor for drinking
                        but water, and to be happily ignorant of the art of fermenting the juice of
                        any vegetable, so as to give it an intoxicating quality: they have, as has
                        been already observed, the sugarcane, but they seemed to make no other use
                        of it than to chew, which they do not do habitually, but only break a piece
                        off when they happen to pass by a place where it is growing.</rs></p><p n="97"><rs type="concept" subtype="pac">Of their domestic life and amusements, we had
                        not sufficient opportunity to obtain much knowlege, but they appear
                        sometimes to have wars with each other, not only from their weapons, but the
                        scars with which many of them were<pb n="485"/> marked, and some of which
                        appeared to be the remains of very considerable wounds, made with stones,
                        bludgeons, or some other obtuse weapon: by these scars also they appear to
                        be no inconsiderable proficients in surgery, of which indeed we happened to
                        have more direct evidence. One of our seamen, when he was on shore, run a
                        large splinter into his foot, and the Surgeon being on board, one of his
                        comrades endeavoured to take it out with a penknife; but after putting the
                        poor fellow to a good deal of pain, was obliged to give it over. Our good
                        old Indian, who happened to be present, then called over one of his
                        countrymen that was standing on the opposite side of the river, who having
                        looked at the seaman's foot, went immediately down to the beach, and taking
                        up a shell, broke it to a point with his teeth; with this instrument, in
                        little more than a minute, he laid open the place, and extracted the
                        splinter; in the mean time the old man, who, as soon as he had called the
                        other over, went a little way into the wood, returned with some gum, which
                        he applied to the wound upon a piece of the cloth that was wrapped round
                        him, and in two days time it was perfectly healed. We afterwards learned
                        that this gum was produced by the apple tree, and our Surgeon procured some
                        of it, and used it as a vulnerary balsam with great success.</rs></p><p n="98"><rs type="concept" subtype="pac">The habitations of these happy people I have
                        described already; and besides these, we saw several sheds inclosed within a
                        wall, on the outside of which there were several uncouth figures of men,
                        women, hogs, and dogs, carved on posts, that were driven into the ground.
                        Several of the natives were from time to time seen to enter these places,
                        with a slow pace and dejected countenance, from which we conjectured that
                        they were repositories of the dead. The area within the walls of these
                        places, was generally well paved<pb n="486"/> with large round stones, but
                        it appeared not to be much trodden, for the grass every where grew up
                        between them. I endeavoured, with particular attention, to discover whether
                        they had a religious worship among them, but never could find the least
                        traces of any.</rs></p><p n="99"><rs type="concept" subtype="pac">The boats or canoes of these people, are of
                        three different sorts. Some are made out of a single tree, and carry from
                        two to six men: these are used chiefly for fishing, and we constantly saw
                        many of them busy upon the reef: some were constructed of planks, very
                        dexterously sewed together: these were of different sizes, and would carry
                        from ten to forty men. Two of them were generally lashed together, and two
                        masts set up between them; if they were single, they had an out-rigger on
                        one side, and only one mast in the middle. With these vessels they sail far
                        beyond the sight of land, probably to other islands, and bring home
                        plantains, bananas, and yams, which seem also to be more plenty upon other
                        parts of this island, than that off which the ship lay. A third sort seem to
                        be intended principally for pleasure and show: they are very large, but have
                        no sail, and in shape resemble the gondolas of Venice: the middle is covered
                        with a large awning, and some of the people sit upon it, some under it. None
                        of these vessels came near the ship, except on the first and second day
                        after our arrival; but we saw, three or four times a week, a procession of
                        eight or ten of them passing at a distance, with streamers flying, and a
                        great number of small canoes attending them, while many hundreds of people
                        ran abreast of them along the shore. They generally rowed to the outward
                        point of a reef which lay about four miles to the westward of us, where they
                        stayed about an hour, and then returned. These processions, however, are
                        never made but in fine weather, and all<pb n="487"/> the people on board are
                        dressed; though in the other canoes they have only a piece of cloth wrapped
                        round their middle. Those who rowed and steered were dressed in white; those
                        who sat upon the awning and under it in white and red, and two men who were
                        mounted on the prow of each vessel, were dressed in red only. We sometimes
                        went out to observe them in our boats, and though we were never nearer than
                        a mile, we saw them with our glasses as distinctly as if we had been upon
                        the spot.</rs></p><p n="100"><rs type="concept" subtype="pac">The plank of which these vessels are
                        constructed, is made by splitting a tree, with the grain, into as many thin
                        pieces as they can. They first fell the tree with a kind of hatchet, or
                        adze, made of a tough greenish kind of stone, very dexterously fitted into a
                        handle; it is then cut into such lengths as are required for the plank, one
                        end of which is heated till it begins to crack, and then with wedges of hard
                        wood they split it down: some of these planks are two feet broad, and from
                        15 to 20 feet long. The sides are smoothed with adzes of the same materials
                        and construction, but of a smaller size. Six or eight men are sometimes at
                        work upon the same plank together, and, as their tools presently lose their
                        edge, every man has by him a cocoa nut-shell filled with water, and a flat
                        stone, with which he sharpens his adze almost every minute. These planks are
                        generally brought to the thickness of about an inch, and are afterwards
                        fitted to the boat with the same exactness that would be expected from an
                        expert joiner. To fasten these planks together, holes are bored with a piece
                        of bone that is fixed into a stick for that purpose, a use to which our
                        nails were afterwards applied with great advantage, and through these holes
                        a kind of plaited cordage is passed, so as to hold the planks strongly
                        together: the seams are caulked with dried rushes, and the whole outside of
                        the vessel is paid with a<pb n="488"/> gummy juice, which some of their
                        trees produce in great plenty, and which is a very good succedaneum for
                        pitch.</rs></p><p n="101">The wood which they use for their large canoes, is that of the apple tree, which
                    grows very tall and strait. Several of them that we measured, were near eight
                    feet in the girth, and from 20 to 40 to the branches, with very little
                    diminution in the size. Our carpenter said, that in other respects it was not a
                    good wood for the purpose, being very light. The small canoes are nothing more
                    than the hollowed trunk of the bread-fruit tree, which is still more light and
                    spongy. The trunk of the bread-fruit tree is six feet in girth, and about 20
                    feet to the branches.</p><p n="102">Their principal weapons are stones, thrown either with the hand or sling, and
                    bludgeons; for though they have bows and arrows, the arrows are only fit to
                    knock down a bird, none of them being pointed, but headed only with a round
                    stone.</p><p n="103">I did not see one turtle all the while I lay off this island, but upon shewing
                    some small ones which I brought from <placeName>Queen Charlotte's
                        Island</placeName>, to the inhabitants, they made signs that they had them
                    of a much larger size. I very much regretted my having lost our he-goat, which
                    died soon after we left <placeName>Saint Iago</placeName>, and that neither of
                    our she-goats, of which we had two, were with kid. If the he-goat had lived, I
                    would have put them all on shore at this place, and I would have left a she-goat
                    here if either of them had been with kid; and I doubt not, but that in a few
                    years they would have stocked the island.</p><p n="104"><rs type="object">The climate here appears to be very good, and the island to be
                        one of the most healthy as well as delightful spots in the world. We saw no
                        appearance of disease among the inhabitants. The hills are covered with
                        wood, and the vallies<pb n="489"/> with herbage; and the air in general is
                        so pure, that, notwithstanding the heat, our flesh meat kept very well two
                        days, and our fish one. We met with no frog, toad, scorpion, centipied, or
                        serpent of any kind: and the only troublesome insects that we saw were ants,
                        of which there were but few.</rs></p><p n="105"><rs type="interact" subtype="trade">The south-east part of the island seems to be
                        better cultivated and inhabited than where we lay, for we saw every day
                        boats come round from thence laden with plantains and other fruit, and we
                        always found greater plenty, and a lower price, soon after their arrival,
                        than before.</rs></p><p n="106">The tide rises and falls very little, and being governed by the winds, is very
                    uncertain; though they generally blow from the E. to the S. S. E. and for the
                    most part a pleasant breeze.</p><p n="107">The benefit that we received while we lay off this island, with respect to the
                    health of the ship's company, was beyond our most sanguine expectations, for we
                    had not now an invalid on board, except the two Lieutenants and myself, and we
                    were recovering, though still in a very feeble condition.</p><p n="108">It is certain that none of our people contracted the venereal disease here, and
                    therefore, as they had free commerce with great numbers of the women, there is
                    the greatest probability that it was not then known in the country. It was,
                    however, found here by <persName>Captain Cook</persName>, in the Endeavour, and
                    as no European vessel is known to have visited this island before
                        <persName>Captain Cook</persName>'s arrival, but the Dolphin, and the
                    Boudeuse and Etoil, commanded by M. Bougainville, the reproach of having
                    contaminated with that dreadful pest, a race of happy people, to whom its
                    miseries had till then been unknown, must be due either to him or to me, to
                    England or to France; and I think myself happy to be able to exculpate myself
                    and my country beyond the possibility of doubt.</p><pb n="490"/><p n="109">It is well known, that the Surgeon on board his Majesty's ships keeps a list of
                    the persons who are sick on board, specifying their diseases, and the times when
                    they came under his care, and when they were discharged. It happened that I was
                    once at the pay-table on board a ship, when several sailors objected to the
                    payment of the Surgeon, alleging, that although he had discharged them from the
                    list, and reported them to be cured, yet their cure was incomplete. From this
                    time, it has been my constant practice when the Surgeon reported a man to be
                    cured, who had been upon the sick list, to call the man before me, and ask him
                    whether the report was true: if he alleged that any symptoms of his complaint
                    remained, I continued him upon the list; if not, I required him, as a
                    confirmation of the Surgeon's report, to sign the book, which was always done in
                    my presence. A copy of the sick list on board the Dolphin, during this voyage,
                    signed by every man in my presence, when he was discharged well, in confirmation
                    of the Surgeon's report, written in my own hand, and confirmed by my affidavit,
                    I have deposited in the Admiralty; by which it appears, that the last man on
                    board the ship, in her voyage outward, who was upon the sick list for the
                    venereal disease, except one who was sent to <placeName>England</placeName> in
                    the Store ship, was discharged cured, and signed the book on the <date when="1766-12-27">27th of December 1766</date>, near six months before our
                    arrival at <placeName>Otaheite</placeName>, which was on the <date when="1767-06-19">19th of June 1767</date>; and that the first man who was
                    upon the list for that disease, in our return home, was entered on the <date when="1768-02-26">26th of February 1768</date>, six months after we left the
                    island, which was on the <date when="1767-07-26">26th of July 1767</date>, so
                    that the ship's company was intirely free fourteen months within one day, the
                    very middle of which time we spent at <placeName>Otaheite</placeName>; and the
                    man who was first entered as a venereal patient, on our return home, was known
                    to have contracted the disease at the <placeName>Cape of Good Hope</placeName>,
                    where we then lay.</p></div></body></text></TEI>