<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ulysses>
<section sectionName="The Wanderings of Ulysses"/>
     <chapter chapterName="The Lotus Eaters"/>
     <location name="Windmill Lane" lat="53.3458100" lon="-6.2456600">By lorries along sir John Rogerson’s quay Mr Bloom walked soberly, past
Windmill lane, Leask’s the linseed crusher,</location> 
     <location name="18 Rogerson's Quay" lat="53.346584" lon="-6.243767">the postal telegraph
office. Could have given that address too. </location>
    <location name="19 Rogerson's Quay" lat="53.346493" lon="-6.243887">And past the sailors’ home.</location>
<location name="Lime Street" lat="53.345819" lon="-6.243710">He turned from the morning noises of the quayside and walked through
Lime street. By Brady’s cottages a boy for the skins lolled, his bucket
of offal linked, smoking a chewed fagbutt. A smaller girl with scars of
eczema on her forehead eyed him, listlessly holding her battered
caskhoop. Tell him if he smokes he won’t grow. O let him! His life
isn’t such a bed of roses. Waiting outside pubs to bring da home. Come
home to ma, da. Slack hour: won’t be many there.</location> <location name="Townsend Street" lat="53.345945" lon="-6.251799">He crossed Townsend
street, passed the frowning face of <reference to="Christianity">Bethel. El, yes: house of: Aleph</reference>,
Beth.</location>
    <location name="26 Lombard Street E." lat="53.344988" lon="-6.249185">And past Nichols’ <reference to="death">the undertaker</reference>. At eleven it is.</location>
    <location name="164 North Strand Road" lat="53.355344" lon="-6.246255"> Time enough.
Daresay Corny Kelleher bagged the job for O’Neill’s. Singing with his
eyes shut. Corny. <allusion to="Kelleher">Met her once in the park. In the dark. What a lark.
Police tout. Her name and address she then told with my tooraloom
tooraloom tay. O, surely he bagged it. Bury him cheap in a
whatyoumaycall. With my tooraloom, tooraloom, tooraloom, tooraloom.</allusion>
    </location>

<location name="6 Westland Row" lat="53.343145" lon="-6.249902">
        <p>In Westland row he halted before the window of the Belfast and <reference to="Orientalism">Oriental</reference>
Tea Company and read the legends of leadpapered packets: choice blend,
finest quality, family tea. Rather warm. Tea. Must get some from <reference to="Catholicism">Tom
Kernan.</reference> Couldn’t ask him at a funeral, though. While his eyes still
read blandly he took off his hat quietly inhaling his hairoil and sent
his right hand with slow grace over his brow and hair. Very warm
morning. Under their dropped lids his eyes found the tiny bow of the
leather headband inside his high grade ha. Just there. His right hand
came down into the bowl of his hat. His fingers found quickly a card
behind the headband and transferred it to his waistcoat pocket.</p>

<p>So warm. His right hand once more more slowly went over his brow and
hair. Then he put on his hat again, relieved: and read again: choice
blend, made of the finest Ceylon brands. The far east. Lovely spot it
must be: the garden of the world, big lazy leaves to float about on,
cactuses, flowery meads, snaky lianas they call them. Wonder is it like
that. Those <reference to="Ceylon">Cinghalese</reference> lobbing about in the sun in <reference to="Italian">_dolce far niente_</reference>,
not doing a hand’s turn all day. Sleep six months out of twelve. Too
hot to quarrel. Influence of the climate. Lethargy. Flowers of
idleness. The air feeds most. <reference to="French">Azotes.</reference> Hothouse in Botanic gardens.
<allusion persName="Percy Shelley">Sensitive plants.</allusion> Waterlilies. Petals too tired to. Sleeping sickness
in the air. Walk on roseleaves. Imagine trying to eat tripe and
cowheel. Where was the chap I saw in that picture somewhere? Ah yes, in
the <reference to="death">dead sea</reference> floating on his back, reading a book with a parasol open.
Couldn’t sink if you tried: so thick with salt. Because the weight of
the water, no, the weight of the body in the water is equal to the
weight of the what? Or is it the volume is equal to the weight? It’s a
<allusion to="Archimedes">law</allusion> something like that. Vance in High school cracking his
fingerjoints, teaching. The college curriculum. Cracking curriculum.
What is weight really when you say the weight? Thirtytwo feet per
second per second. Law of falling bodies: per second per second. They
all fall to the ground. The earth. <reference to="Newton's Law">It’s the force of gravity of the
earth is the weight.</reference>
        </p>

<p>He turned away and sauntered across the road. How did she walk with her
sausages? Like that something. As he walked he took the folded
<allusion to="Freeman's Journal">_Freeman_</allusion> from his sidepocket, unfolded it, rolled it lengthwise in a
baton and tapped it at each sauntering step against his trouserleg.
Careless air: just drop in to see. Per second per second. Per second
for every second it means. From the curbstone he darted a keen glance
through the door of the postoffice. Too late box. Post here. No-one.
In.</p>
    </location>

<location name="49 Westland Row" lat="53.34312" lon="-6.25097">He handed the card through the brass grill.

<said persName=" Leopold Bloom">—Are there any letters for me? he asked.</said>

<p>
            <reference to="Royal Dublin Fusiliers">While the postmistress searched a pigeonhole he gazed at the recruiting
poster with soldiers of all arms on parade: and held the tip of his
baton against his nostrils, smelling freshprinted rag paper. No answer
probably. Went too far last time.</reference>
        </p>

<p>The postmistress handed him back through the grill his card with a
letter. He thanked her and glanced rapidly at the typed envelope.
</p>
<p>Henry Flower Esq,
c/o P. O. Westland Row,
            City.

</p>
<p>Answered anyhow. He slipped card and letter into his sidepocket,
reviewing again the soldiers on parade. <reference to="Royal Dublin Fusiliers">Where’s old Tweedy’s regiment?
Castoff soldier. There: bearskin cap and hackle plume. No, he’s a
grenadier. Pointed cuffs. There he is: royal Dublin fusiliers.
Redcoats. Too showy. That must be why the women go after them. Uniform.
Easier to enlist and drill. </reference>
            <person persName="Maud Gonne">Maud Gonne’s letter about taking them off
O’Connell street at night: disgrace to our Irish capital.</person> <person persName="Arthur Griffith">Griffith’s
paper</person> is on the same tack now: an army rotten with venereal disease:
overseas or halfseasover empire. Half baked they look: hypnotised like.
Eyes front. Mark time. Table: able. Bed: ed. <person persName="Edward VII">The King’s own. Never see
him dressed up as a fireman or a bobby. A mason, yes.</person>
        </p>
<p>
He strolled out of the postoffice and turned to the right. Talk: as if
that would mend matters. His hand went into his pocket and a forefinger
felt its way under the flap of the envelope, ripping it open in jerks.
Women will pay a lot of heed, I don’t think. His fingers drew forth the
letter the letter and crumpled the envelope in his pocket. Something
pinned on: photo perhaps. Hair? No.</p>

<p>M’Coy. Get rid of him quickly. Take me out of my way. Hate company when
you.</p>

<said persName="M'Coy">—Hello, Bloom. Where are you off to?</said>

<said persName="Leopold Bloom">—Hello, M’Coy. Nowhere in particular.</said>

<said persName="M'Coy">—How’s the body?</said>

<said persName="Leopold Bloom">—Fine. How are you?</said>

<said persName="M'Coy">—Just keeping alive, M’Coy said.</said>

<p>His eyes on the black tie and clothes he asked with low respect:
</p>
<said persName="M'Coy">—Is there any... no trouble I hope? I see you’re...</said>

<said persName="Leopold Bloom">—O, no, Mr Bloom said. Poor Dignam, you know. The funeral is today.</said>

<said persName="M'Coy">—To be sure, poor fellow. So it is. What time?</said>

<p>A photo it isn’t. A badge maybe.</p>

<said persName="Leopold Bloom">—E...eleven, Mr Bloom answered.
</said>
<said persName="M'Coy">—I must try to get out there, M’Coy said. Eleven, is it? I only heard
it last night. Who was telling me? Holohan. You know Hoppy?
</said>
<said persName="Leopold Bloom">—I know.</said>

<p>Mr Bloom gazed across the road at the outsider drawn up before the door
of the Grosvenor. The porter hoisted the valise up on the well. She
stood still, waiting, while the man, husband, brother, like her,
searched his pockets for change. Stylish kind of coat with that roll
collar, warm for a day like this, looks like blanketcloth. Careless
stand of her with her hands in those patch pockets. Like that haughty
creature at the polo match. Women all for caste till you touch the
spot. Handsome is and handsome does. Reserved about to yield. The
honourable Mrs and <allusion persName="Shakespeare">Brutus is an honourable man.</allusion> Possess her once take
the starch out of her.</p>
</location>
<location name="31 Westland Row" lat="53.34322" lon="-6.25082">
        <said persName="M'Coy">—I was with Bob Doran, he’s on one of his periodical bends, and what do
you call him Bantam Lyons. Just down there in Conway’s we were.</said>

<p>Doran Lyons in Conway’s. She raised a gloved hand to her hair. In came
Hoppy. Having a wet. Drawing back his head and gazing far from beneath
his vailed eyelids he saw the bright fawn skin shine in the glare, the
braided drums. Clearly I can see today. Moisture about gives long sight
perhaps. Talking of one thing or another. Lady’s hand. Which side will
she get up?</p>

<said persName="M'Coy">—And he said: _Sad thing about our poor friend Paddy! What Paddy?_ I
said. _Poor little Paddy Dignam_, he said.</said>

<p>Off to the country: Broadstone probably. High brown boots with laces
dangling. Wellturned foot. What is he <allusion persName="Robert M. Adams">foostering</allusion> over that change for?
Sees me looking. Eye out for other fellow always. Good fallback. <allusion to="proverb">Two
strings to her bow.
</allusion>
        </p>
<said persName="M'Coy">—_Why?_ I said. _What’s wrong with him?_ I said.</said>

<p>Proud: rich: silk stockings.</p>

<said persName="Leopold Bloom">—Yes, Mr Bloom said.</said>

<p>He moved a little to the side of M’Coy’s talking head. Getting up in a
minute.</p>

<said persName="M'Coy">—_What’s wrong with him_? He said. _He’s dead_, he said. And, faith, he
filled up. _Is it Paddy Dignam_? I said. I couldn’t believe it when I
heard it. I was with him no later than Friday last or Thursday was it
in the Arch. _Yes,_ he said. _He’s gone. He died on Monday, poor
fellow_.</said>

<p>Watch! Watch! Silk flash rich stockings white. Watch!</p>
<p>
A heavy tramcar honking its gong slewed between.</p>

<p>Lost it. Curse your noisy pugnose. Feels locked out of it. <allusion persName="Thomas Moore">Paradise and
the peri.</allusion> Always happening like that. The very moment. Girl in Eustace
street hallway Monday was it settling her garter. Her friend covering
the display of. _Esprit de corps_. Well, what are you gaping at?</p>
<said persName="Leopold Bloom">
—Yes, yes, Mr Bloom said after a dull sigh. Another gone.</said>

<said persName="M'Coy">—One of the best, M’Coy said.</said>

<p>The tram passed. They drove off towards the Loop Line bridge, her rich
gloved hand on the steel grip. Flicker, flicker: the laceflare of her
hat in the sun: flicker, flick.</p>

<said persName="M'Coy">—Wife well, I suppose? M’Coy’s changed voice said.</said>

<said persName="Leopold Bloom">—O, yes, Mr Bloom said. Tiptop, thanks.</said>

<p>He unrolled the newspaper baton idly and read idly:</p>

<p>     What is home without
     Plumtree’s Potted Meat?
     Incomplete.
     With it an abode of bliss.</p>

<said persName="M'Coy">—My missus has just got an engagement. At least it’s not settled yet.</said>

<p>Valise tack again. By the way no harm. I’m off that, thanks.</p>

<p>Mr Bloom turned his largelidded eyes with unhasty friendliness.</p>

<said persName="Leopold Bloom">—My wife too, he said. She’s going to sing at a swagger affair in the
Ulster Hall, Belfast, on the twentyfifth.</said>

<said persName="M'Coy">—That so? M’Coy said. Glad to hear that, old man. Who’s getting it up?</said>

<p>Mrs Marion Bloom. Not up yet. Queen was in her bedroom eating bread
and. No book. <reference to="fortune telling">Blackened court cards laid along her thigh by sevens.
Dark lady and fair man.</reference> Letter. Cat furry black ball. Torn strip of
envelope.</p>

<p>     <allusion persName="Mozart">Love’s
     Old
     Sweet
     Song
     Comes lo-ove’s old...</allusion>
        </p>

<said persName="Leopold Bloom">—It’s a kind of a tour, don’t you see, Mr Bloom said thoughtfully.
_Sweeeet song_. There’s a committee formed. Part shares and part
profits.</said>

<p>M’Coy nodded, picking at his moustache stubble.
</p>
<said persName="M'Coy">—O, well, he said. That’s good news.</said>

<p>He moved to go.</p>

<said persName="M'Coy">—Well, glad to see you looking fit, he said. Meet you knocking around.</said>

<said persName="Leopold Bloom">—Yes, Mr Bloom said.</said>

<said persName="M'Coy">—Tell you what, M’Coy said. You might put down my name at the funeral,
will you? I’d like to go but I mightn’t be able, you see. There’s a
drowning case at Sandycove may turn up and then the coroner and myself
would have to go down if the body is found. You just shove in my name
if I’m not there, will you?</said>

<said persName="Leopold BLoom">—I’ll do that, Mr Bloom said, moving to get off. That’ll be all right.</said>

<said persName="M'Coy">—Right, M’Coy said brightly. Thanks, old man. I’d go if I possibly
could. Well, tolloll. Just C. P. M’Coy will do.</said>

<said persName="Leopold Bloom">—That will be done, Mr Bloom answered firmly.</said>

<p>Didn’t catch me napping that wheeze. The quick touch. Soft mark. I’d
like my job. Valise I have a particular fancy for. Leather. Capped
corners, rivetted edges, double action lever lock. <reference to="Catholicism">Bob Cowley</reference> lent him
his for the Wicklow regatta concert last year and never heard tidings
of it from that good day to this.</p>
    </location>

<location name="Pearse Street" lat="53.34351" lon="-6.24995">
        <p>Mr Bloom, strolling towards Brunswick street, smiled. My missus has
just got an. Reedy freckled soprano. Cheeseparing nose. Nice enough in
its way: for a little ballad. No guts in it. You and me, don’t you
know: in the same boat. Softsoaping. Give you the needle that would.
Can’t he hear the difference? Think he’s that way inclined a bit.
Against my grain somehow. Thought that Belfast would fetch him. I hope
that smallpox up there doesn’t get worse. Suppose she wouldn’t let
herself be vaccinated again. Your wife and my wife.</p>

<p>Wonder is he pimping after me?</p>

<p>Mr Bloom stood at the corner, his eyes wandering over the multicoloured
hoardings. <reference to="Edward VII">Cantrell and Cochrane’s Ginger Ale (Aromatic). </reference>Clery’s
Summer Sale. No, he’s going on straight. Hello. <allusion persName="John Augustin Daly">_Leah_ tonight.</allusion>
            <person persName="Millicent Palmer"> Mrs
Bandmann Palmer.</person> Like to see her again in that. <allusion persName="Shakespeare">_Hamlet_ </allusion>she played
last night. Male impersonator. Perhaps he was a woman. Why Ophelia
committed suicide. Poor papa! How he used to talk of <person persName="Kate Bateman">Kate Bateman</person> in
that. Outside the Adelphi in London waited all the afternoon to get in.
Year before I was born that was: sixtyfive. And <person persName="Adelaide Ristori">Ristori</person> in Vienna. What
is this the right name is? By Mosenthal it is. <allusion persName="Salomon Hermann Mosenhal">Rachel, is it? </allusion>No. The
scene he was always talking about where the old blind Abraham
recognises the voice and puts his fingers on his face.</p>

<p>
            <allusion to="Leah the Forsaken">Nathan’s voice! His son’s voice! I hear the voice of Nathan who left
his father to die of grief and misery in my arms, who left the house of
his father and left the God of his father.</allusion>
        </p>
     <p>Every word is so deep, Leopold.</p>
        <p>Poor papa! Poor man! I’m glad I didn’t go into the room to look at his
face. That day! O, dear! O, dear! Ffoo! Well, perhaps it was best for
him.</p>
        <p>Mr Bloom went round the corner and passed the drooping nags of the
hazard. No use thinking of it any more. Nosebag time. Wish I hadn’t met
that M’Coy fellow.</p>
        <p>He came nearer and heard a crunching of gilded oats, the gently
champing teeth. Their full buck eyes regarded him as he went by, amid
the sweet oaten reek of horsepiss. Their Eldorado. Poor jugginses! Damn
all they know or care about anything with their long noses stuck in
nosebags. Too full for words. Still they get their feed all right and
their doss. Gelded too: a stump of black guttapercha wagging limp
between their haunches. Might be happy all the same that way. Good poor
brutes they look. Still their neigh can be very irritating.</p>
        <p>He drew the letter from his pocket and folded it into the newspaper he
carried. Might just walk into her here. The lane is safer.</p>
        <p>He passed the cabman’s shelter. Curious the life of drifting cabbies.
All weathers, all places, time or setdown, no will of their own.
_Voglio e non_. Like to give them an odd cigarette. Sociable. Shout a
few flying syllables as they pass. He hummed:</p>
        <p>     Là ci darem la mano
     La la lala la la.</p>
    </location>


<location name="Cumberland Street" lat="53.29287" lon="-6.14697">He turned into Cumberland street and, going on some paces, halted in
the lee of the station wall. No-one.</location>
    <location name="153 Pearse Street" lat="53.34511" lon="-6.25791"> <p>Meade’s timberyard. Piled balks.
Ruins and tenements. With careful tread he passed over a hopscotch
court with its forgotten pickeystone. <reference to="Christianity">Not a sinner.</reference> Near the timberyard
a squatted child at marbles, alone, shooting the taw with a cunnythumb.
A wise tabby, a blinking sphinx, watched from her warm sill. Pity to
disturb them. <reference to="Islam">Mohammed cut a piece out of his mantle not to wake her.</reference>
Open it. And once I played marbles when I went to that old dame’s
school. She liked mignonette. <reference to="kindergarten">Mrs Ellis’s. And Mr?</reference> He opened the letter
within the newspaper.</p>

<p>A flower. I think it’s a. A yellow flower with flattened petals. Not
annoyed then? What does she say?</p>


<p>Dear Henry</p>

<p>I got your last letter to me and thank you very much for it. I am sorry
you did not like my last letter. Why did you enclose the stamps? I am
awfully angry with you. I do wish I could punish you for that. I called
you naughty boy because I do not like that other world. Please tell me
what is the real meaning of that word? Are you not happy in your home
you poor little naughty boy? I do wish I could do something for you.
Please tell me what you think of poor me. I often think of the
beautiful name you have. Dear Henry, when will we meet? I think of you
so often you have no idea. I have never felt myself so much drawn to a
man as you. I feel so bad about. Please write me a long letter and tell
me more. Remember if you do not I will punish you. So now you know what
I will do to you, you naughty boy, if you do not wrote. O how I long to
meet you. Henry dear, do not deny my request before my patience are
exhausted. Then I will tell you all. Goodbye now, naughty darling, I
have such a bad headache. today. and write _by return_ to your longing
</p>
<p>Martha</p>


<p>P. S. Do tell me what kind of perfume does your wife use. I want to
know.</p>


<p>He tore the flower gravely from its pinhold smelt its almost no smell
and placed it in his heart pocket. <reference to="florigraphy">Language of flowers.</reference> They like it
because no-one can hear. Or a poison bouquet to strike him down. Then
walking slowly forward he read the letter again, murmuring here and
there a word. Angry tulips with you darling manflower punish your
cactus if you don’t please poor forgetmenot how I long violets to dear
roses when we soon anemone meet all naughty nightstalk wife Martha’s
perfume. Having read it all he took it from the newspaper and put it
back in his sidepocket.</p>

<p>Weak joy opened his lips. Changed since the first letter. Wonder did
she wrote it herself. Doing the indignant: a girl of good family like
me, respectable character. <reference to="Catholicism">Could meet one Sunday after the rosary.</reference>
Thank you: not having any. Usual love scrimmage. Then running round
corners. Bad as a row with Molly. Cigar has a cooling effect. Narcotic.
Go further next time. Naughty boy: punish: afraid of words, of course.
Brutal, why not? Try it anyhow. A bit at a time.</p>

<p>Fingering still the letter in his pocket he drew the pin out of it.
Common pin, eh? He threw it on the road. Out of her clothes somewhere:
pinned together. Queer the number of pins they always have. No roses
without thorns.</p>
    </location>

<location name="The Coombe" lat="53.33914" lon="-6.28034">
        <p>Flat Dublin voices bawled in his head. Those two sluts that night in
the Coombe, linked together in the rain.</p>
        <p>     O, Mairy lost the pin of her drawers.
     She didn’t know what to do
     To keep it up,
     To keep it up.</p>
        <p>It? Them. Such a bad headache. Has her roses probably. Or sitting all
day typing. Eyefocus bad for stomach nerves. What perfume does your
wife use. Now could you make out a thing like that?</p>
        <p>     To keep it up.</p>
        <p>
            <reference to="Christianity">Martha, Mary.</reference> I saw that picture somewhere I forget now old master or
faked for money. He is sitting in their house, talking. Mysterious.
Also the two sluts in the Coombe would listen.</p>
        <p>     To keep it up.</p>
        <p>Nice kind of evening feeling. No more wandering about. Just loll there:
quiet dusk: let everything rip. Forget. Tell about places you have
been, strange customs. The other one, jar on her head, was getting the
supper: fruit, olives, lovely cool water out of a well, stonecold like
<reference to="corruption">the hole in the wall at Ashtown.</reference> Must carry a paper goblet next time I
go to the trottingmatches. She listens with big dark soft eyes. Tell
her: more and more: all. Then a sigh: silence. Long long long rest.</p>
        <p>Going under the railway arch he took out the envelope, tore it swiftly
in shreds and scattered them towards the road. The shreds fluttered
away, sank in the dank air: a white flutter, then all sank.</p>
        <p>Henry Flower. You could tear up a cheque for a hundred pounds in the
same way. Simple bit of paper. <person persName="Edward Cecil Guinness">Lord Iveagh</person> once cashed a sevenfigure
cheque for a million in the bank of Ireland. Shows you the money to be
made out of porter. Still the other brother <person persName="Sir Arthur Guinness">lord Ardilaun</person> has to change
his shirt four times a day, they say. Skin breeds lice or vermin. A
million pounds, wait a moment. Twopence a pint, fourpence a quart,
eightpence a gallon of porter, no, one and fourpence a gallon of
porter. One and four into twenty: fifteen about. Yes, exactly. Fifteen
millions of barrels of porter.</p>
        <p>What am I saying barrels? Gallons. About a million barrels all the
same.</p>
        <p>An incoming train clanked heavily above his head, coach after coach.
Barrels bumped in his head: dull porter slopped and churned inside. The
bungholes sprang open and a huge dull flood leaked out, flowing
together, winding through mudflats all over the level land, a lazy
pooling swirl of liquor bearing along wideleaved flowers of its froth.</p>
    </location>

<location name="46 Westland Row" lat="53.34248" lon="-6.25105">
        <p>He had reached the open backdoor of <reference to="Catholicism">All Hallows.</reference> Stepping into the
porch he doffed his hat, took the card from his pocket and tucked it
again behind the leather headband. Damn it. I might have tried to work
M’Coy for a pass to Mullingar.</p>

<p>Same notice on the door. Sermon by the very reverend <person persName="John Conmee S.J.">John Conmee S. J.</person>
on saint <person persName="Peter Claver">Peter Claver</person> S. J. and <reference to="Jesuits">the African Mission</reference>. Prayers for the
conversion of <person persName="Wiliam Ewart Gladstone">Gladstone</person> they had too when he was almost unconscious.
The protestants are the same. Convert <person persName="Rev. William J. Walsh">Dr William J. Walsh D.D.</person> to the
true religion. <reference to="Jesuits">Save China’s millions.</reference> Wonder how they explain it to the
<allusion persName="Bret Harte">heathen Chinee.</allusion> Prefer an ounce of opium. <reference to="China">Celestials.</reference> Rank heresy for
them. Buddha their god lying on his side in the museum. Taking it easy
with hand under his cheek. <reference to="China">Josssticks</reference> burning. Not like <allusion persName="Pontius Pilate">Ecce Homo.</allusion>
Crown of thorns and cross. Clever idea <person persName="Saint Patrick">Saint Patrick </person>the shamrock.
Chopsticks? Conmee: Martin Cunningham knows him: distinguishedlooking.
Sorry I didn’t work him about <reference to="Pope Pius X">getting Molly into the choir </reference>instead of
that <person persName="Rev. Charles Farrelley">Father Farley</person> who looked a fool but wasn’t. <reference to="Jesuits">They’re taught that.</reference>
He’s not going out in bluey specs with the sweat rolling off him to
baptise blacks, is he? The glasses would take their fancy, flashing.
Like to see them sitting round in a ring with blub lips, entranced,
listening. Still life. Lap it up like milk, I suppose.</p>

<p>The cold smell of sacred stone called him. He trod the worn steps,
pushed the swingdoor and entered softly by the rere.</p>

<p>Something going on: some <reference to="Catholicism">sodality.</reference> Pity so empty. Nice discreet place
to be next some girl. <reference to="Christianity">Who is my neighbour?</reference> Jammed by the hour to slow
music. That woman at midnight mass. <reference to="Judaism or Islam">Seventh heaven.</reference> Women knelt in the
benches with <reference to="religious society">crimson halters</reference> round their necks, heads bowed. A batch
knelt at the altarrails. The priest went along by them, murmuring,
holding <reference to="Catholicism">the thing</reference> in his hands. He stopped at each, took out a
communion, shook a drop or two (are they in water?) off it and put it
neatly into her mouth. Her hat and head sank. Then the next one. Her
hat sank at once. Then the next one: a small old woman. The priest bent
down to put it into her mouth, <reference to="Catholicism">murmuring all the time. Latin.</reference> The next
one. Shut your eyes and open your mouth. What? _Corpus:_ body. Corpse.
Good idea the Latin. Stupefies them first. <reference to="Catholicism">Hospice for the dying.</reference> They
don’t seem to chew it: only swallow it down. Rum idea: eating bits of a
corpse. Why the cannibals cotton to it.</p>

<p>He stood aside watching their blind masks pass down the aisle, one by
one, and seek their places. He approached a bench and seated himself in
its corner, nursing his hat and newspaper. These pots we have to wear.
We ought to have hats modelled on our heads. They were about him here
and there, with heads still bowed in their crimson halters, waiting for
it to melt in their stomachs. Something like those <reference to="Judaism">mazzoth</reference>: it’s that
sort of bread: unleavened shewbread. Look at them. Now I bet it makes
them feel happy. Lollipop. It does. Yes, <reference to="Catholicism">bread of angels</reference> it’s called.
There’s a big idea behind it, kind of kingdom of God is within you
feel. First communicants. <reference to="charlatanism">Hokypoky</reference> penny a lump. Then feel all like one
family party, same in the theatre, all in the same swim. They do. I’m
sure of that. Not so lonely. In our confraternity. Then come out a bit
spreeish. Let off steam. Thing is if you really believe in it. <reference to="Christian pilgrimage">Lourdes
cure, waters of oblivion,</reference> and the <reference to="Catholicism">Knock apparition</reference>, statues bleeding.
Old fellow asleep near that confessionbox. Hence those snores. Blind
faith. <allusion persName="Fanny Crosby">Safe in the arms of kingdom come.</allusion> Lulls all pain. Wake this time
next year.
</p>
<p>He saw the priest stow the communion cup away, well in, and kneel an
instant before it, showing a large grey bootsole from under the lace
affair he had on. Suppose he lost the pin of his. He wouldn’t know what
to do to. Bald spot behind. Letters on his back: <reference to="Jesus">I.N.R.I?</reference> No: <reference to="Jesus">I.H.S.</reference>
Molly told me one time I asked her. I have sinned: or no: I have
suffered, it is. And the other one? Iron nails ran in.
</p>
<p>Meet one Sunday after the rosary. Do not deny my request. Turn up with
a veil and black bag. <allusion to="Gilbert and Sullivan">Dusk and the light behind her.</allusion> She might be here
with a ribbon round her neck and do the other thing all the same on the
sly. Their character. That fellow that turned queen’s evidence on <reference to="Fenians">the
invincibles</reference> he used to receive the, <person persName="James Carey">Carey</person> was his name, the communion
every morning. This very church. Peter Carey, yes. No, <person persName="Peter Claver">Peter Claver</person> I
am thinking of. <person persName="Denis Carey">Denis Carey.</person> And just imagine that. Wife and six
children at home. And plotting that murder all the time. Those
crawthumpers, now that’s a good name for them, there’s always something
shiftylooking about them. They’re not straight men of business either.
O, no, she’s not here: the flower: no, no. By the way, did I tear up
that envelope? Yes: under the bridge.
</p>
<p>The priest was <reference to="Catholicism">rinsing out the chalice: </reference>then he tossed off the dregs
smartly. Wine. Makes it more aristocratic than for example if he drank
what they are used to Guinness’s porter or some temperance beverage
Wheatley’s Dublin <reference to="temperance beverage">hop bitters</reference> or Cantrell and Cochrane’s ginger ale
(aromatic). <reference to="Catholicism">Doesn’t give them any of it: shew wine:</reference> only the other.
Cold comfort. Pious fraud but quite right: otherwise they’d have one
old booser worse than another coming along, cadging for a drink. Queer
the whole atmosphere of the. Quite right. Perfectly right that is.
</p>
<p>Mr Bloom looked back towards the choir. Not going to be any music.
Pity. Who has the organ here I wonder? Old Glynn he knew how to make
that instrument talk, the _vibrato_: fifty pounds a year they say he
had <reference to="Catholicism">in Gardiner street</reference>. Molly was in fine voice that day, <reference to="Catholicism">the _Stabat
Mater_ of Rossini.</reference> <reference to="Christianity">Father Bernard Vaughan’s sermon first. Christ or
Pilate?</reference> Christ, but don’t keep us all night over it. Music they wanted.
Footdrill stopped. Could hear a pin drop. I told her to pitch her voice
against that corner. I could feel the thrill in the air, the full, the
people looking up:</p>

<p>
            <allusion to="Stabat Mater">_Quis est homo._</allusion>
        </p>

<p>Some of that old sacred music splendid. <allusion persName="Giusseppe Saverio Raffaele">Mercadante: seven last words.</allusion>
<allusion persName="Mozart">Mozart’s twelfth mass: _Gloria_ </allusion>in that. Those old popes keen on music,
on art and statues and pictures of all kinds. <allusion persName="Giovanni Pierluigi da Palestrina">Palestrina</allusion> for example
too. They had a gay old time while it lasted. Healthy too, <reference to="Catholicism">chanting,
regular hours,</reference> then brew liqueurs. <reference to="Catholicism">Benedictine. Green Chartreuse.</reference>
Still, <reference to="Catholicism">having eunuchs in their choir</reference> that was coming it a bit thick.
What kind of voice is it? Must be curious to hear after their own
strong basses. Connoisseurs. Suppose they wouldn’t feel anything after.
Kind of a placid. No worry. <reference to="prepubertal castration">Fall into flesh,</reference> don’t they? Gluttons,
tall, long legs. Who knows? Eunuch. One way out of it.
</p>
<p>
            <reference to="Catholicism">He saw the priest bend down and kiss the altar and then face about and
bless all the people.</reference> All crossed themselves and stood up. Mr Bloom
glanced about him and then stood up, looking over the risen hats. Stand
up at the <reference to="Christianity">gospel</reference> of course. Then all settled down on their knees again
and he sat back quietly in his bench. <reference to="Catholicism">The priest came down from the
altar, holding the thing out from him, and he and the massboy answered
each other in Latin. Then the priest knelt down and began to read off a
card:</reference>
</p>
<said persName="John Conmee S.J.">—<reference to="Catholicism">O God, our refuge and our strength...</reference>
        </said>

<p>Mr Bloom put his face forward to catch the words. English. Throw them
the bone. I remember slightly. <reference to="Catholicism">How long since your last mass?</reference> <allusion to="Rosenbach MS">Glorious
and immaculate virgin.</allusion> Joseph, her spouse. Peter and Paul. More
interesting if you understood what it was all about. Wonderful
organisation certainly, goes like clockwork. <reference to="Catholicism">Confession.</reference> Everyone wants
to. Then I will tell you all. Penance. Punish me, please. Great weapon
in their hands. More than doctor or solicitor. Woman dying to. And I
schschschschschsch. And did you chachachachacha? And why did you? Look
down at her ring to find an excuse. Whispering gallery walls have ears.
Husband learn to his surprise. God’s little joke. Then out she comes.
Repentance skindeep. Lovely shame. Pray at an altar. <reference to="Catholicism">Hail Mary and Holy
Mary.</reference> Flowers, incense, candles melting. Hide her blushes. Salvation
army blatant imitation. Reformed prostitute will address the meeting.
How I found the Lord. Squareheaded chaps those must be in Rome: they
work the whole show. And don’t they rake in the money too? Bequests
also: to the <reference to="Catholicism">P.P.</reference> for the time being in his absolute discretion. Masses
for the repose of my soul to be said publicly with open doors.
Monasteries and convents. The priest in that Fermanagh will case in the
witnessbox. No browbeating him. He had his answer pat for everything.
Liberty and exaltation of our holy mother the church. <reference to="Catholicism">The doctors of
the church:</reference> they mapped out the whole theology of it.
</p>
<p>The priest prayed:</p>

<said persName="John Conmee S.J.">—<reference to="Catholicism">Blessed Michael, archangel, defend us in the hour of conflict. Be our
safeguard against the wickedness and snares of the devil (may God
restrain him, we humbly pray!): and do thou, O prince of the heavenly
host, by the power of God thrust Satan down to hell and with him those
other wicked spirits who wander through the world for the ruin of
souls.</reference>
        </said>

<p>The priest and the massboy stood up and walked off. All over. The women
remained behind: thanksgiving.</p>

<p>Better be shoving along. Brother Buzz. Come around with the plate
perhaps. Pay your <reference to="Catholicism">Easter duty.</reference>
        </p>

<p>He stood up. Hello. Were those two buttons of my waistcoat open all the
time? Women enjoy it. Never tell you. But we. Excuse, miss, there’s a
(whh!) just a (whh!) fluff. Or their skirt behind, placket unhooked.
<allusion to="Shakespeare">Glimpses of the moon.</allusion> Annoyed if you don’t. Why didn’t you tell me
before. Still like you better untidy. Good job it wasn’t farther south.
He passed, discreetly buttoning, down the aisle and out through the
main door into the light. He stood a moment unseeing by the cold black
marble bowl while before him and behind two worshippers dipped furtive
hands in the low tide of holy water. Trams: a car of <person persName="William T.C. Prescott">Prescott’s</person>
dyeworks: a widow in her weeds. Notice because I’m in mourning myself.
He covered himself. How goes the time? Quarter past. Time enough yet.
Better get that lotion made up. Where is this? Ah yes, the last time.</p>
    </location>
<location name="1 Lincoln Place" lat="53.34141" lon="-6.25188">
        <p>Sweny’s in Lincoln place. Chemists rarely move. Their green and gold
beaconjars too heavy to stir. <reference to="apothecary">Hamilton Long’s,</reference> founded in the year of
the flood. <reference to="Protestantism">Huguenot churchyard near there. </reference>Visit some day.</p>

<p>He walked southward along Westland row. But the recipe is in the other
trousers. O, and I forgot that latchkey too. Bore this funeral affair.
O well, poor fellow, it’s not his fault. When was it I got it made up
last? Wait. I changed a sovereign I remember. First of the month it
must have been or the second. O, he can look it up in the prescriptions
book.</p>

<p>The chemist turned back page after page. Sandy shrivelled smell he
seems to have. Shrunken skull. And old. Quest for the philosopher’s
stone. <reference to="alchemy">The alchemists.</reference> Drugs age you after mental excitement. Lethargy
then. Why? Reaction. A lifetime in a night. Gradually changes your
character. Living all the day among herbs, ointments, disinfectants.
<reference to="apothecary">All his alabaster lilypots. Mortar and pestle. Aq. Dist. Fol. Laur. Te
Virid.</reference> Smell almost cure you like the dentist’s doorbell. Doctor Whack.
He ought to physic himself a bit. <reference to="medicine">Electuary</reference> or emulsion. The first
fellow that picked an herb to cure himself had a bit of pluck. Simples.
Want to be careful. Enough stuff here to chloroform you. <reference to="chemistry">Test: turns
blue litmus paper red.</reference> Chloroform. Overdose of <reference to="medicine">laudanum.</reference> Sleeping
draughts. Lovephiltres. <reference to="medicine">Paragoric poppysyrup bad for cough.</reference> Clogs the
pores or the phlegm. Poisons the only cures. Remedy where you least
expect it. Clever of nature.</p>

<said persName="chemist">—About a fortnight ago, sir?</said>

<said persName="Leopold Bloom">—Yes, Mr Bloom said.</said>

<p>He waited by the counter, inhaling slowly the keen reek of drugs, the
dusty dry smell of sponges and loofahs. Lot of time taken up telling
your aches and pains.</p>

<said persName="Leopold Bloom">—Sweet almond oil and tincture of benzoin, Mr Bloom said, and then
orangeflower water...</said>

<p>It certainly did make her skin so delicate white like wax.
</p>
<said persName="Leopold BLoom">—And white wax also, he said.</said>

<p>Brings out the darkness of her eyes. Looking at me, the sheet up to her
eyes, Spanish, smelling herself, when I was fixing the links in my
cuffs. Those homely recipes are often the best: <allusion to="Dr. Chase's Recipes or, Information for Everybody">strawberries for the
teeth: nettles and rainwater: oatmeal they say steeped in buttermilk.</allusion>
Skinfood. <person persName="Prince Leopold">One of the old queen’s sons, duke of Albany was it? had only
one skin. Leopold, yes.</person> Three we have. Warts, bunions and pimples to
make it worse. But you want a perfume too. What perfume does your?
_Peau d’Espagne_. That orangeflower water is so fresh. Nice smell these
soaps have. Pure curd soap. Time to get a bath round the corner.
Hammam. Turkish. Massage. Dirt gets rolled up in your navel. Nicer if a
nice girl did it. Also I think I. Yes I. Do it in the bath. Curious
longing I. Water to water. Combine business with pleasure. Pity no time
for massage. Feel fresh then all the day. Funeral be rather glum.
</p>
<said persName="chemist">—Yes, sir, the chemist said. That was two and nine. Have you brought a
bottle?</said>

<said persName="Leopold Bloom">—No, Mr Bloom said. Make it up, please. I’ll call later in the day and
I’ll take one of these soaps. How much are they?</said>

<said persName="chemist">—Fourpence, sir.</said>

<p>Mr Bloom raised a cake to his nostrils. Sweet lemony wax.</p>

<said persName="Leopold Bloom">—I’ll take this one, he said. That makes three and a penny.</said>

<said persName="chemist">—Yes, sir, the chemist said. You can pay all together, sir, when you
come back.</said>

<said persName="Leopold Bloom">—Good, Mr Bloom said.</said>

<p>He strolled out of the shop, the newspaper baton under his armpit, the
coolwrappered soap in his left hand.</p>

<p>At his armpit Bantam Lyons’ voice and hand said:</p>

<said persName="Bantam Lyons">—Hello, Bloom. What’s the best news? Is that today’s? Show us a minute.</said>

<p>Shaved off his moustache again, by Jove! Long cold upper lip. To look
younger. He does look balmy. Younger than I am.</p>

<p>Bantam Lyons’s yellow blacknailed fingers unrolled the baton. Wants a
wash too. Take off the rough dirt. Good morning, have you used Pears’
soap? Dandruff on his shoulders. Scalp wants oiling.</p>

<said persName="Bantam Lyons">—I want to see about that French horse that’s running today, Bantam
Lyons said. Where the bugger is it?</said>

<p>He rustled the pleated pages, jerking his chin on his high collar.
Barber’s itch. Tight collar he’ll lose his hair. Better leave him the
paper and get shut of him.</p>

<said persName="Leopold Bloom">—You can keep it, Mr Bloom said.</said>
<said persName="Bantam Lyons">
—<reference to="horse racing">Ascot. Gold cup.</reference> Wait, Bantam Lyons muttered. Half a mo. Maximum the
second.</said>

<said persName="Leopold Bloom">—I was just going to throw it away, Mr Bloom said.</said>

<p>Bantam Lyons raised his eyes suddenly and leered weakly.</p>

<said persName="Bantam Lyons">—What’s that? his sharp voice said.</said>

<said persName="Leopold Bloom">—I say you can keep it, Mr Bloom answered. I was going to throw it away
that moment.</said>

<p>Bantam Lyons doubted an instant, leering: then thrust the outspread
sheets back on Mr Bloom’s arms.</p>

<said persName="Bantam Lyons">—I’ll risk it, he said. Here, thanks.</said>

<p>He sped off towards Conway’s corner. God speed scut.</p>

<p>Mr Bloom folded the sheets again to a neat square and lodged the soap
in it, smiling. Silly lips of that chap. Betting. Regular hotbed of it
lately. Messenger boys stealing to put on sixpence. Raffle for large
tender turkey. Your Christmas dinner for threepence. Jack Fleming
embezzling to gamble then smuggled off to America. Keeps a hotel now.
They never come back. Fleshpots of Egypt.</p>
</location>
<location name="11 Leinster Street" lat="53.34117" lon="-6.25405">He walked cheerfully towards the mosque of the baths. Remind you of a
mosque, redbaked bricks, the minarets. College sports today I see. He
eyed the horseshoe poster over the gate of college park: <allusion to="Johnny, I hardly knew ye">cyclist
doubled up like a cod in a pot.</allusion> Damn bad ad. Now if they had made it
round like a wheel. Then the spokes: sports, sports, sports: and the
hub big: college. Something to catch the eye.

There’s <reference to="Trinity College">Hornblower</reference> standing at the porter’s lodge. Keep him on hands:
might take a turn in there on the nod. How do you do, Mr Hornblower?
How do you do, sir?

Heavenly weather really. If life was always like that. <reference to="cricket">Cricket weather.</reference>
Sit around under sunshades. <reference to="cricket">Over after over. </reference>Out. <reference to="cricket">They can’t play it
here. Duck for six wickets</reference>. Still Captain Culler broke a window in the
Kildare street club with <reference to="cricket">a slog to square leg.</reference> Donnybrook fair more in
their line. <allusion to="When McCarthy took the flute at Inniscorthy">And the skulls we were acracking when M’Carthy took the
floor.</allusion> Heatwave. Won’t last. <allusion persName="Edward Fitzball">Always passing, the stream of life, which
in the stream of life we trace is dearer than them all.</allusion>

Enjoy a bath now: clean trough of water, cool enamel, the gentle tepid
stream. <reference to="Christianity">This is my body.</reference>

He foresaw his pale body reclined in it at full, naked, in a womb of
warmth, oiled by scented melting soap, softly laved. He saw his trunk
and limbs riprippled over and sustained, buoyed lightly upward,
lemonyellow: his navel, bud of flesh: and saw the dark tangled curls of
his bush floating, floating hair of the stream around the limp father
of thousands, a languid floating flower.</location>
</ulysses>