<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"--><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <!-- Project home: http://digitalthoreau.org/walden -->
      <!-- Report an issue: http://digitalthoreau.org/walden/report-issue -->
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Walden: Reading</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Walden: Fluid Text is published by Digital Thoreau at The State University of
               New York College at Geneseo.</publisher>
            <availability>
               <licence target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/deed.en_US">
                  <p>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0
                     Unported License.</p>
               </licence>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>This text was encoded by the Students of <hi rend="style(italics)">ENG 390:
                  Literature in the Digital Age</hi> at SUNY Geneseo using Text Encoding Initiative
               (TEI) P5 XML Schema, using the Parallel Segmentation method. </note>
            <note>The text presented here is taken from the Princeton edition of Walden, and
               includes critical apparatus laid out by Ronald Clapper, and annotations provided by
               Ronald Clapper, J. Lyndon Shanley, and Walter Harding.</note>
            <note>Source: Clapper, Ronald E.A. The Development of 'Walden': A Genetic Text, revised
               edition of dissertation originally published at UCLA, 1967.</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <listPerson>
               <personGrp>
                  <persName xml:id="thoreau" role="author">Henry David Thoreau</persName>
                  <persName xml:id="harding" role="editor">Walter Harding</persName>
                  <persName xml:id="shanley" role="editor">J. Lyndon Shanley</persName>
                  <persName xml:id="clapper" role="editor">Ronald Clapper</persName>
                  <persName xml:id="easterly" role="manager">Joe Easterly</persName>
               </personGrp>
            </listPerson>

         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <creation>
            <listChange>
               <change xml:id="wc_base">Princeton Ed. of Walden</change>
               <change xml:id="wc_0a">Walden, Version A (1847)</change>
               <change xml:id="wc_a1">Walden, Version A1 (1847)</change>
               <change xml:id="wc_a2">Walden, Version A2 (1847)</change>
               <change xml:id="wc_0b">Walden, Version B (1849)</change>
               <change xml:id="wc_b1">Walden, Version B1 (1849)</change>
               <change xml:id="wc_b2">Walden, Version B2 (1849)</change>
               <change xml:id="wc_0c">Walden, Version C (1849)</change>
               <change xml:id="wc_c1">Walden, Version C1 (1849)</change>
               <change xml:id="wc_c2">Walden, Version C2 (1849)</change>
               <change xml:id="wc_0d">Walden, Version D (1852)</change>
               <change xml:id="wc_d1">Walden, Version D1 (1852)</change>
               <change xml:id="wc_d2">Walden, Version D2 (1852)</change>
               <change xml:id="wc_0e">Walden, Version E (late 1852 - 1853)</change>
               <change xml:id="wc_e1">Walden, Version E1 (late 1852 - 1853)</change>
               <change xml:id="wc_e2">Walden, Version E2 (late 1852 - 1853)</change>
               <change xml:id="wc_0f">Walden, Version F (1853-1854)</change>
               <change xml:id="wc_f1">Walden, Version F1 (1853-1854)</change>
               <change xml:id="wc_f2">Walden, Version F2 (1853-1854)</change>
               <change xml:id="wc_0g">Walden, Version G (1854)</change>
               <change xml:id="wc_g1">Walden, Version G1 (1854)</change>
               <change xml:id="wc_g2">Walden, Version G2 (1854)</change>
            </listChange>
         </creation>
      </profileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <variantEncoding method="parallel-segmentation" location="internal"/>
      </encodingDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:id="walc03">
      <body>
         <div>
            <head>Reading <note type="general" resp="#clapper" ana="#wc_0a">There is no chapter
                  title.</note>
               <note type="general" resp="#clapper" ana="#wc_0b #wc_0c">A fair copy was apparently
                  made of the material from Reading 1-11 on leaves (#31-55) now missing.</note>
            </head>

            <p n="1" change="#wc_0a">
               <note type="header" resp="#clapper">
                  <ab type="string">Reading 1 written: A.</ab>
                  <ab type="parsed">
                     <seg type="chapterNum">3</seg>
                     <seg type="chapterTitle">Reading</seg>
                     <seg type="paragraph">1</seg>
                     <seg type="written">A</seg>
                  </ab>
               </note>
               <anchor type="hn" xml:id="hn-03-001"/>
               <app xml:id="walc03-app-0001">
                  <lem> With a little more deliberation in the choice of their pursuits, all men
                     would perhaps become essentially students and observers, for certainly their
                     nature and destiny are interesting to all alike. In accumulating property for
                     ourselves or our posterity, in founding a family or a state, or acquiring fame
                     even, we are mortal; but in dealing with truth we are immortal, and need fear
                     no change nor accident. The oldest Egyptian or Hindoo philosopher raised a
                     corner of the veil from the statue of the divinity;<anchor type="hn" xml:id="hn-03-002"/> and still the trembling robe remains raised, and I gaze
                     upon as fresh a glory as he did, since it was I in him that was then so bold,
                     and it is he in me that now reviews the vision. No dust has settled on that
                     robe; no time has elapsed since that divinity was revealed. That time which we
                     really improve, or which is improvable, is neither past, present, nor future. </lem>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0b #wc_0c"> With a little more deliberation in the choice of their
                     pursuits, all men would perhaps become essentially students and observers, for
                     certainly their nature and destiny are interesting to all alike. In
                     accumulating property for ourselves or our posterity, in founding a family or a
                     state, or acquiring fame even, we are mortal; but in dealing with truth we are
                     immortal, and need fear no change nor accident. The oldest Egyptian or Hindoo
                     philosopher raised a corner of the veil from the statue of the divinity;<anchor type="hn" xml:id="hn-03-003"/> and still the trembling robe remains raised,
                     and I gaze upon as fresh a glory as he did, since it was I in him that was then
                     so bold, and it is he in me that now reviews the vision. No dust has settled on
                     that robe; no time has elapsed since that divinity was revealed. That time
                     which we really improve, or which is improvable, is neither past, present, nor
                     future. </rdg>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0a" resp="#clapper">It seems as if with a little more reflection all
                     men would be essentially students &amp; observers—For certainly his nature
                     &amp; destiny are equally interesting to every man. <del>It is hard to tell if
                        that time which we really improve is past present or future. I might say
                        that the student always studies antiques. In our studies we do not look
                        forward but backward into antiquity with redoubled pauses. Where is that
                        lost first page of history? We have never found the literature that dated
                        from antiquity sufficiently remote. The most adventurous student seeks the
                        remotest antiquity—the history of a time, as it were, prior to time,—Or, if
                        we prefer, such is the Protean character of things, we may say that he
                        always interprets prophecies and oracles, and is interested solely in the
                        future.—</del> In accumulating property for ourselves, or our posterity, in
                     founding a family, or a state, or acquiring fame, we are mortal, but in dealing
                     with truth we are immortal, and need fear no change nor accident.—The oldest
                     Egyptian or Hindoo philosopher raised a corner of the veil from the statue of
                        divinity,<anchor type="hn" xml:id="hn-03-004"/> and still the trembling robe
                     remains raised, and I gaze upon as fresh a glory as he did, since it was I in
                     him that was then so bold, and <add rendition="pencil">it is</add> he in me
                     that now reviews the vision. No dust has settled upon that robe—no time has
                     elapsed since that divinity was revealed. </rdg>
               </app>
            </p>


            <p n="2" change="#wc_0a">
               <note type="header" resp="#clapper">
                  <ab type="string">Reading 2 written: A.</ab>
                  <ab type="parsed">
                     <seg type="chapterNum">3</seg>
                     <seg type="chapterTitle">Reading</seg>
                     <seg type="paragraph">2</seg>
                     <seg type="written">A</seg>
                  </ab>
               </note>
               <app xml:id="walc03-app-0002">
                  <lem>My residence was more favorable, not only to thought, but to serious reading,
                     than a university; and though I was beyond the range of the ordinary
                     circulating library,<anchor type="hn" xml:id="hn-03-005"/> I had more than ever
                     come within the influence of those books which circulate round the world, whose
                     sentences were first written on bark, and are now merely copied from time to
                     time on to linen paper. Says the poet Mîr Camar Uddîn Mast,<anchor type="hn" xml:id="hn-03-006"/> “Being seated to run through the region of the
                     spiritual world; I have had this advantage in books. To be intoxicated by a
                     single glass of wine; I have experienced this pleasure when I have drunk the
                     liquor of the esoteric doctrines.”</lem>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0b #wc_0c">My residence was more favorable, not only to thought, but
                     to serious reading, than a university; and though I was beyond the range of the
                     ordinary circulating library,<anchor type="hn" xml:id="hn-03-007"/> I had more
                     than ever come within the influence of those books which circulate round the
                     world, whose sentences were first written on bark, and are now merely copied
                     from time to time on to linen paper. Says the poet Mîr Camar Uddîn Mast,<anchor type="hn" xml:id="hn-03-008"/> “Being seated to run through the region of
                     the spiritual world; I have had this advantage in books. To be intoxicated by a
                     single glass of wine; I have experienced this pleasure when I have drunk the
                     liquor of the esoteric doctrines.”</rdg>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0a" resp="#clapper"><!--not in manuscript--></rdg>
               </app> I kept <app xml:id="walc03-app-0003">
                  <lem>Homer’s Iliad</lem>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0b #wc_0c">Homer’s Iliad</rdg>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0a">
                     <del>a Homer</del>
                     <add rendition="pencil">Homer's Iliad</add>
                  </rdg>
               </app>
               <anchor type="hn" xml:id="hn-03-009"/> on my table through the summer, though I <app xml:id="walc03-app-0004">
                  <lem>looked</lem>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0b #wc_0c">looked</rdg>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0a" resp="#clapper">glanced</rdg>
               </app> at his page <app xml:id="walc03-app-0005">
                  <lem>only</lem>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0b #wc_0c">only</rdg>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0a" resp="#clapper"><!--not in manuscript--></rdg>
               </app> now and then. Incessant labor with my hands, <app xml:id="walc03-app-0006">
                  <lem>at first, for I had my house to finish and my beans to hoe at the same
                     time,</lem>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0b #wc_0c">at first, for I had my house to finish and my beans to
                     hoe at the same time,</rdg>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0a" resp="#clapper">
                     <add>for I did work hard <del>while my beans were growing</del> having my house
                        to finish and my beans to hoe at the same time</add>,</rdg>
               </app> made more study impossible. Yet I sustained myself by the prospect of such
               reading in <app xml:id="walc03-app-0007">
                  <lem>future.</lem>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0b #wc_0c">future.</rdg>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0a">future. Here of course I could read the Iliad, if I would have
                     books, as well as in Ionia, and not wish myself in Boston or New York—or London
                     or Rome; in such a place as this rather Homer lived and sung. <add>Here I know
                        that I am in good company—here is the world. Its centre and metropolis and
                        all the poems of Asia and the laurels of Greece and the firs of the Arctic
                        zones incline hither</add>
                  </rdg>
               </app> I read one or two shallow books of travel<anchor type="hn" xml:id="hn-03-010"/> in the intervals of my work, till that employment made me ashamed of myself, and I
                  <app xml:id="walc03-app-0008">
                  <lem>asked</lem>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0b #wc_0c">asked</rdg>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0a">asked myself</rdg>
               </app> where it was then that <hi rend="style(italics)">I</hi> lived.</p>

            <p n="3" change="#wc_0a">
               <seg n="3a" change="#wc_0a"><note type="header" resp="#clapper">
                     <ab type="string">Reading 3a written: A.</ab>
                     <ab type="parsed">
                        <seg type="chapterNum">3</seg>
                        <seg type="chapterTitle">Reading</seg>
                        <seg type="paragraph">3a</seg>
                        <seg type="written">A</seg>
                     </ab>
                  </note> The student may read Homer or Æschylus<anchor type="hn" xml:id="hn-03-011"/> in the <app xml:id="walc03-app-0009">
                     <lem>Greek</lem>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0b #wc_0c">Greek</rdg>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0a">original Greek</rdg>
                  </app>
                  <anchor type="hn" xml:id="hn-03-012"/> without danger of dissipation or
                  luxuriousness, for <app xml:id="walc03-app-0010">
                     <lem>it implies that he</lem>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0b #wc_0c">it implies that he</rdg>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0a">to do so implies that he should</rdg>
                  </app> in some measure emulate their heroes, and consecrate morning hours to their
                  pages. The heroic books, <app xml:id="walc03-app-0011">
                     <lem>even if</lem>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0b #wc_0c">even if</rdg>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0a">though</rdg>
                  </app> printed in the character of our mother tongue, will always be in a language
                  dead to degenerate times; and we must laboriously seek the meaning of each word
                  and line, conjecturing a larger sense than common use permits out of what wisdom
                  and valor and generosity we have. The modern cheap and fertile press, <app xml:id="walc03-app-0012">
                     <lem>with all its translations,</lem>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0b #wc_0c">with all its translations,</rdg>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0a" resp="#clapper">
                        <add>
                           <del>even</del> with all its translations</add>,</rdg>
                  </app> has done little to bring us nearer to the heroic writers of antiquity. They
                  seem as solitary, and the letter in which they are printed as rare and curious, as
                  ever. It is <app xml:id="walc03-app-0013">
                     <lem>worth</lem>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0b #wc_0c">worth</rdg>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0a" resp="#clapper">even worth</rdg>
                  </app> the expense of youthful days and costly hours, if you learn only some words
                  of an ancient language, which are raised out of the trivialness of the street, to
                  be perpetual suggestions and provocations. <app xml:id="walc03-app-0014">
                     <lem>It is not in vain that the farmer remembers and repeats the few Latin
                        words which he has heard.</lem>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0b #wc_0c">It is not in vain that the farmer remembers and
                        repeats the few Latin words which he has heard.</rdg>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0a">
                        <add>Every farmer loves to repeat the few Latin words he has learned.</add>
                     </rdg>
                  </app>
                  <app xml:id="walc03-app-0015">
                     <lem>Men</lem>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0b #wc_0c">Men</rdg>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0a" resp="#clapper">We</rdg>
                  </app> sometimes speak as if the study of the classics would at length make way
                  for more modern and practical studies; but the <app xml:id="walc03-app-0016">
                     <lem>adventurous</lem>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0b #wc_0c">adventurous</rdg>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0a" resp="#clapper">brave and adventurous</rdg>
                  </app> student will always study classics, in whatever language they may be
                  written and however ancient they may <app xml:id="walc03-app-0017">
                     <lem>be.</lem>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0b #wc_0c">be.</rdg>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0a" resp="#clapper">be.—For they have to be studied in the same
                        spirit that we study nature. They are <add>to a great extent</add> only
                        valuable commentaries on her works,— <add>or in one sense her own finest
                           fruits</add> never ancient, and never modern.</rdg>
                  </app>
                  <app xml:id="walc03-app-0018">
                     <lem>For what</lem>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0b #wc_0c">For what</rdg>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0a" resp="#clapper">What</rdg>
                  </app> are the classics but the noblest recorded <app xml:id="walc03-app-0019">
                     <lem>thoughts</lem>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0b #wc_0c">thoughts</rdg>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0a">thought</rdg>
                  </app> of man? They are the only oracles which <app xml:id="walc03-app-0020">
                     <lem>are not decayed, and there</lem>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0b #wc_0c">are not decayed, and there</rdg>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0a">have not decayed. There</rdg>
                  </app> are such answers to the most modern inquiry in them as Delphi and
                     Dodona<anchor type="hn" xml:id="hn-03-013"/>
                  <app xml:id="walc03-app-0021">
                     <lem>never gave.</lem>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0a">
                        <del>never gave</del>
                        <add>could never have given.</add>
                     </rdg>
                  </app>
                  <app xml:id="walc03-app-0022">
                     <lem>We might as well omit to study Nature because she is old.</lem>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0a"><!--not in manuscript--></rdg>
                  </app> To read well, that is, to read true books in a true spirit, is a noble
                  exercise, and one that will task the reader more than any exercise <app xml:id="walc03-app-0023">
                     <lem>which</lem>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0a">
                        <add>which</add>
                     </rdg>
                  </app> the customs of the day esteem. It requires a training such as the athletes
                  underwent, the steady intention <app xml:id="walc03-app-0024">
                     <lem>almost</lem>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0a">
                        <add>almost</add>
                     </rdg>
                  </app>of the whole life to this object. </seg>
               <seg n="3b" change="#wc_0a">
                  <note type="header" resp="#clapper">
                     <ab type="string">Reading 3b written: A.</ab>
                     <ab type="parsed">
                        <seg type="chapterNum">3</seg>
                        <seg type="chapterTitle">Reading</seg>
                        <seg type="paragraph">3b</seg>
                        <seg type="written">A</seg>
                     </ab>
                  </note>Books must be read as deliberately and reservedly as they were written. </seg>
               <seg n="3c" change="#wc_0a">
                  <note type="header" resp="#clapper">
                     <ab type="string">Reading 3c written: A.</ab>
                     <ab type="parsed">
                        <seg type="chapterNum">3</seg>
                        <seg type="chapterTitle">Reading</seg>
                        <seg type="paragraph">3c</seg>
                        <seg type="written">A</seg>
                     </ab>
                  </note>It is not enough even to be able to speak the language <app xml:id="walc03-app-0025">
                     <lem>of that nation by</lem>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0a">in</rdg>
                  </app>which they are written, for there is a memorable interval between the <app xml:id="walc03-app-0026">
                     <lem>spoken and the written</lem>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0b #wc_0c">spoken and the written</rdg>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0a">written and the spoken</rdg>
                  </app> language, the <app xml:id="walc03-app-0027">
                     <lem>language heard and the language read.</lem>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0b #wc_0c">language heard and the language read.</rdg>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0a">read and the language heard.</rdg>
                  </app> The one is commonly <app xml:id="walc03-app-0028">
                     <lem>transitory,</lem>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0b #wc_0c">transitory,</rdg>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0a">transient,</rdg>
                  </app> a sound, a tongue, a dialect merely, almost brutish, and we learn it
                  unconsciously, like the brutes, of our mothers. The other is the maturity and
                  experience of <app xml:id="walc03-app-0029">
                     <lem>that;</lem>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0b #wc_0c">that;</rdg>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0a">this;</rdg>
                  </app> if that is our mother tongue, that this is <app xml:id="walc03-app-0030">
                     <lem>our father tongue,</lem>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0b #wc_0c">our father tongue,</rdg>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0a">
                        <del>our father tongue,</del>
                        <del>
                           <add>the language of the father of men in respect to which all men but
                              lisp and are infants</add>
                        </del>
                        <add rendition="pencil">our intellectual father tongue</add>
                     </rdg>
                  </app> a reserved and select expression, <app xml:id="walc03-app-0031">
                     <lem>too</lem>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0b #wc_0c">too</rdg>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0a">which is too</rdg>
                  </app> significant to be heard by the ear, <app xml:id="walc03-app-0032">
                     <lem>which we must be born again in order to speak.<anchor type="hn" xml:id="hn-03-014"/>
                     </lem>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0b #wc_0c">which we must be born again in order to speak.<anchor type="hn" xml:id="hn-03-015"/>
                     </rdg>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0a">
                        <del>It does not wait to be heard, but is content with its own truth. The
                           one is natural and convenient, the other is divine and instinctive</del>
                     </rdg>
                  </app>
               </seg>
               <seg n="3d" change="#wc_0a">
                  <note type="header" resp="#clapper">
                     <ab type="string">Reading 3d written: A.</ab>
                     <ab type="parsed">
                        <seg type="chapterNum">3</seg>
                        <seg type="chapterTitle">Reading</seg>
                        <seg type="paragraph">3d</seg>
                        <seg type="written">A</seg>
                     </ab>
                  </note>The <app xml:id="walc03-app-0033">
                     <lem>crowds</lem>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0b #wc_0c">crowds</rdg>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0a" resp="#clapper">
                        <del>herd</del>
                        <del>
                           <add>mass</add>
                        </del>
                        <add>crowds</add>
                     </rdg>
                  </app> of men who merely <hi rend="style(italics)">spoke</hi> the Greek and Latin
                  tongues in the middle ages were not entitled by the accident of <app xml:id="walc03-app-0034">
                     <lem>birth</lem>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0a" resp="#clapper">
                        <del>birth</del>
                        <add>their birth and age</add>
                     </rdg>
                  </app> to <hi rend="style(italics)">read</hi> the works of genius written in those
                  languages; for these were not written in that Greek or Latin <app xml:id="walc03-app-0035">
                     <lem resp="#clapper">which they knew,</lem>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0a" resp="#clapper">peculiarly,</rdg>
                  </app>
                  <app xml:id="walc03-app-0036">
                     <lem>but in the select language of literature.</lem>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0b #wc_0c">but in the select language of literature.</rdg>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0a">
                        <add rendition="pencil">but in the select language of literature.</add>
                     </rdg>
                  </app>
                  <app xml:id="walc03-app-0037">
                     <lem>They had not learned the nobler dialects of Greece and Rome,</lem>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0b #wc_0c">They had not learned the nobler dialects of Greece and
                        Rome,</rdg>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0a" resp="#clapper">The men who <add>then</add> glibly spoke the
                        language of the Roman and the Greek, for their mother-tongue, did not learn
                        their nobler dialects,</rdg>
                  </app> but the very materials on which they were written were waste paper to them,
                     <app xml:id="walc03-app-0038">
                     <lem>and</lem>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0b #wc_0c">and</rdg>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0a" resp="#clapper">while</rdg>
                  </app> they prized instead a cheap contemporary <app xml:id="walc03-app-0039">
                     <lem>literature.</lem>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0b #wc_0c">literature.</rdg>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0a" resp="#clapper">
                        <del>learning</del>
                        <add rendition="pencil">literature</add>. The classics were virtually
                        forgotten and lost. <del>So distinct are the spoken &amp; the written
                           language</del>.</rdg>
                  </app> But when the several nations of <app xml:id="walc03-app-0040">
                     <lem>Europe</lem>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0b #wc_0c">Europe</rdg>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0a">
                        <add rendition="pencil">modern</add> Europe</rdg>
                  </app> had acquired <app xml:id="walc03-app-0041">
                     <lem>distinct though rude written languages of their own, sufficient for the
                        purposes of their rising literatures, then first learning revived, and
                        scholars were enabled to discern from that remoteness the treasures of
                        antiquity.</lem>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0b #wc_0c">distinct though rude written languages of their own,
                        sufficient for the purposes of their rising literatures, then first learning
                        revived, and scholars were enabled to discern from that remoteness the
                        treasures of antiquity.</rdg>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0a">
                        <del>rude original languages sufficient for conversation and the daily
                           intercourse of life</del>
                        <add rendition="pencil">distinct though ill-compounded and rude languages of
                           their own sufficient for conversation and an infant literature of their
                           own</add> then first learning revived, and scholars <del>who were seers
                           in their kind arose, who could</del>
                        <add rendition="pencil">were enabled to</add> discern from <del>this remote
                           standpoint</del>
                        <add rendition="pencil">that remoteness</add> the treasures of antiquity;
                           <del>and works of genius first began to be read, and perhaps found their
                           truest <add>&amp; fittest</add> audience when their language could no
                           longer be spoken anywhere</del>.</rdg>
                  </app>
                  <app xml:id="walc03-app-0042">
                     <lem>What the Roman and Grecian</lem>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0b #wc_0c">What the Roman and Grecian</rdg>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0a">What <add rendition="pencil">even</add> the <add rendition="pencil">Roman and Grecian</add>
                     </rdg>
                  </app> multitude could not <hi rend="style(italics)">hear</hi>, after the lapse of
                  ages a few scholars <hi rend="style(italics)">read</hi>,<anchor type="hn" xml:id="hn-03-016"/> and a few scholars only are still reading <app xml:id="walc03-app-0043">
                     <lem>it.</lem>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0b #wc_0c">it.</rdg>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0a">them.</rdg>
                  </app>
               </seg>
            </p>

            <p n="4" change="#wc_0a">
               <note type="header" resp="#clapper">
                  <ab type="string">Reading 4 written: A.</ab>
                  <ab type="parsed">
                     <seg type="chapterNum">3</seg>
                     <seg type="chapterTitle">Reading</seg>
                     <seg type="paragraph">4</seg>
                     <seg type="written">A</seg>
                  </ab>
               </note>
               <app xml:id="walc03-app-0044">
                  <lem>However much we may admire the orator’s occasional bursts of eloquence,</lem>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0b #wc_0c">However much we may admire the orator’s occasional bursts
                     of eloquence,</rdg>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0a" resp="#clapper">
                     <add rendition="pencil">Admire as we will the occasional sudden burst of
                        eloquence in the orator—<add>it seems to me that</add>
                     </add>,</rdg>
               </app> the noblest written words are <app xml:id="walc03-app-0045">
                  <lem>commonly</lem>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0b #wc_0c">commonly</rdg>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0a" resp="#clapper">
                     <add>commonly</add>
                  </rdg>
               </app> as far behind or <app xml:id="walc03-app-0046">
                  <lem>above</lem>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0b #wc_0c">above</rdg>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0a" resp="#clapper">beyond</rdg>
               </app> the fleeting spoken language as the firmament with its stars is behind the
               clouds. <hi rend="style(italics)">There</hi> are the stars, and they who can may read
               them. The astronomers forever comment on and observe them. They are not exhalations
               like our daily colloquies and vaporous breath. <app xml:id="walc03-app-0047">
                  <lem>What is called eloquence in the forum is commonly found to be rhetoric in the
                     study.</lem>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0b #wc_0c">What is called eloquence in the forum is commonly found
                     to be rhetoric in the study.</rdg>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0a" resp="#clapper">
                     <del>When I ask myself whether any unpremeditated speech or conversation of
                        equal length, even by the wisest of mankind and the writers of books, would
                        abide the myriad and impartial tests of time, which some rare and wonderful
                        books have so triumphantly withstood, I cannot doubt the justice of this
                        distinction</del>
                     <add rendition="pencil">What is called eloquence in the forum is commonly found
                        to be rhetoric in the study</add>.</rdg>
               </app>
               <anchor type="hn" xml:id="hn-03-017"/>
               <app xml:id="walc03-app-0048">
                  <lem>The orator yields to the inspiration of a transient occasion, and speaks to
                     the mob before him, to those who can <hi rend="style(italics)">hear</hi> him;
                     but the writer, whose more equable life is his occasion, and who would be
                     distracted by the event and the crowd which inspire the orator, speaks to the
                     intellect and health of mankind, to all in any age who can <hi rend="style(italics)">understand</hi> him.</lem>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0b #wc_0c">The orator yields to the inspiration of a transient
                     occasion, and speaks to the mob before him, to those who can <hi rend="style(italics)">hear</hi> him; but the writer, whose more equable life
                     is his occasion, and who would be distracted by the event and the crowd which
                     inspire the orator, speaks to the intellect and health of mankind, to all in
                     any age who can <hi rend="style(italics)">understand</hi> him.</rdg>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0a" resp="#clapper">
                     <add rendition="pencil">The eloquence of the <del>speaker</del>
                        <add rendition="pencil">orator</add> who yields to the inspiration of a
                        transient occasion can <del>hardly</del>
                        <add rendition="pencil">rarely</add> be compared for deep and permanent
                        effects with that of the writer whose life is his occasion and whose
                        audience is the intellect and heart of mankind. So much finer and purer as
                        well as more durable and salutary is commonly the influence of the
                        latter—thus that event and thing inward which are the source of inspiration
                        to the orator are oftenest the cause of distraction and confusion to the
                        writer.</add>
                  </rdg>
               </app>
            </p>

            <p n="5" change="#wc_0a">
               <note type="header" resp="#clapper">
                  <ab type="string">Reading 5 written: A.</ab>
                  <ab type="parsed">
                     <seg type="chapterNum">3</seg>
                     <seg type="chapterTitle">Reading</seg>
                     <seg type="paragraph">5</seg>
                     <seg type="written">A</seg>
                  </ab>
               </note>
               <app xml:id="walc03-app-0049">
                  <lem> No wonder that Alexander carried the Iliad with him<anchor type="hn" xml:id="hn-03-018"/> on his expeditions in a precious casket. A written word
                     is the choicest of relics. It is something at once more intimate with us and
                     more universal than any other work of art. It is the work of art nearest to
                     life itself. It may be translated into every language, and not only be read but
                     actually breathed from all human lips;—not be represented on canvas or in
                     marble only, but be carved out of the breath of life itself. The symbol of an
                     ancient man’s thought becomes a modern man’s speech. Two thousand summers have
                     imparted to the monuments of Grecian literature, as to her marbles, only a
                     maturer golden and autumnal tint, for they have carried their own serene and
                     celestial atmosphere into all lands to protect them against the corrosion of
                     time. Books are the treasured wealth of the world and the fit inheritance of
                     generations and nations. Books, the oldest and the best, stand naturally and
                     rightfully on the shelves of every cottage. They have no cause of their own to
                     plead, but while they enlighten and sustain the reader his common sense will
                     not refuse them. Their authors are a natural and irresistible aristocracy in
                     every society, and, more than kings or emperors, exert an influence on mankind.
                     When the illiterate and perhaps scornful trader has earned by enterprise and
                     industry his coveted leisure and independence, and is admitted to the circles
                     of wealth and fashion, he turns inevitably at last to those still higher but
                     yet inaccessible circles of intellect and genius, and is sensible only of the
                     imperfection of his culture and the vanity and insufficiency of all his riches,
                     and further proves his good sense by the pains which be takes to secure for his
                     children that intellectual culture whose want he so keenly feels; and thus it
                     is that he becomes the founder of a family. </lem>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0a"> A <add>written</add> word <del>fitly written</del> is the
                        <del>most</del> choice<add>st</add>
                     <del>and select of things</del><add>of relics</add>. No wonder that Alexander
                     carried the Iliad with him<anchor type="hn" xml:id="hn-03-020"/> on his
                     expeditions in a precious casket. It <del>has</del>
                     <add>is</add>something at once more intimate with us and more universal than
                     any other work of art. <add rendition="pencil">It is the work of art nearest to
                        life itself.</add> It may be translated into every language, and <add>not
                        only be read, but, though it is <del>different from</del> not speech<del>it
                           may</del> be</add> breathed from every human mouth, and become anew
                        <add>to some extent</add> the product <del>as it were of our physical
                        organs, as its sense is recognized by our intellectual ones</del>
                     <add>of humbler organs</add>
                     <del>It is the work of art nearest to life itself. Such are the traces of
                        Zoroaster &amp; Confucius &amp; Moses, indelible on the sands of the
                        remotest times</del> There are no monuments of antiquity comparable to the
                     Classics <add>and the Scriptures</add> for interest and importance. <del>It is
                        not necessary that the scholar should be an antiquarian to study them, for
                        these works of art have such an immortality as the works of nature, and are
                        modern at the same time that they are ancient, like the sun and stars,</del>
                     and <add>they</add> occupy <del>by right</del>
                     <add>rightfully</add> no small share of the present hour. <del>As we are told,
                        for instance, that “the serene sky and the brilliant sun of Greece merely
                        communicate to the marble of Paros and Pentelicus a golden tint, resembling
                        that of ripe corn, or the autumnal foliage,” while in other climates “stone
                        of the purest white soon turns black, or of a greenish hue,” so time
                        lends</del>
                     <add rendition="pencil">so time has lent</add>
                     <add>2000 summers have imparted</add> to the <del>pure</del>monuments of
                     Grecian literature <add rendition="pencil">as to her marbles</add> only a
                        <del>golden and mature</del>
                     <del>
                        <add>maturer golden</add>
                     </del>
                     <add>maturer golden and</add>
                     <add rendition="pencil">autumnal tint.</add>
                     <del>The poetry of the Greeks wears even now after the lapse of more than 2000
                        summers only a cereal and autumnal hue. Enveloped still, as it were, in the
                        inspiration which first breathed it, it carries its</del>
                     <add>for they have carried their</add> own serene &amp; celestial atmosphere
                     into all lands to protect them against the corrosions of time. Books are the
                     treasured wealth of the world, and the fit inheritance of generations &amp; of
                     nations. Books are the oldest &amp; the best stand naturally and rightfully on
                     the shelves of every cottage. They do not have to plead their cause—but while
                     they enlighten the reader the common sense of men will not refuse them. -
                        <del>The authors of great books, dead or alive, are an invisible upper class
                        and aristocracy in every civilized society, who</del>
                     <add>Their authors are a natural and irresistible aristocracy in every society
                        and more than kings or emperors</add> exert the last and greatest influence
                        <add rendition="pencil">on mankind</add>
                     <add>When the illiterate and scornful rustic <add rendition="pencil">who
                           is</add> destined to be the founder of a family has earned <add>by his
                           industry &amp; enterprise</add> his imagined leisure and independence
                           <del>by his industry &amp; enterprise</del> and is admitted to the
                        circles of wealth &amp; fashion, he turns inevitably at last to those still
                        higher and yet inaccessible circles of intellect &amp; Genius &amp; is
                        sensible only of the imperfection of his culture &amp; the vanity and
                        insufficiency of all his riches, and further proves his good sense by the
                        pains which he takes to secure for his children that intellectual culture
                        whose want he so keenly feels. And who shall say that the foundations of
                        genius are not thus laid because the poet is born a poet does not prove that
                        his ancestors have not contributed to make him such.</add>
                  </rdg>
               </app>
            </p>

            <p n="6" change="#wc_0a">
               <note type="header" resp="#clapper">
                  <ab type="string">Reading 6 written: A.</ab>
                  <ab type="parsed">
                     <seg type="chapterNum">3</seg>
                     <seg type="chapterTitle">Reading</seg>
                     <seg type="paragraph">6</seg>
                     <seg type="written">A</seg>
                  </ab>
                  <ab change="#wc_0a">"They only talk of forgetting them…hope to scale heaven at
                     last" does not appear in the manuscript.</ab>
               </note> Those who have not learned to read the ancient classics in the language in
               which they were written must have a very imperfect knowledge of the history of the
               human race; <app xml:id="walc03-app-0050">
                  <lem>for</lem>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0b #wc_0c">for</rdg>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0a">for of these after all</rdg>
               </app> it is remarkable that no transcript of them has ever been made into any <app xml:id="walc03-app-0051">
                  <lem>modern</lem>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0b #wc_0c">modern</rdg>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0a" resp="#clapper"><!--not in manuscript--></rdg>
               </app> tongue, unless our civilization itself <app xml:id="walc03-app-0052">
                  <lem>may be regarded as such a transcript. Homer has never yet been printed in
                        English,<anchor type="hn" xml:id="hn-03-021"/> nor Æschylus, nor Virgil
                     even,</lem>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0b #wc_0c">may be regarded as such a transcript. Homer has never yet
                     been printed in English,<anchor type="hn" xml:id="hn-03-022"/> nor Æschylus,
                     nor Virgil even,</rdg>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0a">be <add>regarded as to some extent</add> a transcript. Homer
                        <del>was never to my knowledge</del>
                     <add>has never yet been</add> printed in English,<anchor type="hn" xml:id="hn-03-023"/> nor <del>Socrates</del>
                     <add>Æschylus</add>—nor <del>Horace</del>
                     <add>Virgil</add> even. <del>These great Geniuses and wits who have rendered
                        memorable a remote period of the world's history</del> — <del>now almost in
                        its early age</del>
                  </rdg>
               </app> —works as refined, as solidly done, and as beautiful <app xml:id="walc03-app-0053">
                  <lem>almost</lem>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0b #wc_0c">almost</rdg>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0a">
                     <add>almost</add>
                  </rdg>
               </app> as the morning itself; <app xml:id="walc03-app-0054">
                  <lem>for</lem>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0b #wc_0c">for</rdg>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0a">I think that</rdg>
               </app> later writers, say what we will of their genius, have <app xml:id="walc03-app-0055">
                  <lem>rarely, if ever</lem>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0b #wc_0c">rarely, if ever</rdg>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0a">
                     <del>never</del>
                     <add>rarely if ever</add>
                  </rdg>
               </app> equalled the elaborate <app xml:id="walc03-app-0056">
                  <lem>beauty and finish and the lifelong and heroic literary labors of the
                     ancients</lem>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0b #wc_0c">beauty and finish and the lifelong and heroic literary
                     labors of the ancients</rdg>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0a">
                     <del>
                        <add>finish &amp;</add>
                     </del> beauty <add rendition="pencil">&amp; finish</add>
                     <del>and wonderful</del>
                     <add rendition="pencil">the confidence and</add> skill in the steady and
                     equable excercise of their art, <add rendition="pencil">&amp;</add> the
                     life-long, <add rendition="pencil">&amp;</add> heroic <del>
                        <add rendition="pencil">literary</add>
                     </del> labors <del>&amp; literary architecture</del> of the ancients</rdg>
               </app>. They only talk of forgetting them who never knew them. It will be soon enough
               to forget them when we have the learning and the genius which will enable us to
               attend to and appreciate them. That age will be rich indeed when those relics which
               we call Classics, and the still older and more than classic but even less known
               Scriptures of the nations, shall have still further accumulated, when the
                  Vaticans<anchor type="hn" xml:id="hn-03-024"/> shall be filled with Vedas and
               Zendavestas and Bibles,<anchor type="hn" xml:id="hn-03-025"/> with Homers and Dantes
               and Shakspeares, and all the centuries to come shall have successively deposited
               their trophies in the forum of the world. By such a pile we may hope to scale heaven
               at last.<anchor type="hn" xml:id="hn-03-026"/>
            </p>

            <p n="7" change="#wc_0a">
               <note type="header" resp="#clapper">
                  <ab type="string">Reading 7 written: A.</ab>
                  <ab type="parsed">
                     <seg type="chapterNum">3</seg>
                     <seg type="chapterTitle">Reading</seg>
                     <seg type="paragraph">7</seg>
                     <seg type="written">A</seg>
                  </ab>
                  <ab change="#wc_0a">Reading 7 follows Reading 11.</ab>
               </note>
               <app xml:id="walc03-app-0057">
                  <lem>The works of the great poets have never yet been read by mankind, for only
                     great poets can read them. They have only been read as the multitude read the
                     stars, at most astrologically, not astronomically.</lem>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0b #wc_0c">The works of the great poets have never yet been read by
                     mankind, for only great poets can read them. They have only been read as the
                     multitude read the stars, at most astrologically, not astronomically.</rdg>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0a" resp="#clapper"><!--not in manuscript--></rdg>
               </app> Most men have learned to read to serve a paltry convenience, as they have
               learned to cipher in order to keep accounts and not be cheated in trade; but of
               reading as a noble intellectual exercise they know little or nothing; yet this only
               is reading, <app xml:id="walc03-app-0058">
                  <lem>in a high sense,</lem>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0b #wc_0c">in a high sense,</rdg>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0a" resp="#clapper">properly speaking,</rdg>
               </app> not that which lulls <app xml:id="walc03-app-0059">
                  <lem>us</lem>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0b #wc_0c">us</rdg>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0a" resp="#clapper">&amp; soothes</rdg>
               </app> as a luxury and suffers the nobler faculties to sleep the while, but what we
               have to stand on tiptoe to read and devote our most alert and wakeful hours <app xml:id="walc03-app-0060">
                  <lem>to.</lem>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0b #wc_0c">to.</rdg>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0a" resp="#clapper">to—have to gird up our robes and train ourselves
                     for—as the wrestler is trained for the combat.</rdg>
               </app>
            </p>

            <p n="8" change="#wc_base">
               <note type="header" resp="#clapper">
                  <ab type="string">Reading 8 [not in manuscript].</ab>
                  <ab type="parsed">
                     <seg type="chapterNum">3</seg>
                     <seg type="chapterTitle">Reading</seg>
                     <seg type="paragraph">8</seg>
                     <anchor type="not-in-MS"/>
                  </ab>
               </note>
               <app xml:id="walc03-app-0061">
                  <lem>I think that having learned our letters we should read the best that is in
                     literature, and not be forever repeating our a b abs,<anchor type="hn" xml:id="hn-03-027"/> and words of one syllable, in the fourth or fifth
                     classes, sitting on the lowest and foremost form<anchor type="hn" xml:id="hn-03-028"/> all our lives. Most men are satisfied if they read or
                     hear read, and perchance have been convicted by the wisdom of one good book,
                     the Bible, and for the rest of their lives vegetate and dissipate their
                     faculties in what is called easy reading. There is a work in several volumes in
                     our Circulating Library entitled Little Reading,<anchor type="hn" xml:id="hn-03-029"/> which I thought referred to a town of that name<anchor type="hn" xml:id="hn-03-030"/> which I had not been to. There are those who,
                     like cormorants and ostriches,<anchor type="hn" xml:id="hn-03-031"/> can digest
                     all sorts of this, even after the fullest dinner of meats and vegetables, for
                     they suffer nothing to be wasted. If others are the machines to provide this
                     provender, they are the machines to read it. They read the nine thousandth tale
                     about Zebulon and Sophronia,<anchor type="hn" xml:id="hn-03-032"/> and how they
                     loved as none had ever loved before, and neither did the course of their true
                     love run smooth,<anchor type="hn" xml:id="hn-03-033"/>—at any rate, how it did
                     run and stumble, and get up again and go on! how some poor unfortunate got up
                     onto a steeple,<anchor type="hn" xml:id="hn-03-034"/> who had better never have
                     gone up as far as the belfry; and then, having needlessly got him up there, the
                     happy novelist rings the bell for all the world to come together and hear, O
                     dear! how he did get down again! For my part, I think that they had better
                     metamorphose all such aspiring heroes of universal noveldom into man
                     weathercocks, as they used to put heroes among the constellations, and let them
                     swing round there till they are rusty, and not come down at all to bother
                     honest men with their pranks. The next time the novelist rings the bell I will
                     not stir though the meeting-house burn down. “The Skip of the Tip-Toe-Hop, a
                     Romance of the Middle Ages,<anchor type="hn" xml:id="hn-03-035"/> by the
                     celebrated author of ‘Tittle-Tol-Tan,’<anchor type="hn" xml:id="hn-03-036"/> to
                     appear in monthly parts; a great rush; don't all come together.”<anchor type="hn" xml:id="hn-03-037"/> All this they read with saucer eyes, and
                     erect and primitive curiosity, and with unwearied gizzard, whose corrugations
                     even yet need no sharpening, just as some little four-year-old bencher<anchor type="hn" xml:id="hn-03-038"/> his two-cent gilt-covered edition of
                     Cinderella,—without any improvement, that I can see, in the pronunciation, or
                     accent, or emphasis, or any more skill in extracting or inserting the moral.
                     The result is dulness of sight, a stagnation of the vital circulations, and a
                     general deliquium and sloughing off of all the intellectual faculties. This
                     sort of gingerbread is baked daily and more sedulously than pure wheat or
                     rye-and-Indian in almost every oven,<anchor type="hn" xml:id="hn-03-039"/> and
                     finds a surer market.</lem>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0a #wc_0b #wc_0c" resp="#clapper"><!--not in manuscript--></rdg>
               </app>
               <app>
                  <lem>
                     <lb/> <!--Paragraph break in Princeton edition was inferred, being 'over' the turn of a page Matt.-->
                  </lem>
               </app>
            </p>

            <p n="9" change="#wc_0a">
               <seg n="9a" change="#wc_base">
                  <note type="header" resp="#clapper">
                     <ab type="string">Reading 9a [not in manuscript].</ab>
                     <ab type="parsed">
                        <seg type="chapterNum">3</seg>
                        <seg type="chapterTitle">Reading</seg>
                        <seg type="paragraph">9a</seg>
                        <anchor type="not-in-MS"/>
                     </ab>
                  </note>
                  <app xml:id="walc03-app-0062">
                     <lem>The best books are not read even by those who are called good readers.
                        What does our Concord culture amount to? There is in this town, with a very
                        few exceptions, no taste for the best or for very good books even in English
                        literature, whose words all can read and spell. Even the college-bred and so
                        called liberally educated men here and elsewhere have really little or no
                        acquaintance with the English classics; and as for the recorded wisdom of
                        mankind, the ancient classics and Bibles, which are accessible to all who
                        will know of them, there are the feeblest efforts any where made to become
                        acquainted with them. I know a woodchopper, of middle age,<anchor type="hn" xml:id="hn-03-053"/> who takes a French paper, not for news as he says,
                        for he is above that, but to “keep himself in practice,” he being a Canadian
                        by birth; and when I ask him what he considers the best thing he can do in
                        this world, he says, beside this, to keep up and add to his English. This is
                        about as much as the college bred generally do or aspire to do, and they
                        take an English paper for the purpose. One who has just come from reading
                        perhaps one of the best English books will find how many with whom he can
                        converse about it? Or suppose he comes from reading a Greek or Latin classic
                        in the original, whose praises are familiar even to the so called
                        illiterate; he will find nobody at all to speak to, but must keep silence
                        about it. Indeed, there is hardly the professor in our colleges, who, if he
                        has mastered the difficulties of the language, has proportionally mastered
                        the difficulties of the wit and poetry of a Greek poet, and has any sympathy
                        to impart to the alert and heroic reader; and as for the sacred Scriptures,
                        or Bibles of mankind, who in this town can tell me even their titles? Most
                        men do not know that any nation but the Hebrews have had a scripture. A man,
                        any man, will go considerably out of his way to pick up a silver dollar; but
                        here are golden words, which the wisest men of antiquity have uttered, and
                        whose worth the wise of every succeeding age have assured us of;—and yet we
                        learn to read</lem>

                     <rdg wit="#wc_0a #wc_0b #wc_0c" resp="#clapper">
                        <!--not in ms-->
                     </rdg>
                  </app>
               </seg>
               <seg n="9b" change="#wc_0a">
                  <note type="header" resp="#clapper">
                     <ab type="string">Reading 9b written: A.</ab>
                     <ab type="parsed">
                        <seg type="chapterNum">3</seg>
                        <seg type="chapterTitle">Reading</seg>
                        <seg type="paragraph">9b</seg>
                        <seg type="written">A</seg>
                     </ab>
                     <ab change="#wc_0a">Reading 9b follows three missing leaves (#29-33).</ab>
                  </note> only as far as Easy Reading,<anchor type="hn" xml:id="hn-03-056"/> the
                  primers and class-books,<anchor type="hn" xml:id="hn-03-057"/> and when we leave
                  school, the “Little Reading,” and story books, which are for boys and beginners;
                  and our reading, our conversation and thinking, are all on a very <app xml:id="walc03-app-0063">
                     <lem>low level,</lem>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0b #wc_0c">low level,</rdg>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0a" resp="#clapper">low <del>and inferior</del> level <del>—low
                           statured &amp; feeble and</del>
                     </rdg>
                  </app> worthy only of pygmies and manikins.</seg>
            </p>

            <p n="10" change="#wc_0a">
               <note type="header" resp="#clapper">
                  <ab type="string">Reading 10 written: A.</ab>
                  <ab type="parsed">
                     <seg type="chapterNum">3</seg>
                     <seg type="chapterTitle">Reading</seg>
                     <seg type="paragraph">10</seg>
                     <seg type="written">A</seg>
                  </ab>
               </note>I aspire to be acquainted with wiser men than this our Concord soil has
               produced, whose names are hardly known here. Or shall I hear the name of Plato and
               never read his book? As if Plato were my townsman and I never saw him,—my next
               neighbor and I never heard him speak or attended to the wisdom of his words. But how
               actually is it? His Dialogues, which contain what was immortal in him, lie on the
               next shelf, and yet I never read <app xml:id="walc03-app-0064">
                  <lem>them.</lem>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0b #wc_0c">them.</rdg>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0a" resp="#clapper">them <add>I describe my own case
                     here</add>.</rdg>
               </app> We are underbred and low-lived and illiterate; and in this respect I confess I
               do not make any very broad distinction between the illiterateness of <app xml:id="walc03-app-0065">
                  <lem>my townsman</lem>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0b #wc_0c">my townsman</rdg>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0a" resp="#clapper">
                     <del>my townsman</del>
                     <add rendition="pencil">him</add>
                  </rdg>
               </app> who cannot read at all, and the illiterateness of him who has learned to read
               only what is for children and feeble intellects. We should be as good as the worthies
               of antiquity, but partly by first knowing how good they were. We are a race of
                  tit-men,<anchor type="hn" xml:id="hn-03-058"/> and soar but little higher in our
               intellectual flights than the columns of the daily paper. </p>

            <p n="11" change="#wc_0a">
               <note type="header" resp="#clapper">
                  <ab type="string">Reading 11 written: A.</ab>
                  <ab type="parsed">
                     <seg type="chapterNum">3</seg>
                     <seg type="chapterTitle">Reading</seg>
                     <seg type="paragraph">11</seg>
                     <seg type="written">A</seg>
                  </ab>
               </note>
               <app xml:id="walc03-app-0066">
                  <lem>It is not all books that are as dull as their readers.</lem>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0b #wc_0c">It is not all books that are as dull as their
                     readers.</rdg>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0a" resp="#clapper"><!--not in manuscript--></rdg>
               </app> There are <app xml:id="walc03-app-0067">
                  <lem>probably</lem>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0b #wc_0c">probably</rdg>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0a" resp="#clapper"><!--not in manuscript--></rdg>
               </app> words addressed to our condition <app xml:id="walc03-app-0068">
                  <lem>exactly,</lem>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0b #wc_0c">exactly,</rdg>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0a" resp="#clapper">
                     <add>exactly,</add>
                  </rdg>
               </app> which, if we could <app xml:id="walc03-app-0069">
                  <lem>really</lem>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0b #wc_0c">really</rdg>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0a" resp="#clapper">
                     <add>really</add>
                  </rdg>
               </app> bear and understand, would be <app xml:id="walc03-app-0070">
                  <lem>more salutary than</lem>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0b #wc_0c">more salutary than</rdg>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0a" resp="#clapper">as salutary as</rdg>
               </app> the morning or the spring to our lives, and possibly put a new aspect on the
               face of things <app xml:id="walc03-app-0071">
                  <lem>for us.</lem>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0b #wc_0c">for us.</rdg>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0a" resp="#clapper">
                     <add>for us.</add>
                  </rdg>
               </app> How many a man has dated a new era in his <app xml:id="walc03-app-0072">
                  <lem>life</lem>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0b #wc_0c">life</rdg>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0a" resp="#clapper">life, <del>or a second birth as it were</del>
                  </rdg>
               </app> from the reading of a book.<anchor type="hn" xml:id="hn-03-059"/> The book
               exists for us <app xml:id="walc03-app-0073">
                  <lem>perchance</lem>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0b #wc_0c">perchance</rdg>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0a" resp="#clapper">
                     <add rendition="pencil">perchance</add>
                  </rdg>
               </app> which will explain our miracles and reveal new ones. The at present
               unutterable things we <app xml:id="walc03-app-0074">
                  <lem>may</lem>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0b #wc_0c">may</rdg>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0a" resp="#clapper">
                     <del>shall</del>
                     <add>may</add>
                  </rdg>
               </app> find somewhere uttered. <app xml:id="walc03-app-0075">
                  <lem>These same questions that disturb and puzzle and confound us have in their
                     turn occurred to all the wise men; not one has been omitted; and each has
                     answered them, according to his ability, by his words and his life. Moreover,
                     with wisdom we shall learn liberality.</lem>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0b #wc_0c">These same questions that disturb and puzzle and confound
                     us have in their turn occurred to all the wise men; not one has been omitted;
                     and each has answered them, according to his ability, by his words and his
                     life. Moreover, with wisdom we shall learn liberality.</rdg>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0a" resp="#clapper">
                     <del>Moreover with wisdom we shall learn liberality.</del> These same questions
                     that disturb &amp; puzzle &amp; confound us—have in their turn occurred to all
                     the wise men—not one has been omitted, and each has answered them, according to
                     his ability in his words &amp; his life. <del>They have had the same problems
                        to solve.</del>— <add>Moreover with wisdom we shall learn
                     liberality</add>.</rdg>
               </app> The solitary hired man on a farm in the outskirts of Concord, who has had his
               second birth<anchor type="hn" xml:id="hn-03-060"/> and peculiar religious experience,
               and is driven as he <app xml:id="walc03-app-0076">
                  <lem>believes</lem>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0b #wc_0c">believes</rdg>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0a" resp="#clapper">thinks</rdg>

               </app> into the silent gravity and exclusiveness by his faith, may think it is not
               true; but Zoroaster,<anchor type="hn" xml:id="hn-03-061"/> thousands of years ago,
               travelled the same road and had the same experience; but he, being wise, knew it to
               be universal, and treated <app xml:id="walc03-app-0077">
                  <lem>his neighbors</lem>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0b #wc_0c">his neighbors</rdg>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0a" resp="#clapper">
                     <del>men</del>
                     <add rendition="pencil">his neighbors</add>
                  </rdg>
               </app> accordingly, and is even said to have invented and established worship among
               men. Let him humbly commune with Zoroaster then, and, through the liberalizing
               influence of all the worthies, with Jesus Christ himself, and let “our church” go by
               the board.<anchor type="hn" xml:id="hn-03-062"/>
            </p>

            <p n="12" change="#wc_0a">
               <note type="header" resp="#clapper">
                  <ab type="string">Reading 12 [not in manuscript].</ab>
                  <ab type="parsed">
                     <seg type="chapterNum">3</seg>
                     <seg type="chapterTitle">Reading</seg>
                     <seg type="paragraph">12</seg>
                     <anchor type="not-in-MS"/>
                  </ab>
               </note>We boast that we belong to the nineteenth century and are making the most
               rapid strides of any nation. But consider how little this village does for its own
               culture. I do not wish to flatter my townsmen, nor to be flattered by them, for that
               will not advance either of us. We need to be provoked,—goaded like oxen, as we are,
               into a trot. We have a comparatively decent system of common schools, schools for
               infants only; but excepting the half-starved Lyceum in the winter,<anchor type="hn" xml:id="hn-03-063"/> and latterly the puny beginning of a library suggested by the
                  state,<anchor type="hn" xml:id="hn-03-064"/> no school for ourselves. We spend
               more on almost any article of bodily aliment or ailment than on our mental aliment.
               It is time that we had uncommon schools,<anchor type="hn" xml:id="hn-03-065"/> that
               we did not leave off our education when we begin to be men and women. It is time that
               villages were universities, and their elder inhabitants the fellows of universities,
               with leisure—if they are, indeed, so well off—to pursue liberal studies the rest of
               their lives. Shall the world be confined to one Paris or one Oxford forever? Cannot
               students be boarded here and get a liberal education under the skies of Concord? Can
               we not hire some Abelard<anchor type="hn" xml:id="hn-03-066"/> to lecture to us?
               Alas! what with foddering the cattle and tending the store, we are kept from school
               too long, and our education is sadly neglected. In this country, the village should
               in some respects take the place of the nobleman of Europe. It should be the patron of
               the fine arts. It is rich enough. It wants only the magnanimity and refinement. It
               can spend money enough on such things as farmers and traders value, but it is thought
               Utopian to propose spending money for things which more intelligent men know to be of
               far more worth. This town has spent seventeen thousand dollars on a town-house, thank
               fortune or politics,<anchor type="hn" xml:id="hn-03-067"/> but probably it will not
               spend so much on living wit, the true meat to put into that shell, in a hundred
               years. The one hundred and twenty-five dollars<anchor type="hn" xml:id="hn-03-068"/>
               annually subscribed for a Lyceum in the winter is better spent than any other equal
               sum raised in the town. If we live in the nineteenth century, why should we not enjoy
               the advantages which the nineteenth century offers? Why should our life be in any
               respect provincial? If we will read newspapers, why not skip the gossip of Boston and
               take the best newspaper in the world at once?—not be sucking the pap of “neutral
               family” papers,<anchor type="hn" xml:id="hn-03-069"/> or browsing “Olive-Branches”
               here in New England.<anchor type="hn" xml:id="hn-03-070"/> Let the reports of all the
               learned societies come to us, and we will see if they know any thing. Why should we
               leave it to Harper &amp; Brothers and Redding &amp; Co.<anchor type="hn" xml:id="hn-03-071"/> to select our reading?<anchor type="hn" xml:id="hn-03-072"/>
               As the nobleman of cultivated taste surrounds himself with whatever conduces to his
               culture,—genius—learning—wit—books—paintings—statuary—music—philosophical
               instruments, and the like; so let the village do,—not stop short at a pedagogue, a
               parson, a sexton, a parish library, and three selectmen,<anchor type="hn" xml:id="hn-03-073"/> because our pilgrim forefathers<anchor type="hn" xml:id="hn-03-074"/> got through a cold winter once on a bleak rock with these. To
               act collectively is according to the spirit of our institutions; and I am confident
               that, as our circumstances are more flourishing, our means are greater than the
               nobleman’s. New England can hire all the wise men in the world to come and teach her,
               and board them round the while,<anchor type="hn" xml:id="hn-03-075"/> and not be
               provincial at all. That is the <hi rend="style(italics)">uncommon</hi> school we
               want. Instead of noblemen, let us have noble villages of men. If it is necessary,
               omit one bridge over the river, go round a little there, and throw one arch at least
               over the darker gulf of ignorance which surrounds us. </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>