<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"--><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <!-- Project home: http://digitalthoreau.org/walden -->
      <!-- Report an issue: http://digitalthoreau.org/walden/report-issue -->
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Walden: Visitors</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Walden: Fluid Text is published by Digital Thoreau at The State University of New York College at Geneseo.</publisher>
            <availability>
               <licence target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/deed.en_US">
                  <p>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0
                     Unported License.</p>
               </licence>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>This text was encoded by the Technical Services team at Milne Library, SUNY
               Geneseo using Text Encoding Initiative (TEI) P5 XML Schema, using the Parallel
               Segmentation method. </note>
            <note>The text presented here is taken from the Princeton edition of Walden, and
               includes critical apparatus laid out by Ronald Clapper, and annotations provided by
               Ronald Clapper, J. Lyndon Shanley, and Walter Harding.</note>
            <note>Source: Clapper, Ronald E.A. The Development of 'Walden': A Genetic Text, revised
               edition of dissertation originally published at UCLA, 1967.</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <listPerson>
               <personGrp>
                  <persName xml:id="thoreau" role="author">Henry David Thoreau</persName>
                  <persName xml:id="harding" role="editor">Walter Harding</persName>
                  <persName xml:id="shanley" role="editor">J. Lyndon Shanley</persName>
                  <persName xml:id="clapper" role="editor">Ronald Clapper</persName>
                  <persName xml:id="easterly" role="manager">Joe Easterly</persName>
               </personGrp>
            </listPerson>

         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <creation>
            <listChange>
               <change xml:id="wc_base">Princeton Ed. of Walden</change>
               <change xml:id="wc_0a">Walden, Version A (1847)</change>
               <change xml:id="wc_a1">Walden, Version A1 (1847)</change>
               <change xml:id="wc_a2">Walden, Version A2 (1847)</change>
               <change xml:id="wc_0b">Walden, Version B (1849)</change>
               <change xml:id="wc_b1">Walden, Version B1 (1849)</change>
               <change xml:id="wc_b2">Walden, Version B2 (1849)</change>
               <change xml:id="wc_0c">Walden, Version C (1849)</change>
               <change xml:id="wc_c1">Walden, Version C1 (1849)</change>
               <change xml:id="wc_c2">Walden, Version C2 (1849)</change>
               <change xml:id="wc_0d">Walden, Version D (1852)</change>
               <change xml:id="wc_d1">Walden, Version D1 (1852)</change>
               <change xml:id="wc_d2">Walden, Version D2 (1852)</change>
               <change xml:id="wc_0e">Walden, Version E (late 1852 - 1853)</change>
               <change xml:id="wc_e1">Walden, Version E1 (late 1852 - 1853)</change>
               <change xml:id="wc_e2">Walden, Version E2 (late 1852 - 1853)</change>
               <change xml:id="wc_0f">Walden, Version F (1853-1854)</change>
               <change xml:id="wc_f1">Walden, Version F1 (1853-1854)</change>
               <change xml:id="wc_f2">Walden, Version F2 (1853-1854)</change>
               <change xml:id="wc_0g">Walden, Version G (1854)</change>
               <change xml:id="wc_g1">Walden, Version G1 (1854)</change>
               <change xml:id="wc_g2">Walden, Version G2 (1854)</change>
            </listChange>
         </creation>
      </profileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <variantEncoding method="parallel-segmentation" location="internal"/>
      </encodingDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:id="walc06">
      <body>
         <div>
            <head>Visitors <anchor type="hn" xml:id="hn-06-001"/>
               <note type="general" resp="#clapper" ana="#wc_0d">The title “Society" appears in
                  pencil at the top of the leaf containing Visitors 1.</note>
            </head>

            <p n="1" change="#wc_0a">
               <note type="header" resp="#clapper">
                  <ab type="string">Visitors 1 written: A; rewritten: B, D.</ab>
                  <ab type="parsed">
                     <seg type="chapterNum">6</seg>
                     <seg type="chapterTitle">Visitors</seg>
                     <seg type="paragraph">1</seg>
                     <seg type="written">A</seg>
                     <seg type="rewritten">B, D</seg>
                  </ab>
                  <ab change="#wc_0a #wc_0b"> Visitors 1 precedes Solitude 12a.</ab>
               </note>
               <app xml:id="walc06-app-0002">
                  <lem>I THINK</lem>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0a #wc_0b">Yet I think</rdg>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0d">
                     <del>Yet</del> I think</rdg>
               </app> that I love society as much as most, and am <app xml:id="walc06-app-0003">
                  <lem>ready</lem>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0a #wc_0b">apt</rdg>
               </app> enough to fasten myself like a bloodsucker for the time to any full-blooded
               man that comes in my way. I am naturally no hermit, but <app xml:id="walc06-app-0004">
                  <lem>might possibly</lem>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0a #wc_0b">should probably</rdg>
               </app> sit out the sturdiest frequenter of the bar-room, if my business called me
                  <app xml:id="walc06-app-0005">
                  <lem>thither</lem>

                  <rdg wit="#wc_0a">that way. <quote>
                        <lg>
                           <l>What do we ask?</l>
                           <l>Some worthy task; </l>
                           <l>Never to run </l>
                           <l>Till that be done, </l>
                           <l>That never done </l>
                           <l>Under the sun. </l>
                           <l>By might &amp; main </l>
                           <l>Health and strength gain, </l>
                           <l> So to give nerve </l>
                           <l>To our slenderness, </l>
                           <l>Yet some mighty pain </l>
                           <l>We would sustain, </l>
                           <l>So to preserve </l>
                           <l>Our tenderness. </l>
                           <l>Strength like the rock </l>
                           <l>To withstand every shock, </l>
                           <l>Yet not be deceived, </l>
                           <l>Of suffering bereaved— </l>
                           <l> Occasion to gain </l>
                           <l>To shed human tears, </l>
                           <l>And to entertain </l>
                           <l>Still demonic fears. </l>
                           <l> Not once for all </l>
                           <l>Forever blest. </l>
                           <l>Still to be cheered </l>
                           <l>Out of the west, </l>
                           <l>Not from our heart </l>
                           <l>To banish all sighs, </l>
                           <l>Still be encouraged </l>
                           <l>By the sun-rise— </l>
                           <l> For earthly pleasures, </l>
                           <l>Celestial pains— </l>
                           <l>Heavenly losses, </l>
                           <l>For earthly gains. </l>
                           <l> Must we still eat </l>
                           <l>The bread we have spurned? </l>
                           <l>Must we rekindle </l>
                           <l>The faggots we’ve burned?</l>
                        </lg>
                     </quote>
                  </rdg>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0b">that way</rdg>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0d">in that direction</rdg>
               </app>. </p>

            <p n="2" change="#wc_0a">
               <note type="header" resp="#clapper">
                  <ab type="string">Visitors 2 written: A; rewritten: B.</ab>
                  <ab type="parsed">
                     <seg type="chapterNum">6</seg>
                     <seg type="chapterTitle">Visitors</seg>
                     <seg type="paragraph">2</seg>
                     <seg type="written">A</seg>
                     <seg type="rewritten">B</seg>
                  </ab>
                  <ab change="#wc_0a #wc_0b">Visitors 2-6 is preceded by Visitors 7-13.</ab>
                  <ab change="#wc_0a">[The following passage precedes Visitors 2.] Sometimes there
                     would come half a dozen <add>railroad</add> men to my house at once—healthy and
                     sturdy working men, descended from sound bodies of men, and still transmitting
                     arms &amp; legs &amp; bowels <del>from remote generations to posterity. They
                        had a rude wisdom and courtesy which I love.</del>
                     <add rendition="pencil">downward from remote days to more remote. Some of them
                        had got a rude wisdom withal and a courtesy which I love thanks to their
                        dear-bought experience.</add> I met them so often in the woods—that they
                     began to look upon me at last as one of their kin. One a handsome younger man a
                     sailor-like—Greek-like man—says to me to-day—“Sir, I like your notions—I think
                     I shall live so myself. Only I should like wilder country, where there
                        <del>is</del>
                     <add>was</add> more game. I have been among the Indians near Apallachicola. I
                     have lived with them. I like your kind of life. Good-day, I wish you success
                     and happiness." They came in troops on Sundays in clean shirts, with washed
                     hands &amp; faces, and fresh twigs in their hands. There appeared in some of
                     these men even at a distance, a genuine magnanimity equal to Greek or Roman, of
                     unexplored and uncontaminated descent—The expression of their grimmed &amp;
                     sunburnt features made me think of Epaminondas of Socrates &amp; Cato. The most
                     famous philosophers &amp; poets seem in some respects infantile beside the easy
                     and successful life of natural men. These faces—homely—hard and scarred like
                     the rocks, but human &amp; wise—embracing Copt, and Mussulman and all tribes
                     &amp; nations. One is a pacha or Sultan—Selim—or Mustapha or Mahmoud in
                     disguise. Circumstances and employment may conceal for a season but they do not
                     essentially alter the finer qualities of our nature. I observe among these men
                     when I meet them on the road an ineradicable refinement &amp; delicacy—as old
                     as the sun &amp; moon.—A fineness which is commonly thought to adorn the
                     drawing rooms only. There is no more real rudeness in laborers &amp; washer
                     women—than in gentlemen and ladies. Under some ancient wrinkled, almost forlorn
                     visage of an Indian chieftain slumbers all that was ever writ or spoken of man.
                     You can tell a nobleman’s head though he may be shovelling gravel beneath it
                     six rods off in the midst of a gang with a bandana handkerchief tied about it.
                     Such as are to succeed the worthies of history. Their humble occupation which
                     allows them to take no airs upon themselves seems their least
                     disadvantage—Civilization seems to make bright only the superficial film of the
                     eye. Most men are wrecked upon their consciousness. </ab>
                  <ab change="#wc_0b">(preceded by two leaves, #99-101, from A that were taken into
                     B and renumbered, #117-119) men, descended from sound bodies, and still
                     transmitting arms and legs and bowels downward <del>from remote days to more
                        remote</del>. Some of them had got a rude wisdom withal and a courtesy which
                     I love, thanks to their dear-bought experience. <del>I met them so often in the
                        woods that they began to look upon me at last as one of their kin.</del> One
                     a handsome younger <del>man, a</del> sailor-like <del>Greek-like</del> man,
                     says to me to-day—“Sir, I like your notions, I think I shall live so myself.
                     Only I should like a wilder country where there is more game. I have been among
                     the Indians near Apallachicola. I have lived with them. I like your kind of
                     life. Good-day. I wish you success and happiness." They came in troops on
                     Sundays, in clean shirts with washed hands &amp; faces, and fresh twigs in
                     their hands. <del>Circumstances and employment affect but slowly the finer
                        qualities of our nature.</del> I <del>observe</del>
                     <add rendition="pencil">observed</add> in <add rendition="pencil">some of</add>
                     these men an inextinguishable and ineradicable refinement and delicacy of
                     nature, older and of more worth than the sun &amp; moon, which are commonly
                     thought to adorn the drawing rooms only. Sometimes a genuine magnanimity
                        <del>more than Greek or Roman</del> —equal to the least occasion, of
                     unexplored and uncontaminated descent. Greater traits <del>I seem to observe in
                        them</del>
                     <add rendition="pencil">methought I noticed</add> in the shortest intercourse,
                     than are recorded <del>of Epaminondas Socrates or Cato, With</del>
                     <add>any of these worthies. They had</add> faces homely, hard and seared like
                     the rocks, but human and wise<del>, embracing Copt and Mussulman, all races
                        &amp; nations. One is a pacha or Sultan—Selim—Mustapha or Mahmoud in
                        disguise. There is no more real rudeness in laborers or washerwomen than in
                        gentlemen &amp; ladies</del>. Under some ancient and wrinkled, almost
                     forlorn visage, as of an Indian chieftan <del>slumbers</del>
                     <add rendition="pencil">slumbered</add> the world famous <del>humanities</del>
                     <add rendition="pencil">qualities</add> of man. There is the race, and you need
                     look no further. <del>You can tell a nobleman’s head among a thousand—though he
                        may be shovelling gravel six rods off in the midst of a gang with cotton
                        handkerchief tied about it. Such a one as is to succeed the worthies of
                        history.</del> Their humble occupation and that they take no airs upon
                     themselves, are no disadvantage. Civilization makes bright only the superficial
                     film of the eye. Most men are wrecked upon their <del>consciences</del>
                     <add>consciousness. A farmer who lived near the skirts of the wood would pay me
                        a visit, and we took a sober view or even review of the state of the world,
                        &amp; many times we felt that it was good for us to have come together. We
                        consumed many hours endeavoring to crack those old &amp; now dry nuts on
                        which so many philosophers &amp; sour sectarians have left the marks of
                        their teeth, but for the most part we got only the flavor of their shells.
                        Those which are hardest to crack contain no meat &amp; wise squirrels do not
                        meddle with them</add>
                  </ab>
                  <ab change="#wc_0e">This passage follows Visitors 14b.</ab>
               </note> I had three chairs in my house; one for solitude, two for friendship, three
               for society. When visitors came in larger and unexpected numbers there was but the
               third chair for them all, but they generally economized the room by standing up. It
               is surprising how many great men and women a small house will contain. I have had
               twenty-five <anchor type="hn" xml:id="hn-06-002"/> or thirty souls,
                  <app xml:id="walc06-app-0007">
                  <lem>with their</lem>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0a">
                     <del>and</del>
                     <add rendition="pencil">with their</add>
                  </rdg>
               </app> bodies, at once under my roof, and yet we often parted without being aware
               that we had come very near to one<app xml:id="walc06-app-0008">
                  <lem>another</lem>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0a">other</rdg>
               </app>.<app xml:id="walc06-app-0009">
                  <lem> Many of our houses, both public and private, with their almost innumerable
                     apartments, their huge halls and their cellars for the storage of wines and
                     other munitions of peace, appear to be extravagantly large for their
                     inhabitants. They are so vast and magnificent that the latter seem to be only
                     vermin which infest them. I am surprised when the herald blows his summons
                     before some Tremont or Astor or Middlesex House, to see come creeping out over
                     the piazza for all inhabitants a ridiculous mouse, which soon again slinks into
                     some hole in the pavement</lem>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0a">
                     <del>Our houses generally with their huge halls &amp; garretts &amp; cellars,
                        seem to me extravagantly large for their inhabitants. One would certainly be
                        somewhat astonished, if when the herald blew his summons before the
                        Middle-sex House he should see come creeping out over the piazza for all
                        inhabitants a ridiculous mouse</del>
                     <add rendition="pencil">Many of our houses with their innumerable apartments,
                        their huge halls &amp; cellars for the storage of wines &amp; other
                        munitions of peace, seem to me extravagantly large for their inhabitants.
                        They are so vast &amp; grim—that the latter appear to be only vermin that
                        infest them. I am frequently astonished when the herald blows his summons
                        before some Tremont or Astor or Middle-sex House to see come creeping out
                        over the piazza for all inhabitants a ridiculous mouse, which soon as it
                        appears slinks into some hole in the pavement</add>
                  </rdg>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0b">Many of our houses both public and private, with their
                     innumerable apartments, their huge halls &amp; cellars for the storage of wines
                     and other munitions of peace, <del>seem</del>
                     <add>appear</add> to me extravagantly large for their inhabitants. They are so
                     vast and magnificent that the latter <del>appear</del>
                     <add>seem</add> to be only vermin that infest them. I am frequently astonished
                     when the herald blows his summons before some Tremont or Astor or Middlesex
                     House, to see come creeping out over the piazza for all inhabitants a
                     ridiculous mouse, which soon <add>again</add> slinks into some hole in the
                     doorstep</rdg>
               </app>. </p>

            <p n="3" change="#wc_0a">
               <note type="header" resp="#clapper">
                  <ab type="string">Visitors 3 written: A; rewritten: B, E.</ab>
                  <ab type="parsed">
                     <seg type="chapterNum">6</seg>
                     <seg type="chapterTitle">Visitors</seg>
                     <seg type="paragraph">3</seg>
                     <seg type="written">A</seg>
                     <seg type="rewritten">B, E</seg>
                  </ab>
                  <ab change="#wc_0e">A fair copy was made of only <quote>thoughts to get into
                        sailing trim … we gradually shoved our chairs</quote>.</ab>
               </note> One<app xml:id="walc06-app-0010">
                  <lem>inconvenience</lem>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0b">inconvenience <del>
                        <add>however</add>
                     </del>
                  </rdg>
               </app> I sometimes experienced in so small a house, the difficulty of getting to a
               sufficient distance from my guest when we began to utter the big thoughts in big
               words. You want room for your thoughts to get into sailing trim and run a course or
               two before they make their port. The bullet of your thought must have overcome its
               lateral and ricochet motion and fallen into its last and steady course before it<app xml:id="walc06-app-0011">
                  <lem>reaches</lem>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0a">falls into</rdg>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0b">
                     <del>falls into</del>
                     <add>reaches</add>
                  </rdg>
               </app> the ear of the hearer, else it may plough out<app xml:id="walc06-app-0012">
                  <lem>again</lem>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0a">
                     <add rendition="pencil">again</add>
                  </rdg>
               </app> through the side of his head.<app xml:id="walc06-app-0013">
                  <lem>Also,</lem>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0a #wc_0b #wc_0e"><!--[not in ms.]--></rdg>
               </app> our sentences wanted room to unfold and form their columns in the interval.
                  <app xml:id="walc06-app-0014">
                  <lem>Individuals, like nations, must have suitable broad and natural boundaries,
                     even a considerable neutral ground, between them</lem>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0a">
                     <del>We need a considerable neutral ground—though it be a disputed territory,
                        for</del> individuals like nations must have suitable broad and natural
                     boundaries <add rendition="pencil">even a considerable neutral ground—though it
                        be a disputed territory</add> between them.—The reason why the Kilkenny cats
                     quarrelled and ate each other all up but the tails in that hollow sphere,
                     certainly is that there was not room in that small space for their several
                     spheres to revolve</rdg>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0b #wc_0e">Individuals like nations must have suitable broad and
                     natural boundaries, even a considerable neutral ground, though it be a disputed
                     territory, between them</rdg>
               </app>.<app xml:id="walc06-app-0015">
                  <lem>I have found it a singular luxury to talk across the pond to a companion on
                     the opposite side.</lem>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0a">
                     <add rendition="pencil">I have found it a singular luxury to talk across the
                        pond to a companion on the opposite side.</add>
                  </rdg>
               </app>
               <app xml:id="walc06-app-0016">
                  <lem>In</lem>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0a">
                     <add rendition="pencil">or did you ever talk to the sexton across an empty
                        meeting house after the audience had gone? It is easy to be eloquent at such
                        a time</add> In</rdg>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0b">or did you ever talk to the sexton across an empty meeting house
                     after the audience <del>had gone</del>
                     <add>were gone out</add>? It is easy to be eloquent at such a time. In</rdg>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0e">and did you ever talk to the sexton across an empty
                     meeting-house after the audience were gone out? It is easy to be eloquent at
                     such a time and in such a place. In</rdg>
               </app> my house we were so near that we could not<app xml:id="walc06-app-0017">
                  <lem>begin to</lem>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0a">
                     <add rendition="pencil">begin to</add>
                  </rdg>
               </app> hear,—<app xml:id="walc06-app-0018">
                  <lem>we could not</lem>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0a">
                     <del>and</del>
                     <add rendition="pencil">or</add> we could not</rdg>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0b">and we could not</rdg>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0e">
                     <del>and we could not</del>
                     <del>
                        <add>nor could we</add>
                     </del>
                     <add>we could not</add>
                  </rdg>
               </app> speak low enough to be heard; as when you throw two stones into calm water<app xml:id="walc06-app-0019">
                  <lem>so</lem>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0a">
                     <del>but</del> so</rdg>
               </app> near that they break each other’s undulations. If we are<app xml:id="walc06-app-0020">
                  <lem>merely</lem>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0a #wc_0b">very</rdg>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0e">
                     <del>very</del>
                     <add>merely</add>
                  </rdg>
               </app> loquacious and loud talkers,<app xml:id="walc06-app-0021">
                  <lem>then</lem>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0a">then <add rendition="pencil">indeed</add>
                  </rdg>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0b #wc_0e">then indeed</rdg>
               </app> we can afford to stand very near together,<app xml:id="walc06-app-0022">
                  <lem>cheek by jowl,</lem>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0a">cheek by jowl, and shoulder to shoulder</rdg>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0b">
                     <add>shoulder to shoulder, and</add> cheek by jowl<del>, and shoulder to
                        shoulder</del>
                  </rdg>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0e">shoulder to shoulder, and cheek by jowl</rdg>
               </app>
               <app xml:id="walc06-app-0023">
                  <lem>and feel each other’s breath;</lem>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0a #wc_0b"><!-- [not in ms.]-->
                  </rdg>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0e">
                     <add>and feel each other’s breath;</add>
                  </rdg>
               </app> but if we speak reservedly and thoughtfully, we want to be farther apart, <app xml:id="walc06-app-0024">
                  <lem>that all animal heat and moisture may have a chance to evaporate. If we would
                     enjoy the most intimate society with that in each of us which is without, or
                     above, being spoken to, we must not only be silent, but commonly so far apart
                     bodily that we cannot possibly hear each other’s voice in any case. Referred to
                     this standard, speech is for the convenience of those who are hard of hearing;
                     but there are many fine things which we cannot say if we have to shout</lem>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0a">But if we would be silent we must commonly be so far apart that
                     we cannot possibly hear each other’s voices in any case <add rendition="pencil">&amp; that is what we commonly mean by solitude</add>
                  </rdg>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0b">
                     <del>But</del>
                     <add>Indeed</add> if we would be silent <add>&amp; yet enjoy the most intimate
                        society</add> we must <del>commonly</del> be so far apart <add>bodily</add>
                     that we cannot possibly hear each other’s voices in any case, <del>and</del>
                     <add>though</add> this is what men commonly <del>mean by</del>
                     <add>call</add> solitude</rdg>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0e">
                     <del>If we would be silent, and enjoy the most intimate society, we must
                        be</del>
                     <add>that all animal heat and moisture may have a chance to evaporate. If we
                        would enjoy the most intimate society with that in each of us which is
                        without or above being spoken to, we must</add>
                     <add rendition="pencil">not only be silent but commonly</add> so far apart
                     bodily, that we cannot possibly hear each other’s voices in any case<del>,
                        though this is what men commonly call solitude</del>. <add rendition="pencil">Referred to this standard</add>
                     <add>speech is for the convenience of those who are hard of hearing</add>
                     <add rendition="pencil">but there are many fine things which we cannot say if
                        we have to shout</add>
                  </rdg>
               </app>. As the conversation began to assume a loftier and grander<app xml:id="walc06-app-0025">
                  <lem>tone</lem>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0a">tone<add rendition="pencil">&amp; this was always the case when
                        it was successful</add>
                  </rdg>
               </app>, we gradually shoved our chairs farther apart till they touched the wall in
               opposite corners, and then<app xml:id="walc06-app-0026">
                  <lem>commonly</lem>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0a #wc_0b">sometimes</rdg>
               </app> there was not room<app xml:id="walc06-app-0027">
                  <lem>enough</lem>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0a #wc_0b">enough. If you do not want the fire to smoke you must not
                     stand too near it, so as to divert the current of the chimney’s
                     inspiration</rdg>
               </app>. </p>

            <p n="4" change="#wc_0a">
               <note type="header" resp="#clapper">
                  <ab type="string">Visitors 4 written: A; rewritten: B.</ab>
                  <ab type="parsed">
                     <seg type="chapterNum">6</seg>
                     <seg type="chapterTitle">Visitors</seg>
                     <seg type="paragraph">4</seg>
                     <seg type="written">A</seg>
                     <seg type="rewritten">B</seg>
                  </ab>
               </note> My “best" room, <app xml:id="walc06-app-0028">
                  <lem>however,</lem>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0a"><!-- [not in ms.]-->
                  </rdg>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0b">
                     <add rendition="pencil">however,</add>
                  </rdg>
               </app>
               <app xml:id="walc06-app-0029">
                  <lem>my withdrawing room,</lem>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0a">
                     <add rendition="pencil">my withdrawing room,</add>
                  </rdg>
               </app> always ready for company, on whose carpet the sun rarely<app xml:id="walc06-app-0030">
                  <lem>fell</lem>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0a #wc_0b">fell, for its green blinds were kept always closed</rdg>
               </app>, was the pine wood behind my house.<app xml:id="walc06-app-0031">
                  <lem>Thither in summer days, when distinguished guests came,</lem>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0a">There when distinguished guests came in summer days</rdg>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0b">There <add>in summer days</add> when distinguished guests came
                        <del>in summer days</del>
                  </rdg>
               </app> I took them, and<app xml:id="walc06-app-0032">
                  <lem>a priceless domestic</lem>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0a #wc_0b">Nature was my domestic that</rdg>
               </app> swept the floor and dusted the furniture and kept the things in order. </p>

            <p n="5" change="#wc_0a">
               <note type="header" resp="#clapper">
                  <ab type="string">Visitors 5 written: A; rewritten: B.</ab>
                  <ab type="parsed">
                     <seg type="chapterNum">6</seg>
                     <seg type="chapterTitle">Visitors</seg>
                     <seg type="paragraph">5</seg>
                     <seg type="written">A</seg>
                     <seg type="rewritten">B</seg>
                  </ab>
                  <ab change="#wc_0a">
                     <quote>You need not rest your reputation … never revisit those scenes</quote>
                     is interlined in pencil.</ab>
                  <ab change="#wc_0b">A fair copy was made of only <quote>if one guest came … bread
                        enough for two, more than if eating</quote>. A leaf (#109) from A containing
                     the rest of Visitors 5 and the first half of Visitors 6 was taken into B and
                     renumbered (#127).</ab>
               </note> If one guest<app xml:id="walc06-app-0033">
                  <lem>came</lem>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0b">came <add>to my house</add>
                  </rdg>
               </app> he sometimes partook of my frugal meal, and it was no interruption to
               conversation to be stirring a<app xml:id="walc06-app-0034">
                  <lem>hasty-pudding,</lem>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0a">hasty-pudding,<del>in the meanwhile</del>
                  </rdg>
               </app> or watching the rising and maturing of a loaf of bread in the ashes, in the
               mean while. But if twenty came and sat in my house there was nothing said about
               dinner, though there might be bread enough for two, more than if eating were a
               forsaken habit; but we naturally practised abstinence; and this was never felt to be
               an offence against hospitality, but the most proper and considerate course. The waste
               and decay of physical life, which so often needs repair, seemed miraculously retarded
                  <app xml:id="walc06-app-0035">
                  <lem>in such a case</lem>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0a">
                     <add>in such a case</add>
                  </rdg>
               </app>, and the vital vigor stood its ground. I could entertain thus a thousand as
               well as twenty; and<app xml:id="walc06-app-0036">
                  <lem>if</lem>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0a">
                     <del>I am not aware that</del>
                     <add>if</add>
                  </rdg>
               </app> any ever went away disappointed or hungry from my house when they found me at
               home, <app xml:id="walc06-app-0037">
                  <lem>they may depend upon it that I sympathized with them at least</lem>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0a">
                     <add rendition="pencil">they may depend upon it that I sympathized with them at
                        least</add>
                  </rdg>
               </app>. So easy is it, though many housekeepers doubt it, to establish new and better
               customs in the place of the old.<app xml:id="walc06-app-0038">
                  <lem>You</lem>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0a">I mention this to show that you</rdg>
               </app> need not rest your reputation on the dinners you give. For my own part, I was
               never so effectually deterred from frequenting a man’s house, by any kind of Cerberus
               whatever, as by the parade<app xml:id="walc06-app-0039">
                  <lem>one made about</lem>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0a">he made of</rdg>
               </app> dining me, which I took to be a very polite and roundabout hint never to
               trouble him so again. I think I shall never revisit those scenes.<app xml:id="walc06-app-0040">
                  <lem>I should be proud to have for the motto of my cabin those lines of
                     Spenser</lem>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0a">To quote the lines</rdg>
               </app> which one of my visitors inscribed on a yellow walnut leaf<app xml:id="walc06-app-0041">
                  <lem>for a card</lem>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0a">and which <add>may</add> make <del>part of</del> the motto of my
                     house</rdg>
               </app>:— <quote>
                  <lg>
                     <l>“Arrivéd there, the little house they fill, </l>
                     <l>Ne looke for entertainment where none was; </l>
                     <l>Rest is their feast, and all things at their will: </l>
                     <l>The noblest mind the best contentment has."</l>
                  </lg>
               </quote>
            </p>

            <p n="6" change="#wc_0a">
               <note type="header" resp="#clapper">
                  <ab type="string">Visitors 6 written: A; rewritten: B, C.</ab>
                  <ab type="parsed">
                     <seg type="chapterNum">6</seg>
                     <seg type="chapterTitle">Visitors</seg>
                     <seg type="paragraph">6</seg>
                     <seg type="written">A</seg>
                     <seg type="rewritten">B, C</seg>
                  </ab>
                  <ab change="#wc_0b #wc_0c">Fair copies were made of only <quote>savages’ barbarous
                        singing … no deficiency in this respect</quote>.</ab>
               </note> When Winslow, afterward governor of the Plymouth Colony, went with a
               companion on a visit of ceremony to Massassoit on foot through the woods, and arrived
               tired and hungry <app xml:id="walc06-app-0042">
                  <lem>at his lodge,</lem>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0a">
                     <add>at his lodge,</add>
                  </rdg>
               </app> they were well received by the king, but nothing was said about eating that
               day. When the night arrived, to quote their own words,—“He laid us on the bed with
               himself and his wife, they at the one end and we at the other, it being only plank,
               laid a foot from the ground and a thin mat upon them. Two more of his chief men, for
               want of room, pressed by and upon us; so that we were worse weary of our lodging than
               of our journey." At one o’clock the next day Massassoit "brought two fishes that he
               had shot," about thrice as big as a bream; “these being boiled, there were at least
               forty looked for a share in them. The most ate of them. This meal only we had in two
               nights and a day; and had not one of us bought a partridge, we had taken our journey
               fasting." <app xml:id="walc06-app-0043">
                  <lem>Fearing that they would be light-headed for want of food and also sleep,
                     owing to “the savages’ barbarous singing, (for they use to sing themselves
                     asleep,)" and that they might get home while they had strength to travel, they
                     departed. As for lodging, it is true they were but poorly entertained, though
                     what they found an inconvenience was no doubt intended for an honor; but as far
                     as eating was concerned, I do not see how the Indians could have done better.
                     They had nothing to eat themselves, and they were wiser than to think that
                     apologies could supply the place of food to their guests; so they drew their
                     belts tighter and said nothing about it. Another time when Winslow visited
                     them, it being a season of plenty with them, there was no deficiency in this
                     respect</lem>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0a">
                     <del>For fear</del>
                     <add rendition="pencil">Fearing that</add> they should be light-headed for want
                     of <add rendition="pencil">food &amp; also</add> sleep <del>on account of</del>
                     <add rendition="pencil">owing to</add> “the savages’ barbarous singing (for
                     they used to sing themselves asleep)," and for want of food, and that they
                     might get home while they had strength to travel—they departed. The fact
                     was—the Indians had nothing to eat themselves—and they were wiser than to think
                     that apologies &amp; ceremony could supply the place of food <add rendition="pencil">to their guests</add>—and so <add rendition="pencil">they
                        drew their belts tighter &amp;</add> said nothing about it—<add rendition="pencil">As for lodging indeed they were but poorly entertained,
                        but as far as eating was concerned I do not see how the Indians could have
                        done better.</add> This was a time of fasting with them. At another time
                     when Winslow visited them—<del>they</del>
                     <add>he</add> got as much to eat as he got little before </rdg>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0b">savages’ barbarous singing (for they used to sing themselves
                     asleep)," <del>and for want of food</del> and <add rendition="pencil">in
                        order</add> that they might get home while they had strength to travel they
                     departed. <add rendition="pencil">As for lodging, it must be confessed that the
                        whites were but poorly entertained, but as far as eating was concerned I do
                        not see how the Indians could have done better.</add> The fact was the
                     Indians had nothing to eat themselves, <add rendition="pencil">it was a time of
                        involuntary fasting with them</add> and they were wiser than to think that
                     apologies &amp; ceremony could supply the place of food to their guests,
                        <del>and</del> so they drew their belts tighter and said nothing about it.
                        <del>As for lodging, indeed, they were but poorly entertained, but as far as
                        eating was concerned I do not see how the Indians could have done better.
                        This was a time of fasting with them</del>
                  </rdg>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0c">savages’ barbarous singing (for they used to sing themselves
                     asleep)" and in order that they might get home while they had strength to
                     travel, they departed. As for lodging, it must be confessed that the whites
                     were but poorly entertained, but as far as eating was concerned, I do not see
                     how the Indians could have done better. They had nothing to eat themselves, and
                     they were wiser than to think that apologies &amp; ceremony could supply the
                     place of food to their guests; so they drew their belts tighter, and said
                     nothing about it</rdg>
               </app>. </p>

            <p n="7" change="#wc_0a">
               <note type="header" resp="#clapper">
                  <ab type="string">Visitors 7 written: A; rewritten: E.</ab>
                  <ab type="parsed">
                     <seg type="chapterNum">6</seg>
                     <seg type="chapterTitle">Visitors</seg>
                     <seg type="paragraph">7</seg>
                     <seg type="written">A</seg>
                     <seg type="rewritten">E</seg>
                  </ab>
                  <ab change="#wc_0a #wc_0e">
                     <quote>But fewer came to see me on trivial business … uncultivated continents
                        on the other side</quote> does not appear in the manuscript in A or in the
                     original copying of E but is interlined in pencil in E.</ab>
               </note> As for men, they will hardly fail one any where. I <app xml:id="walc06-app-0044">
                  <lem>had more visitors while</lem>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0a">
                     <del>have</del> had more <add>of their</add> society <del>since</del>
                     <add rendition="pencil">while</add>
                  </rdg>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0e">had more <del>of their society</del>
                     <add rendition="pencil">visitors</add> while</rdg>
               </app> I lived in the woods than at any other period in my life; <app xml:id="walc06-app-0045">
                  <lem>I mean that I had some.</lem>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0a #wc_0e"><!-- [not in ms.]--></rdg>
               </app>
               <app xml:id="walc06-app-0046">
                  <lem>I met several</lem>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0a">I met many <del>men</del>
                  </rdg>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0e">
                     <add rendition="pencil">&amp;</add> I met <del>many</del>
                     <add>several</add>
                  </rdg>
               </app> there under more favorable circumstances than I could any where else.<app xml:id="walc06-app-0047">
                  <lem>But</lem>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0e">
                     <del>Yet</del>
                  </rdg>
               </app> fewer came to see me on trivial<app xml:id="walc06-app-0048">
                  <lem>business.</lem>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0e">business<add>it is true.</add>
                  </rdg>
               </app> In this respect, my company was winnowed by my mere distance from town. I had
               withdrawn so far<app xml:id="walc06-app-0049">
                  <lem>within</lem>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0e">
                     <del>into</del>
                     <add>within</add>
                  </rdg>
               </app> the great ocean of solitude, into which the rivers of society empty, that for
               the most part, so far as my needs were concerned, only the finest sediment was
                  deposited<app xml:id="walc06-app-0050">
                  <lem>around me. Beside,</lem>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0e">
                     <del>where I was. Also</del>
                     <add rendition="pencil">around me. Beside</add>
                  </rdg>
               </app> there were wafted to me evidences of unexplored and uncultivated continents on
               the other side.</p>

            <p n="8" change="#wc_0a">
               <seg n="8a" change="#wc_0a">
                  <note type="header" resp="#clapper">
                     <ab type="string">Visitors 8a written: A; rewritten: E.</ab>
                     <ab type="parsed">
                        <seg type="chapterNum">6</seg>
                        <seg type="chapterTitle">Visitors</seg>
                        <seg type="paragraph">8a</seg>
                        <seg type="written">A</seg>
                        <seg type="rewritten">E</seg>
                     </ab>
                     <ab change="#wc_0a">Visitors 8-13 appears in the following order—8a, 10a, 12a,
                        11b, 8b, 11a, 10b, 13a, 11d, 11f, and 13b.</ab>
                  </note> Who should come to my lodge this morning but a true Homeric<app xml:id="walc06-app-0052">
                     <lem>or Paphlagonian</lem>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0a">
                        <del>or Paphlagonian</del>
                     </rdg>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0e">
                        <del>or</del>
                        <add>a</add> Paphlagonian</rdg>
                  </app> man,—<app xml:id="walc06-app-0053">
                     <lem>he had so suitable and poetic a name that I am sorry I cannot print it
                        here,</lem>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0a #wc_0e">
                        <del>Alex Therien—(terren, Alexander the Farmer) he calls himself</del>
                        <add>he had so suitable and poetic a name that I am sorry I cannot print it
                           here,</add>
                     </rdg>
                  </app>—a Canadian, a wood-chopper and post-maker, who can hole fifty posts in a
                  day, who made his last supper on a woodchuck which his dog caught. He, too, has
                  heard of Homer, and, “if it were not for books," would “not know what to do rainy
                  days," though perhaps he has not read one wholly through for many rainy seasons.
                  Some priest who could pronounce the Greek itself taught him to read his verse in
                  the testament<app xml:id="walc06-app-0054">
                     <lem>in his native parish far away</lem>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0a">at Nicolèt, away by the Trois Riviers once</rdg>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0e">
                        <del>at Nicolèt, away by the Trois Riviers</del> once <add>in his native
                           parish far away</add>
                     </rdg>
                  </app>; and now I must translate to him, while he holds the book, Achilles’
                  reproof to Patroclus for his sad countenance.—“Why are you in tears, Patroclus, like a young girl?"—<lg>
                     <l>“Or have you alone heard some news from Phthia? </l>
                     <l>They say that Menœtius lives yet, son of Actor, </l>
                     <l>And Peleus lives, son of Æacus, among the Myrmidons, </l>
                     <l>Either of whom
                        <app xml:id="walc06-app-0055">
                           <lem>having died,</lem>
                           <rdg wit="#wc_0a">
                              <del>dead</del>
                              <add>having died,</add>
                           </rdg>
                        </app>
                    we should greatly grieve." </l>
                  </lg>
                   He says, “That’s good." He has a great bundle of
                  white-oak bark under his arm for a sick man, gathered this Sunday morning. “I
                  suppose there’s no harm in going after such a thing to-day,"<app xml:id="walc06-app-0056">
                     <lem>says he.</lem>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0a"><!-- [not in ms.]-->
                     </rdg>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0e">
                        <add rendition="pencil">says he.</add>
                     </rdg>
                  </app>
                  <app xml:id="walc06-app-0057">
                     <lem>To him Homer was a great writer, though what his writing was about he did
                        not know</lem>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0a">
                        <del>He had heard of Homer.</del>
                        <add>To him</add> Homer was a great writer, though what his writing was
                        about under the sun he did not know. I have since seen Therien many
                        times</rdg>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0e">To him Homer was a great writer, though what his writing was
                        about under the sun he did not know. <del>I have since seen him many
                           times</del>
                     </rdg>
                  </app>. A more simple and natural man<app xml:id="walc06-app-0058">
                     <lem>it would be hard to find.</lem>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0a">
                        <del>I never saw</del>
                        <add rendition="pencil">it would be hard to find.</add>
                     </rdg>
                  </app> Vice and disease, which cast such a sombre moral hue over the world,<app xml:id="walc06-app-0059">
                     <lem>seemed to have</lem>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0a">had</rdg>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0e">
                        <del>had</del>
                        <del>
                           <add>appeared to</add>
                        </del>
                        <add rendition="pencil">seemed to</add>
                        <add>have</add>
                     </rdg>
                  </app> hardly any existence for him. <app xml:id="walc06-app-0060">
                     <lem>He was about twenty-eight years old, and had left Canada and his father’s
                        house a dozen years before to work in the States, and earn money to buy a
                        farm with at last, perhaps in his native country</lem>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0a">He left Canada and his father’s house a dozen years ago to
                        work in the states, and earn money to buy a farm with at last, perhaps in
                        his native country</rdg>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0e">
                        <del>He left Canada and his father’s house a dozen years ago to work in the
                           States, and earn money perhaps to buy a farm with at last in his native
                           country.</del> He was about twenty-eight years old <add>&amp; had left
                           Canada and his father’s house a dozen years before to work in the States,
                           and earn money to buy a farm with at last perhaps in his native
                           country</add>
                     </rdg>
                  </app>. </seg>
               <seg n="8b" change="#wc_0a">
                  <note type="header" resp="#clapper">
                     <ab type="string">Visitors 8b written: A; rewritten: E.</ab>
                     <ab type="parsed">
                        <seg type="chapterNum">6</seg>
                        <seg type="chapterTitle">Visitors</seg>
                        <seg type="paragraph">8b</seg>
                        <seg type="written">A</seg>
                        <seg type="rewritten">E</seg>
                     </ab>
                     <ab change="#wc_0a">Visitors 8b follows Visitors 11b.</ab>
                  </note>
                  <app xml:id="walc06-app-0062">
                     <lem>He was cast in the coarsest mould; a stout but sluggish body, yet
                        gracefully carried, with a thick sunburnt neck, dark bushy hair, and dull
                        sleepy blue eyes, which were occasionally lit up with expression</lem>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0a">He was about 28 years old—stout &amp; sluggish, with a strong
                        thick fleshy &amp; sunburnt neck &amp; dark bushy hair &amp; dull sleepy
                        &amp; quiet blue eye—breathed hard and smelled of his work</rdg>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0e">He was <del>about twenty-eight years old,</del> cast in the
                        coarsest mould, <del>sluggish and stout of</del>
                        <add rendition="pencil">a stout but sluggish</add> body with a
                           <del>strong</del> thick <del>fleshy</del> sunburnt neck, dark bushy hair,
                        and dull sleepy blue eyes, <del>breathed hard and smelled of his work</del>
                     </rdg>
                  </app>. He wore a flat gray cloth cap, a dingy wool-colored<app xml:id="walc06-app-0063">
                     <lem>greatcoat</lem>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0a">greatcoat which draped and concealed his body</rdg>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0e">greatcoat <del>which draped and concealed his body</del>
                     </rdg>
                  </app>, and cowhide boots. He<app xml:id="walc06-app-0064">
                     <lem>was</lem>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0a">was <del>strong-limbed and</del>
                     </rdg>
                  </app> a great consumer of meat, usually carrying his dinner to his work a couple
                  of miles past my house,—for he chopped all summer,—in a tin pail; cold meats,
                  often cold<app xml:id="walc06-app-0065">
                     <lem>woodchucks</lem>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0a #wc_0e">woodchucks which his dog had caught</rdg>
                  </app>, and coffee in a stone bottle which dangled by a string<app xml:id="walc06-app-0066">
                     <lem>from his belt;</lem>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0a">
                        <add rendition="pencil">from his belt;</add>
                     </rdg>
                  </app> and sometimes he offered me a drink. He came along early, crossing my
                  bean-field, though without<app xml:id="walc06-app-0067">
                     <lem>anxiety</lem>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0a">any anxiety</rdg>
                  </app> or haste to get to his work, such as Yankees exhibit. <app xml:id="walc06-app-0068">
                     <lem>He wasn’t a-going to hurt himself. He didn’t care if he only earned his
                        board.</lem>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0a #wc_0e"><!-- [not in ms.]--></rdg>
                  </app> Frequently he would leave his dinner in the bushes, when his dog had caught
                  a woodchuck<app xml:id="walc06-app-0069">
                     <lem>by the way,</lem>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0a">
                        <add>by the way,</add>
                     </rdg>
                  </app> and go back a mile and a half to dress it and leave it in the cellar of the
                  house where he boarded, after deliberating<app xml:id="walc06-app-0070">
                     <lem>first</lem>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0a #wc_0e"><!-- [not in ms.]--></rdg>
                  </app> for half an hour whether he could not sink it in the pond safely till
                  nightfall,—loving to dwell long upon these themes. He would say, as he went by in
                  the morning, “How thick the pigeons are! If working every day were not my trade, I
                  could get all the meat I should want by hunting,—pigeons, woodchucks, rabbits,
                     partridges,—by<app xml:id="walc06-app-0071">
                     <lem>gosh</lem>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0a">
                        <del>George</del>
                        <add rendition="pencil">gosh</add>
                     </rdg>
                  </app>! I could get all I should want for a week in one day." </seg>
            </p>

            <p n="9" change="#wc_0c">
               <note type="header" resp="#clapper">
                  <ab type="string">Visitors 9 written: C; rewritten: E.</ab>
                  <ab type="parsed">
                     <seg type="chapterNum">6</seg>
                     <seg type="chapterTitle">Visitors</seg>
                     <seg type="paragraph">9</seg>
                     <seg type="written">C</seg>
                     <seg type="rewritten">E</seg>
                  </ab>
                  <ab change="#wc_0c #wc_0e">Visitors 9, which was interlined in pencil in C,
                     follows Visitors 10b and precedes Visitors 12a.</ab>
               </note> He was a skilful chopper, and indulged in some flourishes and ornaments in
               his art. He cut his trees<app xml:id="walc06-app-0072">
                  <lem>level</lem>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0c">so level</rdg>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0e">
                     <del>so</del> level</rdg>
               </app> and close to the ground, <app xml:id="walc06-app-0073">
                  <lem>that the sprouts which came up afterward might be more vigorous and a sled
                     might slide over the stumps</lem>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0c">that a sled could slide over them</rdg>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0e">that a sled could slide over <del>them</del>
                     <add rendition="pencil">the stumps, and because the sprouts that came up
                        afterward were the better for it</add>
                  </rdg>
               </app>; and instead of leaving a whole tree to support his corded wood, he would pare
               it away to a slender stake or splinter which you could break off with your hand at
               last. </p>

            <p n="10" change="#wc_0a">
               <seg n="10a" change="#wc_0a">
                  <note type="header" resp="#clapper">
                     <ab type="string">Visitors 10a written: A; rewritten: C, E.</ab>
                     <ab type="parsed">
                        <seg type="chapterNum">6</seg>
                        <seg type="chapterTitle">Visitors</seg>
                        <seg type="paragraph">10a</seg>
                        <seg type="written">A</seg>
                        <seg type="rewritten">C, E</seg>
                     </ab>
                     <ab change="#wc_0a">Visitors 10a follows Visitors 8a and precedes Visitors
                        12a.</ab>
                  </note>He interested me because he was so<app xml:id="walc06-app-0075">
                     <lem>quiet and solitary and so happy</lem>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0a">
                        <del>happy—so solitary—so quiet</del>
                        <add rendition="pencil">quiet &amp; solitary &amp; so happy</add>
                     </rdg>
                  </app>
                  <app xml:id="walc06-app-0076">
                     <lem>withal;</lem>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0a"><!-- [not in ms.]-->
                     </rdg>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0c">
                        <add rendition="pencil">withal;</add>
                     </rdg>
                  </app>
                  <app xml:id="walc06-app-0077">
                     <lem>a well</lem>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0a">He was a well</rdg>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0c">He was a <del>world</del>
                        <add>well</add>
                     </rdg>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0e">
                        <del>He was</del> a well</rdg>
                  </app> of good humor and<app xml:id="walc06-app-0078">
                     <lem>contentment</lem>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0a">
                        <del>happiness</del>
                        <add rendition="pencil">contentment</add>
                     </rdg>
                  </app> which overflowed at his eyes. His mirth was without alloy.</seg>
               <seg n="10b" change="#wc_0a">
                  <note type="header" resp="#clapper">
                     <ab type="string">Visitors 10b written: A; rewritten: C, E.</ab>
                     <ab type="parsed">
                        <seg type="chapterNum">6</seg>
                        <seg type="chapterTitle">Visitors</seg>
                        <seg type="paragraph">10b</seg>
                        <seg type="written">A</seg>
                        <seg type="rewritten">C, E</seg>
                     </ab>
                     <ab change="#wc_0a">Visitors 10b follows Visitors 11a and precedes Visitors
                        13a.</ab>
                  </note> Sometimes I saw him at <app xml:id="walc06-app-0080">
                     <lem>his</lem>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0a #wc_0c">his own</rdg>
                  </app> work in the woods, felling trees, and he would greet me with a laugh of
                  inexpressible satisfaction, and a salutation in Canadian French, though he spoke
                  English as <app xml:id="walc06-app-0081">
                     <lem>well</lem>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0a">well, and when I asked him in which he thought now, or if he
                        spoke aloud to himself which language he used—you know we sometimes talk to
                        ourselves—“Yes—some times" <del>answered he</del>—He said it was in
                        English</rdg>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0c">well—and when I asked him in which he thought now, or if he
                        spoke aloud to himself, which language he used—you know we sometimes talk to
                        ourselves—Yes, sometimes—he said it was in English</rdg>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0e">well, and when I asked him in which he thought now, or, if he
                        spoke aloud to himself, which language he used, you know we sometimes talk
                        to ourselves, said I—“Yes, sometimes," <del>he would reply</del>—He said it
                        was English</rdg>
                  </app>. When I approached him he would suspend his work, and with half-suppressed
                  mirth lie along the trunk of a <app xml:id="walc06-app-0082">
                     <lem>pine which he had felled, and, peeling off the inner bark, roll it up
                        into</lem>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0a">tree <add rendition="pencil">which</add> he had felled and
                        peeling off the pine bark, roll it up in</rdg>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0c">tree which he had felled, and peeling off the pine bark, roll
                        it up into</rdg>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0e">
                        <add>pine</add> tree which he had felled, and peeling off the bark, roll it
                        up into</rdg>
                  </app> a ball and chew it while he laughed and talked. Such an exuberance of
                  animal spirits had he that he <app xml:id="walc06-app-0083">
                     <lem>sometimes tumbled down and rolled</lem>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0a #wc_0c #wc_0e">would sometimes tumble down and roll</rdg>
                  </app> on the ground with laughter at any thing which made him think and tickled
                  him. <app xml:id="walc06-app-0084">
                     <lem>Looking round upon the trees he would exclaim,—“By George! I can enjoy
                        myself well enough here chopping; I want no better sport."</lem>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0a #wc_0c"><!-- [not in ms.]-->
                     </rdg>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0e">
                        <add rendition="pencil">Looking round upon the trees he would <del>say</del>
                           <add rendition="pencil">exclaim</add>,—By George—I can enjoy myself well
                           enough <del>in the woods</del>
                           <add rendition="pencil">here</add> chopping—I want no better sport.</add>
                     </rdg>
                  </app> Sometimes, when at leisure, he <app xml:id="walc06-app-0085">
                     <lem>amused himself all day in the woods with a pocket pistol, firing salutes
                        to himself at regular intervals as he walked</lem>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0a">would amuse himself all day in the woods with a little pocket
                        pistol firing salutes of powder to himself at regular intervals as he
                        travelled—and would occasionally steal up behind my house and fire a stout
                        charge—&amp; laugh loudly at my surprise <add rendition="pencil"> or at his
                           own trick</add> He loved also to frighten his dog when alone with him in
                        the woods—by pointing his pistol at him &amp; firing powder only</rdg>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0c">would amuse himself all day in the woods with a little pocket
                        pistol firing salutes <del>of powder</del> to himself at regular intervals
                        as he travelled and would occasionally steal up behind my house and fire a
                        stout charge, and laugh loudly at my surprise or at his own trick. He loved
                        also to frighten his dog when alone with him in the woods by pointing his
                        pistol at him and firing powder only</rdg>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0e">would amuse himself all day in the woods with a
                           <del>little</del> pocket pistol firing salutes to himself at regular
                        intervals as he travelled <add>or he would frighten his dog by pointing his
                           pistol at him and firing powder only</add> and <del>would</del>
                        occasionally <add>he would</add> steal up be-hind my house and fire a stout
                        charge, and laugh loudly at my surprise or his own trick. <del>He loved also
                           to frighten his dog when alone with him in his woods by pointing his
                           pistol at him and firing powder only</del>
                     </rdg>
                  </app>. <app xml:id="walc06-app-0086">
                     <lem>In the winter he had a fire by which at noon he warmed his coffee in a
                        kettle; and as he sat on a log to eat his dinner the chickadees would
                        sometimes come round and alight on his arm and peck at the potato in his
                        fingers; and he said that he “liked to have the little <hi rend="italic">fellers</hi> about him."</lem>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0a">
                        <add>In winter days when chopping in the woods he had a fire by which at
                           noon he warmed his coffee in a tin kettle, and <add rendition="pencil">as
                              he</add> sat on a log to eat his dinner<del>. He told me that</del>
                           the chickadees would come round &amp; light on his arm and peck at the
                           potatoe in his fingers, &amp; he <del>added “I like"</del>
                           <add rendition="pencil">said that he “liked</add> to have the little
                           fellers about <del>me</del>
                           <add rendition="pencil">him.</add>
                        </add>
                     </rdg>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0c">In winter he chopped in the woods and had a fire by which at
                        noon he warmed his coffee in a tin kettle and as he sat on a log to eat his
                        dinner the chickadees would come round and light on his arm and peck at the
                        potatoe in his fingers, and he said that he “liked to have the little
                        fellers about him."</rdg>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0e">In <add>the</add> winter he <del>chopped in the woods
                           and</del> had a fire by which at noon he warmed his coffee in a tin
                        kettle, and as he sat on a log to eat his dinner the chickadees would <add rendition="pencil">sometimes</add> come round and <del>light</del>
                        <add rendition="pencil">alight</add> on his arm and peck at the potatoe in
                        his fingers, and he said that he “liked to have the little fellers about
                        him."</rdg>
                  </app>
               </seg>
            </p>

            <p n="11" change="#wc_0a">
               <seg n="11a" change="#wc_0a">
                  <note type="header" resp="#clapper">
                     <ab type="string">Visitors 11a written: A; rewritten: B, C, E.</ab>
                     <ab type="parsed">
                        <seg type="chapterNum">6</seg>
                        <seg type="chapterTitle">Visitors</seg>
                        <seg type="paragraph">11a</seg>
                        <seg type="written">A</seg>
                        <seg type="rewritten">B, C, E</seg>
                     </ab>
                     <ab change="#wc_0a">Visitors 11a follows Visitors 8b and precedes Visitors
                        10b.</ab>
                     <ab change="#wc_0b">Visitors 11a follows Visitors 11e and precedes Visitors
                        12b.</ab>
                     <ab change="#wc_0c">Visitors 11-12 appears in the following order—12a, 12c,
                        11b, 11c, 11d, 11f, 11a, and 12b.</ab>
                  </note>
                  <app xml:id="walc06-app-0088">
                     <lem>In him the animal man chiefly was developed.</lem>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0a"><!-- [not in ms.]-->
                     </rdg>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0b">
                        <add rendition="pencil">In him the animal man chiefly was developed.</add>
                     </rdg>
                  </app>
                  <app xml:id="walc06-app-0089">
                     <lem>In physical endurance and contentment he was cousin to the pine and the
                        rock</lem>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0a">If others had cultivated their intellectual faculties till
                        they astonished him—his physical contentment and endurance—like
                           <del>the</del>
                        <add rendition="pencil">a</add> cousin to the pine &amp; the rock was
                        equally astonishing to them</rdg>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0b">
                        <del>If others had cultivated their intellectual faculties till they
                           astonished him, his</del>
                        <add>In</add> physical contentment &amp; endurance <del>like a</del>
                        <add> he was cousin to the</add> pine and the rock <del>was equally
                           astonishing to them</del>
                     </rdg>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0c">in physical contentment &amp; endurance he was cousin to the
                        pine &amp; the rock</rdg>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0e">In physical <del>contentment and</del> endurance <add>and
                           contentment</add> he was cousin to the pine and the rock</rdg>
                  </app>. I asked him once if he was not sometimes tired at night, after working all
                  day; and he answered, with a sincere and serious <app xml:id="walc06-app-0090">
                     <lem>look</lem>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0a #wc_0b #wc_0c">look, quite truthful</rdg>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0e">look, <del>quite truthful</del>
                     </rdg>
                  </app>, "Gorrappit, I never was tired in my life."<app xml:id="walc06-app-0091">
                     <lem>But the intellectual and what is called spiritual man in him were
                        slumbering as in an infant</lem>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0a">It sounded like the triumph of the physical man</rdg>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0b">It sounded like the triumph of the physical man <add rendition="pencil">But the intellectual and spiritual man in him were
                           slumbering like an infant</add>
                     </rdg>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0c">It sounded like the triumph of the physical man. But the
                        intellectual and spiritual man in him were slumbering <del>like</del>
                        <add rendition="pencil">as in</add> an infant</rdg>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0e">
                        <del>It sounded like the triumph of the physical man.</del> But the
                        intellectual and <add>what is called</add> spiritual man in him were
                        slumbering as in an infant</rdg>
                  </app>. </seg>
               <seg n="11b" change="#wc_0a">
                  <note type="header" resp="#clapper">
                     <ab type="string">Visitors 11b written: A; rewritten: C, E.</ab>
                     <ab type="parsed">
                        <seg type="chapterNum">6</seg>
                        <seg type="chapterTitle">Visitors</seg>
                        <seg type="paragraph">11b</seg>
                        <seg type="written">A</seg>
                        <seg type="rewritten">C, E</seg>
                     </ab>
                     <ab change="#wc_0a">Visitors 11b follows Visitors 12a and precedes Visitors
                        8b.</ab>
                     <ab change="#wc_0c">Visitors 11b follows Visitors 12c.</ab>
                  </note> He had been instructed only in that innocent and ineffectual way in which
                  the Catholic priests teach the aborigines, <app xml:id="walc06-app-0093">
                     <lem>by</lem>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0a #wc_0c">in</rdg>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0e">
                        <del>in</del>
                        <add>by</add>
                     </rdg>
                  </app> which the pupil is never educated to the degree of consciousness, but only
                  to the degree of trust and reverence, and a child is not made a man, but kept a
                  child. When Nature made him, she gave him <app xml:id="walc06-app-0094">
                     <lem>a strong body and contentment for his portion, and propped him</lem>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0a">contentment for his portion, a strong body and health and
                        propped him, as it were</rdg>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0c">
                        <del>contentment for his portion,</del> a strong body <add>&amp; contentment
                           for his portion</add>, and propped him</rdg>
                  </app> on every side with reverence and reliance, that he might live out his
                  threescore years and ten a child.</seg>
               <seg n="11c" change="#wc_0b">
                  <note type="header" resp="#clapper">
                     <ab type="string">Visitors 11c written: B; rewritten: C, E.</ab>
                     <ab type="parsed">
                        <seg type="chapterNum">6</seg>
                        <seg type="chapterTitle">Visitors</seg>
                        <seg type="paragraph">11c</seg>
                        <seg type="written">B</seg>
                        <seg type="rewritten">C, E</seg>
                     </ab>
                     <ab change="#wc_0b">Visitors 11c follows Visitors 13b and precedes Visitors
                        11e.</ab>
                  </note>
                  <app xml:id="walc06-app-0096">
                     <lem>He was so genuine and unsophisticated that</lem>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0b"><!-- [not in ms.]--></rdg>
                  </app> no introduction would serve to introduce him, more than if you introduced a
                  woodchuck to your neighbor. He had got to find him out as you did. He would not
                  play any<app xml:id="walc06-app-0097">
                     <lem>part</lem>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0b">part, <del>Like all children he <del>lived</del>
                           <add rendition="pencil">amused himself chiefly</add> alone, not in
                           society, nor where rumor and fame reach</del>
                     </rdg>
                  </app>. <app xml:id="walc06-app-0098">
                     <lem>Men paid him wages for work, and so helped to feed and clothe him</lem>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0b #wc_0c">Men helped to feed &amp; clothe him &amp; paid him his
                        wages for work</rdg>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0e">Men <del>helped to feed &amp; clothe him &amp;</del> paid him
                        his wages for work <add>&amp; so helped to feed &amp; clothe him</add>
                     </rdg>
                  </app>; but he never exchanged opinions with them. </seg>
               <seg n="11d" change="#wc_0a">
                  <note type="header" resp="#clapper">
                     <ab type="string">Visitors 11d written: A; rewritten: C, E.</ab>
                     <ab type="parsed">
                        <seg type="chapterNum">6</seg>
                        <seg type="chapterTitle">Visitors</seg>
                        <seg type="paragraph">11d</seg>
                        <seg type="written">A</seg>
                        <seg type="rewritten">C, E</seg>
                     </ab>
                     <ab change="#wc_0a">Visitors 11d follows Visitors 13a and precedes Visitors
                        11f.</ab>
                  </note> He was so simply and naturally humble—<app xml:id="walc06-app-0100">
                     <lem>if he can be called humble who never aspires</lem>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0a #wc_0c"><!-- [not in ms.]-->
                     </rdg>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0e">
                        <add>if he can be called humble who never aspires</add>
                     </rdg>
                  </app>—that humility was no distinct quality in him, nor could he conceive of it.
                  Wiser men were demigods to him. </seg>
               <seg n="11e" change="#wc_0b">
                  <note type="header" resp="#clapper">
                     <ab type="string">Visitors 11e written: B; rewritten: E.</ab>
                     <ab type="parsed">
                        <seg type="chapterNum">6</seg>
                        <seg type="chapterTitle">Visitors</seg>
                        <seg type="paragraph">11e</seg>
                        <seg type="written">B</seg>
                        <seg type="rewritten">E</seg>
                     </ab>
                     <ab change="#wc_0b">Visitors 11e follows Visitors 11c and precedes Visitors
                        11a.</ab>
                     <ab change="#wc_0e">Visitors 11e is interlined in pencil in its present
                        position.</ab>
                     <ab change="#wc_0b">Visitors 11e appears as follows. He never heard the sound
                        of praise. If I told him that a wise man was coming to see him he did not
                        know nor think how he would behave more than if I told him an archangel were
                        coming—but <del>he</del> did as if he thought that anything so grand would
                        expect nothing of himself but take all the responsibility on itself, and let
                        him be forgotten still</ab>
                  </note> If you told him that such a one<app xml:id="walc06-app-0102">
                     <lem>was</lem>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0e">were</rdg>
                  </app> coming, he did as if he thought that any thing so grand would expect
                  nothing of himself, but take all the responsibility on itself, and let him be
                  forgotten still. He never heard the sound of praise. </seg>
               <seg n="11f" change="#wc_0a">
                  <note type="header" resp="#clapper">
                     <ab type="string">Visitors 11f written: A; rewritten: C, E.</ab>
                     <ab type="parsed">
                        <seg type="chapterNum">6</seg>
                        <seg type="chapterTitle">Visitors</seg>
                        <seg type="paragraph">11f</seg>
                        <seg type="written">A</seg>
                        <seg type="rewritten">C, E</seg>
                     </ab>
                     <ab change="#wc_0a">Visitors 11f follows Visitors 11d and precedes Visitors
                        13b.</ab>
                     <ab change="#wc_0c">Visitors 11f follows Visitors 11d and precedes Visitors
                        11a.</ab>
                  </note> He particularly reverenced the writer and the preacher. Their performances
                  were miracles. When I told him that I wrote <app xml:id="walc06-app-0104">
                     <lem>considerably,</lem>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0a">a good deal,</rdg>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0c">
                        <del>a good deal</del>
                        <add rendition="pencil">considerably,</add>
                     </rdg>
                  </app> he thought for a long time that it was merely the handwriting<app xml:id="walc06-app-0105">
                     <lem>which</lem>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0a">
                        <add rendition="pencil">which</add>
                     </rdg>
                  </app> I <app xml:id="walc06-app-0106">
                     <lem>meant</lem>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0a">
                        <del>meant</del>
                        <add>spoke of</add>
                     </rdg>
                  </app>,<note ana="#wc_0c" resp="#clapper">“meant" copied and “spoke of" interlined
                     as a variant.</note>
                  <app xml:id="walc06-app-0107">
                     <lem>for he could write a remarkably good hand himself</lem>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0a">
                        <add>for he could write remarkably well himself, indeed much better than I
                           commonly do</add>
                     </rdg>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0c">for he could write remarkably well himself, indeed much
                        better than I commonly do</rdg>

                     <rdg wit="#wc_0e">for he could write a remarkably good hand himself<del>, much
                           better than I commonly do</del>
                     </rdg>
                  </app> . <app xml:id="walc06-app-0108">
                     <lem>I sometimes found the name of his native parish handsomely written in the
                        snow by the highway, with the proper French accent, and knew that he had
                        passed.</lem>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0a #wc_0c"><!-- [not in ms.]-->
                     </rdg>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0e">
                        <add>I sometimes found the name of his native parish handsomely written in
                           the snow by the highway, with the proper French accent, and knew that he
                           had passed.</add>
                     </rdg>
                  </app> I asked him if he ever wished to write his thoughts. He said that he had
                  read and written letters for those who could not, but he never tried to write
                  thoughts,—no, he could not, he could not tell what to put first, it would kill
                  him, and then there was spelling to be attended to at the same time! </seg>
            </p>

            <p n="12" change="#wc_0a">
               <seg n="12a" change="#wc_0a">
                  <note type="header" resp="#clapper">
                     <ab type="string">Visitors 12a written: A; rewritten: C, E.</ab>
                     <ab type="parsed">
                        <seg type="chapterNum">6</seg>
                        <seg type="chapterTitle">Visitors</seg>
                        <seg type="paragraph">12a</seg>
                        <seg type="written">A</seg>
                        <seg type="rewritten">C, E</seg>
                     </ab>
                     <ab change="#wc_0a">Visitors 12a follows Visitors 10a and precedes Visitors
                        11b.</ab>
                     <ab change="#wc_0c">Visitors 12a follows Visitors 10b and precedes Visitors
                        12c.</ab>
                  </note> I heard that a <app xml:id="walc06-app-0110">
                     <lem>distinguished wise man and reformer</lem>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0a">wise man <del>
                           <add>the chief of all the Reformers</add>
                        </del>
                     </rdg>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0c">
                        <del>wise man</del>
                        <del>
                           <add>distinguished reformer</add>
                        </del>
                        <add rendition="pencil">distinguished wise man &amp; reformer</add>
                     </rdg>
                  </app> asked him if he did not want the world to be changed;<app xml:id="walc06-app-0111">
                     <lem>but</lem>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0a">and </rdg>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0c">
                        <del>and</del>
                        <add rendition="pencil">but</add>
                     </rdg>
                  </app> he answered with a chuckle of surprise in his Canadian accent, not knowing
                  that the question had ever been entertained before, “No, <app xml:id="walc06-app-0112">
                     <lem>I like</lem>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0a #wc_0c">he liked</rdg>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0e">
                        <del>he liked</del>
                        <add>I like</add>
                     </rdg>
                  </app> it well enough." It would<app xml:id="walc06-app-0113">
                     <lem>have suggested</lem>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0a">
                        <del>suggest</del>
                        <add>have suggested</add>
                     </rdg>
                  </app> many things to a philosopher to<app xml:id="walc06-app-0114">
                     <lem>have dealings with him</lem>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0c">have dealings with him <del>
                           <add>Indeed he was himself a philosopher in his way, &amp; could take his
                              own views of things</add>
                        </del>
                     </rdg>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0e">have <del>had</del> dealings with him</rdg>
                  </app>. </seg>
               <seg n="12b" change="#wc_0b">
                  <note type="header" resp="#clapper">
                     <ab type="string">Visitors 12b written: B; rewritten: C, E.</ab>
                     <ab type="parsed">
                        <seg type="chapterNum">6</seg>
                        <seg type="chapterTitle">Visitors</seg>
                        <seg type="paragraph">12b</seg>
                        <seg type="written">B</seg>
                        <seg type="rewritten">C, E</seg>
                     </ab>
                     <ab change="#wc_0b">Visitors 12b, 14b and 15a are inserted on the verso of the
                        leaf that contains Visitors 11c, 11e and 11a.</ab>
                     <ab change="#wc_0e">A fair copy was made of only <quote>To a stranger he
                           appeared … as wise as Shakspeare, or as simply</quote>.</ab>
                  </note> To a stranger he<app xml:id="walc06-app-0116">
                     <lem>appeared</lem>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0b">would appear</rdg>
                  </app> to know nothing of things in general; yet I sometimes saw in him a man whom
                  I had not<app xml:id="walc06-app-0117">
                     <lem>seen</lem>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0b">known</rdg>
                  </app> before, and I did not know whether he was as wise as Shakspeare or as
                  simply ignorant as a child, whether to suspect him of a fine poetic consciousness
                  or of stupidity.</seg>
               <seg n="12c" change="#wc_0a">
                  <note type="header" resp="#clapper">
                     <ab type="string">Visitors 12c written: A; rewritten: C.</ab>
                     <ab type="parsed">
                        <seg type="chapterNum">6</seg>
                        <seg type="chapterTitle">Visitors</seg>
                        <seg type="paragraph">12c</seg>
                        <seg type="written">A</seg>
                        <seg type="rewritten">C</seg>
                     </ab>
                     <ab change="#wc_0a #wc_0c">Visitors 12c, which is interlined in pencil in A,
                        follows Visitors 12a and precedes Visitors 11b.</ab>
                  </note>
                  <app xml:id="walc06-app-0119">
                     <lem>A townsman told me</lem>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0a">My friends said</rdg>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0c">One of my friends said</rdg>
                  </app> that when he met him sauntering through the village in his small
                  close-fitting cap, <app xml:id="walc06-app-0120">
                     <lem>and whistling to himself,</lem>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0a"><!--[not in ms.]-->
                     </rdg>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0c">
                        <add rendition="pencil">and whistling to himself,</add>
                     </rdg>
                  </app> he reminded him of a prince in disguise.</seg>
            </p>

            <p n="13" change="#wc_0a">
               <seg n="13a" change="#wc_0a">
                  <note type="header" resp="#clapper">
                     <ab type="string">Visitors 13a written: A; rewritten: C.</ab>
                     <ab type="parsed">
                        <seg type="chapterNum">6</seg>
                        <seg type="chapterTitle">Visitors</seg>
                        <seg type="paragraph">13a</seg>
                        <seg type="written">A</seg>
                        <seg type="rewritten">C</seg>
                     </ab>
                     <ab change="#wc_0a">Visitors 13a follows Visitors 10b and precedes Visitors
                        11d.</ab>
                     <ab change="#wc_0c">Visitors 13a follows Visitors 12b.</ab>
                  </note> His only books were an almanac and an arithmetic, in which last<app xml:id="walc06-app-0122">
                     <lem>he was considerably</lem>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0a">especially he was quite</rdg>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0c">especially he was <del>quite</del>
                        <add rendition="pencil">rather</add>
                     </rdg>
                  </app> expert. The former was a sort of<app xml:id="walc06-app-0123">
                     <lem>cyclopædia</lem>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0a #wc_0c">universal lexicon</rdg>
                  </app> to him, which he supposed <app xml:id="walc06-app-0124">
                     <lem>to contain</lem>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0a">contained</rdg>
                  </app> an abstract of human knowledge, <app xml:id="walc06-app-0125">
                     <lem>as indeed it does to a considerable extent.</lem>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0a #wc_0c"><!-- [not in ms.]--></rdg>
                  </app> I loved to sound him on <app xml:id="walc06-app-0126">
                     <lem>the various</lem>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0a">all the</rdg>
                  </app> reforms of the day, and he<app xml:id="walc06-app-0127">
                     <lem>never</lem>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0a #wc_0c">rarely</rdg>
                  </app> failed to look at them in the most simple and practical<app xml:id="walc06-app-0128">
                     <lem>light</lem>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0a #wc_0c">light and as they concerned him</rdg>
                  </app>. He had never heard of such things before. <app xml:id="walc06-app-0129">
                     <lem>Could he do without factories? I asked.</lem>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0a">He allowed that he might dispense with many articles of
                        commerce to advantage</rdg>
                  </app> He had worn the home-made Vermont gray,<app xml:id="walc06-app-0130">
                     <lem>he said,</lem>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0a"><!-- [not in ms.]--></rdg>
                  </app> and that was good. <app xml:id="walc06-app-0131">
                     <lem>Could he dispense with tea and coffee? Did this country afford any
                        beverage beside water?</lem>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0a">If I didn’t like factories—was it necessary to send abroad
                        for our drink? Did he ever drink anything beside water which the country
                        afforded? </rdg>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0c">Could he dispense with tea and coffee? Did the country afford
                        any beverage?</rdg>
                  </app> He had soaked hemlock leaves in water and drank<app xml:id="walc06-app-0132">
                     <lem>it,</lem>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0a #wc_0c">it in Canada,</rdg>
                  </app> and<app xml:id="walc06-app-0133">
                     <lem>thought</lem>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0a #wc_0c"><!-- [not in ms.]--></rdg>
                  </app> that was better than water in warm weather.<app xml:id="walc06-app-0134">
                     <lem>When I asked him if he could do without money</lem>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0a">
                        <del>Could he</del>
                        <add rendition="pencil">When I asked him once if he could</add> do without
                        money <del>and</del>
                     </rdg>
                  </app>, he showed the convenience of money in such a way as to suggest and
                  coincide with the most philosophical accounts of the origin of this institution,
                  and the very derivation of the word <hi rend="italic">pecunia</hi>. If an ox were
                  his property, and he wished to get <app xml:id="walc06-app-0135">
                     <lem>needles and thread</lem>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0a">needles or thread</rdg>
                  </app> at the store, he thought it would be inconvenient and impossible soon to go
                  on mortgaging some<app xml:id="walc06-app-0136">
                     <lem>portion</lem>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0a">fraction</rdg>
                  </app> of the creature each time to that amount.<app xml:id="walc06-app-0137">
                     <lem> He could defend many institutions better than any philosopher, because,
                        in describing them as they concerned him, he gave the true reason for their
                        prevalence, and speculation had not suggested to him any other.</lem>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0a #wc_0c"><!--[not in ms.]--></rdg>
                  </app>
               </seg>
               <seg n="13b" change="#wc_0a">
                  <note type="header" resp="#clapper">
                     <ab type="string">Visitors 13b written: A; rewritten: C, E.</ab>
                     <ab type="parsed">
                        <seg type="chapterNum">6</seg>
                        <seg type="chapterTitle">Visitors</seg>
                        <seg type="paragraph">13b</seg>
                        <seg type="written">A</seg>
                        <seg type="rewritten">C, E</seg>
                     </ab>
                     <ab change="#wc_0a">Visitors 13b follows Visitors 11f.</ab>
                     <ab change="#wc_0c">Visitors 13b is interlined in pencil in its present
                        order.</ab>
                     <ab change="#wc_0e">A fair copy was made of only <quote>without feathers, —and
                           that one exhibited … </quote>knees<quote> bent the wrong
                        way</quote>.</ab>
                  </note>
                  <app xml:id="walc06-app-0139">
                     <lem>At another time, hearing</lem>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0a">Speaking of</rdg>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0c">Hearing</rdg>
                  </app> Plato’s definition of a man,—<app xml:id="walc06-app-0140">
                     <lem>a biped without feathers,—and that one exhibited a cock plucked and called
                        it Plato’s man, he thought it an important difference that the <hi rend="style(italic)">knees</hi> bent the wrong way</lem>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0a">one day, he said that the knee of the cock turned the other
                        way from man’s, and that was an important difference</rdg>
                  </app>. </seg>
               <seg n="13c" change="#wc_0a">
                  <note type="header" resp="#clapper">
                     <ab type="string">Visitors 13c written: A; rewritten: C, E.</ab>
                     <ab type="parsed">
                        <seg type="chapterNum">6</seg>
                        <seg type="chapterTitle">Visitors</seg>
                        <seg type="paragraph">13c</seg>
                        <seg type="written">A</seg>
                        <seg type="rewritten">C, E</seg>
                     </ab>
                  </note> He would <app xml:id="walc06-app-0141">
                     <lem>sometimes exclaim,</lem>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0a">exclaim sometimes <del>
                           <add>after conversing with me several hours</add>
                        </del>
                     </rdg>
                  </app> “How I love to talk! By George, I could talk all<app xml:id="walc06-app-0142">
                     <lem>day!"</lem>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0a">day! You make me think of things I never thought of
                        before</rdg>
                  </app>
               </seg>
               <seg n="13d" change="#wc_0e">
                  <note type="header" resp="#clapper">
                     <ab type="string">Visitors 13d written: E.</ab>
                     <ab type="parsed">
                        <seg type="chapterNum">6</seg>
                        <seg type="chapterTitle">Visitors</seg>
                        <seg type="paragraph">13d</seg>
                        <seg type="written">E</seg>
                     </ab>
                     <ab change="#wc_0e">
                        <quote>He would sometimes ask me … honesty and the like virtues</quote> is
                        interlined in pencil.</ab>
                  </note> I asked him <app xml:id="walc06-app-0144">
                     <lem>once</lem>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0e">
                        <del>one afternoon</del>
                        <add>once</add>
                     </rdg>

                  </app> when I had not seen him for many months, if he had got a new idea this
                  summer. “Good Lord," <app xml:id="walc06-app-0145">
                     <lem>said</lem>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0e">
                        <del>says</del>
                        <add>said</add>
                     </rdg>
                  </app> he, “a man that has to work as I do, if he does not forget the ideas he has
                  had, he will do well. May be the man you hoe with is inclined to race; then,
                     by<app xml:id="walc06-app-0146">
                     <lem>gorry,</lem>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0e">gorry <del>
                           <add>[Godfrey]</add>
                        </del>
                        <note type="general" subtype="inline" resp="#clapper"> The preceding
                           brackets are Thoreau’s.</note>
                     </rdg>
                  </app> your mind must be there; you think of weeds." He would sometimes ask me
                  first on such occasions, if I had made any improvement. One winter day I asked<app xml:id="walc06-app-0147">
                     <lem>him</lem>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0e">him <del>once</del>
                     </rdg>
                  </app> if he was always satisfied with himself, wishing to suggest a
                     substitute<app xml:id="walc06-app-0148">
                     <lem>within him for the priest without, and some higher motive for
                        living.</lem>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0e">for the priest within him <del>employment &amp; an aim for
                           life</del>
                        <add>&amp; some higher motive for living.</add>
                     </rdg>
                  </app> “Satisfied!" said he; “some men are satisfied with one thing, and some with
                  another. One man, perhaps, if he has got enough, will be satisfied to sit all day
                  with his back to the fire and his belly to the table, by George!" Yet I never, by
                  any manœuvring, could get him to take<app xml:id="walc06-app-0149">
                     <lem>the spiritual</lem>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0e">what is called the spiritual</rdg>
                  </app> view of things; the highest that he appeared to conceive of was a <app xml:id="walc06-app-0150">
                     <lem>simple expediency, such as you might expect an animal to appreciate; and
                        this, practically, is true of most men</lem>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0e">
                        <del>natural</del>
                        <add>simple</add> expediency <add>which did not imply the moral
                           sentiment</add>
                     </rdg>
                  </app>. If I suggested any improvement in his<app xml:id="walc06-app-0151">
                     <lem>mode of life</lem>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0e">own case</rdg>
                  </app>, he merely answered, without expressing any regret, that it was too late.
                  Yet he thoroughly believed in honesty and the like virtues.</seg>
            </p>

            <p n="14" change="#wc_0e">
               <seg n="14a" change="#wc_0e">
                  <note type="header" resp="#clapper">
                     <ab type="string">Visitors 14a written: E.</ab>
                     <ab type="parsed">
                        <seg type="chapterNum">6</seg>
                        <seg type="chapterTitle">Visitors</seg>
                        <seg type="paragraph">14a</seg>
                        <seg type="written">E</seg>
                     </ab>
                     <ab change="#wc_0e">
                        <quote>Though he hesitated … presentable thought behind</quote> is
                        interlined in pencil.</ab>
                  </note>There was a certain positive originality, however slight, to be detected in
                  him, and I occasionally observed that he was thinking for himself and expressing
                  his own<app xml:id="walc06-app-0153">
                     <lem>opinion</lem>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0e">opinion, however crude and indistinct</rdg>
                  </app>, a phenomenon so rare that I would any day walk ten miles to observe it,
                  and it amounted to the re-origination of<app xml:id="walc06-app-0154">
                     <lem>many of</lem>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0e">
                        <add>many of</add>
                     </rdg>
                  </app> the institutions of society. Though he hesitated, and perhaps failed to
                  express himself<app xml:id="walc06-app-0155">
                     <lem>distinctly,</lem>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0e"><!--[not in ms.]--></rdg>
                  </app> he always had a presentable thought behind. Yet his thinking was so
                  primitive and immersed in his animal life, that, though more promising than a
                  merely learned man’s, it<app xml:id="walc06-app-0156">
                     <lem>rarely</lem>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0e">
                        <del>never</del>
                        <add>rarely</add>
                     </rdg>
                  </app> ripened to any thing which can be reported.</seg>
               <seg n="14b" change="#wc_0b">
                  <note type="header" resp="#clapper">
                     <ab type="string">Visitors 14b written: B; rewritten: C, E.</ab>
                     <ab type="parsed">
                        <seg type="chapterNum">6</seg>
                        <seg type="chapterTitle">Visitors</seg>
                        <seg type="paragraph">14b</seg>
                        <seg type="written">B</seg>
                        <seg type="rewritten">C, E</seg>
                     </ab>
                     <ab change="#wc_0b">Visitors 14b is interlined in pencil.</ab>
                  </note> He suggested that there might be men of genius in the lowest grades of
                  life, however permanently humble and illiterate, who <app xml:id="walc06-app-0158">
                     <lem>take their own view always, or do not pretend to see at all</lem>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0b">have a view of their own always &amp; are not indebted to
                        their neighbors</rdg>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0c">take a view of their own always &amp; are not indebted to
                        their neighbors</rdg>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0e">who take their own view always and are not indebted to their
                        neighbors</rdg>
                  </app>; who are as bottomless<app xml:id="walc06-app-0159">
                     <lem>even as</lem>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0b #wc_0c">as even</rdg>
                  </app> Walden Pond was thought to be, though they may be dark and<app xml:id="walc06-app-0160">
                     <lem>muddy</lem>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0e">muddy. Sometimes there would come half a dozen railroad
                        repairers to my house at once, healthy &amp; sturdy working men, descended
                        from sound bodies &amp; still transmitting arms and legs and bowels
                        downward. Some of them had got a rude wisdom withal, and a <add rendition="pencil">genuine</add> courtesy <del>which was sweet</del>
                        thanks to their dear bought experience. One a handsome sailor-like young man
                        I remember who had lived among the Indians near Apollachicola, who said to
                        me “Sir, I like your notions," and went away wishing me “success and
                        happiness." They came in troops on Sunday in clean shirts, with washed hands
                        and faces, and fresh twigs in their hands. I observed in some of these men,
                        under faces homely, hard and <del>seared</del>
                        <add rendition="pencil">scarred</add> like the rocks, <del>but human &amp;
                           wise still</del> an <del>inextinguishable &amp;</del> ineradicable
                        refinement and delicacy of nature, <del>older &amp; of more worth than the
                           sun &amp; moon</del> which are commonly thought to adorn the drawing
                        rooms only—Sometimes, I fancied, a genuine magnanimity equal to the least
                        occasion, <del>and</del> of unexplored &amp; uncontaminated descent,
                           <del>greater traits methought I noticed in the shortest intercourse, than
                           are recorded of any of the worthies. Their humble occupation</del>
                        <add rendition="pencil">such as I had assigned to the worthies of the world.
                           It was no disadvantage that their occupation was humble</add> and that
                        they took no aims upon themselves <del>were no disadvantage. Our employment
                           affects but slowly the finer qualities of our nature.</del>
                        <add rendition="pencil">Of course</add> there is no more real rudeness in
                        laborers &amp; washerwomen than in gentlemen and ladies. <del>Most men are
                           wrecked upon their consciousness. Civilization makes bright only the
                           superficial film of the eye</del>
                     </rdg>
                  </app>.<note type="general" resp="#clapper" ana="#wc_0e"> For earlier versions of
                     this passage in A &amp; B, see Visitors 2.</note>
               </seg>
               <app>
                  <lem>
                     <lb/>
                  </lem>
               </app>
            </p>

            <p n="15" change="#wc_0b">
               <seg n="15a" change="#wc_0b">
                  <note type="header" resp="#clapper">
                     <ab type="string">Visitors 15a written: B; rewritten: D, E.</ab>
                     <ab type="parsed">
                        <seg type="chapterNum">6</seg>
                        <seg type="chapterTitle">Visitors</seg>
                        <seg type="paragraph">15a</seg>
                        <seg type="written">B</seg>
                        <seg type="rewritten">D, E</seg>
                     </ab>
                     <ab change="#wc_0b">Visitors 15a is interlined in pencil.</ab>
                     <ab change="#wc_0e">A fair copy was made of only <quote>Many a traveller came
                           out of his way to see</quote>.</ab>
                  </note> Many a traveller came out of his way to see me and the inside of my house,
                     and,<app xml:id="walc06-app-0162">
                     <lem>as</lem>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0b">
                        <del>for</del>
                        <add rendition="pencil">as</add>
                     </rdg>
                  </app> an excuse for calling, asked for a glass of water. I<app xml:id="walc06-app-0163">
                     <lem>told</lem>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0b #wc_0d">generally told</rdg>
                  </app> them that I drank<app xml:id="walc06-app-0164">
                     <lem>at</lem>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0b">of</rdg>
                  </app> the pond, and pointed thither, offering to lend<app xml:id="walc06-app-0165">
                     <lem>them</lem>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0b">
                        <del>them</del>
                        <add>him</add>
                     </rdg>
                  </app> a<app xml:id="walc06-app-0166">
                     <lem>dipper</lem>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0d">dipper. <del>One Sunday two young women strangers borrowed my
                           dipper; but I never saw them nor the dipper again. They thirsted not for
                           water but threw the dipper into the lake perchance. What the lake to them
                           but liquid fire and brimstone! They will never know peace till they have
                           returned the dipper. In all worlds this is decreed. Before this, even
                           while I was first putting my house</del>
                        <note type="general" subtype="inline" resp="#clapper">the leaf ends here;
                           after an apparently missing leaf, the next leaf begins:</note> Perhaps he
                        is one of the sect of philosophers, the only one, so simple, so abstracted
                        in his thought and life from his contemporaries that his wisdom is
                        foolishness to them—His very vividness of perception—clear knowledge &amp;
                        insight—have made him dumb—leaving no common consciousness &amp; ground of
                        parlance with mankind. I was not to be deceived by a few stupid words of
                        course, or apparent stolidity. A month or two after this, as I heard, his
                        body was found dead among the brush over back of the hills, so far
                        decomposed that his coffin was carried to it, and it was put into it with
                        pitchforks,—But <add rendition="pencil">still in spite of all I
                           cherished</add> I have my <del>doubts still</del>
                        <add rendition="pencil">suspicions</add> that he <del>may</del>
                        <add rendition="pencil">might</add> have died a Brahmin’s death, dwelling at
                        the roots of trees at last, and been absorbed into the spirit of Brahm</rdg>
                  </app>.<app xml:id="walc06-app-0167">
                     <lem> Far off as I lived, I was not exempted from the annual visitation which
                        occurs, methinks, about the first of April, when every body is on the move;
                        and I had my share of good luck, though there were some curious specimens
                        among my visitors.</lem>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0b #wc_0d #wc_0e"><!-- [not in ms.]--></rdg>
                  </app> Half-witted men from the almshouse<app xml:id="walc06-app-0168">
                     <lem>and elsewhere</lem>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0b"><!-- [not in ms.]--></rdg>
                  </app> came to see me; but I<app xml:id="walc06-app-0169">
                     <lem>endeavored to make</lem>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0b">made</rdg>
                  </app> them exercise all the wit they had, and make their confessions to me; in
                  such cases making wit the theme of our conversation; and so was compensated.
                  Indeed, I <app xml:id="walc06-app-0170">
                     <lem>found some of them to be wiser than the so called <hi rend="style(italic)">overseers</hi> of the poor and selectmen of the town, and thought it was
                        time that the tables were turned. With respect to wit, I learned</lem>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0b">find </rdg>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0d">found some of them to be wiser than the so called <hi rend="style(underline)">overseers</hi> of the poor and selectmen of the
                        town, and thought it was time that the tables were turned. <add rendition="pencil">With respect to wit</add> I found</rdg>
                  </app> that there was not much difference between the half and the whole.</seg>
               <seg n="15b" change="#wc_0d">
                  <note type="header" resp="#clapper">
                     <ab type="string">Visitors 15b written: D.</ab>
                     <ab type="parsed">
                        <seg type="chapterNum">6</seg>
                        <seg type="chapterTitle">Visitors</seg>
                        <seg type="paragraph">15b</seg>
                        <seg type="written">D</seg>
                     </ab>
                  </note> One day,<app xml:id="walc06-app-0171">
                     <lem>in particular,</lem>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0d">
                        <add rendition="pencil">in particular</add>,</rdg>
                  </app> an inoffensive, simple-minded pauper, whom with others I had often seen
                  used as fencing stuff, standing or sitting on a bushel in the fields to keep
                  cattle and himself from straying, visited me, and expressed a wish to live as I
                  did. He told me, with the utmost simplicity and truth, quite superior, or rather
                     <hi rend="style(italics)">inferior</hi>, to any thing that is called humility,
                  that he was “deficient in intellect." These were his words. The Lord had made him
                  so, yet he supposed the Lord cared as much for him as for another. “I have always
                  been so," said he, “from my childhood; I never had much mind; I was not like other
                  children; I am weak in the head. It was the Lord’s will, I suppose." <app xml:id="walc06-app-0172">
                     <lem>And there he was to prove the truth of his words. He was a metaphysical
                        puzzle to me.</lem>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0d"><!-- [not in ms.]--></rdg>
                  </app> I have rarely met a fellow-man on such promising ground,—it was so simple
                  and sincere and so true all that he said. <app xml:id="walc06-app-0173">
                     <lem>And, true enough, in proportion as he appeared to humble himself was he
                        exalted. I did not know at first but it was the result of a wise
                        policy</lem>
                     <rdg wit="#wc_0d">I did not know at first but it was the result of a wise
                        policy so to lay the surest foundations for an intercourse, that might come
                        to something. For, true enough, in proportion as he appeared to humble
                        himself <del>he</del> was <add>he</add> exalted</rdg>
                  </app>. It seemed that from such a basis of truth and frankness as the poor
                  weak-headed pauper had laid, our intercourse might go forward to something better
                  than the intercourse of sages.</seg>
            </p>

            <p n="16" change="#wc_0d">
               <note type="header" resp="#clapper">
                  <ab type="string">Visitors 16 written: D.</ab>
                  <ab type="parsed">
                     <seg type="chapterNum">6</seg>
                     <seg type="chapterTitle">Visitors</seg>
                     <seg type="paragraph">16</seg>
                     <seg type="written">D</seg>
                  </ab>
               </note> I had some guests from those not reckoned commonly among the town’s poor, but
               who should be; who are among the world’s poor, at any rate; guests who appeal, not to
               your hospitality, but to your <hi rend="style(italics)">hospitality</hi>; who
               earnestly wish to be helped, and preface their appeal with the information that they
               are resolved, for one thing, never to help themselves. I require of a visitor that he
               be not actually starving, though he may have the very best appetite in the world,<app xml:id="walc06-app-0174">
                  <lem> however he got it</lem>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0d">
                     <add rendition="pencil">however he got it</add> and I will not inquire how he
                     came by it</rdg>
               </app>. Objects of charity are not guests. Men who did not know when their visit had
               terminated, though I went about my business <app xml:id="walc06-app-0175">
                  <lem>again</lem>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0d">again, and regarded myself as alone</rdg>
               </app>, answering them from greater and greater<app xml:id="walc06-app-0176">
                  <lem>remoteness.</lem>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0d">remoteness.<quote>
                        <lg>
                           <l>I’m contented you should stay</l>
                           <l>For ever and aye</l>
                           <l>If you can take yourself away</l>
                           <l>Any day</l>
                        </lg>
                     </quote>
                  </rdg>
               </app> Men of<app xml:id="walc06-app-0177">
                  <lem>almost</lem>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0d"><!-- [not in ms.]--></rdg>
               </app> every degree of wit called on me<app xml:id="walc06-app-0178">
                  <lem>in the migrating season.</lem>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0d"><!-- [not in ms.]--></rdg>
               </app> Some who had more wits than they knew what to do with; runaway slaves with
               plantation manners, who listened from time to time, like the fox in the fable, as if
               they heard the hounds a-baying on their track, and looked at me beseechingly, as much
               as to say, — <quote>
                  <lg>
                     <l>“O Christian, will you send me back?"</l>
                  </lg>
               </quote> One real runaway slave, among the rest, whom I<app xml:id="walc06-app-0179">
                  <lem>helped to forward</lem>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0d">
                     <del>forwarded</del>
                     <add rendition="pencil">helped to forward</add>
                  </rdg>
               </app> toward the northstar. Men of one idea, like a hen with one chicken, and that a
               duckling; men of a thousand ideas, and unkempt heads, like those hens which are made
               to take charge of a hundred chickens, all in pursuit of one bug, a score of them lost
               in every morning’s dew,—<app xml:id="walc06-app-0180">
                  <lem>and become frizzled and mangy in consequence;</lem>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0d"><!-- [not in ms.]--></rdg>
               </app> men of ideas instead of legs, a sort of intellectual centipede that made you
               crawl all over. One man proposed a book in which visitors should write their names,
               as at the White Mountains; <app xml:id="walc06-app-0181">
                  <lem>but, alas! I have too good a memory to make that necessary</lem>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0d">said he would be at the expense of it! As if it were of any
                     significance for a man who had failed to make any impression on you to leave
                     his name. No, I kept a book, it needed only a small one, to put their <hi rend="style(underline)">fames</hi> in; I was at the expense of it</rdg>
               </app>. </p>

            <p n="17" change="#wc_0b">
               <note type="header" resp="#clapper">
                  <ab type="string">Visitors 17 written: B; rewritten: E.</ab>
                  <ab type="parsed">
                     <seg type="chapterNum">6</seg>
                     <seg type="chapterTitle">Visitors</seg>
                     <seg type="paragraph">17</seg>
                     <seg type="written">B</seg>
                     <seg type="rewritten">E</seg>
                  </ab>
                  <ab change="#wc_0b #wc_0e">
                     <quote>and you would suppose that they would not go … as many risks as he
                        runs</quote> does not appear in the manuscript in B or in the original
                     copying of E but is interlined in E.</ab>
                  <ab change="#wc_0e">A fair copy was made of only <quote>that it was not possible
                        to do so much good … feared the men-harriers rather</quote>.</ab>
               </note> I could not<app xml:id="walc06-app-0182">
                  <lem>but notice some of the peculiarities of</lem>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0b">
                     <del>help noticing</del>
                     <add>but notice</add> some <add>of the</add> peculiarities <del>in</del>
                     <add>of</add>
                  </rdg>
               </app> my visitors. Girls and boys and young women generally seemed glad to be in the
               woods. They looked in the pond and at the flowers, and improved their time. Men of
                  business,<app xml:id="walc06-app-0183">
                  <lem>even farmers,</lem>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0b"><!-- [not in ms.]--></rdg>
               </app> thought only of solitude and employment, and of the great distance at which I
               dwelt from something or other; and though they said that they loved a ramble in the
               woods occasionally, it was obvious that they did not. Restless committed men, whose
               time was all taken up in getting a living<app xml:id="walc06-app-0184">
                  <lem>or keeping it;</lem>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0b"><!-- [not in ms.]--></rdg>
               </app> ministers<app xml:id="walc06-app-0185">
                  <lem>who spoke of God as if they enjoyed a monopoly of the subject, who could not
                     bear all kinds of opinions;</lem>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0b">
                     <add>who spoke of God as if they enjoyed a monopoly of the subject, who could
                        not bear all kinds of opinions;</add>
                  </rdg>
               </app> doctors,<app xml:id="walc06-app-0186">
                  <lem>lawyers</lem>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0b">lawyers, conscientious preachers</rdg>
               </app>, uneasy housekeepers who pried into my cupboard and bed <app xml:id="walc06-app-0187">
                  <lem>when I was out,—how came Mrs. —— to know that my sheets were not as clean as
                     hers</lem>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0b">
                     <add rendition="pencil">
                        <del>What right had</del>
                        <add rendition="pencil">How came</add> Mrs. —— to know that my sheets were
                        not <del>the cleanest</del>
                        <add rendition="pencil">as clean as hers</add>
                     </add>
                  </rdg>
               </app>? —young men who had ceased to be young, and had concluded that it was safest
               to follow the beaten track of the professions,—<app xml:id="walc06-app-0188">
                  <lem>all these</lem>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0b"><!-- [not in ms.]--></rdg>
               </app> generally said that it was not possible to do so much good in my position.
                  <app xml:id="walc06-app-0189">
                  <lem>Ay! there was the rub.</lem>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0b">
                     <add>Ay! there was the rub.</add>
                  </rdg>
               </app> The old and infirm and the timid, of whatever age or sex, thought most of
               sickness, and sudden accident and death; to them life seemed full of <app xml:id="walc06-app-0190">
                  <lem>danger,—what danger is there if you don't think of any? —and they thought
                     that a prudent man would carefully select the safest position,</lem>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0b">danger anywhere, and they thought that a prudent man would
                     carefully select the safest position. (What danger is there if you don’t think
                     of any?)</rdg>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0e">Danger <del>anywhere</del>, <add>—<del>but</del> what danger
                           <del>of this kind</del> is there if you don’t think of any?—</add> and
                     they thought that a prudent man would carefully select the safest
                     position.</rdg>
               </app>
               <app xml:id="walc06-app-0191">
                  <lem>where Dr. B. might be on hand at a moment’s warning.</lem>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0b">
                     <add rendition="pencil">where Dr. B. might be on hand at a moment’s
                        warning.</add>
                  </rdg>
               </app> To them the village was literally a <hi rend="style(italics)">com-munity</hi>,
               a league for mutual defence, and you would suppose that they would not go
               a-huckleberrying without a medicine chest. The amount of it is, if a man is alive,
               there is always <hi rend="style(italics)">danger</hi> that he may die, though the
               danger must be allowed to be less in proportion as he<app xml:id="walc06-app-0192">
                  <lem>is</lem>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0e">makes himself <del>the more</del>
                  </rdg>
               </app> dead-and-alive to begin with. A man sits as many risks as he<app xml:id="walc06-app-0193">
                  <lem>runs</lem>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0e">runs<del>, if he did but know it</del>
                  </rdg>
               </app>. Finally, there were the self-styled reformers, the greatest bores of<app xml:id="walc06-app-0194">
                  <lem>all,</lem>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0b">all, <del>not to imply that the others were bores at all</del>
                  </rdg>
               </app> who thought that I was forever singing,— <lg>
                  <l>This is the house that I built;</l>
                  <l>This is the man that lives in the house that I built;</l>
               </lg> but<app xml:id="walc06-app-0195">
                  <lem>they</lem>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0b #wc_0e">who</rdg>
               </app> did not know that the third line was, <lg>
                  <l>These are the folks that worry the man </l>
                  <l>That lives in the house that I built. </l>
               </lg>
               <app xml:id="walc06-app-0196">
                  <lem>I did not fear the hen-harriers, for I kept no chickens; but I feared the
                     men-harriers rather.</lem>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0b"><!-- [not in ms.]-->
                  </rdg>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0e">
                     <add>I did not fear the hen-harriers, for I kept no chickens; but I feared the
                        men-harriers rather.</add>
                  </rdg>
               </app>
            </p>

            <p n="18" change="#wc_0e">
               <note type="header" resp="#clapper">
                  <ab type="string">Visitors 18 written: E.</ab>
                  <ab type="parsed">
                     <seg type="chapterNum">6</seg>
                     <seg type="chapterTitle">Visitors</seg>
                     <seg type="paragraph">18</seg>
                     <seg type="written">E</seg>
                  </ab>
                  <ab change="#wc_0e">Visitors 18 is interlined.</ab>
               </note>
               <app xml:id="walc06-app-0197">
                  <lem>I had more cheering visitors than the last</lem>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0e">
                     <del>But</del> I had more <del>welcome</del>
                     <add>cheering</add> visitors than these <add>last</add>
                     <del>from time to time of whom I shall speak in another place</del>
                  </rdg>
               </app>. Children come a-berrying, railroad men taking a Sunday morning walk<app xml:id="walc06-app-0198">
                  <lem>in clean shirts</lem>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0e">
                     <add>in clean shirts</add>
                  </rdg>
               </app>, fishermen and hunters,<app xml:id="walc06-app-0199">
                  <lem>poets and philosophers</lem>
                  <rdg wit="#wc_0e">
                     <del>—(all in short who really got to the woods and left the woods behind them
                        were welcome)</del> fishers &amp; hunters of men too</rdg>
               </app>, in short, all honest pilgrims, who came out to the woods for freedom’s sake,
               and really left the village behind, I was ready to greet with,—“Welcome, Englishmen!
               welcome, Englishmen!" for I had had communication with that race.</p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>