<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<listBibl><bibl><author>Thomas Keith</author><title>A short and easy introduction to the science of geography: Containing A
            concise and accurate Description of the Situation, Extent, Boundaries,
            Divisions, chief Cities, &amp; amp; of the several Empires, Kingdoms,
            States, and Countries, in the known World: With the Use of the Terrestrial
            Globe, and Geographical Maps, &amp; Designed for the use of schools and
            private tuition. Illustrated with the necessary engravings, and an accurate
            map of the world, including the Modern Discoveries. By Thomas Keith, Teacher
            of the Mathematics, Geography, &amp; at Messrs. Booth and Rawe's Academy,
            Bromley, Kent.</title><editor/><publisher>B. Law</publisher><pubPlace>London</pubPlace><date>1787</date><note>The text gives brief descriptions of different islands and natives,
            including the Otaheitians, and refers to the usage of etoa weapons in one
            entry. </note></bibl><bibl><author>Various</author><title>The fugitive miscellany. Being a collection of such fugitive pieces, in
            prose and verse, as are not in any other collection. With many pieces never
            before published. </title><editor/><publisher/><pubPlace>London</pubPlace><date>1774</date><note>The hit was an epistle written as through it were from Oberea to Joseph
            Banks. The hit for poe was actually poem in the epistle but Otaheite was
            refered to multiple times.</note></bibl><bibl><author>Hawkesworth, John</author><title>An account of the voyages undertaken by the order of His present Majesty,
            for making discoveries in the Southern Hemisphere, and successively ... </title><editor> N/A </editor><publisher> 600 pp. vol. Volume 2 of 2 (2 vols. available) History and Geography </publisher><pubPlace> Dublin </pubPlace><date>1779</date><note>Used as a place name.</note></bibl><bibl><author>Cook, James</author><title>A voyage towards the South Pole, and round the world. Performed in His
            Majesty's ships the Resolution and Adventure, in the years 1772, 1773,
            ...</title><editor>N/A</editor><publisher>468 pp. vol. Volume 1 of 2 (2 vols. available) Literature and
            Language </publisher><pubPlace> London </pubPlace><date>1779</date><note> Discusses the Voyage: BOOK I- the departure from England and leaving the Society Ifles. Book II-Departure from the Society Ifles and the Return back</note><vol> 1,2</vol></bibl><bibl><author>Kippis, Andrew</author><title>The life of Captain James Cook.</title><editor> </editor><publisher>J. J. Tourneisen</publisher><pubPlace>Paris</pubPlace><date>1788</date><note>The term is used to describe the native's wife and her interactions with
            other people.</note><vol> 1,2</vol></bibl><bibl><author>NA</author><title>Beauties of nature and art displayed, in a tour through the world; ...
            Illustrated and embellished with copper plates.</title><editor>NA</editor><publisher> G. Robinson, in Pater-Noster-row</publisher><pubPlace>London</pubPlace><date>1774-75</date><note>The name Kihiargo was used in close relation to King George and also in
            the short passage Tomio and the meantion of a burrial was displayed. This
            could be a passage that relates to the chapter XIV that I am looking at.
            This chapter is about Indian Funeral and other observations. Having the name
            Kihiargo meantioned near bury and also the name Tomio, who is meantioned in
            the chapter may suggest they are about the same voyage.</note></bibl><bibl><author>NA</author><title>A new, authentic, and complete collection of voyages round the world,
            undertaken and performed by royal authority.</title><editor>NA</editor><publisher>Alex Hogg</publisher><pubPlace>London</pubPlace><date>1784-1786</date><note>The name Kihiargo was used in close relation to the name King George as it
            is also in Book I chapter XIV. This is a good indicator that they are
            actually talking about the same person and would maybe help support what we
            are looking for. Also the use of islanders and Tubourai Tamaide were
            meantioned in the short passage in this search for Kihiargo. Tubourai
            Tamaide was a common name meantioned throughout chapter XIV in relation to
            the funeral and general observations.</note></bibl><bibl><author>Fitzgerald, Gerald.</author><title>The injured islanders; or, the influence of art upon the happiness of
            nature.</title><editor/><publisher/><pubPlace>London, MDCCLXXIX. [1779]. Eighteenth Century Collections Online.
            Gale. University of Pittsburgh Libraries </pubPlace><date> Sept. 18, 2013</date><note> </note></bibl><bibl><author>Fitzgerald, Gerald.</author><title>The injured islanders, or the influence of art upon the happiness of
            nature: a poetical epistle from Oberea of Otaheite to Captain Wallis. By the
            ...</title><editor/><publisher/><pubPlace>Dublin, 1779. Eighteenth Century Collections Online. Gale. University
            of Pittsburgh Libraries. 18 Sept. 2013 </pubPlace><date> Sep. 8, 2013</date><note> </note></bibl><bibl><author>Perry, James</author><title>Mimosa: or, The sensitive plant; A poem. Dedicated to Mr. Banks, and
            addressed to Kitt Frederick, Dutchess of Queensberry, Elect.</title><editor/><publisher/><pubPlace>The second edition, with additions. London, 1779. Eighteenth Century
            Collections Online. Gale. University of Pittsburgh Libraries</pubPlace><date> Sep.18, 2013</date><note> </note></bibl><bibl><author>SydneyParkinson</author><title>A journal of a voyage to the South Seas, in his Majesty's ship, the
            Endeavour. Faithfully transcribed from the papers of the late Sydney
            Parkinson, Draughtsman to Joseph Banks, Esq. on his late Expedition, with
            Dr. Solander, round the World. Embellished with views and designs,
            delineated by the Author, and engraved by capital Artists.</title><editor>Stanfield Parkinson</editor><publisher> </publisher><pubPlace>london</pubPlace><date>1773</date><note>Used in original form</note></bibl><bibl><author>Adams, John (1750?-1814)</author><title>Modern voyages: containing a variety of useful and entertaining facts,
            respecting the expeditions and the principal discoveries of Cavendish,
            Dampier, Monk, Spilbergen, Anson, Byron, Wallis, Carteret, Bougainville
            Dixon, Portlock, Paterson, and others. Comprehending The most interesting
            Particulars of Brisson's Narrative of his Shipwreck and Captivity;-The
            Shipwreck of the Antelope, East India Packet, and a Description of the
            amiable Inhabitants of the Pelew Islands, never before known to any
            European;-Also the latest authentic Accounts from Botany Bay;-as well as
            curious Information from several ingenious Writers and Travellers. For the
            Amusement and Instruction of Youth of Both Sexes. In two volumes. ... . By
            the Reverend John Adams, A.M.</title><editor>printed for G. Kearsley, at Johnson's Head, in Fleet Street, MDCCXC.
            [1790].</editor><publisher>G. Kearsley</publisher><pubPlace>London</pubPlace><date>1790</date><note>The term Captain n 10 Wallis found reference to the words Captain and
            Wallis within 10 characters of each other. This helped find a voyage log of
            Captain Wallis Also the date range from 1750-1790 narrowed the search to the
            date range that Captain Wallis's voyages were documented.</note></bibl><bibl><author>Alexander, William (d. 1783)</author><title>The history of women, from the earliest antiquity, to the present time;
            giving some account of almost every interesting particular concerning that
            sex, among all nations, ancient and modern. By William Alexander, M.D. In
            two volumes.</title><editor>London : printed for W. Strahan, and T. Cadell, in the Strand,
            MDCCLXXIX. [1779].</editor><publisher>W. Strahan and T. Cadell</publisher><pubPlace>London</pubPlace><date>1779</date><note>The term Otaheite found references to Otaheite. This helped find a voyage
            logs of when Otaheite was mentioned. Also the date range from 1750-1790
            narrowed the search to the date range that Captain Wallis's voyages were
            documented.</note></bibl><bibl><author>Cook, James (1728-1779)</author><title>A voyage round the world, performed in His Britannic Majesty's ships the
            Resolution and Adventure, in the years 1772, 1773, 1774, and 1775. Written
            by James Cook, commander of the Resolution, and George Forster, F.R.S.
            Illustrated with a chart of the southern hemisphere, shewing the tracts of
            some of the most distinguished navigators; and a variety of portraits of
            persons and views of places, drawn during the voyage by Mr. Hodges. In four
            volumes.</title><editor>Dublin : printed for W. Whitestone, S. Watson, R. Cross, J. Potts, J.
            Hoey, L.L. Flin, J. Williams, W. Colles, W. Wilson, R. Moncrieffe, T.
            Armitage, T. Walker, C. Jenkin, W. Hallhead, G. Burnett, J. Exshaw, L.
            White, and J. Beatty, MDCCLXXVII. [1777].</editor><publisher>W. Whitestone, S. Watson, R. Cross, J. Potts, J. Hoey, L.L. Flin, J.
            Williams, W. Colles, W. Wilson, R. Moncrieffe, T. Armitage, T. Walker, C.
            Jenkin, W. Hallhead, G. Burnett, J. Exshaw, L. White, and J. Beatty,
            MDCCLXXVII. </publisher><pubPlace>Dublin</pubPlace><date>1777</date><note>This result mentioned contact to Matavai in a voyage</note></bibl><bibl><author>Forster, George</author><title>A voyage round the world, in His Britannic Majesty's sloop, Resolution,
            commanded by Capt. James Cook, during the years 1772, 3, 4, and 5. By George
            Forster, F. R. S. Member of the Royal Academy of Madrid, and of the Society
            for promoting Natural Knowledge at Berlin. In two volumes. ...</title><editor>N/A</editor><publisher>printed for B. White, Fleet-Street; J. Robson, Bond Street; P.
            Elmsly, Strand; and G. Robinson, Pater-Noster Row, MDCCLXXVII</publisher><pubPlace>London</pubPlace><date>1777</date><note>Location name use in relation to a voyage.</note></bibl><bibl><author>Cook, James (1728-1779)</author><title>A voyage to the Pacific Ocean. Undertaken, by the command of His Majety,
            for making discoveries in the Northern Hemisphere. Performed under the
            direction of Captains Cook, Clerke, and Gore, in His Majesty's ships the
            Resolution and Discovery; in the years 1776, 1777, 1778, 1779, and 1780. In
            three volumes. Vol. I. and II. written by Captain James Cook, F.R.S. Vol.
            III. by Captain James King, LL.D. and F.R.S. Published by order of the Lords
            Commissioners of the Admiralty.</title><editor>London : printed by H. Hughs, for G. Nicol, bookseller to His Majesty,
            in the Strand; and T. Cadell, in the Strand, M.DCC.LXXXV. [1785].</editor><publisher>H. Hughs, for G. Nicol, bookseller to His Majesty, in the Strand; and
            T. Cadell, in the Strand, M.DCC.LXXXV.</publisher><pubPlace>London</pubPlace><date>1785</date><note>This result mentioned contact to Matavai in a voyage</note></bibl><bibl><author><!-- MISSING --></author><title>Omiah's farewell; inscribed to the ladies of London.</title><editor><!-- MISSING --></editor><publisher>printed for G. Kearsly, in Fleet-Street, MDCCLXXVI.</publisher><pubPlace>London</pubPlace><date>1776</date><note>Talks about tattooing bums (as in butts) in relation to Omai</note></bibl><bibl><author>Alexander, William</author><title>The history of women, from the earliest antiquity, to the present time;
            giving some account of almost every interesting particular concerning ... </title><title/><editor><!-- MISSING --> &gt;</editor><publisher>London : printed for W. Strahan, and T. Cadell, in the Strand,
            MDCCLXXIX</publisher><pubPlace>London</pubPlace><date>1783</date><note>Use in regards to talking about tattos on Tahitian Women </note></bibl><bibl><author> William Stork</author><title> A description of East-Florida, with a journal, kept by John Bartram
            of Philadelphia, botanist to His Majesty for the Floridas; upon a
            journey from St. Augustine up the River St. John's, as far as the lakes.
            With explanatory botanical notes. Illustrated with an accurate Map of
            East-Florida, and two Plans; one of St. Augustine, and the other of the
            Bay of Espiritu Santo. </title><publisher> London : sold by W. Nicoll, at No. 51, St. Paul's Church Yard;
            and T. Jefferies, at Charing-Cross, Geographer to his
            Majesty</publisher><pubPlace> London</pubPlace><date> 1769</date><note> The term is used in the text when Dr. Solander himself is mentioned.
            the part of the text also talks about the others in his company.</note></bibl><bibl><author/> Cook, James.
        <title/> A compendious history of Captain Cook's first
        and second voyages. The first Performed in the Years 1768, 1769, 1770, 1771, in
        the Endeavour 
        <pubPlace/> London <date/> 1784 <note>recounting the trip</note></bibl><bibl><author/> Henry, David. <title/> An historical account of all the voyages
        round the world, performed by English navigators; including those lately
        undertaken by order of His present Majesty. The whole faithfully extracted from
        the journals of the voyagers. ... In four volumes. ... <pubPlace/> London
        <date/> 1773-74 <note>Discuss the trip in comparison to others</note></bibl></listBibl>