<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<eccoLocation><resp>This file prepared by <persName>Elisa Beshero-Bondar</persName></resp><sourceDesc><p>Search terms extracted from the following text(s):
                    <bibl><author/><title/><pubPlace/><publisher/><date/></bibl><bibl><author/><title/><pubPlace/><publisher/><date/></bibl><bibl><author/><title/><pubPlace/><publisher/><date/></bibl></p></sourceDesc><body><head>ECCO Location from ECCO and ECCO TCP: <date>November 2, 2013</date></head><list type="successful"><item><term>Otaheite
                    <num type="hits">41</num></term><term type="var"><!--Successful variation on this term--></term><num type="hits"/><term type="var"/><num type="hits"/><listBibl>
                    <!--Enter bibliographic info and a descriptive note for at least one or two of your especially good results. Follow how we did this above for your voyage text.--><bibl><author>Croft, Herbert, Sir</author><title>Love and madness. A story too true. In a series of letters between parties, whose names would perhaps be mentioned, were they less known, or less lamented.</title><editor/><publisher>printed for G. Kearsly</publisher><pubPlace>London</pubPlace><date>1780</date><note>published anonymously. Forgery of letters between Martha Ray and her murderer (in 1779) James Hackman. Ray was the mistress of John Montagu, 4th Earl of Sandwich (and mother of several of his children). Croft's epistolary novel makes several references to Omiah, as a visitor who knew the parties involved, and once in the famous long letter about Chatterton (who'd committed suicide in 1770), by way of vindicating Chatterton from rumors of venereal disease (or the disease Bougainville supposedly brought to Otaheite). See Letter 3 (p. 6), Letter 9 (p. 18), Letter 18 (p. 40, and Letter 49 (p. 133).</note></bibl><bibl><author>Way, G. L.</author><title>Learning at a loss, or the amours of Mr. Pedant and Miss Hartley. A novel. In two volumes. Vol. II</title><editor/><publisher>printed for the author, and sold by H. Gardner; and J. Bew</publisher><pubPlace>London</pubPlace><date>1778</date><note>In ECCO TCP. Epistolary comical novel. See pp. 10-12, describing a bachelor's study as a place full of interesting stuff: "His Chimney was decorated with Jockey Whips perpendicularly suspended from their Thongs, and every other Part of the Walls seemed loaded with an astonishing Variety of Curbs, Snaffles, Cavessons and Mar∣tingals, with five thousand other Instruments of Equestrian Utility, full as curious and entertaining to me, as the Weapons of New Zealand or Otaheite, or the old Bando∣leers and Shot Pouches in the Ar∣moury in the Tower." (pp. 11-12)</note></bibl><bibl><author>More, Hannah</author><title>Thoughts on the importance of the manners of the great to general society</title><editor/><publisher>printed for T. Cadell</publisher><pubPlace>London</pubPlace><date>1788</date><note>In ECCO TCP. See pp. 35-36: mention of hypocritical people willing to support missions to Tahiti, but sacrilegiously enjoying Sunday haircuts: "I am persuaded that there are multitudes of well-meaning people who would gladly contribute to a mission of Christianity to Japan or Otaheite, to whom it never occurred, that the hair-dresser, whom they are every Sunday detaining from church, has a soul to be saved; that the law of the land co-operates with the law of God, to forbid their employing him; and that they have no right, either legal or moral, to this portion of his time." </note></bibl><bibl><author>Boswell, James</author><title>A letter to the people of Scotland, on the alarming attempt to infringe the Articles of the Union, and introduce a most pernicious innovation, by diminishing the number of the lords of session</title><editor/><publisher>printed for Charles Dilly</publisher><pubPlace>London</pubPlace><date>1785</date><note>In ECCO TCP. See p. 39: Some exaggerated political rhetoric here, apparently on a proposal to cut the number of Lord Justices in Scotland, as analagous to practices of child-murder in Tahiti and China if there aren't enough resources: "Is the state so poor, that we must adopt a measure similar to the barbarous permission in China and Otaheite, to murder their children, lest they should not have food enough?"</note></bibl><bibl><author>MacNally, Leonard</author><title>Sentimental excursions to Windsor: and other places, with notes critical, illustrative, and explanatory</title><editor/><publisher>printed for J. Walker</publisher><pubPlace>London</pubPlace><date>1781</date><note>In ECCO TCP. See "A Meditation," pp. 16-20: on the "Timiradi dance" of Otaheite, saying this dance was apparently practiced by the virtuous yet not modest Lacedaemonians, with a footnote citing "Forster, who attended Captain Cooke on his second voyage." Reflection on whether or not chastity is necessary--"I concluded with a modern voyager (citing Forster)...that modesty and chastity, which have long been supposed to be inherent in the human mind, are local ideas, unknown in the state of nature, and modified according to the various degrees of civilization."</note></bibl><bibl><author>Burgoyne, John</author><title>The maid of the oaks: a new dramatic entertainment. As it is performed at the Theatre-Royal, in Drury-Lane</title><editor/><publisher>printed for T. Becket</publisher><pubPlace>1774</pubPlace><date/><note>In ECCO TCP. In the opening Act I, scene 1 of this play, set on a farm named "Oldsworth's Oaks" described as a "New Arcadia:" Sir Harry Groveby welcomes his friend Mr. Beley to England and this place: Dupeley says: "Novelty and pleasure are the beings I pursue—They have led me half the world over already, and for ought I know they may sometime or other carry me to the Otaheite." and Sir Harry replies: "You have pursued but their shadows—here they reign, in the manners of this New Arcadia, and the smiles of the sweet Maid of the Oaks." </note></bibl><bibl><author>Hull, Thomas</author><author>Colman, G., Esq.</author><title>Henry the Second: or, the fall of Rosamond: a tragedy; as it is performed at the Theatre-Royal, Covent-Garden</title><editor/><publisher>printed for John Bell</publisher><pubPlace>London</pubPlace><date>1774</date><note>In ECCO TCP. Hull is the author of the play, but G. Colman wrote the Epilogue in the voice of Oberea of Otaheite. She's being scornful of the representation of women in the play just performed. "Full three long Hours I've sat, with smother'd Rage,/ To hear the Nonsense of your tragick Stage, / To see a Queen majestically swagger,/ A Bowl in this Hand, and in this a Dagger; / To stab or poison (cruel Inclination!) / A Maid, who gave a Husband Consolation." http://quod.lib.umich.edu/e/ecco/004809950.0001.000/1:8?rgn=div1;view=fulltext;q1=Otaheite</note></bibl><bibl><author>Mason, William</author><title>The Dean and the 'Squire: A Political Eclogue. Humbly dedicated to Soame Jenyns, Esq.</title><editor/><publisher>printed for J. Debrett, successor to Mr. Almon</publisher><pubPlace>London</pubPlace><date>1782</date><note>In ECCO TCP. See lines 210 - 230: References to "Zealand-New," "Otaheite," and "Queen Oberea" with the idea of criminals going into exile to the Pacific, and questioning the kinds of freedom they'd find, "taxed" by Queen Oberea's supposed sexual appetite. Continues by discussing such a life as comparable to Adam and Eve: "But a cool hundred Eves and Adams; / I think they would, or soon, or late, by <em>quasi compact</em> found a state.</note></bibl><bibl><author>Late Member of the Continental Congress</author><title>The true merits of a late treatise, printed in America, intitled, Common sense: clearly pointed out. Addressed to the inhabitants of America. By a late member of the Continental Congress, a native of a republican state.</title><editor/><publisher>printed for W. Nicoll</publisher><pubPlace>London</pubPlace><date>1776</date><note>In ECCO TCP. Essay attacking Thomas Paine's "Common Sense." See pp. 23-24: that England made it possible for Protestants to live in religious freedom in the New World, and if Paine (et. al.) don't like it, they can go to "Otaheite, and the Islands in the North West" as a "Sanctuary for him and his Friends."</note></bibl><bibl><author>Marra, John</author><title>Journal of the Resolution's voyage: in 1772, 1773, 1774, and 1775. On discovery to the southern hemisphere, ... Also a journal of the Adventure's voyage, in the years 1772, 1773, and 1774. ... Illustrated with a chart, ... and other cuts.</title><editor/><publisher>printed for F. Newbery</publisher><pubPlace>London</pubPlace><date>1775</date><note>In ECCO TCP. Note publication date: According to historical sources, John Marra was Cook's gunner's mate on the 2nd voyage.</note></bibl><bibl><author>Kames, Henry Home, Lord</author><title>Sketches of the history of man: In four volumes.</title><editor/><publisher>printed for James Williams</publisher><pubPlace>Dublin</pubPlace><date>1774-1775</date><note>In ECCO TCP. Volume I. Sketch 1 ("DIVERSITY of MEN and of LANGUAGES.") See pp. 20-21 and 24-25. Pp. 20-21: on Commodore Byron's and on Cook's voyages: Mentions of Banks and Solander leaving Otaheite to find Society Islands, Islands of Oahena. See p. 24: Otaheite mentioned in opposition to other more violent cultures, and compared with the ancient Caledonians: Intelligent resistance to Wallis, ease of making peace--more impressive than most, apparently.</note><note>In ECCO TCP. Volume I. Sketch 2 ("Progress Porgress of Men with respect to FOOD and POPULATION.)See p. 58: "The is∣land of Otaheite is healthy, the people tall and well made; and by temperance, vegetables and fish being their chief nourishment, they live to a good old age, with scarce any ailment. There is no such thing known among them as rotten teeth: the very smell of wine or spirits is disagreeable; and they never deal in tobacco nor spiceries."</note><note>In ECCO TCP. Volume I. Sketch 6 ("Progress of the FEMALE SEX.") See pp. 194-196: on free love in Otaheite: They're good people, but "seem to have as little notion of modesty as of chastity. More on "polygamy" on p. 196.</note><note>In ECCO TCP. Volume II. Book I. Continued: Sketch 7 ("Progress of Manners"), pp. 6-7: Otaheite mentioned in a syncretic description of bodily cleaning "in several nations that have made little progress in the arts of life." Otaheitian cleansliness in both sexes is mentioned after Caribbean islanders and before historic descriptions of the ancient Gauls.</note><note>In ECCO TCP. Volume II: Sketch 1 ("Progress of Men in Society"), p. 156: On the practices of stealing and piracy, Otaheitians mentioned after the Scottish Highlanders and the rebellion of 1745! Idea: that theft isn't committed among their own, but against outsiders. "Bougainville observes, that the inhabitants of Otaheite → , named by the English, King-George's island, made no difficulty of stealing from his people; and yet never steal among themselves, having neither locks nor bars in their houses."</note><note>In ECCO TCP. Volume II: Sketch 1 ("Progress of Men in Society"), p. 167: Attempt to address a philosophical question about whether people are naturally sociable or antisocial and brutally violent. "In a nascent society, where men hunt and fish in common, where there is plenty of game, and where the sense of property is faint, mutual affec∣tion prevails, because there is no cause of discord; and dissocial passions find sufficient vent against neighbouring tribes. Such is the condition of the North-American savages, who continue hunters and fishers to this day; and such is the condition of all brute animals that live in society, as mentioned above. The island ← Otaheite is divided into many small cantons, having each a chief of its own. These cantons never make war on each other, tho' they are frequently at war with the inhabitants of neigh∣bouring islands. The inhabitants of the new Philip∣pine islands, if Father Gobien be credited, are bet∣ter fitted for society than any other known nation. Sweetness of temper, and love to do good, form their character. They never commit acts of violence: war they have no notion of; and it is a proverb among them, That a man never puts a man to death. Plato places the seat of justice and of happi∣ness among the first men; and among them existed the golden age, if it ever did exist. But when a nation, becoming populous, begins with rearing flocks and herds, proceeds to appropriate land, and is not satisfied without matters of luxury over and above; selfishness and pride gain ground, and be∣come ruling and unruly passions. Causes of discord multiply, vent is given to avarice and resentment; and among a people not yet perfectly submissive to government, dissocial passions rage, and threaten a total dissolution of society: nothing indeed suspends the impending blow,..." </note><note>In ECCO TCP. Volume IV, Part II: Sketch 3 ("Principles and Progress of THEOLOGY.") Chapter 2, p. 152: Syncretism in action here: Otaheite's spiritual beliefs are sketched here by way of comparison with several other island or "savage" cultures with (according to this author) tendencies toward monotheism. Passage: " The North-Ame∣rican savages have all of them a notion of a su∣preme Deity, creator and governor of the world, and of inferior deities, some good, some ill. These are supposed to have bodies, and to live much as men do, but without being subjected to any distress. The same creed prevails among the negroes of Benin and Congo, among the people of New Zeland, among the inhabitants of Java, of Madagascar, of the Molucca islands, and of the Caribbee islands. The Chingulese, a tribe in the island of Ceylon, acknowledge one God creator of the universe, with subordinate deities who act as his deputies: agriculture is the pecu∣liar province of one, navigation of another. The creed of the Tonquinese is nearly the same. The inhabitants of Otaheite, termed King George's island, believe in one supreme Deity; and in inferior deities without end, who preside over particular parts of the creation. They pay no adoration to the supreme Deity, thinking him too far elevated above his creatures to concern himself with what they do. They believe the stars to be children of the sun and moon, and an eclipse to be the time of copulation."</note></bibl></listBibl></item>

            <!--This is just a repeat, for a second successful search term/topic--><item><term>
                    <!--Successful Search Term here--><num type="hits"><!--Total Number of Hits here--></num></term><term type="var"><!--Successful variation on this term--></term><num type="hits"/><term type="var"/><num type="hits"/><listBibl>
                    <!--Enter bibliographic info and a descriptive note for at least one or two of your especially good results. Follow how we did this above for your voyage text.--><bibl><author/><title/><editor/><publisher/><pubPlace/><date/><note><!--Describe the way the term is used.--></note></bibl><bibl><author/><title/><editor/><publisher/><pubPlace/><date/><note><!--Describe the way the term is used.--></note></bibl><bibl><author/><title/><editor/><publisher/><pubPlace/><date/><note><!--Describe the way the term is used.--></note></bibl></listBibl></item>
            <!--This is just a repeat, for a third successful search term/topic--><item><term>
                    <!--Successful Search Term here--><num type="hits"><!--Total Number of Hits here--></num></term><term type="var"><!--Successful variation on this term--></term><num type="hits"/><term type="var"/><num type="hits"/><listBibl>
                    <!--Enter bibliographic info and a descriptive note for at least one or two of your especially good results. Follow how we did this above for your voyage text.--><bibl><author/><title/><editor/><publisher/><pubPlace/><date/><note><!--Describe the way the term is used.--></note></bibl><bibl><author/><title/><editor/><publisher/><pubPlace/><date/><note><!--Describe the way the term is used.--></note></bibl><bibl><author/><title/><editor/><publisher/><pubPlace/><date/><note><!--Describe the way the term is used.--></note></bibl></listBibl></item></list>

        <!--Record your UNSUCCESSFUL searches here. --><list type="unsuccessful"><item><term>timiradi</term><term type="var"/><term type="var"/><term type="var"/><note>In ECCO TCP. Just returns one text: Sentimaental Excursions to Windsor</note></item><item><term><!--Unsuccesful term--></term><term type="var"/><term type="var"/><term type="var"/><note><!--Optional: Comments / Suggestions to try later?--></note></item>

            <!--Copy the item element to add more as needed.--><item><term><!--Unsuccesful term--></term><term type="var"/><term type="var"/><term type="var"/><note><!--Optional: Comments / Suggestions to try later?--></note></item></list></body></eccoLocation>