<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../../schemas/LocationSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?><location type="city/town">
    <name n="Celdaon City">Celadon City</name>
    <des>A rich, rainbow colored city where people and Pokémon gather.</des>
    <PoI>

        <place>
            <placeName>Celadon Department Store</placeName>
            <des><pref>Celadon's department store</pref> is the largest building in the city, as
                well as the largest shop in Kanto. It is located in the northwest corner of the
                city. The store has two sliding door entrances, and is six stories high, including a
                rooftop floor.</des>
        </place>

        <place>
            <placeName>Celadon Condominiums</placeName>
            <des><pref>Celadon Condominiums</pref> is located next to the <pref>Pokémon
                    Center</pref>.The <pers>player</pers> can find a <item>Poké Ball</item>
                containing an <pokemon dexNum="133">Eevee</pokemon> here. <pers>Game Freak</pers>
                has an office in this building, where the <pers>player</pers> can receive a
                    <item>diploma</item> from the lead developer if they have completed their
                    <item>Pokédex</item>.</des>
        </place>

        <place>
            <placeName>Celadon Game Corner</placeName>
            <des>The <pref>Celadon Game Corner</pref> is located in the southeast of the city. It
                was originally run by <pers>Team Rocket</pers>, being known as the <pref>Rocket Game
                    Corner</pref> while under their management. The <pref>Team Rocket Hideout</pref>
                is located underneath it; the staircase to the base is revealed by pressing a switch
                hidden behind a poster.</des>
        </place>

        <place>
            <placeName>Team Rocket Hideout</placeName>
            <des>The <pref>Team Rocket Hideout</pref> is an underground four-floor-deep complex
                beneath the <pref>Rocket Game Corner</pref>. The <pref>Rocket Hideout</pref> is
                accessed by pressing a switch behind a poster in the <pref>Game Corner</pref> in
                    <pref>Celadon City</pref>.</des>
        </place>

        <place>
            <placeName>Celadon Hotel</placeName>
            <des>The <pref>Celadon Hotel</pref> is a luxurious hotel building located in the
                southeastern part of the city. The <pers>player</pers> is not able to rent a room
                due to all the rooms being booked. The hotel's layout is remarkably similar to a
                    <pref>Pokémon Center</pref>.</des>
        </place>

    </PoI>
</location>