<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<location type="city/town">
    <name n="Cerulean City">Cerulean City</name>
    <des>A beautiful city with flowing water and blooming flowers.</des>
    <PoI>

        <place>
            <placeName>Bike Shop</placeName>
            <des>the <pref>Bike Shop</pref> sells <item>Bicycles</item> produced by the company.
                Designs range from a <item>plain city bike</item> to a f<item>ast mountain
                    bike</item>; however, the <pers>player</pers> can only ever get one: the
                    <item>Bicycle</item>. It can be bought for 1,000,000 or exchanged for a
                    <item>Bike Voucher</item>. </des>
        </place>

        <place>
            <placeName>Cerulean Cave</placeName>
            <des>On the outskirts of <pref>Cerulean City</pref> lies <pref>Cerulean Cave</pref>,
                also known as the <pref>Unknown Dungeon</pref>. It is said to be home to "horribly
                strong Pokémon". The player can capture the level 70 <pokemon dexNum="150">Mewtwo</pokemon>.</des>
        </place>

        <place>
            <placeName>Cerulean Gym</placeName>
            <des>The <pref>Cerulean Gym</pref> is the official Gym of <pref>Cerulean City</pref>. It
                is based on Water-type Pokémon. The Gym Leader is <pers>Misty</pers>. Trainers who
                defeat her will receive the <item>Cascade Badge</item>.</des>
        </place>

        <place>
            <placeName>Berry Powder Man</placeName>
            <des>there is a man in a cottage in the northern part of town who concocts a variety of
                medicines from <item>Berry Powder</item> and will exchange <item>Berry Powder</item>
                for <item>herbal medicine</item> and <item>vitamins</item>.</des>
        </place>

        <place>
            <placeName>Gym Badge Man</placeName>
            <des>there is a man in a cottage in the northwest corner of the city who will explain
                exactly what the effects are for each of the eight <item>Indigo League Gym
                    Badges</item>. He also has a small backyard, where a <item>Rare Candy</item> can
                be found hidden among the flowers.</des>
        </place>

        <place>
            <placeName>Dontae/Melanie"s House</placeName>
            <des>There is a residential house located to the west of the <pref>Pokémon
                Center</pref>, this house belongs to <pers>Dontae</pers> and his wife.
                    <pers>Dontae</pers> will offer to trade the <pers>player</pers> his <pokemon dexNum="124">Jynx</pokemon> for their <pokemon dexNum="061">Poliwhirl</pokemon>.</des>
        </place>

        <place>
            <placeName>Burgled House</placeName>
            <des>a <pers>Team Rocket Grunt</pers> stole the <item>TM for Dig</item> from its owner,
                leaving the house a mess. After defeating the Grunt, the <pers>player</pers> will
                receive the <item>TM</item> from him. The owner then says that since the
                    <item>TM</item> was stolen, he'll find a way of teaching <item>Dig</item> to
                    <pokemon dexNum="050">Diglett</pokemon> without a <item>TM</item>.</des>
        </place>

    </PoI>
</location>