<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../../schemas/LocationSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?><location type="city/town">
    <name n="Saffron City">Saffron City</name>
    <des>The biggest city in Kanto, shining with a golden light.</des>
    <PoI>

        <place>
            <placeName>Silph Co. Head Office</placeName>
            <des>T<pref>he Silph Co. Head Office</pref> is the largest and tallest building in the
                city. <pref>Silph Co.</pref> are the leading manufacturer of Pokémon technology in
                the world, and produce a variety of goods for Trainers, such as the <item>Poké
                    Ball</item> and the <item>Silph Scope</item>.</des>
        </place>

        <place>
            <placeName>Fighting Dojo</placeName>
            <des>there is also an unofficial Gym, the Fighting Dojo, which specializes in
                Fighting-type Pokémon. The <pers>player</pers> can obtain their choice of <pokemon dexNum="107">Hitmonchan</pokemon> or <pokemon dexNum="106">Hitmonlee</pokemon>
                by defeating the Karate Master <pers>Koichi</pers>.</des>
        </place>

        <place>
            <placeName>Mr. Psychic's House</placeName>
            <des><pers>Mr. Psychic</pers> lives in a small house that is located on the southeastern
                side of the city, being better accessible by entering <pref>Saffron City</pref> from
                the southern entrance. He sits at a table in the middle of the room. When talked to
                for the first time in every game he is featured in, he will claim to know that the
                    <pers>player</pers> really wants to receive a gift from him, giving the <item>TM
                    for Psychic</item> to the <pers>player</pers>.</des>
        </place>

        <place>
            <placeName>Pokemon Trainer Fan Club</placeName>
            <des>People gather to discuss their favorite celebrity Trainers at the <pref>Pokémon
                    Trainer Fan Club</pref>, </des>
        </place>

        <place>
            <placeName>Saffron Gym</placeName>
            <des>The <pref>Saffron Gym</pref> is the official Gym of <pref>Saffron City</pref>. It
                is based on Psychic-type Pokémon. The Gym Leader is <pers>Sabrina</pers>. Trainers
                who defeat her receive the <item>Marsh Badge</item>. The <pref>Saffron Gym</pref> is
                a maze of warp tiles and nine rooms. </des>
        </place>

    </PoI>
</location>