<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<location type="city/town">
    <name n="Vermilion City">Vermilion City</name>
    <des>A southern city that is bathed in orange by the setting sun.</des>
    <PoI>

        <place>
            <placeName>Habor</placeName>
            <des>One of the larger docks in the Kanto region, and boats such as the S.S. Anne, S.S.
                Aqua, and Seagallop dock here.</des>
        </place>

        <place>
            <placeName>Pokemon Fan Club</placeName>
            <des>The Kanto chapter of the <pref>Pokémon Fan Club</pref> is located in
                    <pref>Vermilion</pref>. The <pref>Pokémon Fan Club</pref> is an organization
                spread throughout the Pokémon world, with at least one Club House in nearly every
                region. The Fan Club is basically a place for people to meet and chat about their
                favorite Pokémon and to show off their collections to each other.</des>
        </place>

        <place>
            <placeName>Vermilion Gym</placeName>
            <des>The <pref>Vermilion Gym</pref> is the official Gym of <pref>Vermilion City</pref>.
                Its Gym Leader, <pers>Lt. Surge</pers>, focuses on Electric-type Pokémon. Trainers
                who defeat him receive the <item>Thunder Badge</item>.</des>
        </place>

        <place>
            <placeName>Construction Site</placeName>
            <des>In the northeastern part of the city, there is an old man whose <pokemon dexNum="066">Machop</pokemon> is preparing a plot of land for construction of a
                building. They still have not finished three years</des>
        </place>

        <place>
            <placeName>In-game Trade</placeName>
            <des>In one of the houses south and a little east of the Pokémon Center is a girl that
                wants to trade the player a <pokemon dexNum="083">Farfetch'd</pokemon> for a
                    <pokemon dexNum="021">Spearow</pokemon>.</des>
        </place>

        <place>
            <placeName>Fishing Brother</placeName>
            <des>a man known as the <pers>Fishing Guru</pers> can be found in <pref>Vermilion
                    City</pref> who gives away an <item>Old Rod</item> to the
                <pers>player</pers>.</des>
        </place>

        <place>
            <placeName>Sleeping Pokemon Notice</placeName>
            <des>Near the entrance to <pref>Diglett's Cave</pref> about a sleeping Pokémon that's
                blocking <pref>Route 12</pref>, advising people wishing to go to <pref>Lavender
                    Town</pref> to detour through the <pref>Rock Tunnel</pref> instead in the
                meantime.</des>
        </place>

    </PoI>
</location>