<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../../RNC/ulyssesSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?><?xml-model href="../../Schematron/ulyssesSchematron.sch" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?><ulysses>
     <section sectionName="The Wanderings of Ulysses"/>
     <chapter chapterName="The Wandering Rocks"/>
     <location name="Mountjoy Square" lat="53.35568" lon="-6.26023"><p>The superior, the very
               reverend John Conmee S. J. reset his smooth watch in his interior pocket as he came
               down the presbytery steps. Five to three. Just nice time to walk to Artane. What was
               that boy’s name again? Dignam. Yes. <reference to="Catholicism">_Vere dignum et
                    iustum est._</reference> Brother Swan was the person to see. Mr Cunningham’s
               letter. Yes. Oblige him, if possible. <reference to="Catholicism">Good practical
                    catholic: useful at mission time.</reference></p>
          <p>A onelegged sailor, swinging himself onward by lazy jerks of his crutches, growled some
               notes. He jerked short before the convent of the sisters of charity and held out a
               peaked cap for alms towards the very reverend John Conmee S. J. Father Conmee blessed
               him in the sun for his purse held, he knew, one silver crown.</p>
          <p> Father Conmee crossed to Mountjoy square. He thought, but not for long, of soldiers
               and sailors, whose legs had been shot off by cannonballs, ending their days in some
               pauper ward, and of <person who="Cardinal Thomas Wolsey">cardinal Wolsey’s</person>
               words: _If I had served my God as I have served my king He would not have abandoned
               me in my old days._ He walked by the treeshade of sunnywinking leaves: and towards
               him came the wife of <person who="David Sheehy">Mr David Sheehy M.P.</person></p>
          <said who="Mrs. David Sheehy">—Very well, indeed, father. And you, father?</said>
          <p>Father Conmee was wonderfully well indeed. He would go to Buxton probably for the
               waters. And her boys, were they getting on well at <reference to="Jesuits">Belvedere</reference>? Was that so? Father Conmee was very glad indeed to hear
               that. And Mr Sheehy himself? Still in London. The house was still sitting, to be sure
               it was. Beautiful weather it was, delightful indeed. Yes, it was very probable that
                    <person who="Bernard Vaughan">Father Bernard Vaughan</person> would come again
               to preach. O, yes: a very great success. A wonderful man really.</p>
          <p>Father Conmee was very glad to see the wife of Mr David Sheehy M.P. Iooking so well and
               he begged to be remembered to Mr David Sheehy M.P. Yes, he would certainly call.</p>
          <said who="John Conmee">—Good afternoon, Mrs Sheehy.</said>
          <p>Father Conmee doffed his silk hat and smiled, as he took leave, at the jet beads of her
               mantilla inkshining in the sun. And smiled yet again, in going. He had cleaned his
               teeth, he knew, with <reference to="orientalism">arecanut paste.</reference></p>
          <p>Father Conmee walked and, walking, smiled for he thought on Father Bernard Vaughan’s
               droll eyes and cockney voice.</p>
          <said who="John Conmee"><reference to="Christianity">—Pilate! Wy don’t you old back that
                    owlin mob?</reference></said>
          <p>A zealous man, however. Really he was. And really did great good in his way. Beyond a
               doubt. He loved Ireland, he said, and he loved the Irish. Of good family too would
               one think it? Welsh, were they not?</p>
          <p><allusion who="Rudyard Kipling">O, lest he forget.</allusion> That letter to <reference to="Jesuits">father provincial.</reference></p>
          <p>Father Conmee stopped three little schoolboys at the corner of Mountjoy square. Yes:
               they were from Belvedere. The little house. Aha. And were they good boys at school?
               O. That was very good now. And what was his name? Jack Sohan. And his name? Ger.
               Gallaher. And the other little man? His name was Brunny Lynam. O, that was a very
               nice name to have.</p>
     </location>
     <location name="Fitzgibbon Street" lat="53.35749" lon="-6.25721"><p>Father Conmee gave a letter
               from his breast to Master Brunny Lynam and pointed to the red pillarbox at the corner
               of Fitzgibbon street.</p>
          <said who="Father Conmee">—But mind you don’t post yourself into the box, little man, he
               said.</said> The boys sixeyed Father Conmee and laughed: <said who="The Boys">—O,
               sir.</said>
          <said who="Father Conmee">—Well, let me see if you can post a letter, Father Conmee
               said.</said>
          <p> Master Brunny Lynam ran across the road and put Father Conmee’s letter to father
               provincial into the mouth of the bright red letterbox. Father Conmee smiled and
               nodded and smiled and walked along Mountjoy square east.</p>
          <p>Mr Denis J Maginni, professor of dancing &amp;c, in silk hat, slate frockcoat with silk
               facings, white kerchief tie, tight lavender trousers, canary gloves and pointed
               patent boots, walking <allusion who="Charles Dickens">with grave
                    deportment</allusion> most respectfully took the curbstone as he passed lady
               Maxwell at the corner of Dignam’s court.</p>
          <p>Was that not Mrs M’Guinness?</p>
          <p>Mrs M’Guinness, stately, silverhaired, bowed to Father Conmee from the farther footpath
               along which she sailed. And Father Conmee smiled and saluted. How did she do?</p>
          <p>A fine carriage she had. Like <person who="Mary Stuart">Mary, queen of Scots</person>,
               something. And to think that she was a pawnbroker! Well, now! Such a... what should
               he say?... such a queenly mien.</p></location>
     <location name="North Circular Road" lat="53.35929" lon="-6.26262">
          <p>Father Conmee walked down Great Charles street and glanced at the shutup <reference to="Protestantism">free church on his left. The reverend T. R. Greene B.A. will
                    (D.V.) speak.</reference> The incumbent they called him. He felt it incumbent on
               him to say a few words. But one should be charitable. <reference to="Catholicism">Invincible ignorance.</reference> They acted according to their lights.</p>
          <p>Father Conmee turned the corner and walked along the North Circular road. It was a
               wonder that there was not a tramline in such an important thoroughfare. Surely, there
               ought to be</p>. <p>A band of satchelled schoolboys crossed from Richmond street. All
               raised untidy caps. Father Conmee greeted them more than once benignly. Christian
               brother boys.</p>
          <p>Father Conmee smelt incense on his right hand as he walked. Saint Joseph’s church,
               Portland row. For aged and virtuous females. Father Conmee raised his hat to the
               Blessed Sacrament. Virtuous: but occasionally they were also badtempered. </p>
          <p>Near Aldborough house Father Conmee thought of that spendthrift nobleman. And now it
               was an office or something.</p></location>

     <location name="N. Strand Road" lat="53.35443" lon="-6.24785"><p>Father Conmee began to walk
               along the North Strand road and was saluted by Mr William Gallagher who stood in the
               doorway of his shop. Father Conmee saluted Mr William Gallagher and perceived the
               odours that came from baconflitches and ample cools of butter.</p><p>He passed
               Grogan’s the Tobacconist against which newsboards leaned and told of a dreadful
               catastrophe in New York. In America those things were continually happening.
                    <reference to="Catholicism">Unfortunate people to die like that, unprepared.
                    Still, an act of perfect contrition.</reference></p><p>Father Conmee went by
               Daniel Bergin’s publichouse against the window of which two unlabouring men lounged.
               They saluted him and were saluted.</p><p>Father Conmee passed H. J. O’Neill’s funeral
               establishment where Corny Kelleher totted figures in the daybook while he chewed a
               blade of hay. A constable on his beat saluted Father Conmee and Father Conmee saluted
               the constable.</p><p>In Youkstetter’s, the porkbutcher’s, Father Conmee observed
               pig’s puddings, white and black and red, lie neatly curled in tubes.</p>
          <p>Moored under the trees of Charleville Mall Father Conmee saw a turfbarge, a towhorse
               with pendent head, a bargeman with a hat of dirty straw seated amidships, smoking and
               staring at a branch of poplar above him. It was idyllic: and Father Conmee reflected
               on the providence of the Creator who had made turf to be in bogs whence men might dig
               it out and bring it to town and hamlet to make fires in the houses of poor
               people.</p></location>

     <location name="Newcomen Bridge" lat="53.35603" lon="-6.24567"><p>On Newcomen bridge the very
               reverend John Conmee S. J. of saint Francis Xavier’s church, upper Gardiner street,
               stepped on to an outward bound tram.</p>
          <p>Off an inward bound tram stepped the reverend Nicholas Dudley C. C. of saint Agatha’s
               church, north William street, on to Newcomen bridge.</p>
          <p>At Newcomen bridge Father Conmee stepped into an outward bound tram for he disliked to
               traverse on foot the dingy way past Mud Island.</p>
          <p>Father Conmee sat in a corner of the tramcar, a blue ticket tucked with care in the eye
               of one plump kid glove, while four shillings, a sixpence and five pennies chuted from
               his other plump glovepalm into his purse. Passing the ivy church he reflected that
               the ticket inspector usually made his visit when one had carelessly thrown away the
               ticket. The solemnity of the occupants of the car seemed to Father Conmee excessive
               for a journey so short and cheap. Father Conmee liked cheerful decorum.</p>
          <p>It was a peaceful day. The gentleman with the glasses opposite Father Conmee had
               finished explaining and looked down. His wife, Father Conmee supposed. A tiny yawn
               opened the mouth of the wife of the gentleman with the glasses. She raised her small
               gloved fist, yawned ever so gently, tiptapping her small gloved fist on her opening
               mouth and smiled tinily, sweetly.</p>
          <p>Father Conmee perceived her perfume in the car. He perceived also that the awkward man
               at the other side of her was sitting on the edge of the seat.</p>
          <p>Father Conmee at the altarrails placed the host with difficulty in the mouth of the
               awkward old man who had the shaky head.</p></location>

     <location name="Annesley Bridge" lat="53.36031" lon="-6.24020"><p>At Annesley bridge the tram
               halted and, when it was about to go, an old woman rose suddenly from her place to
               alight. The conductor pulled the bellstrap to stay the car for her. She passed out
               with her basket and a marketnet: and Father Conmee saw the conductor help her and net
               and basket down: and Father Conmee thought that, as she had nearly passed the end of
               the penny fare, she was one of those good souls who had always to be told twice
                    <reference to="Catholicism">_bless you, my child,_ that they have been absolved,
                    _pray for me._</reference> But they had so many worries in life, so many cares,
               poor creatures.</p>
          <p>From the hoardings Mr Eugene Stratton grimaced with thick niggerlips at Father
               Conmee.</p>
          <p>Father Conmee thought of the souls of black and brown and yellow men and of his sermon
               on saint Peter Claver S. J. and the African mission and of the propagation of the
               faith and of the millions of black and brown and yellow souls that had not received
               the baptism of water when their last hour came like a thief in the night. <allusion who="Father A. Castelein S.J.">That book by the Belgian jesuit, _Le Nombre des
                    Élus,_</allusion> seemed to Father Conmee a reasonable plea. Those were millions
               of human souls created by God in His Own likeness to whom the faith had not (D.V.)
               been brought. But they were God’s souls, created by God. It seemed to Father Conmee a
               pity that they should all be lost, a waste, if one might say.</p></location>

     <location name="Howth Road" lat="53.37942" lon="-6.16103"><p>At the Howth road stop Father
               Conmee alighted, was saluted by the conductor and saluted in his turn.</p></location>

     <location name="Malahide Road" lat="53.40295" lon="-6.18389"><p>The Malahide road was quiet. It
               pleased Father Conmee, road and name. <allusion who="Gerald Griffin">The joybells
                    were ringing in gay Malahide.</allusion>
               <person who="Sir Richard Talbot of Malahide">Lord Talbot de Malahide</person>,
               immediate hereditary lord admiral of Malahide and the seas adjoining. Then came the
               call to arms and she was maid, wife and widow in one day. Those were old worldish
               days, loyal times in joyous townlands, old times in the barony.</p>
          <p>Father Conmee, walking, thought of his little book _Old Times in the Barony_ and of the
               book that might be written about jesuit houses and of <person who="Mary Rochfort">Mary Rochfort</person>, daughter of lord Molesworth, first countess of
               Belvedere.</p>
          <p>A listless lady, no more young, walked alone the shore of lough Ennel, Mary, first
               countess of Belvedere, listlessly walking in the evening, not startled when an otter
               plunged. Who could know the truth? Not the jealous lord Belvedere and not her
               confessor if she had not committed adultery fully, _eiaculatio seminis inter vas
               naturale mulieris,_ with her husband’s brother? She would half confess if she had not
               all sinned as women did. Only God knew and she and he, her husband’s brother.</p>
          <p>Father Conmee thought of that tyrannous incontinence, needed however for man’s race on
               earth, and of the ways of God which were not our ways.</p>
          <p>Don John Conmee walked and moved in times of yore. He was humane and honoured there. He
               bore in mind secrets confessed and he smiled at smiling noble faces in a beeswaxed
               drawingroom, ceiled with full fruit clusters. And the hands of a bride and of a
               bridegroom, noble to noble, were impalmed by Don John Conmee.</p>
          <p>It was a charming day.</p>
          <p>The lychgate of a field showed Father Conmee breadths of cabbages, curtseying to him
               with ample underleaves. The sky showed him a flock of small white clouds going slowly
               down the wind. _Moutonner,_ the French said. A just and homely word.</p>
          <p>Father Conmee, <reference to="Catholicism">reading his office</reference>, watched a
               flock of muttoning clouds over Rathcoffey. His thinsocked ankles were tickled by the
               stubble of Clongowes field. He walked there, reading in the evening, and heard the
               cries of the boys’ lines at their play, young cries in the quiet evening. He was
               their rector: his reign was mild.</p>
          <p>Father Conmee drew off his gloves and took his rededged breviary out. <reference to="Catholicism">An ivory bookmark</reference> told him the page.</p>
          <p>Nones. He should have read that before lunch. But lady Maxwell had come.</p>
          <p>Father Conmee read in secret <reference to="Catholicism">_Pater_ and _Ave_</reference>
               and crossed his breast. <reference to="Christianity">_Deus in
                    adiutorium._</reference></p>
          <p>He walked calmly and read mutely the nones, walking and reading till he came to
                    <reference to="Christianity">_Res_ in _Beati immaculati: Principium verborum
                    tuorum veritas: in eternum omnia iudicia iustitiæ tuæ._</reference></p>
          <p>A flushed young man came from a gap of a hedge and after him came a young woman with
               wild nodding daisies in her hand. The young man raised his cap abruptly: the young
               woman abruptly bent and with slow care detached from her light skirt a clinging
               twig.</p>
          <p>Father Conmee blessed both gravely and turned a thin page of his breviary. <reference to="Christianity">_Sin: Principes persecuti sunt me gratis: et a verbis tuis
                    formidavit cor meum._</reference> * * * </p>
          <p>Corny Kelleher closed his long daybook and glanced with his drooping eye at a pine
               coffinlid sentried in a corner. He pulled himself erect, went to it and, spinning it
               on its axle, viewed its shape and brass furnishings. Chewing his blade of hay he laid
               the coffinlid by and came to the doorway. There he tilted his hatbrim to give shade
               to his eyes and leaned against the doorcase, looking idly out.</p>
          <p>Father John Conmee stepped into the Dollymount tram on Newcomen bridge.</p>
          <p>Corny Kelleher locked his largefooted boots and gazed, his hat downtilted, chewing his
               blade of hay.</p>
          <p>Constable 57C, on his beat, stood to pass the time of day. —That’s a fine day, Mr
               Kelleher. —Ay, Corny Kelleher said. —It’s very close, the constable said.</p>
          <p>Corny Kelleher sped a silent jet of hayjuice arching from his mouth while a generous
               white arm from a window in Eccles street flung forth a coin. —What’s the best news?
               he asked. —I seen that particular party last evening, the constable said with bated
               breath. * * * </p></location>
     <location name="Dorset Street Lower" lat="53.35735" lon="-6.26569"><p>A onelegged sailor
               crutched himself round MacConnell’s corner, skirting Rabaiotti’s icecream car, and
               jerked himself up Eccles street. Towards Larry O’Rourke, in shirtsleeves in his
               doorway, he growled unamiably:</p>
          <said who="Onelegged Sailor"><allusion who="S.J. Arnold">—_For
               England_...</allusion></said>
          <p>He swung himself violently forward past Katey and Boody Dedalus, halted and
               growled:</p>
          <said who="Onelegged Sailor"><allusion who="S.J. Arnold">—_home and
               beauty._</allusion></said>
          <p>J. J. O’Molloy’s white careworn face was told that Mr Lambert was in the warehouse with
               a visitor.</p>
          <p>A stout lady stopped, took a copper coin from her purse and dropped it into the cap
               held out to her. The sailor grumbled thanks, glanced sourly at the unheeding windows,
               sank his head and swung himself forward four strides.</p>
          <p>He halted and growled angrily: <said who="Onelegged Sailor">—_For England_... </said>
               Two barefoot urchins, sucking long liquorice laces, halted near him, gaping at his
               stump with their yellowslobbered mouths.</p>
          <p>He swung himself forward in vigorous jerks, halted, lifted his head towards a window
               and bayed deeply: <said who="Onelegged Sailor">—_home and beauty._ </said> The gay
               sweet chirping whistling within went on a bar or two, ceased. The blind of the window
               was drawn aside. A card _Unfurnished Apartments_ slipped from the sash and fell. A
               plump bare generous arm shone, was seen, held forth from a white petticoatbodice and
               taut shiftstraps. A woman’s hand flung forth a coin over the area railings. It fell
               on the path.</p>
          <p>One of the urchins ran to it, picked it up and dropped it into the minstrel’s cap,
               saying: <said who="urchin">—There, sir. </said> * * * </p>
          <p>Katey and Boody Dedalus shoved in the door of the closesteaming kitchen. <said who="Boody Dedalus">—Did you put in the books? Boody asked. </said> Maggy at the
               range rammed down a greyish mass beneath bubbling suds twice with her potstick and
               wiped her brow. <said who="Katey Dedalus">—They wouldn’t give anything on them, she
                    said. </said></p></location>
     <location name="Clongowes Fields" lat="53.2957" lon="-6.7293"><p>Father Conmee walked through
               Clongowes fields, his thinsocked ankles tickled by stubble.</p>
          <said who="Boody Dedalus">—Where did you try? Boody asked.</said>
          <said who="Father Conmee">—M’Guinness’s.</said>
          <p>Boody stamped her foot and threw her satchel on the table. <said who="Katey Dedalus">—Bad cess to her big face! she cried.</said></p>
          <p>Katey went to the range and peered with squinting eyes. <said who="Katey Dedalus">—What’s in the pot? she asked.</said>
               <said who="Maggy">—Shirts, Maggy said.</said></p>
          <p>Boody cried angrily: <said who="Boody Dedalus">—Crickey, is there nothing for us to
                    eat?</said></p>
          <p>Katey, lifting the kettlelid in a pad of her stained skirt, asked: <said who="Katey Dedalus">—And what’s in this?</said></p>
          <p>A heavy fume gushed in answer. <said who="Maggy">—Peasoup, Maggy said.</said>
               <said who="Katey Dedalus">—Where did you get it? Katey asked.</said>
               <said who="Magg">—Sister Mary Patrick, Maggy said.</said></p>
          <p>The lacquey rang his bell. <said who="Lacquey">—Barang!</said></p>
          <p>Boody sat down at the table and said hungrily: <said who="Boody Dedalus">—Give us it
                    here.</said></p>
          <p>Maggy poured yellow thick soup from the kettle into a bowl. Katey, sitting opposite
               Boody, said quietly, as her fingertip lifted to her mouth random crumbs: <said who="Katey Dedalus">—A good job we have that much. Where’s Dilly?</said>
               <said who="Maggy">—Gone to meet father, Maggy said.</said></p>
          <p>Boody, breaking big chunks of bread into the yellow soup, added: <said who="Boody Dedalus"><reference to="Christianity">—Our father who art not in
                         heaven.</reference></said></p>
          <p>Maggy, pouring yellow soup in Katey’s bowl, exclaimed: <said who="Bood Dedalus">—Boody!
                    For shame!</said></p>
          <p>A skiff, a crumpled throwaway, Elijah is coming, rode lightly down the Liffey, under
               Loopline bridge, shooting the rapids where water chafed around the bridgepiers,
               sailing eastward past hulls and anchorchains, between the Customhouse old dock and
               George’s quay. * * * </p>
          <p>The blond girl in Thornton’s bedded the wicker basket with rustling fibre. Blazes
               Boylan handed her the bottle swathed in pink tissue paper and a small jar. <said who="Blazes Boylan">—Put these in first, will you? he said.</said>
               <said who="Blond Girl">—Yes, sir, the blond girl said. And the fruit on top.</said>
               <said who="Blazes Boylan">—That’ll do, game ball, Blazes Boylan said.</said></p>
          <p>She bestowed fat pears neatly, head by tail, and among them ripe shamefaced
               peaches.</p>
          <p>Blazes Boylan walked here and there in new tan shoes about the fruitsmelling shop,
               lifting fruits, young juicy crinkled and plump red tomatoes, sniffing smells.</p>
     </location>
     <location name="Grafton Street" lat="53.34394" lon="-6.26083"><p>H. E. L. Y.’S filed before
               him, tallwhitehatted, past Tangier lane, plodding towards their goal.</p>
          <p>He turned suddenly from a chip of strawberries, drew a gold watch from his fob and held
               it at its chain’s length. <said who="Blazes Boylan">—Can you send them by tram?
                    Now?</said></p>
          <p>A darkbacked figure under Merchants’ arch scanned books on the hawker’s cart. <said who="Blond Girl">—Certainly, sir. Is it in the city?</said>
               <said who="Blazes Boylan">—O, yes, Blazes Boylan said. Ten minutes.</said></p>
          <p>The blond girl handed him a docket and pencil. <said who="Blond Girl">—Will you write
                    the address, sir?</said></p>
          <p>Blazes Boylan at the counter wrote and pushed the docket to her. <said who="Blazes Boylan">—Send it at once, will you? he said. It’s for an
                    invalid.</said>
               <said who="Blond Girl">—Yes, sir. I will, sir.</said></p>
          <p>Blazes Boylan rattled merry money in his trousers’ pocket. <said who="Blazes Boylan">—What’s the damage? he asked.</said></p>
          <p>The blond girl’s slim fingers reckoned the fruits.</p>
          <p>Blazes Boylan looked into the cut of her blouse. A young pullet. He took a red
               carnation from the tall stemglass. <said who="Blazes Boylan">—This for me? he asked
                    gallantly.</said></p>
          <p>The blond girl glanced sideways at him, got up regardless, with his tie a bit crooked,
               blushing. <said who="Blond Girl">—Yes, sir, she said.</said></p>
          <p>Bending archly she reckoned again fat pears and blushing peaches.</p>
          <p>Blazes Boylan looked in her blouse with more favour, the stalk of the red flower
               between his smiling teeth. <said who="Blazes Boylan">—May I say a word to your
                    telephone, missy? he asked roguishly.</said> * * * </p>
          <p>_<said who="Stephen Dedalus">—Ma!_ Almidano Artifoni said.</said></p>
          <p>He gazed over Stephen’s shoulder at <person who="Oliver Goldsmith">Goldsmith’s knobby
                    poll.</person></p>
          <p>Two carfuls of tourists passed slowly, their women sitting fore, gripping the
               handrests. Palefaces. Men’s arms frankly round their stunted forms.</p></location>
     <location name="College Green" lat="53.34412" lon="-6.26078">
          <p>They looked from Trinity to the blind columned porch of the bank of Ireland where
               pigeons roocoocooed.</p>
          <said who="Almidano Artifoni">—_Anch’io ho avuto di queste idee_, Almidano Artifoni said,
               _quand’ ero giovine come Lei. Eppoi mi sono convinto che il mondo è una bestia. È
               peccato. Perchè la sua voce... sarebbe un cespite di rendita, via. Invece, Lei si
               sacrifica._</said>
          <said who="Stephen Dedalus">—_Sacrifizio incruento,_ Stephen said smiling, swaying his
               ashplant in slow swingswong from its midpoint, lightly.</said>
          <said who="Almidano Artifoni"> _—Speriamo,_ the round mustachioed face said pleasantly.
               _Ma, dia retta a me. Ci rifletta_.</said>
          <p>By the stern stone hand of <person who="Henry Grattan">Grattan</person>, bidding halt,
               an Inchicore tram unloaded straggling Highland soldiers of a band.</p>
          <said who="Stephen Dedalus">—_Ci rifletterò,_ Stephen said, glancing down the solid
               trouserleg.</said>
          <said who="Almidano Artifoni">—_Ma, sul serio, eh?_ Almidano Artifoni said.</said>
          <p>His heavy hand took Stephen’s firmly. Human eyes. They gazed curiously an instant and
               turned quickly towards a Dalkey tram.</p>
          <said who="Almidano Artifoni">_—Eccolo,_ Almidano Artifoni said in friendly haste. _Venga
               a trovarmi e ci pensi. Addio, caro._</said>
          <said who="Stephen Dedalus">—_Arrivederla, maestro,_ Stephen said, raising his hat when
               his hand was freed. _E grazie._ </said>
          <said who="Almidano Artifoni">—_Di che?_ Almidano Artifoni said. _Scusi, eh? Tante belle
               cose!_</said>
          <p>Almidano Artifoni, holding up a baton of rolled music as a signal, trotted on stout
               trousers after the Dalkey tram. In vain he trotted, signalling in vain among the rout
               of barekneed gillies smuggling implements of music through Trinity gates.</p> * * *
               <p>Miss Dunne hid the Capel street library copy of <allusion who="Charles Dickens">_The Woman in White_</allusion> far back in her drawer and rolled a sheet of
               gaudy notepaper into her typewriter.</p>
          <p>Too much mystery business in it. <allusion who="Marian Halcombe">Is he in love with
                    that one, Marion?</allusion> Change it and get another by <person who="Mary Cecil Haye">Mary Cecil Haye.</person>
          </p>
          <p>The disk shot down the groove, wobbled a while, ceased and ogled them: six.</p>
          <p>Miss Dunne clicked on the keyboard: </p>
          <said who="Miss Dunne">—16 June 1904.</said></location>

     <location name="Grafton Street" lat="53.34394" lon="-6.26083"><p>Five tallwhitehatted
               sandwichmen between Monypeny’s corner and the slab where <person who="Theobald Wolfe Tone">Wolfe Tone’s</person> statue was not, eeled themselves
               turning H. E. L. Y.’S and plodded back as they had come.</p>
          <p>Then she stared at the large poster of <person who="Marie Kendall">Marie
                    Kendall</person>, charming soubrette, and, listlessly lolling, scribbled on the
               jotter sixteens and capital esses. Mustard hair and dauby cheeks. She’s not
               nicelooking, is she? The way she’s holding up her bit of a skirt. Wonder will that
               fellow be at the band tonight. If I could get that dressmaker to make a concertina
               skirt like Susy Nagle’s. They kick out grand. Shannon and all the boatclub swells
               never took his eyes off her. Hope to goodness he won’t keep me here till seven.</p>
          <p>The telephone rang rudely by her ear. <said who="Miss Dunne">—Hello. Yes, sir. No, sir.
                    Yes, sir. I’ll ring them up after five. Only those two, sir, for Belfast and
                    Liverpool. All right, sir. Then I can go after six if you’re not back. A quarter
                    after. Yes, sir. Twentyseven and six. I’ll tell him. Yes: one, seven,
                    six.</said></p>
          <p>She scribbled three figures on an envelope. <said who="Miss Dunne">—Mr Boylan! Hello!
                    That gentleman from _Sport_ was in looking for you. Mr Lenehan, yes. He said
                    he’ll be in the Ormond at four. No, sir. Yes, sir. I’ll ring them up after
                    five.</said></p></location>

     <location name="8 Ormond Quay Upper" lat="53.34560" lon="-6.27049"> * * * <p>Two pink faces
               turned in the flare of the tiny torch.</p>
          <said who="Ned Lambert">—Who’s that? Ned Lambert asked. Is that Crotty?</said>
          <said who="Jack">—Ringabella and Crosshaven, a voice replied groping for foothold.</said>
          <said who="Ned Lambert">—Hello, Jack, is that yourself? Ned Lambert said, raising in
               salute his pliant lath among the flickering arches. Come on. Mind your steps
               there.</said>
          <p>The <reference to="Greek Mythology">vesta</reference> in the clergyman’s uplifted hand consumed itself in a long soft flame and was
               let fall. At their feet its red speck died: and mouldy air closed round them.</p>
          <said who="Jack">—How interesting! a refined accent said in the gloom.</said>
          <said who="Ned Lambert">—Yes, sir, Ned Lambert said heartily.<reference to="St. Mary's Abbey"> We are standing in the
               historic council chamber of saint Mary’s abbey where silken Thomas proclaimed himself
               a rebel in 1534. This is the most historic spot in all Dublin.</reference> O’Madden Burke is
               going to write something about it one of these days. <reference to="Bank of Ireland">The old bank of Ireland</reference> was over
               the way till the time of the union and the <reference to="Judaisim">original jews’ temple was here too before
               they built their synagogue over in Adelaide road.</reference> You were never here before, Jack,
               were you?</said>
          <said who="Jack">—No, Ned.</said> —He rode down through Dame walk, the refined accent
          said, if my memory serves me. The mansion of the Kildares was in <reference to="Medieval Ireland">Thomas court</reference>. —That’s
          right, Ned Lambert said. That’s quite right, sir. —If you will be so kind then, the
          clergyman said, the next time to allow me perhaps... —Certainly, Ned Lambert said. Bring
          the camera whenever you like. I’ll get those bags cleared away from the windows. You can
          take it from here or from here. In the still faint light he moved about, tapping with his
          lath the piled seedbags and points of vantage on the floor. From a long face a beard and
          gaze hung on a chessboard. —I’m deeply obliged, Mr Lambert, the clergyman said. I won’t
          trespass on your valuable time... —You’re welcome, sir, Ned Lambert said. Drop in whenever
          you like. Next week, say. Can you see? —Yes, yes. Good afternoon, Mr Lambert. Very pleased
          to have met you. —Pleasure is mine, sir, Ned Lambert answered. He followed his guest to
          the outlet and then whirled his lath away among the pillars. With J. J. O’Molloy he came
          forth slowly into Mary’s abbey where draymen were loading floats with sacks of carob and
          palmnut meal, O’Connor, Wexford. He stood to read the card in his hand. —The reverend Hugh
          C. Love, Rathcoffey. Present address: Saint Michael’s, Sallins. Nice young chap he is.
          He’s writing a book about the Fitzgeralds he told me. He’s well up in history, faith. The
          young woman with slow care detached from her light skirt a clinging twig. —I thought you
          were at a new gunpowder plot, J. J. O’Molloy said. Ned Lambert cracked his fingers in the
          air. —God! he cried. I forgot to tell him that one about <person who="Gerald Fitzgerald">the earl of Kildare</person> after he set
          fire to Cashel cathedral. You know that one? _I’m bloody sorry I did it,_ says he, _but I
          declare to God I thought the archbishop was inside._ He mightn’t like it, though. What?
          God, I’ll tell him anyhow. That was the great earl, the Fitzgerald Mor. Hot members they
          were all of them, the Geraldines. The horses he passed started nervously under their slack
          harness. He slapped a piebald haunch quivering near him and cried: —Woa, sonny! He turned
          to J. J. O’Molloy and asked: —Well, Jack. What is it? What’s the trouble? Wait awhile.
          Hold hard. With gaping mouth and head far back he stood still and, after an instant,
          sneezed loudly. —Chow! he said. Blast you! —The dust from those sacks, J. J. O’Molloy said
          politely. —No, Ned Lambert gasped, I caught a... cold night before... blast your soul...
          night before last... and there was a hell of a lot of draught... He held his handkerchief
          ready for the coming... —I was... Glasnevin this morning... poor little... what do you
          call him... Chow!... Mother of Moses! * * * Tom Rochford took the top disk from the pile
          he clasped against his claret waistcoat. —See? he said. Say it’s turn six. In here, see.
          Turn Now On. He slid it into the left slot for them. It shot down the groove, wobbled a
          while, ceased, ogling them: six. <reference to="The Four Courts">Lawyers of the past, haughty, pleading, beheld pass from
          the consolidated taxing office to Nisi Prius court Richie Goulding carrying the costbag of
          Goulding, Collis and Ward and heard rustling from the admiralty division of king’s bench
          to the court of appeal</reference> an elderly female with false teeth smiling incredulously and a
          black silk skirt of great amplitude. —See? he said. See now the last one I put in is over
          here: Turns Over. The impact. Leverage, see? He showed them the rising column of disks on
          the right. —Smart idea, Nosey Flynn said, snuffling. So a fellow coming in late can see
          what turn is on and what turns are over. —See? Tom Rochford said. He slid in a disk for
          himself: and watched it shoot, wobble, ogle, stop: four. Turn Now On. —I’ll see him now in
          the Ormond, Lenehan said, and sound him. One good turn deserves another. —Do, Tom Rochford
          said. Tell him I’m Boylan with impatience. —Goodnight, M’Coy said abruptly. When you two
          begin... Nosey Flynn stooped towards the lever, snuffling at it. —But how does it work
          here, Tommy? he asked. —Tooraloo, Lenehan said. See you later. </location>
     <location name="Crampton Court" lat="53.34456" lon="-6.26809"><p>He followed M’Coy out across
               the tiny square of Crampton court.</p>
          <said who="Lenehan">—He’s a hero, he said simply.</said>
          <said who="M'Coy">—I know, M’Coy said. The drain, you mean.</said>
          <said who="Lenehan">—Drain? Lenehan said. It was down a manhole.</said>
          <p>They passed Dan Lowry’s musichall where Marie Kendall, charming soubrette, smiled on
               them from a poster a dauby smile.</p>
     </location>
     <location name="Sycamore Street" lat="53.34375" lon="-6.26859"><p>Going down the path of
               Sycamore street beside the Empire musichall Lenehan showed M’Coy how the whole thing
               was. One of those manholes like a bloody gaspipe and there was the poor devil stuck
               down in it, half choked with sewer gas. Down went Tom Rochford anyhow, booky’s vest
               and all, with the rope round him. And be damned but he got the rope round the poor
               devil and the two were hauled up.</p>
          <said who="Lenehan">—The act of a hero, he said.</said>
     </location>
     <location name="Jervis Street" lat="53.34663" lon="-6.27200"><p>At the Dolphin they halted to
               allow the ambulance car to gallop past them for Jervis street.</p>
          <said who="Lenehan">—This way, he said, walking to the right. I want to pop into Lynam’s
               to see Sceptre’s starting price. What’s the time by your gold watch and
          chain?</said></location>

     <location name="Essex Street East" lat="53.34473" lon="-6.26759"><p>M’Coy peered into Marcus
               Tertius Moses’ sombre office,</p><p>then at O’Neill’s clock.</p>
          <said who="M'Coy">—After three, he said. Who’s riding her?</said>
          <said who="Lenehan">—O. Madden, Lenehan said. And a game filly she is.</said>
          <p>While he waited in Temple bar M’Coy dodged a banana peel with gentle pushes of his toe
               from the path to the gutter. Fellow might damn easy get a nasty fall there coming
               along tight in the dark.</p>
          <p>The gates of the drive opened wide to give egress to the viceregal cavalcade.</p>
          <said who="Lenehan">—Even money, Lenehan said returning. I knocked against Bantam Lyons in
               there going to back a bloody horse someone gave him that hasn’t an earthly. Through
               here.</said>
     </location>
     <location name="Merchant's Arch" lat="53.34546" lon="-6.26429"><p>They went up the steps and
               under Merchants’ arch. A darkbacked figure scanned books on the hawker’s cart.</p>
          <said who="Lenehan">—There he is, Lenehan said.</said>
          <said who="M'Coy">—Wonder what he’s buying, M’Coy said, glancing behind.</said>
          <said who="Lenehan"><allusion who="Edward Fitzball">—_Leopoldo or the Bloom is on the Rye,_</allusion> Lenehan said.</said>
          <said who="M'Coy">—He’s dead nuts on sales, M’Coy said. I was with him one day and he
               bought a book from an old one in Liffey street for two bob. There were fine plates in
               it worth double the money, the stars and the moon and comets with long tails.
               Astronomy it was about.</said>
          <p>Lenehan laughed.</p>
          <said who="Lenehan">—I’ll tell you a damn good one about comets’ tails, he said. Come over
               in the sun.</said>
          <p>They crossed to the metal bridge</p></location>
     <location name="Wellington Quay" lat="53.34471" lon="-6.26830">
          <p>and went along Wellington quay by the riverwall.</p>
          <p>Master Patrick Aloysius Dignam came out of Mangan’s, late Fehrenbach’s, carrying a
               pound and a half of porksteaks.</p>
          <said who="Lenehan">—There was a long spread out at <reference to="Catholicism">Glencree reformatory</reference>, Lenehan said
               eagerly. The annual dinner, you know. Boiled shirt affair. The lord mayor was there,
               Val Dillon it was, and <person who="Charles Cameron">sir Charles Cameron</person> and Dan Dawson spoke and there was music.
               Bartell d’Arcy sang and Benjamin Dollard...</said>
          <said who="M'Coy">—I know, M’Coy broke in. My missus sang there once.</said>
          <said who="Lenehan">—Did she? Lenehan said.</said>
          <p>A card _Unfurnished Apartments_ reappeared on the windowsash of number 7 Eccles
               street.</p>
          <p>He checked his tale a moment but broke out in a wheezy laugh.</p></location>

     <location name="42 Camden Street Lower" lat="53.33357" lon="-6.26640"><said who="Lenehan">—But
               wait till I tell you, he said. Delahunt of Camden street had the catering and yours
               truly was chief bottlewasher. Bloom and the wife were there. Lashings of stuff we put
               up: port wine and sherry and curacoa to which we did ample justice. Fast and furious
               it was. After liquids came solids. Cold joints galore and mince pies...</said>
          <said who="M'Coy">—I know, M’Coy said. The year the missus was there...</said>
          <p>Lenehan linked his arm warmly.</p>
          <said who="Lenehan">—But wait till I tell you, he said. We had a midnight lunch too after
               all the jollification and when we sallied forth it was blue o’clock the morning after
               the night before. Coming home it was a gorgeous winter’s night on the Featherbed
               Mountain. Bloom and Chris Callinan were on one side of the car and I was with the
               wife on the other. We started singing glees and duets: <allusion who="Michael William Balfe">_Lo, the early beam of
               morning_</allusion>. She was well primed with a good load of Delahunt’s port under her
               bellyband. Every jolt the bloody car gave I had her bumping up against me. Hell’s
               delights! She has a fine pair, God bless her. Like that.</said>
          <p>He held his caved hands a <allusion to="Bible">cubit</allusion> from him, frowning:</p>
          <said who="Lenehan">—I was tucking the rug under her and settling her boa all the time.
               Know what I mean?</said>
          <p>His hands moulded ample curves of air. He shut his eyes tight in delight, his body
               shrinking, and blew a sweet chirp from his lips. </p>
          <said who="Lenehan">—The lad stood to attention anyhow, he said with a sigh. She’s a gamey
               mare and no mistake. Bloom was pointing out all the stars and the comets in the
               heavens to Chris Callinan and the jarvey: the great bear and Hercules and the dragon,
               and the whole jingbang lot. But, by God, I was lost, so to speak, in the milky way.
               He knows them all, faith. At last she spotted a weeny weeshy one miles away. _And
               what star is that, Poldy?_ says she. By God, she had Bloom cornered. _That one, is
               it?_ says Chris Callinan, _sure that’s only what you might call a pinprick._ By God,
               he wasn’t far wide of the mark.</said>
          <p>Lenehan stopped and leaned on the riverwall, panting with soft laughter.</p>
          <said who="Lenehan">—I’m weak, he gasped.</said>
          <p>M’Coy’s white face smiled about it at instants and grew grave. Lenehan walked on again.
               He lifted his yachtingcap and scratched his hindhead rapidly. He glanced sideways in
               the sunlight at M’Coy.</p>
          <said who="M'Coy">—He’s a cultured allroundman, Bloom is, he said seriously. He’s not one
               of your common or garden... you know... There’s a touch of the artist about old
               Bloom.</said> * * * <p>Mr Bloom turned over idly pages of <person who="Maria Monk">_The Awful Disclosures of
               Maria Monk_</person>, then of <allusion who="Aristotle">Aristotle’s _Masterpiece._</allusion> Crooked botched print. Plates:
               infants cuddled in a ball in bloodred wombs like livers of slaughtered cows. Lots of
               them like that at this moment all over the world. All butting with their skulls to
               get out of it. Child born every minute somewhere. Mrs Purefoy.</p>
          <p>He laid both books aside and glanced at the third: <allusion who="Sacher-Masoch">_Tales of the Ghetto_ by Leopold von
               Sacher Masoch</allusion></p>. <said who="Leopold Bloom">—That I had, he said, pushing it
               by.</said>
          <p>The shopman let two volumes fall on the counter.</p>
          <said who="shopman">—Them are two good ones, he said. </said>
          <p>Onions of his breath came across the counter out of his ruined mouth. He bent to make a
               bundle of the other books, hugged them against his unbuttoned waistcoat and bore them
               off behind the dingy curtain.</p>
          <p>On O’Connell bridge many persons observed the grave deportment and gay apparel of Mr
               Denis J Maginni, professor of dancing &amp;c. </p>
          <p>Mr Bloom, alone, looked at the titles. <allusion who="James Lovebirch">_Fair Tyrants_ by James Lovebirch</allusion>. Know the kind
               that is. Had it? Yes. </p>
          <p>He opened it. Thought so. </p>
          <p>A woman’s voice behind the dingy curtain. Listen: the man. </p>
          <p>No: she wouldn’t like that much. Got her it once. </p>
          <p>He read the other title: _Sweets of Sin_. More in her line. Let us see. </p>
          <p>He read where his finger opened. </p>
          <said who="Sweets of Sin">_—All the dollarbills her husband gave her were spent in the
               stores on wondrous gowns and costliest frillies. For him! For Raoul!_ </said>
          <p>Yes. This. Here. Try. </p>
          <said who="Sweets of Sin">—_Her mouth glued on his in a luscious voluptuous kiss while his
               hands felt for the opulent curves inside her déshabillé._ </said>
          <p>Yes. Take this. The end. </p>
          <said who="Sweets of Sin">—You are late, he spoke hoarsely, eying her with a suspicious
               glare. </said>
          <p>The beautiful woman threw off her sabletrimmed wrap, displaying her queenly shoulders
               and heaving embonpoint. An imperceptible smile played round her perfect lips as she
               turned to him calmly. </p>
          <p>Mr Bloom read again: _The beautiful woman._ </p>
          <p>Warmth showered gently over him, cowing his flesh. Flesh yielded amply amid rumpled
               clothes: whites of eyes swooning up. His nostrils arched themselves for prey. Melting
               breast ointments (_for him! For Raoul!_). Armpits’ oniony sweat. Fishgluey slime
               (_her heaving embonpoint!_). Feel! Press! Crished! Sulphur dung of lions! </p>
          <p>Young! Young! </p>
          <p>An elderly female, no more young, left the building of the courts of chancery, king’s
               bench, exchequer and common pleas, having heard in the lord chancellor’s court the
               case in lunacy of Potterton, in the admiralty division the summons, exparte motion,
               of the owners of the Lady Cairns versus the owners of the barque Mona, in the court
               of appeal reservation of judgment in the case of Harvey versus the Ocean Accident and
               <reference to="The Four Courts">Guarantee Corporation.</reference> </p>
          <p>Phlegmy coughs shook the air of the bookshop, bulging out the dingy curtains. The
               shopman’s uncombed grey head came out and his unshaven reddened face, coughing. He
               raked his throat rudely, puked phlegm on the floor. He put his boot on what he had
               spat, wiping his sole along it, and bent, showing a rawskinned crown, scantily
               haired. </p>
          <p>Mr Bloom beheld it. </p>
          <p>Mastering his troubled breath, he said: </p>
          <said who="Leopold Bloom">—I’ll take this one. </said>
          <said who="Shopman">The shopman lifted eyes bleared with old rheum. —_Sweets of Sin,_ he
               said, tapping on it. That’s a good one. </said> * * * </location>

     <location name="25 Bachelor's Walk" lat="53.34685" lon="-6.26215"><p>The lacquey by the door of
               Dillon’s auctionrooms shook his handbell twice again and viewed himself in the
               chalked mirror of the cabinet.</p>
          <p>Dilly Dedalus, loitering by the curbstone, heard the beats of the bell, the cries of
               the auctioneer within. Four and nine. Those lovely curtains. Five shillings. Cosy
               curtains. Selling new at two guineas. Any advance on five shillings? Going for five
               shillings.</p>
          <p>The lacquey lifted his handbell and shook it: <said who="Lacquey">—Barang!</said></p>
          <p>Bang of the lastlap bell spurred the halfmile wheelmen to their sprint. J. A. Jackson,
               W. E. Wylie, A. Munro and H. T. Gahan, their stretched necks wagging, negotiated the
               curve by the College library.</p>
          <p>Mr Dedalus, tugging a long moustache, came round from Williams’s row. He halted near
               his daughter. <said who="Dilly">—It’s time for you, she said.</said>
               <said who="Mr. Dedalus">—Stand up straight for the love of the lord Jesus, Mr Dedalus
                    said. Are</said> you trying to imitate your uncle John, the cornetplayer, head
               upon shoulder? Melancholy God!</p>
          <p>Dilly shrugged her shoulders. Mr Dedalus placed his hands on them and held them back.
                    <said who="Mr. Dedalus">—Stand up straight, girl, he said. You’ll get curvature
                    of the spine.</said> Do you know what you look like?</p>
          <p>He let his head sink suddenly down and forward, hunching his shoulders and dropping his
               underjaw. <said who="Dilly">—Give it up, father, Dilly said. All the people are
                    looking at you.</said></p>
          <p>Mr Dedalus drew himself upright and tugged again at his moustache.</p>
          <said who="Dilly">—Did you get any money? Dilly asked.</said>
          <said who="Mr. Dedalus">—Where would I get money? Mr Dedalus said. There is no-one in
               Dublin</said> would lend me fourpence. <said who="Dilly">—You got some, Dilly said,
               looking in his eyes.</said>
          <said who="Mr. Dedalus">—How do you know that? Mr Dedalus asked, his tongue in his
               cheek.</said>
          <p>Mr Kernan, pleased with the order he had booked, walked boldly along James’s
               street.</p>
          <said who="Dilly">—I know you did, Dilly answered. Were you in the Scotch house
               now?</said>
          <said who="Mr. Dedalus">—I was not, then, Mr Dedalus said, smiling. Was it the little nuns
               taught you to be so saucy? Here.</said>
          <p>He handed her a shilling.</p>
          <said who="Mr. Dedalus">—See if you can do anything with that, he said.</said>
          <said who="Dilly">—I suppose you got five, Dilly said. Give me more than that.</said>
          <said who="Mr. Dedalus">—Wait awhile, Mr Dedalus said threateningly. You’re like the rest
               of them, are you? An insolent pack of little bitches since your poor mother died. But
               wait awhile. You’ll all get a short shrift and a long day from me. Low blackguardism!
               I’m going to get rid of you. Wouldn’t care if I was stretched out stiff. He’s dead.
               The man upstairs is dead.</said>
          <p>He left her and walked on. Dilly followed quickly and pulled his coat.</p>
          <said who="Mr. Dedalus">—Well, what is it? he said, stopping.</said>
          <p>The lacquey rang his bell behind their backs.</p>
          <said who="Lacquey">—Barang!</said>
          <said who="Mr. Dedalus">—Curse your bloody blatant soul, Mr Dedalus cried, turning on
               him.</said>
          <p>The lacquey, aware of comment, shook the lolling clapper of his bell but feebly:</p>
          <said who="Lacquey">—Bang!</said>
          <p>Mr Dedalus stared at him.</p>
          <said who="Mr. Dedalus">—Watch him, he said. It’s instructive. I wonder will he allow us
               to talk.</said>
          <said who="Dilly">—You got more than that, father, Dilly said.</said>
          <said who="Mr. Dedalus">—I’m going to show you a little trick, Mr Dedalus said. I’ll leave
               you all where <reference to="Christianity">Jesus left the jews.</reference> Look, there’s all I have. I got two shillings from
               Jack Power and I spent twopence for a shave for the funeral.</said>
          <p>He drew forth a handful of copper coins, nervously.</p>
          <said who="Dilly">—Can’t you look for some money somewhere? Dilly said.</said>
          <p>Mr Dedalus thought and nodded.</p>
          <said who="Mr. Dedalus">—I will, he said gravely. I looked all along the gutter in
               O’Connell street. I’ll try this one now.</said>
          <said who="Dilly">—You’re very funny, Dilly said, grinning.</said>
          <said who="Mr. Dedalus">—Here, Mr Dedalus said, handing her two pennies. Get a glass of
               milk for yourself and a bun or a something. I’ll be home shortly.</said>
          <p>He put the other coins in his pocket and started to walk on.</p>
          <p>The viceregal cavalcade passed, greeted by obsequious policemen, out of Parkgate.</p>
          <said who="Dilly">—I’m sure you have another shilling, Dilly said.</said>
          <p>The lacquey banged loudly.</p>
          <p>Mr Dedalus amid the din walked off, murmuring to himself with a pursing mincing mouth
               gently:</p>
          <said who="Mr. Dedalus">—The little nuns! Nice little things! O, sure they wouldn’t do
               anything! O, sure they wouldn’t really! Is it <reference to="St. Monica's Widow's Almshouse">little sister Monica</reference>!</said> * * * </location>
     <location name="Dame Street" lat="53.34367" lon="-6.26841"><p>From the sundial towards James’s
               gate walked Mr Kernan, pleased with the order he had booked for Pulbrook Robertson,
               boldly along James’s street,</p><p> past Shackleton’s offices.</p><p>Got round him
               all right. How do you do, Mr Crimmins? First rate, sir. I was afraid you might be up
               in your other establishment in Pimlico. How are things going? Just keeping alive.
               Lovely weather we’re having. Yes, indeed. Good for the country. Those farmers are
               always grumbling. I’ll just take a thimbleful of your best gin, Mr Crimmins. A small
               gin, sir. Yes, sir. Terrible affair that _General Slocum_ explosion. Terrible,
               terrible! A thousand casualties. And heartrending scenes. Men trampling down women
               and children. Most brutal thing. What do they say was the cause? Spontaneous
               combustion. Most scandalous revelation. Not a single lifeboat would float and the
               firehose all burst. What I can’t understand is how the inspectors ever allowed a boat
               like that... Now, you’re talking straight, Mr Crimmins. You know why? Palm oil. Is
               that a fact? Without a doubt. Well now, look at that. And America they say is the
               land of the free. I thought we were bad here.</p>
          <p>I smiled at him. _America,_ I said quietly, just like that. _What is it? The sweepings
               of every country including our own. Isn’t that true?_ That’s a fact.</p>
          <p>Graft, my dear sir. Well, of course, where there’s money going there’s always someone
               to pick it up.</p>
          <p>Saw him looking at my frockcoat. Dress does it. Nothing like a dressy appearance. Bowls
               them over.</p>
          <said who="Father Cowley">—Hello, Simon, Father Cowley said. How are things?</said>
          <said who="Mr. Dedalus">—Hello, Bob, old man, Mr Dedalus answered, stopping.</said><p>Mr
               Kernan halted and preened himself before the sloping mirror of Peter Kennedy,
               hairdresser. Stylish coat, beyond a doubt.</p><p>Scott of Dawson street. Well worth
               the half sovereign I gave Neary for it. Never built under three guineas. Fits me down
               to the ground. Some Kildare street club toff had it probably.</p><p>John Mulligan,
               the manager of the Hibernian bank, gave me a very sharp eye yesterday </p></location>
     <location name="O'Connell Bridge" lat="53.34681" lon="-6.26047"><p>on Carlisle bridge as if he
               remembered me.</p>
          <p>Aham! Must dress the character for those fellows. Knight of the road. Gentleman. And
               now, Mr Crimmins, may we have the honour of your custom again, sir. <allusion who="Bishop Berkeley">The cup that
               cheers but not inebriates</allusion>, as the old saying has it.</p>
          <p>North wall and sir John Rogerson’s quay, with hulls and anchorchains, sailing westward,
               sailed by a skiff, a crumpled throwaway, rocked on the ferrywash, Elijah is
               coming.</p>
          <p>Mr Kernan glanced in farewell at his image. High colour, of course. Grizzled moustache.
               Returned Indian officer. Bravely he bore his stumpy body forward on spatted feet,
               squaring his shoulders. Is that Ned Lambert’s brother over the way, Sam? What? Yes.
               He’s as like it as damn it. No. The windscreen of that motorcar in the sun there.
               Just a flash like that. Damn like him.</p>
          <p>Aham! Hot spirit of juniper juice warmed his vitals and his breath. Good drop of gin,
               that was. His frocktails winked in bright sunshine to his fat strut.</p>
          <p><person who="Robert Emmet">Down there Emmet was hanged, drawn and quartered</person>. Greasy black rope. Dogs licking the
               blood off the street when the lord lieutenant’s wife drove by in her noddy.</p>
          <p>Bad times those were. Well, well. Over and done with. Great topers too. Fourbottle
               men.</p>
          <p>Let me see. <reference to="Catholicism">Is he buried in saint Michan’s? Or no, there was a midnight burial in
               Glasnevin.</reference> Corpse brought in through a secret door in the wall. Dignam is there now.
               Went out in a puff. Well, well. Better turn down here. Make a detour.</p></location>

     <location name="Watling Street" lat="53.34315" lon="-6.28995"><p><reference to="Guinness">Mr Kernan turned and walked
               down the slope of Watling street by the corner of Guinness’s visitors’ waitingroom.</reference>
               Outside the Dublin Distillers Company’s stores an outside car without fare or jarvey
               stood, the reins knotted to the wheel. Damn dangerous thing. Some Tipperary bosthoon
               endangering the lives of the citizens. Runaway horse.</p></location>

     <location name="27 Bachelor's Walk" lat="53.34694" lon="-6.26195"><p>Denis Breen with his
               tomes, weary of having waited an hour in John Henry Menton’s office, led his wife
               over O’Connell bridge,</p>
     </location>
     <location name="31 Dame Street" lat="53.34360" lon="-6.26493"><p>bound for the office of Messrs
               Collis and Ward.</p>
     </location>
     <location name="Island Street" lat="53.34474" lon="-6.28541"><p>Mr Kernan approached Island
               street.</p>
          <p>Times of the troubles. Must ask Ned Lambert to lend me those reminiscences of <person who="Jonah Barrington">sir Jonah
               Barrington.</person> When you look back on it all now in a kind of retrospective arrangement.
               Gaming at Daly’s. No cardsharping then. One of those fellows got his hand nailed to
               the table by a dagger. Somewhere here <person who="Lord Edward Fitzgerald">lord Edward Fitzgerald escaped from major Sirr.
               Stables behind Moira house.</person></p>
          <p>Damn good gin that was.</p>
          <p>Fine dashing young nobleman. Good stock, of course. That ruffian, that sham squire,
               with his violet gloves gave him away. Course they were on the wrong side. <allusion who="John Kells Ingram">They rose
               in dark and evil days. Fine poem that is: Ingram.</allusion> They were gentlemen. Ben Dollard
               does sing that ballad touchingly. Masterly rendition.</p>
          <p><allusion to="The Croppy Boy">_At the siege of Ross did my father fall._</allusion></p></location>

     <location name="Watling Street" lat="53.34315" lon="-6.28995"><p>A cavalcade in easy trot along
               Pembroke quay passed, outriders leaping, leaping in their, in their saddles.
               Frockcoats. Cream sunshades.</p>
          <p>Mr Kernan hurried forward, blowing pursily.</p>
          <p>His Excellency! Too bad! Just missed that by a hair. Damn it! What a pity!</p>
          <p>* * *</p>
          <p> Stephen Dedalus watched through the webbed window the lapidary’s fingers prove a
               timedulled chain. Dust webbed the window and the showtrays. Dust darkened the toiling
               fingers with their vulture nails. Dust slept on dull coils of bronze and silver,
               lozenges of cinnabar, on rubies, leprous and winedark stones.</p>
          <p><allusion who="John Milton">Born all in the dark wormy earth, cold specks of fire, evil, lights shining in the
               darkness. Where fallen archangels flung the stars of their brows. Muddy swinesnouts,
               hands, root and root, gripe and wrest them.</allusion></p>
          <p>She dances in a foul gloom where gum bums with garlic. A sailorman, rustbearded, sips
               from a beaker rum and eyes her. A long and seafed silent rut. She dances, capers,
               wagging her sowish haunches and her hips, on her gross belly flapping a ruby egg.</p>
          <p>Old Russell with a smeared shammy rag burnished again his gem, turned it and held it at
               the point of his Moses’ beard. Grandfather ape gloating on a stolen hoard.</p>
          <p>And you who wrest old images from the burial earth? The brainsick words of sophists:
               Antisthenes. A lore of drugs. <reference to="Orientalism">Orient and immortal</reference> wheat standing from everlasting to
               everlasting.</p>
          <p>Two old women fresh from their whiff of the briny trudged through Irishtown along
               London bridge road, one with a sanded tired umbrella, one with a midwife’s bag in
               which eleven cockles rolled.</p></location>

     <location name="Fleet Street" lat="53.34528" lon="-6.26184"><p>The whirr of flapping leathern
               bands and hum of dynamos from the powerhouse urged Stephen to be on. Beingless
               beings. Stop! <allusion who="James Lane Allen">Throb always without you and the throb always within.</allusion> Your heart you
               sing of. I between them. Where? <allusion who="Matthew Arnold">Between two roaring worlds where they swirl</allusion>, I.
               Shatter them, one and both. But stun myself too in the blow. Shatter me you who can.
               Bawd and butcher were the words. I say! Not yet awhile. A look around.</p>
     </location>
     <location name="Bedford Row" lat="53.34551" lon="-6.26321"><p>Yes, quite true. Very large and
               wonderful and keeps famous time. <allusion who="Shakespeare">You say right,</allusion> sir. A Monday morning, ’twas so,
               indeed.</p><p>Stephen went down Bedford row, the handle of the ash clacking against
               his shoulderblade. In Clohissey’s window a faded 1860 print of <reference to="boxing">Heenan boxing Sayers</reference>
               held his eye. Staring backers with square hats stood round the roped prizering. The
               heavyweights in tight loincloths proposed gently each to other his bulbous fists. And
               they are throbbing: heroes’ hearts.</p>
          <p>He turned and halted by the slanted bookcart.</p>
          <said who="The Huckster"> —Twopence each, the huckster said. Four for sixpence.</said>
          <p>Tattered pages. _The Irish Beekeeper. <allusion to="French of Abbe Mounin">Life and Miracles of the Curé of Ars.</allusion> Pocket
               Guide to Killarney._</p>
          <p>I might find here one of my pawned schoolprizes. _Stephano Dedalo, alumno optimo,
               palmam ferenti.</p>
          <p>Father Conmee, having read his little hours, walked through the hamlet of Donnycarney,
               murmuring vespers.</p>
          <p>Binding too good probably. What is this? <reference to="Bible">Eighth and ninth book of Moses.</reference> Secret of all
               secrets. <reference to="Judaism">Seal of King David.</reference> Thumbed pages: read and read. Who has passed here before
               me? How to soften chapped hands. Recipe for white wine vinegar. How to win a woman’s
               love. For me this. Say the following talisman three times with hands folded:</p>
          <said who="Father Conmee">—<reference to="Bible">_Se el yilo nebrakada femininum! Amor me solo! Sanktus!
               Amen._</reference></said>
          <p>Who wrote this? Charms and invocations of the most blessed abbot Peter Salanka to all
               true believers divulged. As good as any other abbot’s charms, as mumbling Joachim’s.
               Down, baldynoddle, or we’ll wool your wool.</p>
          <said who="Father Conmee">—What are you doing here, Stephen?</said>
          <p>Dilly’s high shoulders and shabby dress.</p>
          <p>Shut the book quick. Don’t let see.</p>
          <said who="Stephen Dedalus">—What are you doing? Stephen said.</said>
          <p>A Stuart face of nonesuch Charles, lank locks falling at its sides. It glowed as she
               crouched feeding the fire with broken boots. I told her of Paris. Late lieabed under
               a quilt of old overcoats, fingering a pinchbeck bracelet, Dan Kelly’s token.
               _Nebrakada femininum._</p>
          <said who="Stephen Dedalus">—What have you there? Stephen asked.</said>
          <said who="Dilly">—I bought it from the other cart for a penny, Dilly said, laughing
               nervously. Is it any good?</said>
          <p>My eyes they say she has. Do others see me so? Quick, far and daring. Shadow of my
               mind.</p>
          <p>He took the coverless book from her hand. Chardenal’s French primer.</p>
          <said who="Stephen Dedalus">—What did you buy that for? he asked. To learn French?</said>
          <p>She nodded, reddening and closing tight her lips.</p>
          <p>Show no surprise. Quite natural.</p>
          <said who="Stephen Dedalus">—Here, Stephen said. It’s all right. Mind Maggy doesn’t pawn
               it on you. I suppose all my books are gone.</said>
          <said who="Dilly">—Some, Dilly said. We had to.</said>
          <p>She is drowning. Agenbite. Save her. Agenbite. All against us. She will drown me with
               her, eyes and hair. Lank coils of seaweed hair around me, my heart, my soul. Salt
               green death.</p>
          <p>We.</p>
          <p>Agenbite of inwit. Inwit’s agenbite.</p>
          <p>Misery! Misery!</p>
          <p>* * *</p>
     </location>

     <location name="Ormond Quay Lower" lat="53.34542" lon="-6.26828"><said who="Father Cowley">—Hello, Simon, Father Cowley said. How are things? </said><said who="Mr. Dedalus">—Hello, Bob, old man, Mr Dedalus answered, stopping. </said><p>They clasped hands
               loudly outside Reddy and Daughter’s. Father Cowley brushed his moustache often
               downward with a scooping hand.</p>
          <said who="Mr. Dedalus">—What’s the best news? Mr Dedalus said. </said><said who="Father Cowley">—Why then not much, Father Cowley said. I’m barricaded up, Simon,
               with two men prowling around the house trying to effect an entrance. </said><said who="Mr. Dedalus">—Jolly, Mr Dedalus said. Who is it? </said><said who="Father Cowley">—O, Father Cowley said. A certain gombeen man of our
               acquaintance. </said><said who="Mr. Dedalus">—With a broken back, is it? Mr Dedalus
               asked. </said><said who="Father Cowley">—The same, Simon, Father Cowley answered.
               Reuben of that ilk. I’m just waiting for Ben Dollard. He’s going to say a word to
               long John to get him to take those two men off. All I want is a little time.
               </said><p>He looked with vague hope up and down the quay, a big apple bulging in his
               neck.</p>
          <said who="Mr. Dedalus">—I know, Mr Dedalus said, nodding. Poor old bockedy Ben! He’s
               always doing a good turn for someone. Hold hard! </said><p>He put on his glasses and
               gazed towards the metal bridge an instant. </p>
          <said who="Mr. Dedalus">—There he is, by God, he said, arse and pockets. </said><p>Ben
               Dollard’s loose blue cutaway and square hat above large slops crossed the quay in
               full gait from the metal bridge. He came towards them at an amble, scratching
               actively behind his coattails. </p>
          <p>As he came near Mr Dedalus greeted: </p>
          <said who="Mr. Dedalus">—Hold that fellow with the bad trousers. </said><said who="Ben Dollard">—Hold him now, Ben Dollard said. </said><p>Mr Dedalus eyed with
               cold wandering scorn various points of Ben Dollard’s figure. Then, turning to Father
               Cowley with a nod, he muttered sneeringly:</p>
          <said who="Mr. Dedalus">—That’s a pretty garment, isn’t it, for a summer’s day?
               </said><said who="Ben Dollard">—Why, God eternally curse your soul, Ben Dollard
               growled furiously, I threw out more clothes in my time than you ever saw.
               </said><p>He stood beside them beaming, on them first and on his roomy clothes from
               points of which Mr Dedalus flicked fluff, saying:</p>
          <said who="Mr. Dedalus">—They were made for a man in his health, Ben, anyhow. </said><said who="Ben Dollard">—Bad luck to the jewman that made them, Ben Dollard said. Thanks be
               to God he’s not paid yet. </said><said who="Father Cowley">—And how is that _basso
               profondo_, Benjamin? Father Cowley asked. </said><p>Cashel Boyle O’Connor Fitzmaurice
               Tisdall Farrell, murmuring, glassyeyed, strode past the Kildare street club. </p>
          <p>Ben Dollard frowned and, making suddenly a chanter’s mouth, gave forth a deep note.</p>
          <said who="Ben Dollard">—Aw! he said. </said><said who="Mr. Dedalus">—That’s the style, Mr
               Dedalus said, nodding to its drone. </said><said who="Ben Dollard">—What about that?
               Ben Dollard said. Not too dusty? What? </said><p>He turned to both.</p>
          <said who="Father Cowley">—That’ll do, Father Cowley said, nodding also.</said>
     </location>
     <location name="Mary's Abbey" lat="53.34675" lon="-6.27069"><p>The reverend Hugh C. Love walked
               from the old chapterhouse of <reference to="St. Mary's Abbey">saint Mary’s abbey </reference>past James and Charles Kennedy’s,
               rectifiers, attended by Geraldines tall and personable,</p></location>
     <location name="Christchurch Place" lat="53.34277" lon="-6.27167">
          <p>towards the Tholsel beyond the ford of hurdles.</p>
          <p>Ben Dollard with a heavy list towards the shopfronts led them forward, his joyful
               fingers in the air.</p>
          <said who="Ben Dollard">—Come along with me to the subsheriff’s office, he said. I want to
               show you the new beauty Rock has for a bailiff. He’s a cross between <person who="Matabele">Lobengula</person> and
               <person who="James Walshe">Lynchehaun</person>. He’s well worth seeing, mind you.</said></location>
     <location name="Dame Street" lat="53.34367" lon="-6.26841"><said who="Ben Dollard">Come along.
               I saw John Henry Menton casually in the Bodega just now and it will cost me a fall if
               I don’t... Wait awhile... We’re on the right lay, Bob, believe you me.</said>
          <said who="Father Cowley">—For a few days tell him, Father Cowley said anxiously.</said>
          <p>Ben Dollard halted and stared, his loud orifice open, a dangling button of his coat
               wagging brightbacked from its thread as he wiped away the heavy shraums that clogged
               his eyes to hear aright.</p>
          <said who="Ben Dollard">—What few days? he boomed. Hasn’t your landlord distrained for
               rent? </said>
          <said who="Father Cowley">—He has, Father Cowley said. </said>
          <said who="Ben Dollard">—Then our friend’s writ is not worth the paper it’s printed on,
               Ben Dollard said. The landlord has the prior claim. I gave him all the particulars.
               29 Windsor avenue. Love is the name? </said><said who="Father Cowley">—That’s right,
               Father Cowley said. The reverend Mr Love. He’s a minister in the country somewhere.
               But are you sure of that? </said>
          <said who="Ben Dollard">—You can tell Barabbas from me, Ben Dollard said, that he can put
               that writ where Jacko put the nuts. </said>
          <p>He led Father Cowley boldly forward, linked to his bulk. </p>
          <said who="Mr. Dedalus">—Filberts I believe they were, Mr Dedalus said, as he dropped his
               glasses on his coatfront, following them. </said> * * *</location>


     <location name="Lord Edward Street" lat="53.34334" lon="-6.27031"><said who="Martin Cunningham">—The youngster will be all right, Martin Cunningham said, as they passed out of the
               Castleyard gate.</said>
          <p>The policeman touched his forehead. </p>
          <said who="Martin Cunningham">—God bless you, Martin Cunningham said, cheerily. </said>
          <p>He signed to the waiting jarvey who chucked at the reins and set on towards Lord Edward
               street. </p>
          <p>Bronze by gold, Miss Kennedy’s head by Miss Douce’s head, appeared above the crossblind
               of the Ormond hotel. </p>
          <said who="Martin Cunningham">—Yes, Martin Cunningham said, fingering his beard. I wrote
               to Father Conmee and laid the whole case before him. </said>
          <said who="Mr. Power">—You could try our friend, Mr Power suggested backward. </said>
          <said who="Martin Cunningham">—Boyd? Martin Cunningham said shortly. <reference to="Christianity">Touch me not.</reference></said>
     </location>
     <location name="Cork Hill" lat="53.34359" lon="-6.26911"><p>John Wyse Nolan, lagging behind,
               reading the list, came after them quickly down Cork hill.</p>
          <p>On the steps of the City hall Councillor Nannetti, descending, hailed Alderman Cowley
               and Councillor Abraham Lyon ascending.</p>
          <p>The castle car wheeled empty into upper Exchange street.</p>
     </location>
     <location name="Parliament Street" lat="53.34380" lon="-6.27017"><said who="John Wyse Nolan">—Look here, Martin, John Wyse Nolan said, overtaking them at the _Mail_ office. I
               see Bloom put his name down for five shillings.</said>
          <said who="Martin Cunningham">—Quite right, Martin Cunningham said, taking the list. And
               put down the five shillings too.</said>
          <said who="Mr. Power">—Without a second word either, Mr Power said. </said>
          <said who="Martin Cunningham">—Strange but true, Martin Cunningham added. </said>
          <p>John Wyse Nolan opened wide eyes. </p>
          <said who="John Wyse Nolan">—I’ll say there is much kindness in the jew, he quoted,
               elegantly. </said>
          <p>They went down Parliament street.</p>
          <said who="Mr. Power">—There’s Jimmy Henry, Mr Power said, just heading for Kavanagh’s.
               </said><said who="Martin Cunningham">—Righto, Martin Cunningham said. Here goes.
               </said><p>Outside _la Maison Claire_ Blazes Boylan waylaid Jack Mooney’s
               brother-in-law, humpy, tight, making for the liberties.</p>
          <p>John Wyse Nolan fell back with Mr Power, while Martin Cunningham took the elbow of a
               dapper little man in a shower of hail suit, who walked uncertainly,</p><p>with hasty
               steps past Micky Anderson’s watches. </p>
          <said who="John Wyse Nolan">—The assistant town clerk’s corns are giving him some trouble,
               John Wyse Nolan told Mr Power.</said>
          <p>They followed round the corner towards James Kavanagh’s winerooms. The empty castle car
               fronted them at rest in Essex gate. Martin Cunningham, speaking always, showed often
               the list at which Jimmy Henry did not glance.</p>
          <said who="John Wyse Nolan">—And long John Fanning is here too, John Wyse Nolan said, as
               large as life.</said>
          <p>The tall form of long John Fanning filled the doorway where he stood. </p>
          <said who="Martin Cunningham">—Good day, Mr Subsheriff, Martin Cunningham said, as all
               halted and greeted.</said>
          <p>Long John Fanning made no way for them. He removed his large <person who="Henry Clay">Henry Clay</person> decisively and
               his large fierce eyes scowled intelligently over all their faces.</p>
          <said who="Long John Fanning">—Are the <reference to="Roman senators">conscript fathers</reference> pursuing their peaceful
               deliberations? he said with rich acrid utterance to the assistant town clerk. </said>
          <p><allusion who="Giovanni Pietro Pinamonti">Hell open to christians</allusion> they were having, Jimmy Henry said pettishly, about their
               damned Irish language. Where was the marshal, he wanted to know, to keep order in the
               council chamber. And old Barlow the macebearer laid up with asthma, no mace on the
               table, nothing in order, no quorum even, and Hutchinson, the lord mayor, in Llandudno
               and little Lorcan Sherlock doing _locum tenens_ for him. Damned Irish language,
               language of our forefathers. </p>
          <p>Long John Fanning blew a plume of smoke from his lips. </p>
          <p>Martin Cunningham spoke by turns, twirling the peak of his beard, to the assistant town
               clerk and the subsheriff, while John Wyse Nolan held his peace.</p>
          <said who="Long John Fanning">—What Dignam was that? long John Fanning asked. </said>
          <p>Jimmy Henry made a grimace and lifted his left foot. </p>
          <said who="Jimmy Henry">—O, my corns! he said plaintively. Come upstairs for goodness’
               sake till I sit down somewhere. Uff! Ooo! Mind!</said>
          <p>Testily he made room for himself beside long John Fanning’s flank and passed in and up
               the stairs.</p>
          <said who="Martin Cunningham">—Come on up, Martin Cunningham said to the subsheriff. I
               don’t think you knew him or perhaps you did, though.</said>
          <p>With John Wyse Nolan Mr Power followed them in.</p>
          <said who="John Wyse Nolan">—Decent little soul he was, Mr Power said to the stalwart back
               of long John Fanning ascending towards long John Fanning in the mirror. </said>
          <said who="Martin Cunningham">—Rather lowsized. Dignam of Menton’s office that was, Martin
               Cunningham said.</said>
          <p>Long John Fanning could not remember him. </p>
          <p>Clatter of horsehoofs sounded from the air. </p>
          <said who="Martin Cunningham">—What’s that? Martin Cunningham said. </said>
          <p>All turned where they stood. John Wyse Nolan came down again. From the cool shadow of
               the doorway he saw the horses pass Parliament street, harness and glossy pasterns in
               sunlight shimmering. Gaily they went past before his cool unfriendly eyes, not
               quickly. In saddles of the leaders, leaping leaders, rode outriders.</p>
          <said who="Martin Cunningham">—What was it? Martin Cunningham asked, as they went on up
               the staircase.</said>
          <said who="John Wyse Nolan">—The lord lieutenantgeneral and general governor of Ireland,
               John Wyse Nolan answered from the stairfoot.</said> * * * <p>As they trod across the
               thick carpet Buck Mulligan whispered behind his Panama to Haines:</p>
          <said who="Buck Mulligan">—Parnell’s brother. There in the corner. </said>
          <p>They chose a small table near the window, opposite a longfaced man whose beard and gaze
               hung intently down on a chessboard.</p>
          <said who="Haines">—Is that he? Haines asked, twisting round in his seat.</said>
          <said who="Buck Mulligan">—Yes, Mulligan said. That’s John Howard, his brother, our city
               marshal.</said>
          <p>John Howard Parnell translated a white bishop quietly and his grey claw went up again
               to his forehead whereat it rested. An instant after, under its screen, his eyes
               looked quickly, ghostbright, at his foe and fell once more upon a working corner.</p>
          <said who="Haines">—I’ll take a _mélange,_ Haines said to the waitress.</said>
          <said who="Buck Mulligan">—Two _mélanges,_ Buck Mulligan said. And bring us some scones
               and butter and some cakes as well.</said></location>

     <location name="33 Dame Street" lat="53.34353" lon="-6.26467"><p>When she had gone he said,
               laughing:</p>
          <said who="Buck Mulligan">—We call it D.B.C. because they have damn bad cakes. O, but you
               missed Dedalus on _Hamlet._</said>
          <p>Haines opened his newbought book. </p>
          <said who="Haines">—I’m sorry, he said. <allusion who="Shakespeare">Shakespeare is the happy huntingground of all
               minds that have lost their balance.</allusion></said></location>

     <location name="Nelson Street" lat="53.35699" lon="-6.26924"><p>The onelegged sailor growled at
               the area of 14 Nelson street:</p>
          <said who="onelegged sailor">—_England expects_... </said><p>Buck Mulligan’s primrose
               waistcoat shook gaily to his laughter.</p>
          <said who="Buck Mullign">—You should see him, he said, when his body loses its balance.
               Wandering Ængus I call him. </said><said who="Haines">—I am sure he has an _idée
               fixe,_ Haines said, pinching his chin thoughtfully with thumb and forefinger. Now I
               am speculating what it would be likely to be. Such persons always have.
               </said><p>Buck Mulligan bent across the table gravely.</p>
          <said who="Buck Mulligan">—They drove his wits astray, he said, by visions of hell. He
               will never capture the Attic note. <reference to="Swinburne">The note of Swinburne</reference>, of all poets, <reference to="Swinburne">the white
               death and the ruddy birth.</reference> That is his tragedy. He can never be a poet. The joy of
               creation... </said><said who="Haines">—Eternal punishment, Haines said, nodding
               curtly. I see. I tackled him this morning on belief. There was something on his mind,
               I saw. It’s rather interesting because <person who="Julius P. Pokorny">professor Pokorny of Vienna</person> makes an
               interesting point out of that. </said><p>Buck Mulligan’s watchful eyes saw the
               waitress come. He helped her to unload her tray.</p>
          <said who="Haines">—He can find no <reference to="Irish Mythology">trace of hell in ancient Irish myth</reference>, Haines said, amid
               the cheerful cups. The moral idea seems lacking, the sense of destiny, of
               retribution. Rather strange he should have just that fixed idea. Does he write
               anything for your movement? </said><p>He sank two lumps of sugar deftly longwise
               through the whipped cream. Buck Mulligan slit a steaming scone in two and plastered
               butter over its smoking pith. He bit off a soft piece hungrily.</p>
          <said who="Buck Mulligan">—Ten years, he said, chewing and laughing. He is going to write
               something in ten years. </said><said who="Haines">—Seems a long way off, Haines said,
               thoughtfully lifting his spoon. Still, I shouldn’t wonder if he did after all.
               </said><p>He tasted a spoonful from the creamy cone of his cup. </p>
          <said who="Haines">—This is real Irish cream I take it, he said with forbearance. I don’t
               want to be imposed on. </said><p>Elijah, skiff, light crumpled throwaway, sailed
               eastward by flanks of ships and trawlers, amid an archipelago of corks, beyond new
               Wapping street past Benson’s ferry, and by the threemasted schooner _Rosevean_ from
               Bridgwater with bricks.</p> * * *</location>


     <location name="60 Mount Street Lower" lat="53.33915" lon="-6.24726"><p>Almidano Artifoni
               walked past Holles street, past Sewell’s yard. Behind him Cashel Boyle O’Connor
               Fitzmaurice Tisdall Farrell, with stickumbrelladustcoat dangling,</p></location>
     <location name="Clare Street" lat="53.34101" lon="-6.25302"><p>shunned the lamp before Mr Law
               Smith’s house and, crossing, walked along Merrion square. Distantly behind him a
               blind stripling tapped his way by the wall of College park. Cashel Boyle O’Connor
               Fitzmaurice Tisdall</p></location>
     <location name="31 Merrion Square North" lat="53.33950" lon="-6.24816"><p>Farrell walked as far
               as Mr Lewis Werner’s cheerful windows, then turned and strode back along Merrion
               square, his stickumbrelladustcoat dangling.</p>
     </location>
     <location name="1 Merrion Square North" lat="53.34080" lon="-6.25171">At the corner of <person who="Oscar Wilde">Wilde’s</person>
          house he halted, frowned at Elijah’s name announced on the Metropolitan hall, frowned at
          the distant pleasance of duke’s lawn. His eyeglass flashed frowning in the sun. With
          ratsteeth bared he muttered: —_Coactus volui._ He strode on for Clare street, grinding his
          fierce word. As he strode past Mr Bloom’s dental windows the sway of his dustcoat brushed
          rudely from its angle a slender tapping cane and swept onwards, having buffeted a thewless
          body. The blind stripling turned his sickly face after the striding form. —God’s curse on
          you, he said sourly, whoever you are! You’re blinder nor I am, you bitch’s bastard! * * * </location>

     <location name="Wicklow Street" lat="53.34225" lon="-6.26147"><p>Opposite Ruggy O’Donohoe’s
               Master Patrick Aloysius Dignam, pawing the pound and a half of Mangan’s, late
               Fehrenbach’s, porksteaks he had been sent for, went along warm Wicklow street
               dawdling. It was too blooming dull sitting in the parlour with Mrs Stoer and Mrs
               Quigley and Mrs MacDowell and the blind down and they all at their sniffles and
               sipping sups of the superior tawny sherry uncle Barney brought from Tunney’s. And
               they eating crumbs of the cottage fruitcake, jawing the whole blooming time and
               sighing.</p>
          <p>After Wicklow lane the window of Madame Doyle, courtdress milliner, stopped him. He
               stood looking in at the two puckers stripped to their pelts and putting up their
               props. From the sidemirrors two mourning Masters Dignam gaped silently. <reference to="boxing">Myler Keogh,
               Dublin’s pet lamb, will meet sergeantmajor Bennett</reference>, the Portobello bruiser, for a
               purse of fifty sovereigns. Gob, that’d be a good pucking match to see. Myler Keogh,
               that’s the chap sparring out to him with the green sash. Two bar entrance, soldiers
               half price. I could easy do a bunk on ma. Master Dignam on his left turned as he
               turned. That’s me in mourning. When is it? May the twentysecond. Sure, the blooming
               thing is all over. He turned to the right and on his right Master Dignam turned, his
               cap awry, his collar sticking up. Buttoning it down, his chin lifted, he saw the
               image of Marie Kendall, charming soubrette, beside the two puckers. One of them mots
               that do be in the packets of fags Stoer smokes that his old fellow welted hell out of
               him for one time he found out.</p>
          <p>Master Dignam got his collar down and dawdled on. The best pucker going for strength
               was <person who="Robert Fitzsimmons">Fitzsimons</person>. One puck in the wind from that fellow would knock you into the middle
               of next week, man. But the best pucker for science was <person who="James John Corbett">Jem Corbet</person> before Fitzsimons
               knocked the stuffings out of him, dodging and all.</p>
          <p>In Grafton street Master Dignam saw a red flower in a toff’s mouth and a swell pair of
               kicks on him and he listening to what the drunk was telling him and grinning all the
               time.</p>
          <p>No Sandymount tram.</p>
          <p>Master Dignam walked along Nassau street, shifted the porksteaks to his other hand. His
               collar sprang up again and he tugged it down. The blooming stud was too small for the
               buttonhole of the shirt, blooming end to it. He met schoolboys with satchels. I’m not
               going tomorrow either, stay away till Monday. He met other schoolboys. Do they notice
               I’m in mourning? Uncle Barney said he’d get it into the paper tonight. Then they’ll
               all see it in the paper and read my name printed and pa’s name.</p>
          <p> His face got all grey instead of being red like it was and there was a fly walking
               over it up to his eye. The scrunch that was when they were screwing the screws into
               the coffin: and the bumps when they were bringing it downstairs.</p>
          <p>Pa was inside it and ma crying in the parlour and uncle Barney telling the men how to
               get it round the bend. A big coffin it was, and high and heavylooking. How was
               that?</p></location>
     <location name="Bridge Street" lat="53.34110" lon="-6.23171"><p>The last night pa was boosed he
               was standing on the landing there bawling out for his boots to go out to Tunney’s for
               to boose more and he looked butty and short in his shirt. Never see him again. Death,
               that is. Pa is dead. My father is dead. He told me to be a good son to ma. I couldn’t
               hear the other things he said but I saw his tongue and his teeth trying to say it
               better. Poor pa. That was Mr Dignam, my father. I hope he’s in purgatory now because
               he went to confession to Father Conroy on Saturday night.</p> * * *</location>


     <location name="Wicklow Street" lat="53.34225" lon="-6.26147"><p>William Humble, earl of
               Dudley, and lady Dudley, accompanied by lieutenantcolonel Heseltine, drove out after
               luncheon from the viceregal lodge. In the following carriage were the honourable Mrs
               Paget, Miss de Courcy and the honourable Gerald Ward A. D. C. in
          attendance.</p></location>

     <location name="Sean Heuston Bridge" lat="53.34695" lon="-6.29313"><p>The cavalcade passed out
               by the lower gate of Phoenix park saluted by obsequious policemen and proceeded past
               Kingsbridge along the northern quays. The viceroy was most cordially greeted on his
               way through the metropolis.</p></location>
     <location name="Rory O'More Bridge" lat="53.34629" lon="-6.28539">
          <p>At Bloody bridge Mr Thomas Kernan beyond the river greeted him vainly from afar.</p>
     </location>
     <location name="Father Mathew Bridge" lat="53.34507" lon="-6.27711"><p>Between Queen’s and
               Whitworth bridges lord Dudley’s viceregal carriages passed and were unsaluted
          by</p></location>
     <location name="29 Kildare Street" lat="53.33976" lon="-6.25716"><p>Mr Dudley White, B. L., M.
               A., who stood on Arran quay outside</p></location>
     <location name="Arran Quay" lat="53.34612" lon="-6.28141"><p>Mrs M. E. White’s, the
               pawnbroker’s, at the corner of Arran street west stroking his nose with his
               forefinger, undecided whether he should arrive at Phibsborough more quickly by a
               triple change of tram or by hailing a car or on foot through Smithfield, Constitution
               hill and Broadstone terminus. In the porch of Four Courts Richie Goulding with the
               costbag of Goulding, Collis and Ward saw him with surprise.</p></location>
     <location name="O'Donovan Rossa Bridge" lat="53.34492" lon="-6.27354"><p>Past Richmond bridge
               at the doorstep of </p></location>
     <location name="Ormond Quay Upper" lat="53.34490" lon="-6.27252"><p>the office of Reuben J
               Dodd, solicitor, agent for the Patriotic Insurance Company, an elderly female about
               to enter changed her plan and retracing her steps</p><p>by King’s windows smiled
               credulously on the representative of His Majesty. From its sluice in Wood quay wall
               under </p></location>
     <location name="Wood Quay" lat="53.34459" lon="-6.27241"><p>Tom Devan’s office Poddle river
               hung out in fealty a tongue of liquid sewage. Above the crossblind of
          the</p></location>
     <location name="Ormond Quay Upper" lat="53.34490" lon="-6.27252"><p>Ormond hotel, gold by
               bronze, Miss Kennedy’s head by Miss Douce’s head watched and admired. On Ormond quay
               Mr Simon Dedalus, steering his way from the greenhouse for</p>
          <p>the subsheriff’s office, stood still in midstreet and brought his hat low. His
               Excellency graciously returned Mr Dedalus’ greeting. From Cahill’s corner the
               reverend Hugh C. Love, M. A., made obeisance unperceived, mindful of lords deputies
               whose hands benignant had held of yore rich <reference to="English law">advowsons.</reference></p></location>
     <location name="Grattan Bridge" lat="53.34527" lon="-6.26916"><p>On Grattan bridge Lenehan and
               M’Coy, taking leave of each other, watched the carriages go by.</p></location>
     <location name="11 Wellington Quay" lat="53.34495" lon="-6.26774">Passing by Roger Greene’s
          office and</location>
     <location name="2 Wellington Quay" lat="53.34485" lon="-6.26853">
          <p>Dollard’s big red printinghouse Gerty MacDowell, carrying the Catesby’s cork lino
               letters for her father who was laid up, knew by the style it was the lord and lady
               lieutenant but she couldn’t see what Her Excellency had on because the tram
          and</p></location>
     <location name="Granby Row" lat="53.35343" lon="-6.26759">
          <p>Spring’s big yellow furniture van had to stop in front of her on account of its being
               the lord lieutenant.</p></location>
     <location name="Parliament Street" lat="53.34380" lon="-6.27017"><p>Beyond Lundy Foot’s from
               the shaded door of Kavanagh’s winerooms John Wyse Nolan smiled with unseen coldness
               towards the lord lieutenantgeneral and general governor of Ireland. The Right
               Honourable William Humble, earl of Dudley, <reference to="Knight Grand Cross of Royal Victorian Order">G. C. V. O.</reference>, passed Micky Anderson’s all
               times ticking watches and</p></location>
     <location name="Dame Street" lat="53.34367" lon="-6.26841"><p>Henry and James’s wax smartsuited
               freshcheeked models, the gentleman <allusion who="Henry James">Henry, _dernier cri_ James.</allusion> Over against Dame gate
               Tom Rochford and Nosey Flynn watched the approach of the cavalcade. Tom Rochford,
               seeing the eyes of lady Dudley fixed on him, took his thumbs quickly out of the
               pockets of his claret waistcoat and doffed his cap to her. A charming _soubrette,_
               great</p><p>Marie Kendall, with dauby cheeks and lifted skirt smiled daubily from her
               poster upon William Humble, earl of Dudley, and upon lieutenantcolonel H. G.
               Heseltine, and also upon the honourable Gerald Ward A. D. C. From the window of the
               D. B. C. Buck Mulligan gaily, and Haines gravely, gazed down on the viceregal
               equipage over the shoulders of eager guests, whose mass of forms darkened the
               chessboard whereon John Howard Parnell looked intently. In Fownes’s street Dilly
               Dedalus, straining her sight upward from Chardenal’s first French primer, saw
               sunshades spanned and wheelspokes spinning in the glare.</p></location>
     <location name="College Green" lat="53.34412" lon="-6.26078"><p>John Henry Menton, filling the
               doorway of Commercial Buildings, stared from winebig oyster eyes, holding a fat gold
               hunter watch not looked at in his fat left hand not feeling it. Where the foreleg of
               <person who="King William III">King Billy’s horse</person> pawed the air Mrs Breen plucked her hastening husband back from
               under the hoofs of the outriders. She shouted in his ear the tidings. Understanding,
               he shifted his tomes to his left breast and saluted the second carriage. The
               honourable Gerald Ward A. D. C., agreeably surprised, made haste to reply. At
               Ponsonby’s corner a jaded white flagon H. halted and four tallhatted white flagons
               halted behind him, E.L.Y.’S, while outriders pranced past and carriages. Opposite
               Pigott’s music warerooms Mr Denis J Maginni, professor of dancing &amp;c, gaily
               apparelled, gravely walked, outpassed by a viceroy and unobserved. By the provost’s
               wall came jauntily Blazes Boylan, stepping in tan shoes and socks with skyblue clocks
               to the refrain of <allusion who="CW Murphy and Dan Lipton">_My girl’s a Yorkshire girl._</allusion></p>
          <p>Blazes Boylan presented to the leaders’ skyblue frontlets and high action a skyblue
               tie, a widebrimmed straw hat at a rakish angle and a suit of indigo serge. His hands
               in his jacket pockets forgot to salute but he offered to the three ladies the bold
               admiration of his eyes and the red flower between his lips. As they drove along
               Nassau street His Excellency drew the attention of his bowing consort to the
               programme of music which was being discoursed in College park. Unseen brazen highland
               laddies blared and drumthumped after the _cortège_:</p>
          <p> But though she’s a factory lass And wears no fancy clothes. Baraabum. Yet I’ve a sort
               of a Yorkshire relish for My little Yorkshire rose. Baraabum.</p>
          <p>Thither of the wall the quartermile flat handicappers, M. C. Green, H. Shrift, T. M.
               Patey, C. Scaife, J. B. Jeffs, G. N. Morphy, F. Stevenson, C. Adderly and W. C.
               Huggard, started in pursuit. Striding past</p><p> Finn’s hotel Cashel Boyle O’Connor
               Fitzmaurice Tisdall Farrell stared through a fierce eyeglass across the carriages at
               the head of Mr M. E. Solomons in the window of the Austro-Hungarian viceconsulate.
               Deep in Leinster street by Trinity’s postern a loyal king’s man, Hornblower, touched
               his <reference to="Trinity College Porters">tallyho cap.</reference></p></location>
     <location name="Merrion Square" lat="53.33945" lon="-6.24888">
          <p>As the glossy horses pranced by Merrion square Master Patrick Aloysius Dignam, waiting,
               saw salutes being given to the gent with the topper and raised also his new black cap
               with fingers greased by porksteak paper. His collar too sprang up. The viceroy, on
               his way to inaugurate the Mirus bazaar in aid of funds for Mercer’s hospital, drove
               with his following towards Lower Mount street. He passed a blind stripling
               opposite</p></location>
     <location name="Mount Street Lower" lat="53.33894" lon="-6.24715"><p> Broadbent’s. In Lower
               Mount street a pedestrian in a brown macintosh, eating dry bread, passed swiftly and
               unscathed across the viceroy’s path. At the Royal Canal bridge, from his hoarding, Mr
               Eugene Stratton, his blub lips agrin, bade all comers welcome to Pembroke
               township.</p></location>
     <location name="Haddington Road" lat="53.33324" lon="-6.24710">
          <p>At Haddington road corner two sanded women halted themselves, an umbrella and a bag in
               which eleven cockles rolled to view with wonder the lord mayor and lady mayoress
               without his golden chain.</p></location>
     <location name="Northumberland Road" lat="53.33548" lon="-6.23933"><p>On Northumberland and
               Lansdowne roads His Excellency acknowledged punctually salutes from rare male
               walkers, the salute of two small schoolboys at the garden gate of the <reference to="Queen Victoria and Prince Albert">house said to have been admired by the
                    late queen when visiting the Irish capital with her husband, the prince consort,
                    in 1849</reference> and the salute of Almidano Artifoni’s sturdy trousers
               swallowed by a closing door.</p></location>

</ulysses>